<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 20:27:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[乔·拜登与习近平在军事、经济问题上发生分歧]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/FvilMKflkrYZQdGP7GSAh5f5V5c=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/47OZBB6DJZPCBBXDPLRZ52XHGM.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden shakes hands with Chinese President Xi Jinping at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登在菲洛丽庄园与中国国家主席习近平握手。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/uJlbUuBKlrkFU-CkBFWK1pCOyn8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4LSUN2CXHZKPXNOXEZKFD47QI4.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping attend a bilateral meeting at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经济合作组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平出席在菲洛丽庄园举行的双边会议。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/1aQy68ht2GBcwt8yS92TftHRBS0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/IXQBFFPVX5NWBIPIGGTFBAM2GE.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden welcomes Chinese President Xi Jinping at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登在菲洛丽庄园欢迎中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tqs78ae9Y1UTE522yIVIOzSVmBI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/P3ULMM4OFBJNRKE5X3M2YDA7FQ.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登在菲洛丽庄园会见中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TG1TEqoix0BmSLzAs_2ZQkKdhx0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XVZII463FBIDNM7WDJMOYPZZ6Q.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden disembarks from Air Force One at San Francisco International Airport, as he arrives to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 14 日，美国总统乔·拜登在旧金山国际机场从空军一号下机，抵达美国加利福尼亚州旧金山参加亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会。 REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lTdjpZN9pb-WDBwFVbkn4Qq-Rig=/1878x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JFCDJ65EHNIW7MVYN3IPSOJ6AQ.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping waves as he arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的APEC（亚太经合组织）峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small/资料照片</figcaption></figure>                       <p>U.S. President Joe Biden met Chinese leader Xi Jinping for the first time in a year on Wednesday for talks that <a href="https://www.reuters.com/podcasts/biden-meet-xi-san-francisco-2023-11-12/?%24web_only=true&amp;_branch_match_id=1161293349163474432&amp;utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_medium=marketing&amp;_branch_referrer=H4sIAAAAAAAAA8soKSkottLXz8nMy9YrSi0tSS0q1kvOz9VP1Q9wSwzOLi7O8XZNAgBzJOFkJgAAAA%3D%3D">may ease friction</a> between the two superpowers over military conflicts, drug-trafficking and artificial intelligence.翻译:美国总统乔·拜登周三与中国领导人习近平一年来首次会面，会谈<a href="https://www.reuters.com/podcasts/biden-meet-xi-san-francisco-2023-11-12/?%24web_only=true&amp;_branch_match_id=1161293349163474432&amp;utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_medium=marketing&amp;_branch_referrer=H4sIAAAAAAAAA8soKSkottLXz8nMy9YrSi0tSS0q1kvOz9VP1Q9wSwzOLi7O8XZNAgBzJOFkJgAAAA%3D%3D">可能会缓解两个超级大国之间在军事冲突、贩毒和人工智能方面的摩擦</a>。</p>   <p>Biden welcomed the Chinese leader at the Filoli estate, a country house and gardens about 30 miles (48 km) south of San Francisco, where they will move later for a summit of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum.翻译:拜登在位于旧金山以南约 30 英里（48 公里）的菲洛丽庄园（Filoli Estate）欢迎了中国领导人，这是一座乡村别墅和花园，他们稍后将前往那里参加亚太经济合作组织（APEC）论坛峰会。</p>   <p>The U.S. and Chinese leaders will be seeking to reduce friction in what many see as the world's most important relationship, but deep progress on the vast differences separating them may have to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">wait for another day</a>.翻译:美国和中国领导人将寻求减少这一被许多人视为世界上最重要的关系中的摩擦，但在解决两国之间的巨大分歧方面取得深入进展可能需要<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">等到另一天</a>。</p>   <p>Officials on both sides of the Pacific have set expectations low as Biden and Xi are set to discuss Taiwan, the South China Sea, the Israel-Hamas war, Russia's invasion of Ukraine, North Korea and human rights - areas where the leaders have been unable to resolve long-standing disagreements.翻译:由于拜登和习近平将讨论台湾、南中国海、以色列-哈马斯战争、俄罗斯入侵乌克兰、朝鲜和人权等领导人未能讨论的领域，太平洋两岸的官员都降低了预期以解决长期存在的分歧。</p>   <p>Biden and Xi <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/">arrived in San Francisco</a> on Tuesday where they will both participate in the (APEC) summit.翻译:拜登和习近平周二<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/">抵达旧金山</a>，他们将参加亚太经合组织峰会。</p>   <p>Leaders from the 21-country group - and hundreds of CEOs in San Francisco to court them - meet amid relative <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">Chinese economic weakness</a>, Beijing's territorial feuds with neighbors, and a Middle East conflict that is dividing the United States from allies.翻译:来自21个国家的领导人以及在旧金山向他们示好的数百名首席执行官在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">中国相对疲软的经济</a>、北京与邻国的领土争端以及导致美国与盟友分裂的中东冲突中召开会议。</p>   <p>Experts say Xi will be looking for a smooth summit with Biden to show those at home concerned about the economy and dwindling foreign investment that he can successfully handle relations between the world's two largest economies.翻译:专家表示，习近平将寻求与拜登举行顺利的峰会，向那些担心经济和外国投资减少的国内人士表明，他能够成功处理世界两大经济体之间的关系。</p>   <p>Efforts to carefully choreograph Xi's visit may be upended in San Francisco despite <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/san-francisco-patches-over-homelessness-drug-abuse-apec-2023-11-15/">efforts to drive homeless people</a> from the streets. The route from the airport to the conference site was lined with demonstrators for and against China's ruling Communist Party, an unusual sight for Xi, who last visited the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/cnews-us-usa-china-idCAKBN1792KA-OCATP">United States in 2017</a>.翻译:尽管旧金山努力<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/san-francisco-patches-over-homelessness-drug-abuse-apec-2023-11-15/">将无家可归的人</a>赶出街头，但精心策划习近平访问的努力可能会在旧金山遭到颠覆。从机场到会议地点的路上，挤满了支持和反对中国执政共产党的示威者，这对于习近平来说是不寻常的景象，他上次访问<a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/cnews-us-usa-china-idCAKBN1792KA-OCATP">美国是在 2017 年</a>。</p>   <p>The venue for the bilateral summit, far from the APEC conference location, offers the leaders a combination of security, serenity and remoteness.翻译:双边峰会举办地远离APEC会议地点，为领导人提供了安全、宁静和偏僻的环境。</p>   <p>Biden has sought direct diplomacy with Xi, betting that a personal relationship he has cultivated for a dozen years with the most powerful Chinese leader since Mao Zedong might salvage ties that are increasingly turning hostile.翻译:拜登寻求与习近平进行直接外交，押注他与自毛泽东以来最强大的中国领导人十几年建立的个人关系可能会挽救日益变得敌对的关系。</p>   <p>Chong Ja Ian, a political science professor at the National University of Singapore, said the two sides are engaged in what Mao referred to during the Chinese civil war as "talk and fight, fight and talk".翻译:新加坡国立大学政治学教授庄嘉欣表示，两国正在进行毛泽东在中国内战期间所说的“谈打打打谈”。</p>   <p>"That is, to talk while building up forces," Chong said.翻译:“就是一边说话一边积蓄力量，”冲说。</p>   <p>The White House hopes the meeting could set the stage for further talks.翻译:白宫希望这次会议能为进一步谈判奠定基础。</p>   <p>"We're all expecting that this will be a productive discussion today, and hopefully, a precursor to much more communication and dialogue between our two teams going forward," White House spokesperson John Kirby told reporters ahead of the meeting.</p>    <h 1="">IRAN, ELECTION INTERFERENCE, FENTANYL</h>  <p>During the meeting, Biden is expected to press Xi to use China's influence to urge Iran to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/irans-axis-resistance-against-israel-faces-trial-by-fire-2023-11-15/">avoid provocative action</a> or encouraging its proxies to enter the fray in what, moves that could spread the Israel-Hamas conflict across the Middle East.翻译:在会议期间，预计拜登将敦促习近平利用中国的影响力敦促伊朗<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/irans-axis-resistance-against-israel-faces-trial-by-fire-2023-11-15/">避免采取挑衅行动</a>，或鼓励其代理人卷入冲突，此举可能会将以色列与哈马斯的冲突蔓延到整个中东地区。</p>   <p>He is also expected to raise alleged Chinese operations to influence foreign elections, the status of U.S. citizens that Washington believes are wrongly detained in China and human rights.翻译:预计他还将提出涉嫌中国影响外国选举的行动、华盛顿认为在中国被错误拘留的美国公民的地位以及人权问题。</p>   <p>U.S. officials expected concrete steps to restore staff-level conversations between the two countries on issues from military-to-military communications to reducing the flow of fentanyl, managing the growth of artificial intelligence technologies, and managing trade and climate.翻译:美国官员预计将采取具体措施，恢复两国人员层面的对话，讨论从军事通讯到减少芬太尼的流动、管理人工智能技术的发展以及管理贸易和气候等问题。</p>   <p>Many of the chemicals used to make fentanyl come from China, U.S. officials say.翻译:美国官员表示，许多用于制造芬太尼的化学品来自中国。</p>   <p>Before the meeting, both countries <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/us-china-pledge-cooperation-climate-following-california-talks-2023-11-15/">backed a new renewable energy target</a> and said they would work to reduce methane and plastic pollution, a renewal of climate cooperate suspended after former U.S. Speaker of the House <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-premier-evil-neighbour-next-door-is-showing-off-her-power-our-door-2022-08-05/">Nancy Pelosi visited Taiwan</a> in 2022.翻译:会前，两国都<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/us-china-pledge-cooperation-climate-following-california-talks-2023-11-15/">支持新的可再生能源目标</a>，并表示将努力减少甲烷和塑料污染，这是继美国前众议院议长<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-premier-evil-neighbour-next-door-is-showing-off-her-power-our-door-2022-08-05/">南希·佩洛西 2022 年访问台湾</a>后暂停的气候合作更新。</p>   <p>Biden, 80, presides over an economy that has outperformed expectations and most rich nations after the COVID-19 pandemic. He is seeking a second term in office.翻译:80 岁的拜登领导的经济在 COVID-19 大流行后的表现超出了预期，也超出了大多数富裕国家的表现。他正在寻求连任。</p>   <p>He has corralled the nation's traditional allies from Europe to Asia to confront Russia in Ukraine, although some have differences over the Israel-Hamas conflict.翻译:他召集了该国从欧洲到亚洲的传统盟友，在乌克兰对抗俄罗斯，尽管其中一些盟友在以色列与哈马斯冲突问题上存在分歧。</p>   <p>Xi, a decade Biden's junior, has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/ways-chinas-xi-jinping-amassed-power-over-decade-2022-10-10/">tightened control</a> over policy, state leaders, the media and military and changing the constitution. But <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">economic challenges</a> have thrown the country off its three-decade growth trajectory.翻译:比拜登小十岁的习近平<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/ways-chinas-xi-jinping-amassed-power-over-decade-2022-10-10/">加强了对政策、国家领导人、媒体和军队的控制</a>，并修改了宪法。但<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">经济挑战</a>使该国脱离了三年的增长轨迹。</p>   <p>Government officials across the region expect Beijing to test Washington in coming weeks, taking advantage of the United States' perceived shift in focus on Ukraine and Israel as it pursues its own ambitions in the Indo-Pacific.翻译:该地区的政府官员预计，北京将在未来几周内考验华盛顿，利用美国在印度太平洋地区追求自己的野心时将重点转移到乌克兰和以色列的机会。</p>   <p>Biden is expected to tell Xi that U.S. commitments in the Indo-Pacific are unchanged. China has worried its neighbors in recent years with steps in the Taiwan Strait, South China Sea and East China Sea, areas of international dispute.翻译:预计拜登将告诉习近平，美国在印太地区的承诺没有改变。近年来，中国在台湾海峡、南海和东海等国际争议地区采取的行动令邻国感到担忧。</p>   <p>(This story has been refiled to correct typos in paragraphs 10, 11, 23 and 25)翻译:（这个故事已重新提交以纠正第 10、11、23 和 25 段中的拼写错误）</p>    <span>Reporting by Trevor Hunnicutt; Additional reporting by Steve Holland, Michael Martina, Martin Pollard Jeff Mason and David Brunnstrom; Editing by Heather Timmons, Angus MacSwan, Don Durfee and Josie Kao翻译:特雷弗·亨尼卡特报道； Steve Holland、Michael Martina、Martin Pollard Jeff Mason 和 David Brunnstrom 的补充报道；编辑：Heather Timmons、Angus MacSwan、Don Durfee 和 Josie Kao</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 19:46:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZYRPUF6GFRLTHLGM6Y6UA65MXU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Trevor Hunnicutt]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA (CORRECTED, UPDATE 3, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[国际原子能机构报告显示，伊朗阻碍联合国，其核浓缩活动取得进展]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Iran continues to enrich to 60% at rate of 3 kg a month</li>  <li>Issues the IAEA is seeking urgent progress on are stuck</li>  <li>Iran rebuffs Grossi request to undo barring of inspectors</li>  <li>Despite all that, resolution at next IAEA board unlikely</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>伊朗继续以每月3公斤的速度浓缩至60%</li><li>国际原子能机构寻求紧急进展的问题陷入困境</li><li>伊朗拒绝格罗西取消检查员禁令的请求</li><li>尽管如此，下一届国际原子能机构理事会不太可能做出决议</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/-0oRtgTG-OQt0KDP_fggFwueHOk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HWPLGTZ4EVJOHGP5CZSIRYAHQE.jpg" alt="The logo of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) is seen at the organisation's headquarters in Vienna翻译:国际原子能机构 (IAEA) 的标志位于该组织位于维也纳的总部" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) is seen at the organisation's headquarters in Vienna翻译:国际原子能机构 (IAEA) 的标志位于该组织位于维也纳的总部, Austria, June 5, 2023. REUTERS/Leonhard Foeger/File Photo翻译:2023 年 6 月 5 日，国际原子能机构 (IAEA) 的标志出现在该组织位于奥地利维也纳的总部。路透社/Leonhard Foeger/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UwsSlArxWEk23l_y5q3faGt5GY4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/Q3ED3TX6MZJKNNTYRQJE4DFRGE.jpg" alt="The Iranian flag flutters in front of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) organisation's headquarters in Vienna翻译:伊朗国旗在维也纳国际原子能机构（IAEA）总部前飘扬" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The Iranian flag flutters in front of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) organisation's headquarters in Vienna翻译:伊朗国旗在维也纳国际原子能机构（IAEA）总部前飘扬, Austria, June 5, 2023. REUTERS/Leonhard Foeger/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Psd3Mu1hE4smNTlXP3CppMhEX1I=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MGMXH67AQFIZ3M6NRML37P3OXE.jpg" alt="The Iranian and other flags flutter in front of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) organisation's headquarters in Vienna翻译:伊朗和其他国家的旗帜在维也纳国际原子能机构（IAEA）总部前飘扬" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The Iranian and other flags flutter in front of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) organisation's headquarters in Vienna翻译:伊朗和其他国家的旗帜在维也纳国际原子能机构（IAEA）总部前飘扬, Austria, June 5, 2023. REUTERS/Leonhard Foeger/File Photo</figcaption></figure>                 <p>Iran has enough uranium enriched to up to 60% purity, close to weapons-grade, for three atom bombs by the International Atomic Energy Agency's definition and is still stonewalling the agency on key issues, confidential IAEA reports showed on Wednesday.翻译:国际原子能机构的机密报告周三显示，伊朗拥有足够的浓缩铀，纯度高达 60%，接近武器级，足以制造国际原子能机构定义的三颗原子弹，并且仍在关键问题上阻碍该机构。</p>   <p>Iran's steady progress in enriching to very high levels while failing to provide the International Atomic Energy Agency with the cooperation it demands on a growing list of issues presents a challenge to both the agency and Western powers that have repeatedly called on Iran to reverse course.翻译:伊朗在铀浓缩方面取得了稳步进展，达到了非常高的水平，但却未能向国际原子能机构提供其在越来越多的问题上所要求的合作，这对该机构和一再呼吁伊朗改变路线的西方国家都构成了挑战。</p>   <p>Iran's stock of uranium enriched to up to 60% grew by 6.7 kg (14.8 pounds) to 128.3 kg (282.9 pounds) since the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/iaea-reports-no-progress-iran-uranium-stock-enriched-60-grows-2023-09-04/">last report</a> on Sept. 4, one of the two reports to member states seen by Reuters said. That is more than three times the roughly 42 kg (92.6 pounds) that by the IAEA's definition is theoretically enough, if enriched further, for a nuclear bomb.翻译:路透社看到的两份向成员国提交的报告之一称，自9月4日<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/iaea-reports-no-progress-iran-uranium-stock-enriched-60-grows-2023-09-04/">上次报告</a>以来，伊朗浓缩铀库存高达60%，增加了6.7公斤（14.8磅），达到128.3公斤（282.9磅）。根据国际原子能机构的定义，如果进一步浓缩，理论上足以制造一枚核弹，这个重量大约是 42 公斤（92.6 磅）的三倍多。</p>   <p>"That's quite an amount, especially if you don't use it for anything," a senior diplomat said, referring to the fact Iran is the only country to enrich to such a high level without producing nuclear weapons. Weapons-grade is around 90%.翻译:一位高级外交官表示：“这是一个相当大的数额，特别是如果你不将其用于任何用途的话。”他指的是伊朗是唯一一个在不生产核武器的情况下浓缩到如此高水平的国家。武器等级约为90%。</p>   <p>Iran has enough uranium enriched to lower levels for more bombs, but it denies seeking such weapons.翻译:伊朗拥有足够的浓缩铀来制造更多炸弹，但它否认寻求此类武器。</p>   <p>The rate at which Iran is enriching to 60%, however, has slowed to around 3 kg (6.6 pounds) a month from 9 kg (19.8 pounds) earlier this year, which diplomats said is the apparent result of indirect negotiations with the United States that led to a prisoner exchange between the two countries in September.翻译:然而，伊朗浓缩至 60% 的速度已从今年早些时候的每月 9 公斤（19.8 磅）放缓至每月 3 公斤（6.6 磅）左右，外交官表示，这显然是与美国间接谈判的结果这导致两国于九月进行了囚犯交换。</p>   <p>The number of cascades, or clusters, of uranium-enriching centrifuges in operation is also unchanged, the report said. Tensions between the agency and Iran, however, have only increased.翻译:报告称，正在运行的浓缩铀离心机的级联或集群数量也没有变化。然而，该机构与伊朗之间的紧张关系有增无减。</p>   <p>The U.N. nuclear watchdog's 35-nation Board of Governors passed a resolution a year ago ordering Iran to comply with an IAEA investigation into uranium traces found at three undeclared sites. Since then the IAEA has narrowed the list of sites to two but little other progress has been made.</p>    <h 1="">NO CONSEQUENCES</h>  <p>The IAEA's list of pressing issues in Iran has also grown, with a deal in March to re-install monitoring equipment including surveillance cameras removed last year at Iran's behest having only partially been honoured, and Tehran's so-called "de-designation" in September of highly experienced IAEA inspectors.翻译:国际原子能机构在伊朗面临的紧迫问题清单也在增加，3月份达成了一项重新安装监控设备的协议，其中包括去年应伊朗要求拆除的监控摄像头，但仅部分得到履行，而德黑兰在9月份所谓的“取消指定”经验丰富的原子能机构视察员。</p>   <p>The second report issued on Wednesday said there had been no progress on those issues. IAEA chief Rafael Grossi wrote to Iran asking it to reconsider the de-designation, and Iran replied on Wednesday to say merely that it was "exploring possibilities to address the request", the report said.翻译:周三发布的第二份报告称，这些问题尚未取得进展。报道称，国际原子能机构主席拉斐尔·格罗西致信伊朗，要求其重新考虑取消指定的决定，伊朗周三回复称，它正在“探索满足这一请求的可能性”。</p>   <p>"This measure, while formally permitted... was exercised by Iran in a manner that directly and seriously affects the Agency's ability to conduct effectively its verification activities in Iran, in particular at the enrichment facilities," the second report said.翻译:第二份报告称：“这项措施虽然得到正式许可……但伊朗采取的方式直接严重影响了原子能机构在伊朗有效开展核查活动的能力，特别是在浓缩设施方面。”</p>   <p>"The (IAEA) Director General (Grossi) continues to strongly condemn Iran's sudden withdrawal of the designations of several experienced Agency inspectors," it added.翻译:声明补充说：“（国际原子能机构）总干事（格罗西）继续强烈谴责伊朗突然撤回对几名经验丰富的原子能机构视察员的任命。”</p>   <p>Despite the standoffs over the inspectors, particles and monitoring equipment, Iran is unlikely to face serious consequences when the IAEA board meets next week.翻译:尽管在检查员、颗粒物和监测设备方面存在僵局，但在下周国际原子能机构理事会会议上，伊朗不太可能面临严重后果。</p>   <p>While the United States and its European allies have previously threatened to pass another binding resolution against Iran, diplomats say that will not happen this time for reasons including avoiding a diplomatic escalation with Iran while attention is focused on <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israel-raids-gazas-al-shifa-hospital-2023-11-15/">Israel's conflict with Hamas in Gaza</a>.翻译:尽管美国及其欧洲盟友此前曾威胁要通过另一项针对伊朗的具有约束力的决议，但外交官表示，这次不会发生，原因包括避免与伊朗的外交升级，同时人们的注意力集中在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israel-raids-gazas-al-shifa-hospital-2023-11-15/">以色列与加沙哈马斯的冲突</a>上。</p>    <span>Additional reporting by John Irish in Paris; Editing by Toby Chopra and Jonathan Oatis翻译:约翰·爱尔兰在巴黎的补充报道；托比·乔普拉和乔纳森·奥蒂斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 19:31:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FQRDXVEGUJIOJF32TCE2LIRRNM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/irans-nuclear-enrichment-advances-it-stonewalls-un-iaea-reports-show-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Francois Murphy]]></author>
            
                
                <category>IRAN</category>
                
                <category>NUCLEAR/IAEA (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国议员就乔恩·斯图尔特 (Jon Stewart) 的中国内容质疑苹果]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ihlwvgzsGnBRqDzxZ30h6kE-pl0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3MDUJ3B26FNB5MS7MYOFDRNI5Q.jpg" alt="People arrive on the red carpet before comedian and talk show host Jon Stewart receives the Mark Twain Prize For American Humor at The Kennedy Center翻译:人们在喜剧演员兼脱口秀主持人乔恩·斯图尔特在肯尼迪中心接受马克·吐温美国幽默奖之前走上红地毯" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Comedian and talk show host Jon Stewart arrives on the red carpet before receiving the Mark Twain Prize For American Humor, at The Kennedy Center in Washington, U.S.,&nbsp;April 24 2022. &nbsp;REUTERS/Cheriss May/File Photo翻译:喜剧演员兼脱口秀主持人乔恩·斯图尔特于 2022 年 4 月 24 日在美国华盛顿肯尼迪中心登上红地毯，然后接受马克·吐温美国幽默奖。路透社/Cheriss May/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S. lawmakers asked Apple Inc to explain the abrupt end of political comedian Jon Stewart's television show on its streaming service, according to a letter made public on Wednesday, citing concerns that content related to China was behind the cancellation.翻译:根据周三公开的一封信，美国立法者要求苹果公司解释政治喜剧演员乔恩·斯图尔特在其流媒体服务上的电视节目突然结束的原因，理由是担心取消节目背后涉及与中国有关的内容。</p>   <p>The New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/19/business/media/jon-stewart-the-problem-ends.html" target="_blank">reported last month</a> that Stewart's show on Apple's streaming service was ending, the result of creative differences. The newspaper said Stewart told members of his staff that potential show topics related to China and artificial intelligence were causing concern to Apple executives.翻译:《纽约时报》 <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/19/business/media/jon-stewart-the-problem-ends.html" target="_blank">上个月报道</a>称，由于创意分歧，斯图尔特在苹果流媒体服务上的节目即将结束。该报称，斯图尔特告诉他的员工，与中国和人工智能相关的潜在展会主题引起了苹果高管的担忧。</p>   <p>Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a> declined comment to the Times.翻译:苹果公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a>拒绝向《纽约时报》发表评论。</p>   <p>"While companies have the right to determine what content is appropriate for their streaming service, the coercive tactics of a foreign power should not be directly or indirectly influencing these determinations," the Republican and Democratic leaders of the House of Representatives' Select Committee on Competition with the Chinese Communist Party said in the letter to Apple Chief Executive Tim Cook.翻译:众议院竞争特别委员会的共和党和民主党领导人表示：“虽然公司有权决定哪些内容适合其流媒体服务，但外国势力的胁迫策略不应直接或间接影响这些决定。”与中国共产党在给苹果首席执行官蒂姆·库克的信中说。</p>   <p>The letter asked representatives of Apple for a briefing on its concerns by Dec. 15, 2023. It said the committee also expected to speak with representatives of Stewart.翻译:这封信要求苹果代表在 2023 年 12 月 15 日之前就其担忧进行简报。信中称，委员会还希望与斯图尔特的代表进行交谈。</p>   <p>"To reassure the creative community in light of these reports, we also respectfully request that Apple publicly commit that content that could be perceived as critical of the CCP or the PRC is welcome on Apple TV+ and other Apple services," said the letter, signed by the panel's Republican chairperson, Representative Michael Gallagher, and Representative Raja Krishnamoorthi, the panel's ranking Democrat.翻译:信中写道：“为了根据这些报告让创意界放心，我们还诚挚地要求苹果公司公开承诺，Apple TV+ 和其他苹果服务上欢迎可能被视为批评中共或中华人民共和国的内容。”由该小组的共和党主席、众议员迈克尔·加拉格尔（Michael Gallagher）和该小组的民主党众议员拉贾·克里希纳莫蒂（Raja Krishnamoorthi）组成。</p>   <p>Representatives for Stewart and Apple did not respond to Reuters' requests for comment.翻译:斯图尔特和苹果的代表没有回应路透社的置评请求。</p>   <p>The letter was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/tricky-politics-menu-chinas-xi-us-business-dinner-2023-11-14/">released ahead of a dinner</a> expected on Wednesday night at which top U.S. business leaders were to dine with Chinese President Xi Jinping in San Francisco as he seeks to court American companies and counter his country's recent struggles to entice foreign investment.翻译:这封信是在周三晚上举行的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/tricky-politics-menu-chinas-xi-us-business-dinner-2023-11-14/">晚宴之前发布的</a>，届时美国高层商界领袖将在旧金山与中国国家主席习近平共进晚餐，习近平寻求讨好美国公司，并应对中国最近在吸引外国投资方面的困难。</p>   <p>The dinner on the margins of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum would follow a day of talks between Xi and U.S. President Joe Biden, aimed at stabilizing fraught ties between the world's two largest economies.翻译:在亚太经合组织（APEC）论坛间隙举行的晚宴之前，习近平和美国总统乔·拜登进行了一天的会谈，旨在稳定世界最大两个经济体之间紧张的关系。</p>   <p>The House committee has made China's controls on media a focus of its work.翻译:众议院委员会已将中国对媒体的控制作为其工作重点。</p>   <p>U.S. lawmakers have long expressed concerns about potential Chinese government censorship given the ruling Communist Party’s strict media controls. The concern is particularly acute for Hollywood films, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/china-film/">as some studios have altered</a> or self-censored scripts to appease Chinese government minders and gain access to the country’s market.翻译:鉴于执政的共产党对媒体的严格控制，美国立法者长期以来一直对中国政府可能进行的审查表示担忧。对于好莱坞电影来说，这种担忧尤其严重，<a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/china-film/">因为一些电影公司已经改变</a>或自我审查剧本，以安抚中国政府监管人员并进入该国市场。</p>    <span>Reporting by Patricia Zengerle and Michael Martina; Additional reporting by Stephen Nellis and Dawn Chmielewski; Editing by Stephen Coates翻译:帕特里夏·曾格尔 (Patricia Zengerle) 和迈克尔·马丁纳 (Michael Martina) 报道； Stephen Nellis 和 Dawn Chmielewski 的补充报道；斯蒂芬·科茨编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 19:25:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6KO56ZNXIFLGJPAQSQP23VJLFM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/media-telecom/us-lawmakers-question-apple-over-jon-stewarts-china-content-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Patricia Zengerle, Michael Martina]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CONGRESS</category>
                
                <category>APPLE (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美元因零售销售数据上涨，美联储降息日期不明]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/MuEa6XE1m4y5QPDfu0feX-x7KzY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MMZ3XFL5RBPETA3FNYTXFW4MWA.jpg" alt="Illustration shows U.S. Dollar banknotes翻译:插图显示美元纸币" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Dollar banknotes are seen in this illustration taken July 17, 2022. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:这张 2022 年 7 月 17 日拍摄的插图中可以看到美元纸币。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>The dollar gained on Wednesday after still strong U.S. retail sales fell less than expected in October, a reminder for the market that a definitive date for the Federal Reserve to cut interest rates is still unknown.翻译:美元周三上涨，此前美国 10 月份零售销售仍强劲，降幅低于预期，提醒市场美联储降息的具体日期仍未知。</p>   <p>The dollar bounced off its biggest drop in a year on Tuesday when the consumer price index (CPI) showed U.S. inflation was cooling faster than expected. But at an annualized 3.2%, the pace of inflation remains well above the Fed's 2% target.翻译:周二，消费者价格指数（CPI）显示美国通胀降温速度快于预期，美元从一年来最大跌幅中反弹。但年化通胀率为 3.2%，仍远高于美联储 2% 的目标。</p>   <p>"Until the market believes that the next Fed move is going to be a cut and believes that concretely, we'll see episodic patches of dollar strength before dollar weakness becomes the trade," said Steven Englander, head of global G10 FX research at Standard Chartered Bank in New York.翻译:标准银行全球G10外汇研究主管史蒂文·英格兰德(Steven Englander)表示，“除非市场相信美联储的下一步行动将是降息，并相信具体而言，在美元疲软成为常态之前，我们将看到美元间歇性走强”。纽约渣打银行。</p>   <p>"Today's data were neutral to slightly stronger than expected," he said. "The market is still not sure on U.S. growth."翻译:“今天的数据是中性至略强于预期，”他说。 “市场仍不确定美国的增长。”</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-retail-sales-fall-slightly-october-2023-11-15/">U.S. retail sales</a> fell for the first time in seven months in October, the Commerce Department's Census Bureau said, while producer prices posted the biggest decline in three-and-a-half years last month, according to the Labor Department's Bureau of Labor Statistics.翻译:美国商务部人口普查局表示，<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-retail-sales-fall-slightly-october-2023-11-15/">美国 10 月份零售额</a>出现七个月以来的首次下降，而美国劳工部劳工统计局的数据显示，上个月生产者价格出现三年半来最大跌幅。</p>   <p>More than 80% of the decline last month in the Producer Price Index for final demand goods was attributed to a 15.3% drop in gasoline prices, BLS said.翻译:BLS 表示，上个月最终需求商品生产者价格指数下降 80% 以上是由于汽油价格下降 15.3%。</p>      <p>"The markets are anticipating rate cuts coming in the first couple of quarters next year," said Roosevelt Bowman, senior investment strategist at Bernstein Private Wealth Management in New York.翻译:纽约伯恩斯坦私人财富管理公司高级投资策略师罗斯福·鲍曼表示：“市场预计明年前几个季度将降息。”</p>   <p>"But in our view, we just don't think that downward momentum in inflation is going to be nearly as fast as what the market is estimating," he said.翻译:“但我们认为，通胀下降势头不会像市场预期的那么快，”他表示。</p>   <p>The dollar index, a measure of the U.S. currency versus six others, rose 0.31%, off its two-month low of 103.98 on Tuesday. The euro was down 0.34% at $1.0842, after touching its highest since August the day before.翻译:衡量美元兑其他六种货币的美元指数周二上涨 0.31%，脱离两个月低点 103.98。欧元兑美元汇率下跌0.34%至1.0842美元，前一天触及8月以来最高点。</p>   <p>Investors have all but eliminated the likelihood of another rate hike when Fed policymakers meet in December, while bets of a rate cut in May 2024 increased to more than 65%, according to the CME Group's FedWatch Tool.翻译:根据 CME 集团的 FedWatch 工具，投资者几乎消除了美联储政策制定者 12 月会议时再次加息的可能性，而对 2024 年 5 月降息的押注增加至 65% 以上。</p>      <p>The fourth quarter in the past two years has not been good for the dollar, which peaked in the third quarter of both 2021 and 2022 and sold off through to January each year, said Brad Bechtel, global head of FX at Jefferies in New York.翻译:杰富瑞驻纽约的全球外汇主管 Brad Bechtel 表示，过去两年的第四季度对美元来说并不好，美元在 2021 年和 2022 年第三季度达到顶峰，然后一直到每年 1 月都遭到抛售。</p>   <p>"I'm not necessarily saying that history is going exactly to repeat itself, but I don't necessarily want to be buying or getting long the dollar just yet," he said. "We need to see more of this play out."翻译:他表示：“我不一定说历史会重演，但我暂时还不一定想买入或做多美元。” “我们需要看到更多这样的事情发生。”</p>   <p>Earlier in Britain, data showed inflation last month eased to 4.6%, its slowest pace in two years. The reading, below forecasts of 4.8%, prompted a reassessment of the outlook for Bank of England policy and dented sterling.翻译:英国早些时候的数据显示，上个月通胀率降至 4.6%，为两年来最低增速。该数据低于 4.8% 的预期，促使人们重新评估英国央行的政策前景，并打压了英镑。</p>   <p>Sterling was last trading at $1.241, down 0.70%. On Tuesday, the pound rose by 1.8% against the dollar, marking its biggest one-day gain in a year.翻译:英镑最新交易价格为 1.241 美元，下跌 0.70%。周二，英镑兑美元上涨1.8%，创下一年来最大单日涨幅。</p>   <p>The Japanese yen weakened 0.65% at 151.36 per dollar.翻译:日元兑美元汇率下跌 0.65%，至 151.36 日元。</p>   <p>Earlier in Japan, data showed the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/japans-economy-contracts-demand-wanes-2023-11-15/">economy contracted</a> in July-September, complicating the Japanese central bank's efforts to ease out of its ultra-easy monetary policy. On Monday, the yen hit a one-year low close to 152.翻译:日本早些时候的数据显示，7 月至 9 月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/japans-economy-contracts-demand-wanes-2023-11-15/">经济出现萎缩</a>，这使得日本央行放松超宽松货币政策的努力变得更加复杂。周一，日元触及一年低点，接近152。</p>   <p>The dollar was knocked back from the 152 level on Monday, after a routine options expiry unleashed some profit-taking that took the yen to around 151.20.翻译:周一，常规期权到期引发了一些获利了结，日元汇率升至 151.20 左右，美元从 152 水平回落。</p>   <p>The offshore Chinese yuan, meanwhile, received some support The offshore yuan , meanwhile, briefly ticked up to a three-month high of $7.2385 against the dollar after domestic industrial output and retail sales growth <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/">beat expectations</a>.翻译:与此同时，离岸人民币获得了一些支撑 在国内工业产出和零售销售增长<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/">超出预期</a>后，离岸人民币兑美元短暂升至三个月高点7.2385美元。</p>   <p>Evidence of ongoing weakness in China's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/">property</a> sector, where data showed sales fell faster in October and investment in real estate slumped, took some of the shine off the rally.翻译:中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/">房地产</a>行业持续疲软的证据显示，10 月份销售下滑更快，房地产投资也大幅下滑，这让涨势黯淡了一些。</p>   <p>The offshore Chinese yuan rose 0.12% versus the greenback at $7.2602 per dollar.翻译:离岸人民币兑美元汇率上涨 0.12%，至每美元 7.2602 美元。</p>    <span>Reporting by Herbert Lash, additional reporting by Amanda Cooper and Brigid Riley; Editing by Lincoln Feast, Angus MacSwan, Chizu Nomiyama and Alexander Smith翻译:赫伯特·拉什 (Herbert Lash) 报道，阿曼达·库珀 (Amanda Cooper) 和布里吉德·莱利 (Brigid Riley) 补充报道；编辑：Lincoln Feast、Angus MacSwan、Chizu Nomiyama 和 Alexander Smith</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 19:17:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RWBD4ZMXDVPS7NQE2PKUAJEXKE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/dollar-down-markets-bet-fed-done-with-hikes-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Herbert Lash]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>FOREX/ (UPDATE 5)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[意大利打击从中国走私芬太尼至美国逮捕六人]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/q17ApiU0bqq2v3yh5BrAc_xeQ4M=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DQ57AQMHKVMXTBZWJYS4QT6WGM.jpg" alt="Italy arrests six in crackdown on fentanyl smuggling from China to U.S翻译:意大利打击从中国走私芬太尼至美国逮捕六人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An undated handout picture released by Guardia di Finanza shows banknotes that were seized as a part of an operation against fentanyl trafficking from China to U.S., in Piacenza, Italy. Guardia di Finanza Press Office/Handout via REUTERS 翻译:金融卫报发布的一张未注明日期的讲义图片显示，意大利皮亚琴察在打击从中国向美国贩运芬太尼的行动中查获的钞票。 Guardia di Finanza 新闻办公室/路透社的讲义</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/3hXmboWQLjwkfzJtjCmE7ixe-hM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CFCW4ALHFJMSXPUISTX34FUEHI.jpg" alt="Italy arrests six in crackdown on fentanyl smuggling from China to U.S翻译:意大利打击从中国走私芬太尼至美国逮捕六人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An undated handout picture released by Guardia di Finanza shows tools that were seized as a part of an operation against fentanyl trafficking from China to U.S., in Piacenza, Italy. Guardia di Finanza Press Office/Handout via REUTERS 翻译:Guardia di Finanza 发布的一张未注明日期的讲义图片显示，在意大利皮亚琴察打击从中国向美国贩运芬太尼的行动中查获的工具。 Guardia di Finanza 新闻办公室/路透社的讲义</figcaption></figure>               <p>Italian police have arrested six people in a crackdown on a network that allegedly played go-between for fentanyl trafficking from China to the United States, Guardia di Finanza police and prosecutors in the northern city of Piacenza said on Wednesday.翻译:北部城市皮亚琴察的金融警卫队警方和检察官周三表示，意大利警方在打击一个涉嫌从中国向美国贩运芬太尼的网络中逮捕了六人。</p>   <p>"It was really good work, achieved through direct cooperation with investigators from the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA)," Piacenza chief prosecutor Grazia Pradella told Reuters, adding that U.S police arrested 11 other people and seized 2 kg of the synthetic drug.翻译:皮亚琴察首席检察官格拉齐亚·普拉德拉 (Grazia Pradella) 告诉路透社：“这确实是一项出色的工作，是通过与美国缉毒局 (DEA) 调查人员的直接合作完成的。”他补充说，美国警方逮捕了另外 11 人，并缴获了 2 公斤合成毒品。</p>   <p>Washington is hoping to secure more cooperation from Beijing in combating production of the potent synthetic opioid fentanyl, a scourge in the United States, when President Joe Biden meets <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">Chinese President Xi Jinping</a> on Wednesday.翻译:当乔·拜登总统周三会见<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">中国国家主席习近平</a>时，华盛顿希望获得北京方面的更多合作，打击强效合成阿片类药物芬太尼的生产，芬太尼在美国是一个祸害。</p>   <p>The rate of drug overdose deaths involving fentanyl more than tripled from 2016 through 2021 in the U.S, according to the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).翻译:根据美国疾病控制与预防中心 (CDC) 的数据，从 2016 年到 2021 年，美国涉及芬太尼的药物过量死亡率增加了两倍多。</p>   <p>Among those arrested in Italy is the alleged head of the network, a 51-year-old Italian man suspected of buying fentanyl from China over the past three years. He sold it on to buyers in the United States, and in one case in Mexico, the chief prosecutor said.翻译:在意大利被捕的人中有一名被指控为该网络负责人的人，他是一名 51 岁的意大利男子，涉嫌在过去三年从中国购买芬太尼。首席检察官表示，他将其卖给了美国的买家，其中还包括墨西哥的买家。</p>   <p>The investigation began in April after a report sent by the DEA liaison officer at the U.S. embassy in Rome, Guardia di Finanza police said in a statement, adding the fentanyl arrived in Piacenza inside packages sent from China and labelled as containing electronics or books.翻译:Guardia di Finanza警方在一份声明中表示，美国驻罗马大使馆缉毒局联络官发出报告后，调查于四月开始，并补充说，芬太尼装在从中国寄出的包裹中抵达皮亚琴察，并贴有电子产品或书籍的标签。</p>   <p>Police said they were able to trace 100,000 packaged doses and that related economic transactions amounting to more than 250,000 euros ($275,000) took place through untraceable payment instruments using cryptocurrency.翻译:警方表示，他们能够追踪到 100,000 个包装剂量，并且通过使用加密货币的无法追踪的支付工具进行了价值超过 250,000 欧元（275,000 美元）的相关经济交易。</p>   <p>The judge in Piacenza had ordered seven arrests but a Ukrainian national is a fugitive and international law enforcement agencies have been alerted to track him down, police said.翻译:警方表示，皮亚琴察的法官已下令逮捕七人，但一名乌克兰国民是逃犯，国际执法机构已接到通知追查他。</p>   <p>Italian police also found that the group had minted near-perfect fake Swiss coins, smuggled them across the border to Switzerland where they laundered them through automated sports betting machines and bitcoin ATMs.翻译:意大利警方还发现，该团伙铸造了近乎完美的假瑞士硬币，并将其偷运至瑞士，并通过自动体育博彩机和比特币 ATM 机进行洗钱。</p>   <p>The conversion of bitcoins back into euros was then entrusted to people in Eastern Europe who would return the "cleaned" sum minus 7% commission to the counterfeiter in Piacenza.翻译:然后，将比特币兑换回欧元的工作委托给东欧的人，他们将“干净”的金额减去 7% 的佣金返还给皮亚琴察的造假者。</p>   <p>Police said they seized 300,000 euros in cash, about 26,000 euros in bitcoin, 70 computer devices and three valuable watches, as well as a property and the equipment for counterfeiting currency.
($1 = 0.9207 euros)翻译:警方称，他们查获了 30 万欧元现金、约 2.6 万欧元比特币、70 台电脑设备和三块贵重手表，以及一处财产和用于伪造货币的设备。 （1 美元 = 0.9207 欧元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Emilio Parodi
Editing by Keith Weir翻译:埃米利奥·帕罗迪 (Emilio Parodi) 报道 基思·威尔 (Keith Weir) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 19:00:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZGCKWXSDZJMMDO2M7QZBA3HYGA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/italy-arrests-six-crackdown-fentanyl-smuggling-china-us-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Emilio Parodi]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ITALY</category>
                
                <category>FENTANYL/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>USA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[习近平与乔·拜登会面当天，亚太经合组织抗议者提前出现]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/mHzw_v1AemJoPfV5IzGGk_F8yI0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/EA2DFZKAJ5NW7FGUCLYMYGR7QI.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Protesters taunt people in suit, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会集会上，抗议者嘲笑着西装革履的人。 REUTERS/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UMFDwww_h47JGqvWkeFsnZ0rKXs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TJQXEP2ANVJMXD47UT2A2VOM4M.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Protesters scuffle with police, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，美国加利福尼亚州旧金山，抗议者在反对亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会的集会上与警察发生扭打。 REUTERS/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TSIg-P9NS4Ne-gHbR_bIxWnkapM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZFDYBYLUE5PSZDJXXFR7OL545Y.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Protesters demonstrate on the ground, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，抗议者在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的反对亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会的集会上进行示威。路透社/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/FbCF-nFb9S5t9yAyO4QUZLIXcKE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TZPHLS7UGRM7RKWTRGW23AQOGQ.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A protester confronts with a person, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，美国加利福尼亚州旧金山，在反对亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会的集会上，一名抗议者与一人对峙。路透社/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/yC244DtSNHKhuneBU8iUTECU2kw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/K5Q3RI6BG5LGHOUNEPPJRQU3DM.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Police get through the line of protesters to reinforce, as protesters block, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的一场反对亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会的集会上，警方冲破抗议者的队伍进行增援。路透社/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>                     <p>Protesters took to the streets of San Francisco early on Wednesday morning <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">ahead of a meeting</a> between U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping, obstructing some entrances to the APEC conference.翻译:周三清晨，在美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">会晤之前</a>，抗议者走上旧金山街头，堵塞了亚太经合组织会议的一些入口。</p>   <p>Global leaders and CEOs of major U.S. corporations will all be at the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation</a> (APEC) forum in San Francisco, offering tempting targets to protest.翻译:全球领导人和美国大公司的首席执行官都将出席在旧金山举行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">的亚太经济合作组织</a>（APEC）论坛，提出诱人的抗议目标。</p>   <p>Opponents of Xi hope hundreds of people will <a href="https://www.reuters.com/podcasts/biden-meet-xi-san-francisco-2023-11-12/?%24web_only=true&amp;_branch_match_id=1161293349163474432&amp;utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_medium=marketing&amp;_branch_referrer=H4sIAAAAAAAAA8soKSkottLXz8nMy9YrSi0tSS0q1kvOz9VP1Q9wSwzOLi7O8XZNAgBzJOFkJgAAAA%3D%3D">demonstrate against Chinese policies</a>, while others are using the meeting as a forum for global issues such as the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-public-support-israel-drops-majority-backs-ceasefire-reutersipsos-2023-11-15/">Israel-Hamas war</a>.翻译:习近平的反对者希望数百人举行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/podcasts/biden-meet-xi-san-francisco-2023-11-12/?%24web_only=true&amp;_branch_match_id=1161293349163474432&amp;utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_medium=marketing&amp;_branch_referrer=H4sIAAAAAAAAA8soKSkottLXz8nMy9YrSi0tSS0q1kvOz9VP1Q9wSwzOLi7O8XZNAgBzJOFkJgAAAA%3D%3D">示威反对中国的政策</a>，而其他人则利用这次会议作为讨论<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-public-support-israel-drops-majority-backs-ceasefire-reutersipsos-2023-11-15/">以色列与哈马斯战争</a>等全球问题的论坛。</p>   <p>Roughly 150 people gathered at an intersection outside the security zone at the city's convention center around 8 a.m. local time (1400 GMT). The group aimed to block conference attendees from passing through the intersection, and formed a human chain that diverted some commuters and delegates.翻译:当地时间上午 8 点（格林威治标准时间 1400）左右，大约 150 人聚集在该市会议中心安全区外的十字路口。该组织旨在阻止与会者通过十字路口，并形成了一条人链，分流了一些通勤者和代表。</p>   <p>Police donned protective helmets and formed a line about 50 feet (15 meters) from a speaker and microphone for speeches that criticized APEC and the Biden administration, and urged climate change action and voiced support for Palestinians.翻译:警察戴上防护头盔，在距离扬声器和麦克风约 50 英尺（15 米）的地方排成一队，发表批评 APEC 和拜登政府、敦促采取气候变化行动并表示支持巴勒斯坦人的演讲。</p>   <p>Pema Doma, executive director of Students for a Free Tibet, said protest organizers were expecting hundreds of people from all over the U.S. to demonstrate against Xi’s policies.翻译:自由西藏学生组织执行主任佩玛·多玛表示，抗议组织者预计将有来自美国各地的数百人举行示威，反对习近平的政策。</p>   <p>“We can say beyond a reasonable doubt that this will be the largest anti-Xi protest during the bilateral talks hosted here in the United States in the history of Xi Jinping’s time as a dictator of China,” she said.翻译:“我们可以毫无疑问地说，这将是习近平作为中国独裁者时期历史上在美国举行的双边会谈期间最大规模的反习近平抗议活动，”她说。</p>   <p>Protesters supporting spiritual group Falun Gong, which is banned in China, lined motorcade entry points into the convention center area.翻译:支持在中国被禁止的法轮功精神团体的抗议者在进入会议中心区域的车队入口处排队。</p>   <p>Nearby, dozens of supporters and opponents of Chinese policies faced off, Chinese flags on one side and a banner calling the Chinese Communist Party a "virus" on the other, separated by police lines.翻译:附近，数十名中国政策的支持者和反对者对峙，一边是中国国旗，另一边是称中国共产党是“病毒”的横幅，中间被警戒线隔开。</p>   <p>Supporters of China also turned out near where Biden and Xi will meet, waving Chinese and U.S. flags as well as posters with both flags together.翻译:中国的支持者也出现在拜登和习近平会面地点附近，挥舞着中美两国国旗以及印有两国国旗的海报。</p>   <p>Thousands of police lined streets near the San Francisco convention center, and protests in the days before Biden and Xi's meeting have been relatively peaceful, with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/apec-san-francisco-protesters-span-gamut-political-issues-2023-11-13/">some crowds stretching for blocks</a>, including a march uniting several interest groups on Sunday.翻译:旧金山会议中心附近的街道上有数千名警察，拜登和习近平会面前几天的抗议活动相对和平， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/apec-san-francisco-protesters-span-gamut-political-issues-2023-11-13/">一些人群延伸了几个街区</a>，包括周日联合多个利益团体举行的游行。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/san-francisco-patches-over-homelessness-drug-abuse-apec-2023-11-15/">San Francisco has cleaned up downtown streets</a> for the meeting, and it has prepared for potential confrontation with demonstrators: eight-foot high metal mesh barriers have been erected to keep people on sidewalks from interfering with vehicle traffic near the convention center.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/san-francisco-patches-over-homelessness-drug-abuse-apec-2023-11-15/">旧金山已经为会议清理了市中心街道</a>，并为可能与示威者发生冲突做好了准备：竖起了八英尺高的金属网屏障，以防止人行道上的人们干扰会议中心附近的车辆交通。</p>   <p>The potential for disruptions around the summit site in downtown San Francisco, portions of which will be shut to vehicles and foot traffic, led the U.S. Department of Homeland Security to designate the meeting a national special security event, putting the U.S. Secret Service in charge of coordination of policing agencies.翻译:由于旧金山市中心的峰会地点周围可能会出现干扰，其中部分地区将禁止车辆和人行通行，因此美国国土安全部将此次会议指定为国家特别安全活动，并由美国特勤局负责警务机构的协调。</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Ann Saphir; Writing By Peter Henderson; Editing by Josie Kao翻译:Ann Saphir 的补充报道；彼得·亨德森撰写；编辑：高乔茜</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 18:35:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">V5Z5PTD2ABL6LAMVFZUIDWAYCM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/apec-protesters-turn-out-early-xi-jinping-joe-biden-meeting-day-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Max Cherney, Michael Martina]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/PROTEST (PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[在拜登与习近平会面之前，与中国相关的 ETF 吸引了看涨期权押注]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/phtpuAUxstUjXz0AIES4Vnt1wPw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PBUKQQHJBFJV5FEUJSN5OL5XGM.jpg" alt="Traders work on the floor of the NYSE in New York翻译:交易员在纽约证券交易所工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Traders work on the floor at the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) in New York City, U.S., November 15, 2023.  REUTERS/Brendan McDermid/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，交易员在美国纽约市纽约证券交易所 (NYSE) 的交易大厅工作。REUTERS/Brendan McDermid/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S.-listed exchange traded funds focused on China are seeing bullish options activity as investors await U.S. President Joe Biden's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">meeting</a> with Chinese leader Xi Jinping on Wednesday for signs of easing friction between the two superpowers.翻译:随着投资者等待美国总统乔·拜登周三与中国领导人习近平<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">会面</a>，以寻找两个超级大国之间摩擦缓和的迹象，专注于中国的美国上市交易所交易基金看到了看涨的期权活动。</p>   <p>Some of the bullish positions included call options on the Xtrackers Harvest CSI 300 China A-Shares ETF with a $27 strike price - some 6% higher than where the fund trades today - set to expire Friday.翻译:部分看涨头寸包括 Xtrackers Harvest CSI 300 China A-Shares ETF 的看涨期权，执行价为 27 美元，比该基金今天的交易价格高出约 6%，将于周五到期。</p>   <p>The iShares Trust-China Large-Cap ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FXI.P" target="_blank">(FXI.P)</a> also sport multiple lines of at-money and upside calls with sizeable open interest, including almost 100,000 contracts at the 29.85 strike. The ETF was trading at $27.28 on Wednesday.翻译:iShares Trust-China Large-Cap ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FXI.P" target="_blank">(FXI.P)</a>还拥有多条平价和上行看涨期权，持仓量相当大，其中包括近 100,000 份合约，执行价为 29.85。该 ETF 周三交易价格为 27.28 美元。</p>   <p>Other large China-focused ETFs, including the iShares MSCI China ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MCHI.O" target="_blank">(MCHI.O)</a>, KraneShares CSI China Internet ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/KWEB.P" target="_blank">(KWEB.P)</a>, also showed upbeat options activity, according to Trade Alert data.翻译:根据 Trade Alert 数据，其他专注于中国的大型 ETF，包括 iShares MSCI 中国 ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MCHI.O" target="_blank">(MCHI.O)</a> 、KraneShares CSI China Internet ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/KWEB.P" target="_blank">(KWEB.P)</a> ，也显示出乐观的期权活动。</p>   <p>"It certainly seems that there is generally bullish positioning ahead of the meeting," said Steve Sosnick, chief strategist at Interactive Brokers, noting that the positions had been built up over several days. "The open interest in options expiring Friday is heavily skewed to the upside."翻译:盈透证券（Interactive Brokers）首席策略师史蒂夫·索斯尼克（Steve Sosnick）表示：“在会议之前，似乎普遍存在看涨头寸。”他指出，这些头寸是在几天内建立起来的。 “周五到期的期权的未平仓合约严重偏向上行。”</p>   <p>While some of the upside positioning may be tied to a rally in the broader equity market - including a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/goldilocks-hopes-return-wall-st-after-benign-inflation-report-2023-11-14/">Tuesday surge</a> that saw the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/goldilocks-hopes-return-wall-st-after-benign-inflation-report-2023-11-14/">S&amp;P 500 rise 1.9%</a> on bets that the Federal Reserve is done hiking interest rates - investors are also likely speculating on a positive outcome from the meeting between Biden and Xi, Sosnick said.翻译:虽然部分上行定位可能与更广泛的股市反弹有关——包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/goldilocks-hopes-return-wall-st-after-benign-inflation-report-2023-11-14/">周二的飙升</a>， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/goldilocks-hopes-return-wall-st-after-benign-inflation-report-2023-11-14/">标普 500 指数因押注美联储不再加息而上涨 1.9%</a> ——但投资者也可能对利好进行投机。索斯尼克表示，拜登和习近平的会晤成果。</p>   <p>"The bullish positioning in ASHR and FXI is almost certainly the result of pre-meeting enthusiasm since it is highly biased to near-term upside calls and the positioning occurred prior to yesterday's run-up," Sosnick said.翻译:Sosnick 表示：“ASHR 和 FXI 的看涨定位几乎肯定是会议前热情的结果，因为它高度偏向于近期上涨的呼声，并且定位发生在昨天的上涨之前。”</p>   <p>Biden and Xi arrived in San Francisco on Tuesday, where they were set to hold their meeting on the sidelines the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit. The meeting is set for 2 p.m. ET (1900 GMT).翻译:拜登和习近平周二抵达旧金山，原定在亚太经合组织（APEC）峰会期间举行会晤。会议定于美国东部时间下午 2 点（格林尼治标准时间 1900）。</p>      <p>Investors' nascent enthusiasm for Chinese stocks is at odds with how these ETF's have performed this year. The largest China-linked ETFs are down anywhere between 3% to 9% for the year. Meanwhile the S&amp;P 500 is up nearly 18%.翻译:投资者对中国股票的热情与这些 ETF 今年的表现不一致。最大的中国相关 ETF 今年下跌了 3% 至 9%。与此同时，标准普尔 500 指数上涨近 18%。</p>   <p>Fund managers in the November BofA Global Research survey named shorting China equities as the market's second "most crowded" trade.翻译:基金经理在 11 月份美国银行全球研究调查中将做空中国股票列为市场第二“最拥挤”的交易。</p>   <p>Daniel Kirsch, head of options at Piper Sandler, said recent bullish options flows into KWEB may be to do with a combination of enthusiasm ahead of the Biden-Xi meeting as well as results from Chinese e-commerce companies JD.com and Alibaba . On Wednesday, JD.com reported a surge in third-quarter profit, while Alibaba results are expected after the close of trading.翻译:Piper Sandler 期权主管 Daniel Kirsch 表示，最近看涨期权流入 KWEB 可能与拜登与习主席会面前的热情以及中国电子商务公司京东和阿里巴巴的业绩有关。周三，京东公布第三季度利润大幅增长，而阿里巴巴的业绩预计将在收盘后公布。</p>   <p>"People are looking for areas that could be catching up (to the rally in broader markets)," Kirsch said.翻译:基尔希表示：“人们正在寻找可能追赶（追赶更广泛市场反弹）的领域。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Saqib Iqbal Ahmed; Additional reporting by Suzanne McGee; Editing by Ira Iosebashvili and Jonathan Oatis翻译:萨奇布·伊克巴尔·艾哈迈德报道；苏珊·麦吉 (Suzanne McGee) 的补充报道；编辑：Ira Iosebashvili 和 Jonathan Oatis</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 18:28:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">NPASMWJJYNLH5A2UTAHMGDIDTY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/china-linked-etfs-draw-bullish-options-bets-ahead-biden-xi-meet-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Saqib Ahmed]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>STOCKS/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ETFS</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[巴克莱银行在中国工商银行遭到黑客攻击后指出美国财政部中央清算网络存在安全风险]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/6T18G_p6ITtj2RhHs2V6Ch3nd60=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TBGJ2NDWAVKHLHEBTYSEPCNV5Y.jpg" alt="The logo of Barclays bank is seen on glass lamps outside of a branch of the bank in the City of London financial district in London翻译:伦敦金融城金融区一家分行外的玻璃灯上可见巴克莱银行的标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of Barclays bank is seen on glass lamps outside of a branch of the bank in the City of London financial district in London翻译:伦敦金融城金融区一家分行外的玻璃灯上可见巴克莱银行的标志 September 4, 2017. REUTERS/Toby Melville/File Photo翻译:2017年9月4日，伦敦金融城金融区一家分行外的玻璃灯上可见巴克莱银行的标志。路透社/托比·梅尔维尔/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TScIha-aTXhV_ncIXhPKwvORv7c=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4MGW3R6M25KFHF4CWWD37SUWLU.jpg" alt="The logo of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China is seen at its branch at its headquarters in Beijing翻译:中国工商银行北京总部分行的标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China (ICBC) is seen at its branch at its headquarters in Beijing, China, March 30, 2016.  REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/File Photo翻译:2016 年 3 月 30 日，中国工商银行 (ICBC) 标志出现在中国北京总部分行。 REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>A key reform proposed by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission to boost the use of central clearing for U.S. Treasuries could leave the market more exposed to cybersecurity risks, Barclays said, referring to the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-largest-bank-icbc-hit-by-ransomware-software-ft-2023-11-09/">cyber hack</a> of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China's U.S. broker-dealer last week.翻译:巴克莱银行表示，美国证券交易委员会提出的一项旨在促进美国国债中央清算使用的重大改革可能会使市场更容易面临网络安全风险，他指的是中国工商银行美国经纪自营商的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-largest-bank-icbc-hit-by-ransomware-software-ft-2023-11-09/">网络黑客攻击事件。</a>上星期。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/why-us-sec-is-looking-reform-treasury-market-2022-09-12/">SEC central clearing rule</a>, first proposed in September last year, would apply to the cash Treasury and repurchase agreements (repo) markets, where banks and other players such as hedge funds borrow short-term loans backed by Treasuries.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/why-us-sec-is-looking-reform-treasury-market-2022-09-12/">SEC 中央清算规则</a>于去年 9 月首次提出，将适用于现金国债和回购协议 (repo) 市场，银行和对冲基金等其他参与者借入由国债支持的短期贷款。</p>   <p>Under the rule, more trades would be sent to a clearing house, requiring counterparties to put up cash to guarantee execution in the event of defaults.翻译:根据该规则，更多的交易将被发送到清算所，要求交易对手提供现金以保证在违约情况下的执行。</p>   <p>Because the Fixed Income Clearing Corporation (FICC), a subsidiary of the Depository Trust &amp; Clearing Corporation (DTCC), is currently the only central clearing platform for repo and Treasuries, activity on the FICC platform will more than double with the proposed reform, Joseph Abate, a strategist at Barclays, said in a note on Tuesday.翻译:Joseph 表示，由于美国存款信托与清算公司 (DTCC) 的子公司固定收益清算公司 (FICC) 是目前唯一的回购和国债中央清算平台，因此随着拟议的改革，FICC 平台上的活动将增加一倍以上巴克莱银行策略师阿巴特周二在一份报告中表示。</p>   <p>"This creates a potential single-point of failure risk as recent events illustrate," he said, referring to the ICBC hack.翻译:“正如最近发生的事件所表明的那样，这会造成潜在的单点故障风险，”他指的是中国工商银行的黑客事件。</p>   <p>"That has potential systemic consequences," he said.翻译:“这具有潜在的系统性后果，”他说。</p>   <p>ICBC' U.S. arm was hit by a ransomware attack that disrupted trades in the U.S. Treasury market on Nov. 9 and left the bank temporarily owing BNY Mellon <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BK.N" target="_blank">(BK.N)</a> $9 billion for unsettled trades, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/icbc-ransomware-attack-triggers-global-regulator-trader-scrutiny-2023-11-10/">Reuters reported</a>.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/icbc-ransomware-attack-triggers-global-regulator-trader-scrutiny-2023-11-10/">据路透社报道，</a> 11 月 9 日，中国工商银行美国分行遭受勒索软件攻击，美国国债市场交易中断，导致该行因未结算的交易而暂时欠纽约梅隆银行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BK.N" target="_blank">(BK.N)</a> 90 亿美元。</p>   <p>Abate also flagged cybersecurity risks for direct members of the FICC, as well as clients they sponsor to access the clearing platform, saying mandatory central clearing could make FICC "a fortress with many doors."翻译:Abate 还指出了 FICC 直接成员及其赞助的访问清算平台的客户面临的网络安全风险，并表示强制中央清算可能使 FICC 成为“一座有许多门的堡垒”。</p>   <p>DTCC said on Wednesday its systems were not impacted by the ICBC incident and that it works with internal specialists and external partners to stay ahead of evolving cybersecurity threats.翻译:DTCC 周三表示，其系统未受到 ICBC 事件的影响，并与内部专家和外部合作伙伴合作，以应对不断变化的网络安全威胁。</p>   <p>"We are committed to safeguarding our clients and stakeholders through this dynamic synergy of internal and external expertise,” it said in a statement to Reuters.翻译:该公司在给路透社的一份声明中表示：“我们致力于通过内部和外部专业知识的动态协同来保护我们的客户和利益相关者。”</p>   <p>The SEC is expected to finalize the rule early next year, said Barclays, but it is unclear how much time the industry would have to implement it and whether central clearing will occur simultaneously for Treasuries and repo transactions.翻译:巴克莱表示，预计美国证券交易委员会将在明年初敲定该规则，但目前尚不清楚该行业需要多长时间来实施该规则，以及国债和回购交易是否会同时进行中央清算。</p>    <span>Reporting by Davide Barbuscia
Editing by Marguerita Choy翻译:大卫·巴布西亚 (Davide Barbuscia) 报道 玛格丽塔·蔡 (Marguerita Choy) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 17:20:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ARUC5VRC45OERIS3W5KBHAYKWQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/barclays-flags-treasuries-central-clearing-cybersecurity-risks-after-icbc-hack-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Davide Barbuscia]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>BONDS/REFORMS</category>
                
                <category>CYBER</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[加州会谈后中美推进气候合作]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UXrIOsXLuqEBGqgp6K0eh3Y4cXw=/1832x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SSSVDHPBXFOYVATNIL6GPT7QVY.jpg" alt="U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry meets with his Chinese counterpart Xie Zhenhua in Beijing翻译:美国总统气候特使约翰·克里在北京会见中国气候变化特使解振华" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry shakes hands with his Chinese counterpart Xie Zhenhua before a meeting in Beijing, China July 17, 2023. REUTERS/Valerie Volcovici/ File Photo翻译:2023 年 7 月 17 日，美国总统气候特使约翰·克里 (John Kerry) 在中国北京举行会议前与中国气候特使解振华握手。 REUTERS/Valerie Volcovici/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The United States and China will back a new global renewables target and work together on methane and plastic pollution, they said in a joint statement on Wednesday after a meeting to find common ground ahead of COP28 talks in Dubai later this month.翻译:本月晚些时候在迪拜举行的第 28 次缔约方会议 (COP28) 之前，美国和中国举行会议寻找共同点，周三在一份联合声明中表示，美国和中国将支持新的全球可再生能源目标，并在甲烷和塑料污染问题上开展合作。</p>   <p>Climate envoys John Kerry and Xie Zhenhua, meeting in Sunnylands, California, from Nov. 4-8, agreed to revive a bilateral climate working group that will discuss areas of cooperation, the joint statement said, though differences remain on issues like phasing out fossil fuels.翻译:联合声明称，气候特使约翰·克里和解振华于 11 月 4 日至 8 日在加利福尼亚州桑尼兰兹举行会议，同意恢复双边气候工作组，讨论合作领域，尽管在逐步淘汰化石燃料等问题上仍存在分歧燃料。</p>   <p>"The Sunnylands statement is a timely effort of aligning the United States and China ahead of COP28," said Li Shuo, incoming director of the China Climate Hub at the Asia Society.翻译:即将上任的亚洲协会中国气候中心主任李硕表示：“《阳光之乡》的声明是在 COP28 之前协调美国和中国的及时努力。”</p>   <p>Li described the relationship between the world's two biggest greenhouse gas emitters as "a precondition for meaningful global progress" and said the Sunnylands agreement would help "stabilise the politics" ahead of the Dubai talks.翻译:李将世界上最大的两个温室气体排放国之间的关系描述为“全球取得有意义进展的先决条件”，并表示《阳光之乡》协议将有助于在迪拜会谈之前“稳定政治”。</p>   <p>The re-launch of the working group marks the normalisation of the climate relationship between the two countries following a hiatus triggered in 2022 by the visit of former House of Representatives speaker Nancy Pelosi to Taiwan, a self-governing island that China claims as its own.翻译:该工作组的重新启动标志着两国气候关系的正常化，该关系因前众议院议长南希·佩洛西 (Nancy Pelosi) 2022 年访问台湾而中断。台湾是一个中国声称拥有主权的岛屿。 。</p>   <p>Partnership between the world's two biggest emitting countries is seen as a crucial element to securing a consensus agreement at COP28.翻译:世界上两个最大排放国之间的伙伴关系被视为在 COP28 上达成共识协议的关键因素。</p>   <p>For the first time, China - the world's biggest emitter of greenhouse gas emissions - will include non-carbon dioxide greenhouse gases like nitrogen oxide in its 2035 national climate plan as well as specific actions to curb methane emissions, major sources of global emissions.翻译:作为全球最大的温室气体排放国，中国首次将氮氧化物等非二氧化碳温室气体纳入其2035年国家气候计划以及遏制全球主要排放源甲烷排放的具体行动。</p>   <p>"This implies that China needs to do a lot more to be in line with ambitious global goals," said Joanna Lewis, a professor at Georgetown University's School of Foreign Service.翻译:乔治城大学外交学院教授乔安娜·刘易斯表示：“这意味着中国需要做更多的事情来实现雄心勃勃的全球目标。”</p>   <p>It also focuses on key areas of cooperation, including abating methane and boosting efficiency and the "circular economy", and exchanging information on policies and technologies to reduce emissions. The two sides also promised to work together to curb forest loss and plastic pollution.</p>    <h 1="">"WORK CUT OUT"</h>  <p>China's efforts to cut its own carbon emissions will be in sharp focus at COP28, with the country still approving new coal-fired power plants in a bid to ensure energy security.翻译:中国削减自身碳排放的努力将成为COP28的焦点，中国仍在批准新的燃煤电厂以确保能源安全。</p>   <p>The United States and China said they support a declaration by G20 leaders to triple global renewable energy capacity by 2030, and also agreed to "accelerate the substitution for coal, oil and gas generation," which would result in "meaningful absolute power sector emission reductions" this decade.翻译:美国和中国表示，他们支持二十国集团领导人的宣言，即到2030年将全球可再生能源发电能力增加两倍，并同意“加速替代煤炭、石油和天然气发电”，这将导致“电力行业绝对排放量大幅减少” “这十年。</p>   <p>That falls short of calling for the phasing out of fossil fuels, a goal that China has described as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-climate-envoy-says-phasing-out-fossil-fuels-unrealistic-2023-09-22/">"unrealistic"</a>. However, a report released earlier this week said that record levels of new <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-emissions-could-go-into-structural-decline-next-year-research-2023-11-14/">renewable installations</a> in China may help "all but guarantee" a decline in China's CO2 emissions next year.翻译:这还不足以呼吁逐步淘汰化石燃料，中国称这一目标<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-climate-envoy-says-phasing-out-fossil-fuels-unrealistic-2023-09-22/">“不切实际”</a> 。然而，本周早些时候发布的一份报告称，中国新增<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-emissions-could-go-into-structural-decline-next-year-research-2023-11-14/">可再生能源装机</a>量创历史新高，可能有助于“几乎保证”中国明年二氧化碳排放量的下降。</p>   <p>Both sides also agreed to include methane in their 2035 climate goals - the first time China has made such a pledge - and committed to advancing "at least five" large-scale cooperation projects in carbon capture, utilisation and storage by the end of the decade.翻译:双方还同意将甲烷纳入2035年气候目标，这是中国首次做出此类承诺，并承诺到本十年末推进“至少5个”碳捕集、利用和封存大型合作项目。</p>   <p>The joint statement said that the United States, China and COP28 host the United Arab Emirates will hold a Methane and Non-CO2 Greenhouse Gases Summit at COP28.翻译:联合声明称，美国、中国和COP28主办国阿联酋将在COP28期间举行甲烷和非二氧化碳温室气体峰会。</p>   <p>Li said COP28 still "has its work cut out", particularly on fossil fuels.翻译:李说，COP28 仍然“有许多工作要做”，特别是在化石燃料方面。</p>   <p>"China also needs to consider what further ambition can be brought to COP," he added. "Stopping the approval of new coal power projects is a good next step."翻译:“中国还需要考虑可以为缔约方大会带来哪些进一步的雄心，”他补充道。 “停止批准新的煤电项目是下一步的好举措。”</p>    <span>Reporting by David Stanway; Editing by Muralikumar Anantharaman, Raju Gopalakrishnan and Nick Macfie翻译:大卫·斯坦威报道；编辑：Muralikumar Anantharaman、Raju Gopalakrishnan 和 Nick Macfie</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 17:13:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MMEHXKCLHBMKREBS5CHXKMMOXI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/us-china-pledge-cooperation-climate-following-california-talks-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Stanway, Valerie Volcovici]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CLIMATE CHANGE</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA (UPDATE 3)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[InVivo 将开设沙特办事处以适应全球粮食变化]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/PIzz282X4070OtfZANrNp_27YpI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2LHFOMVSKBMIDOOHZTYC66UYRE.jpg" alt="Thierry Blandinieres, CEO of InVivo, poses after a news conference in Paris翻译:InVivo 首席执行官蒂埃里·布兰迪尼尔 (Thierry Blandinieres) 在巴黎举行的新闻发布会后合影" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Thierry Blandinieres, Chief Executive Officer of InVivo, poses after a news conference at the company's headquarters in Paris, France, December 9, 2021. REUTERS/Sarah Meyssonnier/File Photo翻译:InVivo 首席执行官蒂埃里·布兰迪尼埃 (Thierry Blandinieres) 于 2021 年 12 月 9 日在法国巴黎公司总部举行新闻发布会后摆姿势。REUTERS/Sarah Meyssonnier/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>InVivo will open a marketing office in Saudi Arabia early next year as it seeks to secure new outlets at a time of changing global grain demand, the French agribusiness group's chief executive told Reuters.翻译:法国农业综合企业集团首席执行官告诉路透社，InVivo 将于明年初在沙特阿拉伯开设营销办事处，以寻求在全球粮食需求变化之际确保新的销售点。</p>   <p>The office, to be based in the Saudi port of Damman, aims to secure grain supplies for local feed makers in the fast-developing country, InVivo CEO Thierry Blandinieres said.翻译:InVivo 首席执行官蒂埃里·布兰迪尼尔斯 (Thierry Blandinieres) 表示，该办事处将设在沙特达曼港，旨在确保这个快速发展国家的当地饲料制造商的粮食供应。</p>   <p>The cooperative group, with activities from grain trading to wine distribution, became one of Europe's largest agricultural firms through its takeover of French rival Soufflet in 2021.翻译:该合作集团业务范围涵盖谷物贸易和葡萄酒分销，并于 2021 年收购法国竞争对手 Soufflet，成为欧洲最大的农业公司之一。</p>   <p>Algeria has been traditionally the biggest market for French wheat but exports to the north African country have fallen dramatically as Algiers turned to cheaper Russian supplies.翻译:阿尔及利亚传统上一直是法国小麦的最大市场，但随着阿尔及尔转向更便宜的俄罗斯供应，对北非国家的出口大幅下降。</p>   <p>French wheat exports to Algeria this season were down 85% by the end of last month compared to a year earlier. However, the fall was set to be compensated later in the season by <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-snaps-up-australian-french-wheat-crop-damage-spurs-buying-spree-2023-10-31/">a sharp rise</a> in sales to China, where crops have been damaged by rain.翻译:截至上月底，法国本季对阿尔及利亚的小麦出口较去年同期下降了 85%。然而，在本季后期，对中国农作物的销量<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-snaps-up-australian-french-wheat-crop-damage-spurs-buying-spree-2023-10-31/">急剧上升</a>，将弥补这一下降，因为中国的农作物因降雨而受损。</p>   <p>"Geographies are changing in terms of customers. We know that Algeria is no longer a loyal customer. The good surprise is that the Chinese order a lot, that Egypt is buying again and Saudi Arabia wants to have ties with France," Blandinieres said.翻译:“就客户而言，地理位置正在发生变化。我们知道阿尔及利亚不再是忠实客户。令人惊讶的是，中国订单很多，埃及再次购买，沙特阿拉伯希望与法国建立联系，”布兰迪尼尔斯说。</p>   <p>"But China will eventually stop, it is not a continuum, so we have to find outlets elsewhere and that's what we are trying to do," he said, adding that InVivo was also working on securing its west African markets.翻译:“但中国最终会停下来，这不是一个连续体，所以我们必须在其他地方寻找出路，这就是我们正在努力做的事情，”他说，并补充说 InVivo 也在努力确保其西非市场。</p>   <p>The Saudi office will be directed from Dubai by Aman Sethi, who was previously based at InVivo's Singapore office, Jean-Francois Lepy, head of InVivo's trading arm Soufflet Negoce, said separately.翻译:InVivo 交易部门 Soufflet Negoce 负责人 Jean-Francois Lepy 单独表示，沙特办事处将由 Aman Sethi 在迪拜领导，Aman Sethi 此前在 InVivo 新加坡办事处工作。</p>   <p>InVivo said on Wednesday its Malteries Soufflet unit had completed the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/australias-united-malt-agrees-1-billion-takeover-offer-frances-invivo-2023-07-02/">takeover of Australia's United Malt Group</a> following clearance from relevant regulatory authorities and shareholders, creating the world's largest maltster.翻译:InVivo 周三表示，在获得相关监管机构和股东批准后，其 Malteries Soufflet 子公司已完成<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/australias-united-malt-agrees-1-billion-takeover-offer-frances-invivo-2023-07-02/">对澳大利亚联合麦芽集团 (United Malt Group) 的收购</a>，打造全球最大的麦芽制造商。</p>   <p>($1 = 1.5370 Australian dollars)翻译:（1 美元 = 1.5370 澳元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Sybille de La Hamaide; Editing by Alexander Smith翻译:Sybille de La Hamaide 报道；亚历山大·史密斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:48:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7JGQ2TM5IFPNTMYTLS6Y2DN334</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/invivo-open-saudi-office-adapts-global-grain-shifts-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Sybille Hamaide]]></author>
            
                
                <category>FRANCE</category>
                
                <category>GRAINS/INVIVO (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[游戏、广告销售表现强劲，腾讯收入强劲增长]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/qFVUKfKVs5luffgqpNnGBv-B5FY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/J2BIS7JP7FPYDEIR7AEOVNZO4A.jpg" alt="A Tencent sign is seen at the World Internet Conference (WIC) in Wuzhen翻译:乌镇世界互联网大会上的腾讯标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Tencent sign is seen at the World Internet Conference (WIC) in Wuzhen翻译:乌镇世界互联网大会上的腾讯标志, Zhejiang province, China, October 20, 2019. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's Tencent Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0700.HK" target="_blank">(0700.HK)</a> said third-quarter revenue climbed 10%, as its games business rebounded from a regulatory crackdown on the country's tech sector and online advertising sales surged.翻译:中国腾讯控股<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0700.HK" target="_blank">(0700.HK)</a>表示，第三季度收入增长10%，其游戏业务从中国科技行业监管打压中反弹，在线广告销售激增。</p>   <p>Sales for the world's largest video game company and operator of the WeChat messaging platform came in at 154.6 billion yuan ($21.4 billion) - in line with market forecasts - for the three months to end September, its third straight quarter of revenue growth.翻译:截至 9 月底的三个月，全球最大的视频游戏公司和微信消息平台运营商的销售额为 1,546 亿元人民币（合 214 亿美元），与市场预测一致，这是其收入连续第三个季度增长。</p>   <p>Last year was one of the toughest years for Chinese video game companies after a regulatory crackdown that began in 2021 led to an eight month-long freeze in licences for new games and more restrictions on playing time for minors. Tencent ended up posting an annual revenue decline for the first time.翻译:去年是中国视频游戏公司最艰难的一年，自 2021 年开始的监管打击导致新游戏许可冻结长达八个月，并对未成年人的游戏时间施加更多限制。腾讯最终公布年度收入首次出现下滑。</p>   <p>The industry has rallied this year after regulators resumed granting game licences.翻译:在监管机构恢复发放游戏牌照后，该行业今年出现了反弹。</p>   <p>Tencent's domestic games revenue for the quarter grew 5%, driven by titles such as the multiplayer role-playing game "Lost Ark" and shooting game "Valorant", developed by Riot Games - both of which Tencent launched for the first time in China in July.翻译:受Riot Games开发的多人角色扮演游戏《失落的方舟》和射击游戏《Valorant》等游戏的推动，腾讯本季度国内游戏收入增长了5%，这两款游戏都是腾讯于2017年首次在中国推出的。七月。</p>   <p>In a call with analysts on Wednesday, Tencent highlighted nine games, including Honor of Kings World, Valorant Mobile, Monster Hunter Mobile and Assassin's Creed Mobile, that are pending to be released.翻译:在周三与分析师的电话会议中，腾讯重点介绍了九款即将发布的游戏，包括《王者荣耀》、《Valorant Mobile》、《怪物猎人手游》和《刺客信条手游》。</p>   <p>"We have a substantial pipeline of new games in development including games that expand our own game IPs... and mobile games that utilise well-loved licensed IPs," Martin Lau, the company's president, said.翻译:该公司总裁刘炽平表示：“我们正在开发大量新游戏，包括扩展我们自己的游戏 IP 的游戏……以及利用深受喜爱的授权 IP 的手机游戏。”</p>   <p>In August, the Chinese video games sector achieved combined revenue of 29.2 billion yuan, the most in at least 20 months, according to CNG, a government-backed industry data firm.翻译:根据政府支持的行业数据公司 CNG 的数据，8 月份，中国视频游戏行业的总收入达到 292 亿元人民币，是至少 20 个月来的最高水平。</p>   <p>Tencent shares closed up 4.8% prior to earnings in Hong Kong. It is up just 1.7% so far this year, beating a 8.6% drop in the broader market <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a>. In the U.S., its shares rose 5.4% in over-the-counter trade early on Wednesday.</p>    <h 1="">ADVERTISING BOOST</h>  <p>Tencent's online advertising business also reported a solid quarter, posting a 20% jump in revenue driven by strong demand for advertising in its video content.翻译:腾讯的在线广告业务也报告了强劲的季度业绩，在视频内容广告的强劲需求推动下，收入增长了 20%。</p>   <p>Tencent said ecommcerce companies have "beomce a much bigger contributor to [the company's] ad revenue in recent periods".翻译:腾讯表示，电子商务公司“近年来对[公司]广告收入做出了更大的贡献”。</p>   <p>Ecommerce companies tend to advertise in the second half of the year, explaining the ad sales surge Tencent experienced in the quarter.翻译:电子商务公司倾向于在下半年投放广告，这解释了腾讯在本季度广告销售激增的原因。</p>   <p>Its fintech business, its second-largest business unit, reported a 16% climb in sales following an improved performance from wealth management services and online transactions.翻译:其第二大业务部门金融科技业务的销售额增长了 16%，得益于财富管理服务和在线交易的业绩改善。</p>   <p>Net profit declined 9% to 36.1 billion yuan from a year ago when the company had a strong quarter after divesting stakes in portfolio companies such as Sea.翻译:在剥离 Sea 等投资组合公司的股份后，该公司季度业绩表现强劲，净利润较上年同期下降 9% 至 361 亿元。</p>   <p>Tencent also saw its overall gross margin continue to improve in the third quarter. It neared 50%, reaching levels last seen in 2018. The company attributes the improvement to its willingness to kill unprofitable businesses, a strategy it has made clear in recent quarters.翻译:腾讯第三季度的整体毛利率也继续改善。该比率接近 50%，达到 2018 年的水平。该公司将这一改善归因于其愿意取消不盈利的业务，​​这是该公司在最近几个季度明确的战略。</p>   <p>Pony Ma, chairman of Tencent, said the company had in the third quarter continued to "refocus away from less scalable activities" while emphasising high-margin revenue streams.翻译:腾讯董事长马化腾表示，该公司在第三季度继续“重新关注规模较小的业务”，同时强调高利润收入来源。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2405 Chinese yuan)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2405 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Josh Ye; Editing by Miyoung Kim, Edwina Gibbs and Barbara Lewis翻译:乔希·叶报道；编辑：Miyoung Kim、Edwina Gibbs 和 Barbara Lewis</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:01:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">NBSW7X37R5MHTLKYFUNSR3KCVU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/tencent-logs-strong-revenue-growth-games-sales-shine-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Josh Ye]]></author>
            
                
                <category>TENCENT</category>
                
                <category>RESULTS/ (UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[国际货币基金组织总裁敦促央行更积极推动数字货币]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/k5TR6omoCMWr3tJjvV5YB9zFO0w=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WI7BDNQ4VRKOFCCQMOLJ6CDSVI.jpg" alt="The IMF logo is seen outside the headquarters building in Washington翻译:华盛顿总部大楼外可见国际货币基金组织的标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) logo is seen outside the headquarters building in Washington, U.S., September 4, 2018. REUTERS/Yuri Gripas/File Photo翻译:2018年9月4日，国际货币基金组织（IMF）标志出现在美国华盛顿总部大楼外。REUTERS/Yuri Gripas/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The head of the International Monetary Fund has urged countries to make a more proactive push to develop central bank digital currencies (CBDC).翻译:国际货币基金组织总裁敦促各国更加积极地推动央行数字货币（CBDC）的发展。</p>   <p>Eleven countries, including a number in the Caribbean, and Nigeria, have already launched CBDCs. Around 120 others are exploring them, although progress and approaches differ widely and a few have even abandoned the idea altogether.翻译:包括加勒比地区的一些国家和尼日利亚在内的 11 个国家已经推出了 CBDC。大约 120 个人正在探索它们，尽管进展和方法差异很大，有些人甚至完全放弃了这个想法。</p>   <p>"We may be at a point where the public sector needs to offer a little more guidance," IMF Managing Director Kristalina Georgieva said in a speech in Singapore.翻译:国际货币基金组织总裁克里斯塔利娜·格奥尔基耶娃在新加坡的一次演讲中表示：“我们可能正处于公共部门需要提供更多指导的时刻。”</p>   <p>"Not to crowd out, not to disrupt," she added. "But to act as a catalyst, to ensure safety and efficiency - and to counter fragmentation."翻译:“不要排挤，也不要扰乱，”她补充道。 “但要充当催化剂，确保安全和效率，并对抗碎片化。”</p>   <p>She made her remarks as the IMF published the first instalment of a <a href="https://www.imf.org/en/Topics/fintech/central-bank-digital-currency/virtual-handbook" target="_blank">"virtual handbook"</a> on CBDCs, designed to help countries with the design and set-up process and ensure that the new technologies are globally interoperable.翻译:她是在国际货币基金组织发布第一部分有关 CBDC 的<a href="https://www.imf.org/en/Topics/fintech/central-bank-digital-currency/virtual-handbook" target="_blank">“虚拟手册”</a>时发表上述言论的，该手册旨在帮助各国进行设计和设置过程，并确保新技术在全球范围内可互操作。</p>   <p>Supporters say CBDCs will modernise payments with new functionality and provide an alternative to physical cash, which seems in terminal decline.翻译:支持者表示，CBDC 将通过新功能实现支付现代化，并提供实物现金的替代品，而实物现金似乎正在走向衰落。</p>   <p>But <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/time-central-bank-digital-currencies-prove-their-worth-2023-10-22/">questions remain</a> as to why they represent an advance when current systems are already capable of many of the proposed benefits, and countries such as Nigeria that have already launched CBDCs are seeing very low uptake among the public.翻译:但<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/time-central-bank-digital-currencies-prove-their-worth-2023-10-22/">问题仍然在于</a>，当当前系统已经能够实现许多拟议的好处时，为什么它们代表了一种进步，而尼日利亚等已经推出 CBDC 的国家却发现公众的接受度非常低。</p>   <p>Georgieva said that with technology advancing so rapidly, countries needed to push ahead with development now to avoid getting caught out in future.翻译:格奥尔基耶娃表示，随着技术进步如此之快，各国现在需要推动发展，以避免未来陷入困境。</p>   <p>"If anything, we need to raise another sail to pick up speed," she said, likening the efforts to a nautical journey. "The world is changing faster than most imagined".翻译:“如果有的话，我们需要再次扬帆以加快速度，”她说，并将这些努力比作航海之旅。 “世界的变化比大多数人想象的要快”。</p>    <span>Reporting by Marc Jones; Editing by Paul Simao翻译:马克·琼斯的报道；保罗·西毛编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 15:05:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">QZXVH7YS2FORJMLCBOYXZW7MLQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/imf-chief-urges-more-proactive-push-central-bank-digital-currencies-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Marc Jones]]></author>
            
                
                <category>IMF</category>
                
                <category>DIGITALCURRENCIES/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[欧洲公司探索增加稀有金属供应的方法]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>China has imposed export restrictions on gallium, germanium</li>  <li>Industry says underlying aluminium, zinc smelting needs support</li>  <li>Zinc, aluminium sectors under pressure from high energy costs</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>中国对镓、锗实施出口限制</li><li>行业称基础铝、锌冶炼需支撑</li><li>锌、铝行业面临高能源成本压力</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/QvTbfyDZrb0eakF8DW56tMtf8NM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HPZKJDXGGVOZNCI4I6PGQL5WP4.jpg" alt="An undated photo shows a rare earth open pit near Nam Xe mine in Lai Chau province翻译:一张未注明日期的照片显示了莱州省 Nam Xe 矿附近的一个稀土露天矿坑" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An undated photo shows a rare earth open pit near Nam Xe mine in Lai Chau province翻译:一张未注明日期的照片显示了莱州省 Nam Xe 矿附近的一个稀土露天矿坑. REUTERS/File Photo翻译:一张未注明日期的照片显示了莱州省 Nam Xe 矿附近的一个稀土露天矿坑。路透社/资料图</figcaption></figure>       <p>European companies are exploring ways to replace the gallium and germanium supply put at risk by China's export curbs after pressure from EU authorities, but the industry says incentives will be needed to make critical mineral production viable.翻译:在欧盟当局的压力下，欧洲公司正在探索替代因中国出口限制而面临风险的镓和锗供应的方法，但该行业表示，需要采取激励措施才能使关键矿产生产可行。</p>   <p>China, which processes 80% of the world's gallium and 60% of its germanium, imposed restrictions on exports of the metals used in high-tech electronics from August, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-export-curbs-choke-off-shipments-gallium-germanium-second-month-2023-10-20/">choking off shipments</a>.翻译:中国加工了全球 80% 的镓和 60% 的锗，从 8 月起对用于高科技电子产品的金属实施出口限制， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-export-curbs-choke-off-shipments-gallium-germanium-second-month-2023-10-20/">导致出货量受阻</a>。</p>   <p>The European Commission gathered potential suppliers and buyers last week in a bid to encourage local production, people familiar with the meeting said.翻译:知情人士称，欧盟委员会上周召集了潜在供应商和买家，以鼓励本地生产。</p>   <p>Greek energy and metals group Mytilineos <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MYTr.AT" target="_blank">(MYTr.AT)</a>, present at the meeting, said it has a pilot project to assess the most cost-effective way to extract gallium that it could build to scale in 18 months.翻译:出席会议的希腊能源和金属集团 Mytilineos <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MYTr.AT" target="_blank">(MYTr.AT)</a>表示，该公司有一个试点项目，旨在评估最具成本效益的镓提取方法，并可在 18 个月内实现规模化生产。</p>   <p>That could produce 40-45 metric tons of the metal a year, roughly equal to current EU demand, it said. Gallium is typically a by-product of processing bauxite into aluminium precursor alumina.翻译:该公司表示，每年可生产 40-45 吨金属，大致相当于欧盟目前的需求。镓通常是将铝土矿加工成铝前体氧化铝的副产品。</p>   <p>CEO Evangelos Mytilineos said a key requirement is support for its core aluminium business, which the industry says has in Europe been labouring under high energy prices and levies to come for carbon emissions.翻译:首席执行官 Evangelos Mytilineos 表示，关键要求是对其核心铝业务的支持，业内人士表示，欧洲的铝业务一直在高能源价格和碳排放税的压力下苦苦挣扎。</p>   <p>"We are trapped by the tools selected by the EU for the green transition. We need massive affordable energy," Mytilineos said.翻译:“我们被欧盟选择的绿色转型工具所困。我们需要大量负担得起的能源，”米蒂利内奥斯说。</p>   <p>"We see demand is rising. The Commission needs to provide incentives to go for it." The company said EU-supported contracts for difference that ensure future prices could help.翻译:“我们看到需求正在上升。委员会需要提供激励措施来实现这一目标。”该公司表示，欧盟支持的确保未来价格的差价合约可能会有所帮助。</p>   <p>European primary aluminium production fell by a third from a peak in 2008 to 2022. Smelters of zinc ore, from which germanium is a by-product, face similar pressure from energy costs.翻译:欧洲原铝产量从 2008 年的峰值到 2022 年下降了三分之一。副产品锗的锌矿冶炼厂也面临着类似的能源成本压力。</p>   <p>Belgian zinc producer Nyrstar <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NYR.BR" target="_blank">(NYR.BR)</a> has said it is looking into potential projects for gallium and germanium recovery in Europe, although is more advanced in its search in the U.S., with a $150 million project in mind.翻译:比利时锌生产商 Nyrstar <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NYR.BR" target="_blank">(NYR.BR)</a>表示，它正在欧洲寻找潜在的镓和锗回收项目，尽管在美国的搜索更为深入，考虑的是一个 1.5 亿美元的项目。</p>   <p>The EU's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/eu-set-okay-rules-secure-critical-raw-materials-eu-official-says-2023-11-13/">Critical Raw Materials Act</a>, which will set targets for mining, recycling and processing of 17 key materials, is likely to enter force in the coming months.翻译:欧盟<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/eu-set-okay-rules-secure-critical-raw-materials-eu-official-says-2023-11-13/">《关键原材料法案》</a>可能会在未来几个月生效，该法案将为 17 种关键材料的开采、回收和加工设定目标。</p>   <p>The European association for non-ferrous metal producers Eurometaux said it needed to be backed by funding and measures to cut operating costs for the industry.翻译:欧洲有色金属生产商协会 Eurometaux 表示，它需要资金和措施的支持，以削减该行业的运营成本。</p>   <p>Eurometaux said the issue was broader than just gallium and germanium supply, and the EU needed to create conditions for future operations to be viable.翻译:Eurometaux表示，这个问题不仅仅是镓和锗的供应，欧盟需要为未来的运营创造条件。</p>   <p>"Last year it was magnesium, last month graphite, and we don't know what metals will be next. We in Europe need to move from reactive to proactive mode, preparing for future shocks," it said.翻译:“去年是镁，上个月是石墨，我们不知道接下来会是什么金属。我们欧洲需要从被动模式转向主动模式，为未来的冲击做好准备，”它说。</p>    <span>Reporting by Philip Blenkinsop; Editing by Jan Harvey翻译:菲利普·布伦金索普报道；扬·哈维编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 14:43:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">YJVDQYNAOJOLXF6MD2RGARGKSY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/european-companies-exploring-ways-boost-rare-metal-supply-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Philip Blenkinsop]]></author>
            
                
                <category>EU</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/METALS</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[英国工党将追求更少、更高质量的贸易协议]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Simultaneous trade talks undermine quality, Reynolds says</li>  <li>Labour would give parliament more power over trade deals</li>  <li>Labour's Reynolds questions review of takeover powers</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>雷诺兹表示，同时进行的贸易谈判损害了质量</li><li>工党将赋予议会更多贸易协议权力</li><li>工党雷诺兹质疑收购权审查</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/WcyjUelRFclFqW0CxUHSve6czKQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/F3JQOA2LONL5NFPB46N3YAXIXI.jpg" alt="Britain’s Labour Party annual conference in Liverpool翻译:英国工党年会在利物浦举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Britain’s Shadow Secretary of State for Business and Trade Jonathan Reynolds, makes his keynote speech during the Labour Party annual conference in Liverpool, Britain, October 9, 2023. REUTERS/Phil Noble/File photo翻译:英国影子商业和贸易大臣乔纳森·雷诺兹于 2023 年 10 月 9 日在英国利物浦举行的工党年会上发表主旨演讲。路透社/Phil Noble/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>英国工党将追求更少、更高质量的贸易协议 if it came to power, and give parliament stronger oversight, its trade policy chief said on Wednesday, criticising the government's approach as "scattergun".</p>   <p>Britain has pursued a range of trade deals since it left the European Union, clinching agreements with the likes of Australia and New Zealand, while talks with India this year have gathered momentum.翻译:自离开欧盟以来，英国一直在寻求一系列贸易协议，与澳大利亚和新西兰等国达成了协议，而今年与印度的谈判势头强劲。</p>   <p>Labour's Jonathan Reynolds said he would support a trade deal with India and that countries currently negotiating with Britain would find a "willing partner" in Labour because "stability matters".翻译:工党的乔纳森·雷诺兹表示，他将支持与印度达成贸易协议，目前正在与英国谈判的国家将在工党中找到“愿意的合作伙伴”，因为“稳定很重要”。</p>   <p>However, asked if nascent trade talks with the likes of Canada and Mexico would continue under a Labour government, he said "I don't think you can find another example of a country negotiating so much simultaneously, and you have to wonder about the impact that has on the overall quality."翻译:然而，当被问及与加拿大和墨西哥等国的新贸易谈判是否会在工党政府领导下继续进行时，他说：“我认为你找不到另一个国家同时进行如此多谈判的例子，你必须想知道其影响这关系到整体质量。”</p>   <p>"The specifics of finishing those deals depends on where they are, but I think focusing more on the quality of what we're seeking to achieve in each of these negotiations is a far better objective than the kind of scattergun strategy we see today," he said at an event in London.翻译:“完成这些交易的具体细节取决于它们的进展情况，但我认为，更多地关注我们在每项谈判中寻求实现的目标的质量，比我们今天看到的那种散弹枪策略要好得多。”他在伦敦的一次活动中说道。</p>   <p>The opposition Labour Party holds a lead in opinion polls of around 20 points ahead of an election expected next year, and business leaders have taken an increasing interest in what any new Labour government would do if it got into power.翻译:在预计明年举行的大选之前，反对党工党在民意调查中领先约 20 个百分点，商界领袖对新工党政府上台后会做什么越来越感兴趣。</p>   <p>Reynolds told representatives from banks, consultancies, and FTSE 100 companies that Labour would also give parliament a "proper role" in how trade deals are ratified, after lawmakers criticised the lack of oversight currently.翻译:雷诺兹告诉银行、咨询公司和富时 100 指数公司的代表，在立法者批评目前缺乏监督之后，工党还将让议会在如何批准贸易协议方面发挥“适当的作用”。</p>   <p>Outside of free trade agreements, he said Britain should also pursue standalone deals on areas like digital and critical minerals.翻译:他表示，除了自由贸易协定之外，英国还应该在数字和关键矿产等领域寻求独立协议。</p>   <p>Reynolds also questioned a decision by the government to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/britain-reviews-scrutiny-foreign-takeovers-2023-11-13/">review</a> how it screens foreign takeovers for national security concerns, powers that have been used several times to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-opposes-uks-discriminatory-actions-against-china-linked-deals-2023-07-12/">intervene</a> in takeovers, particularly linked to China.翻译:雷诺兹还质疑政府出于国家安全考虑而<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/britain-reviews-scrutiny-foreign-takeovers-2023-11-13/">审查</a>如何审查外国收购的决定，这些权力已多次被用来<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-opposes-uks-discriminatory-actions-against-china-linked-deals-2023-07-12/">干预</a>收购，特别是与中国有关的收购。</p>   <p>"Chinese investment simply cannot be treated in the same way we would some other countries," he said, adding new foreign minister David Cameron had shown "incredible naivety" towards China when he was prime minister.翻译:他说：“根本不能像对待其他一些国家那样对待中国投资。”他补充说，新任外交部长戴维·卡梅伦在担任首相期间对中国表现出了“令人难以置信的天真”。</p>   <p>"The measures as they are now are sufficient, and to dilute them would be a worrying signal to send."翻译:“目前的措施已经足够了，削弱这些措施将是一个令人担忧的信号。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Alistair Smout; Editing by Toby Chopra翻译:阿利斯泰尔·斯莫特报道；托比·乔普拉编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 13:44:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5OGPUMOLEZN67OHNVVVJDBJMOE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/britains-labour-party-would-pursue-fewer-higher-quality-trade-deals-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Alistair Smout]]></author>
            
                
                <category>BRITAIN</category>
                
                <category>POLITICS/LABOUR</category>
                
                <category>TRADE (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[百度首席执行官警告中国急于开发人工智能模型可能会浪费资源]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/zW2Ia7qPsYkjbH89Fifs3NlvDFw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/U6WCYQF7ENNHNJKJ2ZMM7GRFEQ.jpg" alt="Men interact with a Baidu AI robot near the company logo at its headquarters in Beijing翻译:在北京总部的公司标志附近，男性与百度人工智能机器人互动" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Men interact with a Baidu AI robot near the company logo at its headquarters in Beijing翻译:在北京总部的公司标志附近，男性与百度人工智能机器人互动, China April 23, 2021. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo翻译:2021 年 4 月 23 日，中国北京总部，男性在公司徽标附近与百度人工智能机器人互动。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/wSpWE3v-pYE_l7PBFoRNoGJwE4M=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZZCDNTM76FPAXMENIGWKAKF2XQ.jpg" alt="News conference on Ernie Bot by Baidu at the company's headquarters in Beijing翻译:百度在北京总部举行 Ernie Bot 新闻发布会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Baidu's co-founder and Chief Executive Officer (CEO) Robin Li showcases artificial intelligence-powered chatbot known as Ernie Bot by Baidu, during a news conference at the company's headquarters in Beijing, China March 16, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo翻译:2023 年 3 月 16 日，百度联合创始人兼首席执行官 (CEO) 李彦宏在中国北京公司总部举行的新闻发布会上展示了人工智能驱动的聊天机器人，即百度的 Ernie Bot。 REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/档案照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>The head of one of China's leading AI firms, Baidu <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9888.HK" target="_blank">(9888.HK)</a>, warned on Wednesday that the fervor rushing to develop large language models in China could lead to a waste of resources, saying firms needed to focus their efforts on developing practical applications.翻译:中国领先的人工智能公司之一百度<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9888.HK" target="_blank">（9888.HK）</a>的负责人周三警告称，中国急于开发大型语言模型的热潮可能会导致资源浪费，并表示企业需要将精力集中在开发实际应用上。</p>   <p>Robin Li made his comments at an industry forum in Shenzhen amid mounting market worries over a potential <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-ai-war-hundred-models-heads-shakeout-2023-09-21/">industry shakeout</a> as companies developing large language models have yet to find viable business models.翻译:李彦宏在深圳的一个行业论坛上发表上述言论之际，市场对潜在的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-ai-war-hundred-models-heads-shakeout-2023-09-21/">行业震荡</a>日益担忧，因为开发大型语言模型的公司尚未找到可行的商业模式。</p>   <p>Since the release of chatbot ChatGPT by OpenAI late last year, generative artificial intelligence (AI) has attracted significant interest in China, with both established companies and startups jumping into the field.翻译:自去年年底 OpenAI 发布聊天机器人 ChatGPT 以来，生成式人工智能（AI）在中国引起了极大的兴趣，老牌公司和初创公司纷纷涌入该领域。</p>   <p>"I've observed a phenomenon (in China) where many industries, companies and even cities are purchasing hardware, stocking chips, (and) building computing centres to train proprietary large models from scratch."翻译:“我观察到一个现象（在中国），许多行业、公司甚至城市都在购买硬件、储备芯片、（和）建造计算中心，从头开始训练专有的大型模型。”</p>   <p>"A large language model itself is a basic foundation akin to an operating system, but ultimately developers need to rely on a limited number of large models to develop various native applications. Therefore, constantly redeveloping foundational large models represents an enormous waste of social resources," Li said.翻译:“大语言模型本身是类似于操作系统的基础，但最终开发者需要依靠有限数量的大模型来开发各种原生应用。因此，不断地重新开发基础大模型是对社会资源的巨大浪费， ”李说。</p>   <p>Li said there are many large models in China, but AI applications developed based on large models are still very few.翻译:李说，中国有很多大型模型，但基于大型模型开发的人工智能应用仍然很少。</p>   <p>As of October, 238 large language models have been released, up from just 79 in June, according to Li, citing a third-party report.翻译:Li 援引第三方报告称，截至 10 月，已经发布了 238 个大型语言模型，而 6 月份仅为 79 个。</p>   <p>Baidu's own large language model, called Ernie, was opened to public use in August, joining other products that have received government approval for release. Last month, Baidu <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-baidu-unveils-latest-version-its-ernie-ai-model-2023-10-17/">unveiled</a> the newest version of its generative AI model Ernie 4.0, whose first version was first rolled out in March.翻译:百度自己的大型语言模型 Ernie 于 8 月向公众开放，加入了其他已获得政府批准发布的产品行列。上个月，百度<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-baidu-unveils-latest-version-its-ernie-ai-model-2023-10-17/">推出了</a>最新版本的生成式人工智能模型Ernie 4.0，其首个版本已于3月份首次推出。</p>    <span>Reporting by Yelin Mo in Beijing and Brenda Goh in Shanghai; Additional reporting by Eduardo Baptista; Editing by Kim Coghill翻译:莫叶琳北京报道、布兰达吴上海报道；爱德华多·巴普蒂斯塔 (Eduardo Baptista) 的补充报道；编辑：金·科吉尔</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 12:47:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">N3LFDJDUJJNAFB7PYU5XAZRIBI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/baidu-ceo-warns-chinas-rush-develop-ai-models-risks-wasting-resources-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>BAIDU</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[丹麦海峡：俄罗斯三分之一海运原油出口的门户]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/pD9dyauZ2uVuw9TbKbTCQSbkb3w=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZNHXV7YG7NKCDNV6JX2G5KNISA.jpg" alt="Shun Tai crude oil tanker is seen anchored at the terminal Kozmino in Nakhodka Bay翻译:顺泰原油轮停泊在纳霍德卡湾科兹米诺码头" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Shun Tai crude oil tanker is seen anchored at the terminal Kozmino in Nakhodka Bay翻译:顺泰原油轮停泊在纳霍德卡湾科兹米诺码头 near the port city of Nakhodka, Russia, December 4, 2022. REUTERS/Tatiana Meel/File Photo翻译:2022年12月4日，顺泰原油轮停泊在俄罗斯港口城市纳霍德卡附近纳霍德卡湾的科兹米诺码头。REUTERS/Tatiana Meel/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Denmark could potentially block Russian oil tankers sailing through its waters under new European Union plans, the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/denmark-could-block-russian-oil-tankers-reaching-markets-ft-2023-11-15/">Financial Times reported</a> on Wednesday, as the West explores more ways of enforcing a price cap on Moscow's exported crude.翻译:据<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/denmark-could-block-russian-oil-tankers-reaching-markets-ft-2023-11-15/">英国《金融时报》周三报道</a>，随着西方探索更多方式对莫斯科出口原油实施价格上限，丹麦可能根据欧盟新计划阻止俄罗斯油轮通过其水域。</p>   <p>Following are details about the route:翻译:以下是有关路线的详细信息：</p>   <p>* The Danish straits between Jutland (mainland Denmark) and the Scandinavian Peninsula (Norway, Sweden and Finland) allow vessels to exit the Baltic Sea and include two fairways for commercial shipping.翻译:* 日德兰半岛（丹麦大陆）和斯堪的纳维亚半岛（挪威、瑞典和芬兰）之间的丹麦海峡允许船只驶出波罗的海，并包括两条商业航运航道。</p>   <p>* Russia's main Baltic Sea ports are Primorsk, Ust-Luga, St. Petersburg, Vyborg, Vysotsk and Kaliningrad. Russia exports its flagship Urals oil grade via the ports, while Kazakhstan uses them to export its Kazakhstan Export Blend Crude Oil (KEBCO).翻译:* 俄罗斯波罗的海的主要港口有滨海边疆区、乌斯季卢加、圣彼得堡、维堡、维索茨克和加里宁格勒。俄罗斯通过这些港口出口其旗舰级乌拉尔石油，而哈萨克斯坦则利用这些港口出口哈萨克斯坦出口混合原油（KEBCO）。</p>   <p>* The ports of Primorsk and Ust-Luga are set to export more than 1.5 million barrels per day (bpd) of crude oil in November, which is around 1.5% of global oil supply, or more than a third of Russia's total seaborne oil exports.翻译:* 普里莫尔斯克港和乌斯季卢加港预计11月份每天出口超过150万桶原油，约占全球石油供应量的1.5%，或占俄罗斯海运石油出口总量的三分之一以上。</p>   <p>* Cargo handling at Russia's Baltic Sea ports fell by almost 3% last year to 245.6 million metric tons while the volume of liquid cargoes rose by 11.8% to 148.6 million tons, according to data from the Russian Federal Agency for Sea and Inland Water Transport (Rosmorrechflot).翻译:* 根据俄罗斯联邦海上和内陆水运局的数据，去年俄罗斯波罗的海港口的货物吞吐量下降近 3%，至 2.456 亿吨，而液体货物量则增长 11.8%，至 1.486 亿吨。罗斯莫雷赫弗洛特）。</p>   <p>* Before the start of the conflict in Ukraine in February 2022, all Russian oil exports from the Baltic Sea were shipped to Europe. Since then, the bulk has gone to India, China, Egypt and Turkey.翻译:* 2022年2月乌克兰冲突爆发之前，俄罗斯从波罗的海出口的所有石油都运往欧洲。从那时起，大部分销往印度、中国、埃及和土耳其。</p>    <span>Reporting by Vladimir Soldatkin; editing by Guy Faulconbridge and Jason Neely翻译:弗拉基米尔·索尔达特金报道；盖伊·福尔肯布里奇和杰森·尼利编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 11:22:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7VIB7K3LZZL7FDTWE7GSN4BCFQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/danish-straits-gateway-third-russias-sea-borne-crude-exports-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>UKRAINE</category>
                
                <category>CRISIS/RUSSIA</category>
                
                <category>OIL</category>
                
                <category>DENMARK (FACTBOX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[日本和中国将就贸易问题举行定期会谈 - 媒体]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ou9Sk6ccXVlkLm_qd6XsyX4MZRo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TD3VAGTBZVJJ5EH53YM4EBOJHU.jpg" alt="Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida reshuffles his cabinet翻译:日本首相岸田文雄改组内阁" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Japan's Minister of Economy, Trade and Industry Yasutoshi Nishimura walks on the day of the cabinet reshuffle, at the Prime Minister's office in Tokyo, Japan September 13, 2023. REUTERS/Issei Kato/File photo翻译:2023年9月13日，日本经济产业大臣西村康稔在内阁改组当天在日本东京首相办公室散步。路透社/Issei Kato/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Japanese and Chinese trade ministers have agreed to establish a framework to discuss export controls, Japanese media reported on Wednesday, indicating steps on economic cooperation after a period of strained ties between the neighbours.翻译:据日本媒体周三报道，日本和中国贸易部长已同意建立一个讨论出口管制的框架，这表明在邻国关系紧张一段时间后将采取经济合作措施。</p>   <p>Japanese Trade Minister Yasutoshi Nishimura said the talks could help stabilise relations.翻译:日本经济产业大臣西村康稔表示，会谈有助于稳定关系。</p>   <p>"We will hold firm discussions with Chinese officials to build constructive and stable Japan-China relations," Nishimura was quoted as saying after talks with his counterpart, Wang Wentao, on the sidelines of an Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation meeting in San Francisco.翻译:“我们将与中国官员进行坚定的讨论，以建立建设性和稳定的日中关系，”西村在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织会议期间与外长王文涛会谈后表示。</p>   <p>The dialogue is expected to be held by officials at the level of director-general and section chief, who are in charge of export controls, the Yomiuri newspaper reported.翻译:据《读卖新闻》报道，此次对话预计将由负责出口管制的总干事和科长级别的官员举行。</p>   <p>China has recently imposed curbs on the exports of some materials, including chipmaking metals like <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-export-curbs-choke-off-shipments-gallium-germanium-second-month-2023-10-20/">gallium</a>, and is expected to restrict exports of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-ups-critical-minerals-heat-with-graphite-controls-2023-10-24/">graphite</a>, used in batteries, in December.翻译:中国最近对一些材料的出口实施了限制，包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-export-curbs-choke-off-shipments-gallium-germanium-second-month-2023-10-20/">镓</a>等芯片制造金属，并预计将于 12 月限制用于电池的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-ups-critical-minerals-heat-with-graphite-controls-2023-10-24/">石墨</a>的出口。</p>   <p>The talks are aimed at preventing an escalation of retaliatory trade disputes with China, the Yomiuri reported.翻译:据《读卖新闻》报道，此次会谈旨在防止与中国的报复性贸易争端升级。</p>   <p>Before heading to the U.S. to attend the APEC meeting, Kishida told reporters nothing has been decided regarding a meeting with China's leader Xi Jinping on the sidelines.翻译:在前往美国参加亚太经合组织会议之前，岸田告诉记者，关于与中国领导人习近平会面的事宜尚未做出任何决定。</p>   <p>"There is no change in our basic stance that both sides must make the effort to maintain stable and constructive relations," Kishida said. "We would like to continue communicating (with China) in various forms."翻译:岸田说：“我们的基本立场没有改变，即双方必须努力维持稳定和建设性的关系。” “我们愿意继续以各种形式（与中国）进行沟通。”</p>   <p>Relations between China and Japan, rarely smooth, have been particularly strained over recent months.翻译:中国和日本之间的关系绝非一帆风顺，近几个月来尤其紧张。</p>   <p>Japan <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japan-says-harassment-calls-china-regarding-fukushima-water-release-extremely-2023-08-28/">infuriated </a>China when it began releasing treated radioactive water from its wrecked Fukushima nuclear plant into the ocean in August.翻译:日本八月开始将受损福岛核电站处理过的放射性水排入海洋， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japan-says-harassment-calls-china-regarding-fukushima-water-release-extremely-2023-08-28/">激怒了</a>中国。</p>   <p>China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-formally-arrests-astellas-employee-suspected-spying-japan-urges-release-2023-10-19/">last month</a> formally arrested a Japanese executive, an employee of Japanese drugmaker Astellas Pharma <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/4503.T" target="_blank">(4503.T)</a>, on suspicion of espionage. The arrest has had a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/how-an-executives-arrest-struck-blow-japan-china-business-2023-11-14/">chilling effect</a> on business, Japanese officials said.翻译:中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-formally-arrests-astellas-employee-suspected-spying-japan-urges-release-2023-10-19/">上个月</a>以涉嫌间谍罪正式逮捕了一名日本制药商安斯泰来制药公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/4503.T" target="_blank">（Astellas Pharma，4503.T）</a>员工的日本高管。日本官员表示，这次逮捕对商业产生了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/how-an-executives-arrest-struck-blow-japan-china-business-2023-11-14/">寒蝉效应</a>。</p>    <span>Reporting by Satoshi Sugiyama and Sakura Murakami; Editing by Jan Harvey and Robert Birsel翻译:杉山聪和村上樱的报道；扬·哈维和罗伯特·伯塞尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 11:20:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6C2CTCIDOBI3NKAZFZDKRPRQBE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japan-china-hold-regular-talks-trade-issues-media-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>JAPAN</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/TRADE (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[北汽集团申请批准在中国生产小米品牌电动汽车]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/A6KRCsJlEONddXqagYCvBz2fpAk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SPJ4YBH6ERL3NJPGPUFBWXH5QU.jpg" alt="View of BAIC Group automobile maker stall at the IEEV New Energy Vehicles Exhibition in Beijing翻译:北汽集团汽车制造商在北京IEEV新能源汽车展上的摊位视图" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People clean the floor at the stall of the BAIC Group automobile maker at the IEEV New Energy Vehicles Exhibition in Beijing, China October 18, 2018.  Picture taken October 18, 2018.   REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2018年10月18日，在中国北京举行的IEEV新能源汽车展览会上，人们在北汽集团汽车制造商的摊位上清洁地板。照片拍摄于2018年10月18日。路透社/Thomas Peter/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A unit of Beijing-based automaker BAIC Group &lt;1958.HK&gt; has applied to regulators for approval to build two Xiaomi-branded &lt;1810.HK&gt; electric vehicles (EVs), China's industry ministry website showed on Wednesday.翻译:中国工信部网站周三显示，北京汽车制造商北汽集团&lt;1958.HK&gt;旗下子公司已向监管机构申请批准生产两辆小米品牌&lt;1810.HK&gt;电动汽车(EV)。</p>   <p>The foray by Xiaomi, best known for making smartphones and appliances, could intensify competition in the world's largest auto market, where overcapacity and slowing demand have fanned a bruising price war and hit supplier margins.翻译:以生产智能手机和家电而闻名的小米的进军可能会加剧全球最大汽车市场的竞争，该市场产能过剩和需求放缓引发了激烈的价格战，并打击了供应商的利润率。</p>   <p>BAIC ORV is proposing to build two versions of the new Xiaomi-branded model in Beijing, according to its filing: the SU7 with BYD's lithium iron phosphate batteries and a top speed of 210 kilometres per hour (kph); and the SU7 Max with CATL's nickel- and cobalt-based lithium batteries and speed of up to 265 kph.翻译:根据其备案文件，北汽 ORV 拟在北京生产两种版本的新小米品牌车型：配备比亚迪磷酸铁锂电池的 SU7，最高时速为 210 公里每小时 (kph)； SU7 Max配备宁德时代镍钴锂电池，时速可达265公里。</p>   <p>Both models bore a "MI" logo in the front and carried the "Xiaomi" name on their rear, pictures published on the Ministry of Industry and Information's (MIIT) website showed.翻译:工业和信息化部（工信部）网站上发布的图片显示，这两款机型的正面均带有“MI”标志，背面均带有“小米”名称。</p>   <p>The filing indicates that BAIC will be the manufacturer for these two models, even though Xiaomi has built a plant that can produce 200,000 EVs annually in Beijing. The new EVs will be built at a site that is the same address as the Xiaomi plant, China Business News reported.翻译:文件显示，尽管小米已在北京建立了一家年产 20 万辆电动汽车的工厂，但北汽集团将成为这两款车型的制造商。据第一财经报道，新电动汽车将在与小米工厂相同的地点生产。</p>   <p>Xiaomi has listed many job openings for auto sales, including postings for new energy vehicles sales manager and Xiaomi car showroom manager in Beijing and Shanghai, business publication STAR Market Daily reported on Wednesday.翻译:据商业刊物《星空市场日报》周三报道，小米列出了许多汽车销售职位空缺，包括北京和上海的新能源汽车销售经理和小米汽车展厅经理的职位空缺。</p>   <p>Both BAIC and Xiaomi did not immediately respond to requests for comment on the EV applications.翻译:北汽和小米均未立即回应对电动汽车应用的置评请求。</p>   <p>Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-xiaomi-wins-state-planner-nod-make-evs-amid-glut-autos-2023-08-23/">reported</a> in August that China's state planner had given approval to Xiaomi to build electric vehicles but that it still needed clearance from the MIIT, which assesses new automakers and models for technical and safety requirements.翻译:路透社8月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-xiaomi-wins-state-planner-nod-make-evs-amid-glut-autos-2023-08-23/">报道</a>称，中国国家规划部门已批准小米生产电动汽车，但仍需要工信部的批准，工信部负责评估新汽车制造商和车型的技术和安全要求。</p>   <p>The ministry publishes lists almost on a monthly basis of aspiring auto manufacturers applying for approvals, but Xiaomi was not among firms named on the latest list published on Wednesday.翻译:工信部几乎每月都会公布有抱负的汽车制造商申请批准的名单，但小米并不在周三公布的最新名单上。</p>   <p>The company's progress on EV manufacturing is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/xiaomi-president-says-ev-manufacturing-plans-ahead-schedule-2023-08-29/">ahead</a> of schedule, Xiaomi President Lu Weibing told a company earnings call in late August. Its revenue fell 4% in the second quarter from a year earlier amid a shrinkage in China's smartphone market.翻译:小米总裁卢伟冰在八月下旬的公司财报电话会议上表示，该公司在电动汽车制造方面的进展<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/xiaomi-president-says-ev-manufacturing-plans-ahead-schedule-2023-08-29/">提前</a>了。由于中国智能手机市场萎缩，其第二季度收入同比下降4%。</p>   <p>The world's largest automotive market, however, is grappling with overcapacity and a deepening price war that has pulled in over 40 brands and is weighing on the supply chain's profit margins.翻译:然而，这个全球最大的汽车市场正在努力应对产能过剩和不断深化的价格战，这场价格战已吸引了 40 多个品牌入驻，并给供应链的利润率带来压力。</p>   <p>Tesla Inc <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a> had yet to win a regulatory nod to proceed with its Shanghai plant expansion <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/teslas-china-expansion-hits-speed-bump-amid-industry-overcapacity-2023-06-16/">plan</a>, Reuters reported in June. U.S. luxury EV maker Lucid Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LCID.O" target="_blank">(LCID.O)</a>, keen on made-in-China cars, has also been advised of the low likelihood for approval, sources have told Reuters.翻译:据路透社 6 月份报道，特斯拉公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a>尚未获得监管机构批准继续其上海工厂扩建<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/teslas-china-expansion-hits-speed-bump-amid-industry-overcapacity-2023-06-16/">计划</a>。消息人士告诉路透社，热衷于中国制造汽车的美国豪华电动汽车制造商 Lucid Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LCID.O" target="_blank">(LCID.O)</a>也被告知获得批准的可能性很低。</p>    <span>Reporting by Qiaoyi Li, Zhang Yan and Brenda Goh; Additional reporting by Mo Yelin in Beijing; Editing by Muralikumar Anantharaman and Kim Coghill翻译:李巧仪、张岩、Brenda Goh 报道；莫叶林北京补充报道； Muralikumar Anantharaman 和 Kim Coghill 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 10:09:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">GOWUX7L7KJMVJNTATE7HQIYXKE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/baic-unit-applies-manufacturing-approval-xiaomi-branded-evs-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AUTOS/BAIC (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[拜登和习近平将在受阿片类药物危机困扰的城市讨论芬太尼问题]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/OOzC6ioQ-mgW-8aYP2bkIe3IQFc=/1200x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZCI4IIB2RNMYHP6QARETZE2TBM.jpg" alt="U.S. Customs and Border Protection photo of packets of fentanyl mostly in powder form and methamphetamine which U.S. Customs and Border Protection say they seized from a truck crossing into Arizona from Mexico翻译:美国海关和边境保护局照片，其中大部分是粉末形式的芬太尼和甲基苯丙胺，美国海关和边境保护局表示，他们从一辆从墨西哥进入亚利桑那州的卡车上查获了这些物品" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Packets of fentanyl mostly in powder form and methamphetamine, which U.S. Customs and Border Protection say they seized from a truck crossing into Arizona from Mexico, is on display during a news conference at the Port of Nogales, Arizona, U.S., January 31, 2019.   Courtesy U.S. Customs and Border Protection/Handout via REUTERS /File Photo翻译:2019 年 1 月 31 日，在美国亚利桑那州诺加利斯港举行的新闻发布会上，美国海关和边境保护局表示，他们从一辆从墨西哥进入亚利桑那州的卡车上查获了几包芬太尼和甲基苯丙胺，这些芬太尼主要是粉末形式和甲基苯丙胺。由美国海关和边境保护局提供/来自路透社的讲义/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TG1TEqoix0BmSLzAs_2ZQkKdhx0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XVZII463FBIDNM7WDJMOYPZZ6Q.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden disembarks from Air Force One at San Francisco International Airport, as he arrives to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 14 日，美国总统乔·拜登在旧金山国际机场从空军一号下机，抵达美国加利福尼亚州旧金山参加亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会。 REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lTdjpZN9pb-WDBwFVbkn4Qq-Rig=/1878x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JFCDJ65EHNIW7MVYN3IPSOJ6AQ.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping waves as he arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的APEC（亚太经合组织）峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small/资料照片</figcaption></figure>                 <p>Just blocks from where U.S. President Joe Biden and his Chinese counterpart Xi Jinping will meet other Asia-Pacific leaders this week in San Francisco is a neighborhood where it is commonplace to see people using and selling drugs.翻译:距离美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平本周在旧金山会见其他亚太领导人的地点仅几个街区，在这个街区，人们吸毒和贩卖毒品的现象司空见惯。</p>   <p>While the leaders are unlikely to see the blunt reality of the U.S. opioid crisis as they attend the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum, it will be a topic of discussion when <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">Biden and Xi meet</a> one-on-one on Wednesday.翻译:尽管领导人在出席亚太经合组织（APEC）论坛时不太可能看到美国阿片类药物危机的严峻现实，但这将成为<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">拜登和习近平周三一对一会面</a>时讨论的话题。</p>   <p>The United States wants China's cooperation to stop an illicit flow of "precursor" chemicals that are used to make fentanyl, which is up to 50 times stronger than heroin and is increasingly mixed with other drugs - often with lethal results.翻译:美国希望与中国合作，制止用于制造芬太尼的“前体”化学品的非法流动，芬太尼的浓度比海洛因高出 50 倍，并且越来越多地与其他药物混合 - 往往会造成致命的结果。</p>   <p>In the first nine months of this year, 619 people died of an opioid overdose in San Francisco, most related to the synthetic opioids, compared with 647 such deaths in the whole of 2022, according to the city's Office of the Chief Medical Examiner.翻译:据旧金山首席法医办公室称，今年前 9 个月，旧金山有 619 人死于阿片类药物过量，其中大部分与合成阿片类药物有关，而 2022 年全年此类死亡人数为 647 人。</p>   <p>"It's out of control," said Mike Odeh, 36, a salesperson at a liquor store near where APEC leaders will meet.翻译:“事情已经失控了，”36 岁的迈克·奥德 (Mike Odeh) 说，他是 APEC 领导人会面地点附近一家酒类商店的销售人员。</p>   <p>He said that while the city had been cleaning up the streets ahead of APEC, he normally sees people using fentanyl while walking his son to the park and to school, adding: "You can see it all over. Not this week of course."翻译:他说，虽然该市在亚太经合组织之前一直在清理街道，但他通常会看到人们在送儿子去公园和上学时使用芬太尼，并补充道：“你可以看到这一切。当然不是本周。”</p>   <p>Across the country the rate of drug overdose deaths involving fentanyl more than tripled from 2016 through 2021, according to the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Tens of thousands of people die annually from synthetic opioid overdoses, government statistics show.翻译:根据美国疾病控制与预防中心 (CDC) 的数据，从 2016 年到 2021 年，全国范围内涉及芬太尼的药物过量死亡率增加了两倍多。政府统计数据显示，每年有数万人死于合成阿片类药物过量。</p>   <p>U.S. National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan said on Tuesday that Washington hoped the Biden-Xi summit would result in action to combat the fentanyl trade. A source familiar with plans said the U.S. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-set-take-action-win-chinas-cooperation-fentanyl-2023-11-14/">was ready to remove</a> restrictions on the Institute of Forensic Science, part of China's Ministry of Public Security.翻译:美国国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文周二表示，华盛顿希望拜登与习近平的峰会能够采取行动打击芬太尼贸易。一位熟悉计划的消息人士称，美国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-set-take-action-win-chinas-cooperation-fentanyl-2023-11-14/">准备取消</a>对中国公安部司法鉴定所的限制。</p>   <p>Washington put the institute on the Commerce Department's "entity list" in 2020 over alleged abuses toward Uyghurs and other minority groups - effectively barring it from receiving U.S. exports. China has long questioned why the U.S. would expect cooperation on fentanyl while targeting the institute.</p>    <h 1="">CHINA, MEXICO, US STANCES</h>  <p>China's embassy in Washington declined to comment on the fentanyl issue. Chinese state media has repeatedly said addiction and demand for the drug are U.S. domestic problems.翻译:中国驻华盛顿大使馆拒绝就芬太尼问题发表评论。中国官方媒体多次表示，这种药物的成瘾和需求是美国的国内问题。</p>   <p>U.S. officials say that small chemical businesses in China make precursor chemicals that are shipped to Mexico to produce illicit fentanyl, which is often mixed with other illegal drugs, sold as powders and nasal sprays, and increasingly turned into pills that look like legitimate prescription opioids. These are then smuggled into the United States, the officials say.翻译:美国官员表示，中国的小型化学企业生产前体化学品，然后运往墨西哥生产非法芬太尼，芬太尼通常与其他非法药物混合，以粉末和鼻喷雾剂的形式出售，并越来越多地制成看起来像合法处方阿片类药物的药丸。官员们说，这些东西随后被走私到美国。</p>   <p>Last month, the United States imposed sanctions on 28 people and entities involved with the international proliferation of illicit drugs, including a large China-based network.翻译:上个月，美国对 28 名参与国际非法毒品扩散的个人和实体实施制裁，其中包括一个大型中国网络。</p>   <p>"We know that this global fentanyl supply chain, which ends with the deaths of Americans, often starts with chemical companies in China," said U.S. Attorney General Merrick Garland.翻译:美国司法部长梅里克·加兰表示：“我们知道，这条以美国人死亡为终点的全球芬太尼供应链，往往始于中国的化学公司。”</p>   <p>Advocates have also accused pharmaceutical companies and related businesses of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/rite-aid-joins-companies-going-bankrupt-amid-opioid-litigation-2023-10-16/">fueling the crisis</a> through downplaying the risks of opioids and lack of regulation. Landmark settlements since 2021 have set compensation at a total of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/groups-fighting-us-opioid-crisis-settlement-money-can-be-hard-come-by-2023-06-17/">more than $50 billion nationwide</a>.翻译:支持者还指责制药公司和相关企业淡化阿片类药物的风险和缺乏监管，从而<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/rite-aid-joins-companies-going-bankrupt-amid-opioid-litigation-2023-10-16/">加剧了危机</a>。自 2021 年以来，具有里程碑意义的和解协议已将<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/groups-fighting-us-opioid-crisis-settlement-money-can-be-hard-come-by-2023-06-17/">全国范围内的赔偿总额定为超过 500 亿美元</a>。</p>   <p>Biden is also due to meet with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/mexicos-president-meet-chinese-counterpart-apec-summit-minister-2023-11-14/">Mexican President</a> Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador in San Francisco. Mexican Foreign Minister Alicia Barcena said talks would include how to better control the arrival from Asia of precursors used to make fentanyl.翻译:拜登还将于旧金山会见<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/mexicos-president-meet-chinese-counterpart-apec-summit-minister-2023-11-14/">墨西哥总统</a>安德烈斯·曼努埃尔·洛佩兹·奥夫拉多尔。墨西哥外交部长阿丽西娅·巴尔塞纳表示，会谈将包括如何更好地控制来自亚洲的用于制造芬太尼的前体。</p>   <p>In San Francisco, state and local officials have tried to clean up drugs from the city's streets, with limited success. The crisis has drawn sharp criticism from residents in the city, where drug-fuelled crime has forced some businesses to leave.翻译:在旧金山，州和地方官员试图清除该市街道上的毒品，但收效甚微。这场危机引起了该市居民的尖锐批评，毒品犯罪迫使一些企业离开。</p>   <p>San Francisco's new district attorney, Brooke Jenkins, has made prosecuting drug dealers a cornerstone of her agenda. The city recently formed a law enforcement task force to investigate opioid-linked deaths and poisonings.翻译:旧金山新任地方检察官布鲁克·詹金斯 (Brooke Jenkins) 将起诉毒贩作为她议程的基石。该市最近成立了一个执法工作组，调查与阿片类药物相关的死亡和中毒事件。</p>   <p>The city's Mayor London Breed has pushed to prioritize treatment for drug users, talked of police action as a way to solve the problem, and has called on the federal government to boost its drug trafficking enforcement.翻译:该市市长伦敦·布里德（London Breed）推动优先考虑吸毒者的治疗，谈到警方采取行动作为解决问题的一种方式，并呼吁联邦政府加强对贩毒的执法力度。</p>   <p>"We know San Francisco - and cities across the United States - will benefit from more targeting of the trafficking and production of fentanyl worldwide," a spokesperson for Breed said in a statement.翻译:布里德发言人在一份声明中表示：“我们知道，旧金山以及美国各地的城市将受益于全球范围内更多针对芬太尼贩运和生产的打击。”</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Michael Martina; Writing by Sayantani Ghosh and Michelle Nichols; Editing by Josie Kao翻译:迈克尔·玛蒂娜 (Michael Martina) 的补充报道；由 Sayantani Ghosh 和 Michelle Nichols 撰写；编辑：高乔茜</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 07:03:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">67JHX74B4BIPXL3MEJMYDJ3MRI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Peter Henderson, Anna Tong, Trevor Hunnicutt]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>FENTANYL (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国工厂产量和消费超出预期，但房地产仍拖累经济]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Industrial output, retail sales growth better than expected</li>  <li>Property sales extend declines, investment slumps</li>  <li>Oct indicators still show significant areas of economic weakness</li>  <li>Economists expect RRR, interest rate cuts</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>工业产出、零售额增速好于预期</li><li>房地产销售延续下滑，投资下滑</li><li>10 月指标仍显示经济显着疲软</li><li>经济学家预计存款准备金率、降息</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/LTq4T77li8f_4bULKrm5bT1ogEs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KIYGJWK6EFJNVKRZ5J5SSLFNOU.jpg" alt="FILE PHOTO: Leapmotor's EV production line in Jinhua翻译:资料图：零跑汽车位于金华的电动汽车生产线" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>FILE PHOTO: Robotic arms assemble cars in the production line for Leapmotor's electric vehicles at a factory in Jinhua, Zhejiang province, China, April 26, 2023. China Daily via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:资料照片：2023 年 4 月 26 日，中国浙江省金华市一家工厂，机械臂在零跑电动汽车生产线上组装汽车。《中国日报》来自路透社/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/L7KVqCa_-hprbq8GJSuMHMR2QR4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/77V6VO752FLN7CTZ4APEUIYDHU.jpg" alt="National Day holiday, in Shanghai翻译:国庆假期，上海" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk along Nanjing Pedestrian Road, a main shopping area, ahead of the National Day holiday, in Shanghai翻译:国庆假期，上海, China September 26, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2023年9月26日，中国上海，国庆假期前夕，人们沿着主要购物区南京步行路行走。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>China's industrial output and retail sales growth beat expectations in October, but the underlying economic picture highlighted significant pockets of weakness with the crisis-hit property sector continuing to forestall a full-blown revival.翻译:中国10月份的工业产出和零售销售增长超出预期，但基本经济形势凸显了显着的疲软，受危机打击的房地产行业继续阻碍全面复苏。</p>   <p>The world's second-biggest economy has struggled to mount a strong post-COVID recovery as distress in the housing market, local government debt risks, slow global growth and geopolitical tensions have dented momentum. A flurry of policy support measures have proven only modestly beneficial, raising pressure on authorities to roll out more stimulus.翻译:由于房地产市场低迷、地方政府债务风险、全球经济增长缓慢和地缘政治紧张局势削弱了经济增长势头，全球第二大经济体在新冠疫情后一直难以实现强劲复苏。事实证明，一系列政策支持措施的效果有限，这加大了当局推出更多刺激措施的压力。</p>   <p>China's industrial output grew 4.6% in October year-on-year, accelerating from the 4.5% pace seen in September, data from the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) showed on Wednesday, beating expectations for a 4.4% increase in a Reuters poll. It also marked the strongest growth since April.翻译:中国国家统计局(NBS)周三公布的数据显示，中国10月份工业产出同比增长4.6%，较9月份的4.5%有所加快，超过路透调查中4.4%的增长预期。这也标志着自四月份以来最强劲的增长。</p>   <p>Retail sales rose 7.6% in October with improvement in both auto and restaurant sales growth, quickening from a 5.5% gain in September and hitting the fastest pace since May. Analysts had expected retail sales to grow 7.0% due to the low base effect in 2022 when COVID curbs disrupted consumers and businesses.翻译:10 月份零售额增长 7.6%，汽车和餐饮销售增长均有所改善，增速较 9 月份 5.5% 有所加快，达到 5 月份以来的最快增速。分析师此前预计，由于 2022 年新冠疫情遏制扰乱了消费者和企业，基数较低，零售额将增长 7.0%。</p>      <p>Analysts struck a cautious note on the upside data surprise, noting that the property sector remains a weak link for the economy and pointed to the lack of major <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-choose-fiscal-muscle-over-big-reforms-revive-economy-2023-10-24/">reforms</a> as another impediment to sustainable longer term revival in growth.翻译:分析师对意外的上行数据持谨慎态度，指出房地产行业仍然是经济的薄弱环节，并指出缺乏重大<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-choose-fiscal-muscle-over-big-reforms-revive-economy-2023-10-24/">改革</a>是可持续长期增长复苏的另一个障碍。</p>   <p>"Due to the impact of holidays and low base effect in 2022, year-on-year figures cannot reflect the actual momentum of the economy," said Xing Zhaopeng, senior China strategist at ANZ.翻译:澳新银行高级中国策略师邢兆鹏表示，“由于2022年假期影响和低基数效应，同比数据无法反映经济的实际动力。”</p>   <p>He said month-on-month figures suggest economic momentum has further weakened with "increasing deflationary risks".翻译:他表示，环比数据表明，随着“通缩风险增加”，经济势头进一步减弱。</p>   <p>Louise Loo, China economist at Oxford Economics, said prolonged weakness in external demand could hamper industrial production despite strengthening last month as destocking pressures eased further.翻译:牛津经济研究院(Oxford Economics)中国经济学家Louise Loo表示，尽管上个月随着去库存压力进一步缓解，外部需求有所增强，但长期疲软可能会阻碍工业生产。</p>   <p>Consumption didn't make much headway either during the eight-day Golden Week holiday earlier in October. Trips made in that period missed government estimate as economists say consumers are concerned about their jobs and income growth in an uncertain employment market.翻译:十月初的八天黄金周假期期间，消费也没有取得太大进展。经济学家表示，这一时期的旅行人数未达到政府的预期，因为消费者担心就业市场不确定性下的工作和收入增长。</p>   <p>The nationwide survey-based jobless rate stayed at 5.0% in October, unchanged from September, the NBS data showed. Youth unemployment, which hit a record high 21.3% in June, wasn't available after the statistics bureau stopped publishing it since July.翻译:国家统计局数据显示，10月份全国调查失业率保持在5.0%，与9月份持平。统计局自7月起停止发布青年失业率后，6月份青年失业率创下历史新高21.3%。</p>   <p>China has been ramping up efforts to revive its post-COVID economy with a slew of policy support measures in recent months, although the positive effects have been marginal so far.翻译:近几个月来，中国一直在加大力度通过一系列政策支持措施重振后疫情时代的经济，但迄今为止积极效果甚微。</p>   <p>Wednesday's upbeat data comes as a raft of other indicators for October released over recent weeks pointed to muted growth momentum. Imports grew unexpectedly, but exports shrank at a quicker pace, household borrowing remained weak, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">consumer prices</a> swung lower while factory deflation persisted.翻译:周三公布乐观数据之际，近几周发布的 10 月份其他一系列指标均显示增长势头疲弱。进口意外增长，但出口萎缩加快，家庭借贷依然疲弱， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">消费者价格</a>下跌，而工厂通货紧缩持续存在。</p>   <p>Authorities are faced with a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/part-chinas-economic-miracle-was-mirage-reality-check-is-next-2023-09-03/">challenging task</a> as any aggressive monetary support would further widen interest rate differentials between China and the West, especially the United States, and dent an already weakened yuan. That could intensify capital outflows, while Beijing is wary of a return to the big-bang fiscal stimulus of the past which created massive debt and hamstrung the economy.翻译:当局面临着一项<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/part-chinas-economic-miracle-was-mirage-reality-check-is-next-2023-09-03/">艰巨的任务</a>，因为任何激进的货币支持都将进一步扩大中国与西方（尤其是美国）之间的利差，并削弱本已疲软的人民币。这可能会加剧资本外流，而北京方面则对回到过去的大规模财政刺激措施持谨慎态度，这种财政刺激措施造成了巨额债务并阻碍了经济。</p>   <p>The economy grew faster-than-expected in the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">third quarter</a>, with analysts generally expecting it to reach the government's full-year growth target of around 5%, though a full-blown recovery is still some time away.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">第三季度</a>经济增长快于预期，分析师普遍预计将达到政府5%左右的全年增长目标，但全面复苏尚需时日。</p>   <p>The yuan held near a more than two-month high after surprisingly softer U.S. inflation reading overnight boosted bets that the Federal Reserve had reached the end of its tightening cycle.</p>    <h 1="">PROPERTY, INVESTMENT DISAPPOINT</h>  <p>The country's central bank, People's Bank of China (PBOC), <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cbank-boosts-liquidity-injection-through-policy-loan-rate-unchanged-2023-11-15/">boosted liquidity injections</a> but kept the interest rate unchanged when rolling over maturing medium-term policy loans on Wednesday.翻译:周三，中国央行中国人民银行在展期到期中期政策贷款时<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cbank-boosts-liquidity-injection-through-policy-loan-rate-unchanged-2023-11-15/">加大了流动性注入力度</a>，但维持利率不变。</p>   <p>In a rare revision last month, the government also lifted its 2023 budget deficit to around 3.8% of gross domestic product from 3% to account for the planned issuance of 1 trillion yuan ($137.10 billion) in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/chinas-new-bonds-help-economic-recovery-official-says-budget-deficit-rises-2023-10-25/">sovereign bonds</a>.翻译:上个月，政府罕见地进行了修订，将2023年预算赤字占国内生产总值的比例从3%提高到3.8%左右，以占计划发行1万亿元人民币（1,371亿美元） <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/chinas-new-bonds-help-economic-recovery-official-says-budget-deficit-rises-2023-10-25/">主权债券</a>的比例。</p>   <p>The PBOC has cut banks' reserve requirement ratio (RRR) twice this year to free up liquidity to aid the economic recovery. Analysts widely expect another RRR cut and an interest rate cut in the final months of this year.翻译:中国人民银行今年已两次下调银行存款准备金率（RRR），以释放流动性以帮助经济复苏。分析师普遍预计今年最后几个月将再次下调存款准备金率和利率。</p>   <p>China's crisis-hit <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/">property sector</a> has yet to see a meaningful rebound despite strengthened <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-its-indebted-property-sector-2023-11-08/">support</a> measures for homebuyers, including relaxing of home purchase restrictions, lowering in borrowing costs and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-is-eyeing-137-bln-new-funding-boost-housing-market-bloomberg-news-2023-11-14/">other programmes.</a>翻译:尽管中国加强了对购房者<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-its-indebted-property-sector-2023-11-08/">的支持</a>措施，包括放宽购房限制、降低借贷成本等，但受危机打击的中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/">房地产行业</a>尚未出现有意义的反弹<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-is-eyeing-137-bln-new-funding-boost-housing-market-bloomberg-news-2023-11-14/">。</a></p>   <p>Property investment fell 9.3% in January-October year-on-year, after a similarly sharp 9.1% drop in January-September.翻译:继1-9月大幅下降9.1%之后，1-10月房地产投资同比下降9.3%。</p>   <p>Fixed asset investment disappointed with a 2.9% expansion year-on-year in the first 10 months, missing expectations for a 3.1% rise. It grew 3.1% in the January-September period.翻译:前10个月固定资产投资同比增长2.9%，低于预期的3.1%。 1-9月增长3.1%。</p>   <p>Confidence among private businesses also remained depressed, with investment in the sector shrinking 0.5% during January-October, narrowing slightly from the 0.6% decline in the first nine months.翻译:私营企业信心依然低迷，1-10月该行业投资下降0.5%，较前9个月0.6%的降幅略有收窄。</p>   <p>"Overall, the data published today suggest that the recovery was struggling to gain a strong footing at the start of Q4, but it was not nearly as weak as some had feared," said Sheana Yue, China economist at Capital Economics.翻译:凯投宏观(Capital Economics)中国经济学家谢娜·岳(Sheana Yue)表示：“总体而言，今天公布的数据表明，第四季度初经济复苏正在努力站稳脚跟，但并不像一些人担心的那么疲软。”</p>   <p>"Policy looks set to remain supportive, and possibly even stepped up to prevent the economy from backsliding."翻译:“政策看起来将继续保持支持性，甚至可能加强以防止经济倒退。”</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2939 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2939 人民币）</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Albee Zhang and Liangping Gao;
Editing by Shri Navaratnam翻译:Albee 张和亮平高的补充报道；编辑：Shri Navaratnam</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:38:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TPUCTHUAIJI75IGHIQFYSOENNM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ellen Zhang, Kevin Yao]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/ACTIVITY (WRAPUP 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
