<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 23:27:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[拜登和中国习近平将在亚太经合组织峰会上讨论沟通和竞争]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/SFmRtqPmpDU0oQvqzVeyXmjCW8Y=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/RB5ZXO6VRJPJVKYIQJAO7VQMEY.jpg" alt="G20 summit in Bali翻译:G20巴厘岛峰会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of the G20 leaders' summit in Bali, Indonesia, November 14, 2022.  REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque/File Photo翻译:美国总统乔·拜登于 2022 年 11 月 14 日在印度尼西亚巴厘岛举行的 G20 领导人峰会期间会见中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The White House said on Monday President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping will discuss strengthening communication and managing competition when they meet on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit this week.翻译:白宫周一表示，美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平本周将在亚太经合组织（APEC）峰会期间会面，讨论加强沟通和管理竞争的问题。</p>   <p>The face-to-face meeting in the San Francisco Bay Area on Wednesday will be the first between Biden and Xi in a year, with the high-stakes diplomacy aimed at curbing tensions between the two superpowers.翻译:周三在旧金山湾区举行的面对面会晤将是拜登和习近平一年来的首次会面，此次高风险外交旨在遏制两个超级大国之间的紧张关系。</p>   <p>White House national security adviser Jake Sullivan told reporters Biden believes there is no substitute for face-to-face diplomacy to manage the complex relationship.翻译:白宫国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文告诉记者，拜登认为，在处理复杂的关系方面，面对面的外交是无可替代的。</p>   <p>"We anticipate that the leaders will discuss some of the most fundamental elements of the U.S.-PRC bilateral relationship, including the continued importance of strengthening open lines of communication and managing competition responsibly so that it does not veer into conflict," Sullivan said, referring to the People's Republic of China.翻译:沙利文表示：“我们预计领导人将讨论美中双边关系的一些最基本要素，包括加强开放的沟通渠道和负责任地管理竞争以使其不会演变成冲突的持续重要性。”至中华人民共和国。</p>   <p>"The way we achieve that is through intense diplomacy. That's how we clear up misperceptions and avoid surprises."翻译:“我们实现这一目标的方法是通过激烈的外交。这就是我们消除误解并避免意外的方法。”</p>   <p>Sullivan said Biden would go into the summit "on a solid footing," having positioned the United States to be able to compete effectively at home and abroad and with "the strongest recovery and lowest inflation of any leading economy."翻译:沙利文表示，拜登将以“坚实的基础”参加峰会，使美国能够在国内外进行有效竞争，并实现“所有主要经济体中最强劲的复苏和最低的通胀”。</p>   <p>He said Washington is looking for specific outcomes from the meeting and hoped to see progress in reestablishing military-to military ties with China and in combating the trade in fentanyl that has become a scourge in the United States.翻译:他表示，华盛顿正在寻求此次会议的具体成果，并希望看到在与中国重建军事关系以及打击已成为美国祸害的芬太尼贸易方面取得进展。</p>   <p>China cut off military-to-military communications with the United States last year after a visit to Taiwan, a democratically governed island China claims as its own, by then U.S. House speaker Nancy Pelosi. Tense relations soured further when the U.S. shot down U.S. spy balloon In February.翻译:去年，时任美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西访问台湾后，中国切断了与美国的军事联系。台湾是一个民主治理的岛屿，中国声称拥有自己的岛屿。当美国二月份击落美国间谍气球后，紧张关系进一步恶化。</p>   <p>Sullivan said communication between the militaries was the way to ensure competition did not veer into conflict and that China had been "constructive" on the issue in dialogue leading up to the summit.翻译:沙利文表示，军方之间的沟通是确保竞争不会演变成冲突的方式，并且中国在峰会前的对话中对此问题表现出“建设性”态度。</p>   <p>"We will see what happens in San Francisco and the President will be able to report after the meeting, whether in fact, we've made progress on restoring military-to-military links," he said.翻译:他说：“我们将看看旧金山会发生什么，总统将能够在会后报告，我们是否在恢复军事联系方面确实取得了进展。”</p>   <p>Biden and Xi have known each other for more than a decade and have shared hours of conversation over six interactions since Biden's 2021 inauguration.翻译:拜登和习近平已经相识十多年，自拜登 2021 年就职以来，双方已进行了六次互动，进行了数小时的交谈。</p>   <p>However, they have met only once in person since then and Xi has not visited the United States since 2017. Analysts and officials say they will come to the table in an atmosphere of mutual suspicion and garbled impressions of what the other is seeking.翻译:然而，自那以后，他们只见过一次面，而习近平自 2017 年以来就没有访问过美国。分析人士和官员表示，他们将在相互猜疑的气氛中进行会谈，并对对方的追求产生错误的印象。</p>   <p>The meeting is also <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/">expected to cover</a> global issues from the Israel-Hamas war to Russia's invasion of Ukraine, North Korea's ties with Russia, Taiwan, human rights, artificial intelligence, as well as "fair" trade and economic relations, senior Biden administration officials said.翻译:拜登政府高级官员<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/">预计，此次会议还将涵盖</a>以色列与哈马斯战争、俄罗斯入侵乌克兰、朝鲜与俄罗斯的关系、台湾、人权、人工智能以及“公平”贸易和经济关系等全球问题。说。</p>   <p>Sullivan said Biden would raise stability across the Middle East, adding that Beijing should share an interest in de-escalation there.翻译:沙利文表示，拜登将提高整个中东地区的稳定，并补充说，北京应该对缓和那里的局势感兴趣。</p>   <p>Biden would make the point that Iran acting in an "escalatory, destabilizing way" was not in the interests of China, he said. "And the PRC, of course, has a relationship with Iran, and it's capable, if it chooses, to of making those points directly to the Iranian government."翻译:他说，拜登将指出伊朗以“升级、破坏稳定的方式”行事不符合中国的利益。 “当然，中华人民共和国与伊朗有关系，如果它愿意的话，它有能力直接向伊朗政府提出这些观点。”</p>   <p>Leaders from the 21-member APEC forum <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">are due to gather</a> in San Francisco from Wednesday until Friday and the wars in the Middle East and Ukraine have divided opinion among them.翻译:由 21 个成员组成的亚太经合组织论坛的领导人<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">定于周三至周五齐聚</a>旧金山，中东和乌克兰的战争使他们意见分歧。</p>   <p>The senior U.S. official for APEC, Matt Murray, told reporters on Monday that the U.S. was working hard to try to get a strong <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-says-its-working-hard-have-strong-consensus-leaders-declaration-apec-2023-11-13/">consensus statement</a> from the leaders, but analysts say the divisions make drafting this difficult.翻译:美国亚太经合组织高级官员马特·默里周一对记者表示，美国正在努力争取领导人达成强有力的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-says-its-working-hard-have-strong-consensus-leaders-declaration-apec-2023-11-13/">共识声明</a>，但分析人士表示，分歧使得起草过程变得困难。</p>   <p>Sullivan said that at APEC Biden would put forward his economic vision for the region and speak about "how the United States is the preeminent driver of inclusive, sustainable economic growth in the Asia Pacific."翻译:沙利文表示，拜登将在亚太经合组织上提出他对该地区的经济愿景，并谈到“美国如何成为亚太地区包容性、可持续经济增长的卓越推动者”。</p>   <p>(This story has been refiled to remove extraneous words from paragraph 1)翻译:（这个故事已被重新归档，以删除第 1 段中无关的文字）</p>    <span>Reporting by Steve Holland, Nandita Bose in Washington; Additional reporting by David Brunnstrom; Editing by Alistair Bell翻译:史蒂夫·霍兰德 (Steve Holland)、南迪塔·博斯 (Nandita Bose) 驻华盛顿报道；大卫·布伦斯特罗姆 (David Brunnstrom) 的补充报道；阿利斯泰尔·贝尔 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 22:32:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">SS6BME357JKGRHOQDVIUIRZTGE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-chinas-xi-will-discuss-communication-competition-apec-summit-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Steve Holland, Nandita Bose]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/ (CORRECTED, UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[拜登在习近平峰会前会见印度尼西亚总统]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/emxFP8d5t2kpfeHNBuwFTnOJ-xc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/V6F7SYEXTFN6PMLIHRVYSVTWQE.jpg" alt="U.S. President Biden&nbsp;meets with Indonesian President Widodo in Washington, U.S.翻译:美国总统拜登在美国华盛顿会见印度尼西亚总统维多多" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Indonesian President Joko Widodo for talks on regional security and clean-energy transition, among other things, in the Oval Office at the White House in Washington, U.S., November 13, 2023. REUTERS/Leah Millis翻译:2023 年 11 月 13 日，美国总统乔·拜登在美国华盛顿白宫椭圆形办公室会见印度尼西亚总统佐科·维多多，就地区安全和清洁能源转型等问题进行会谈。 REUTERS/Leah Millis</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/DDms8tiAfK7rU4HZaVL-bFZT0HQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VMXSKTXGVBKNTNTTCBSLCTBZTA.jpg" alt="U.S. President Biden&nbsp;meets with Indonesian President Widodo in Washington, U.S.翻译:美国总统拜登在美国华盛顿会见印度尼西亚总统维多多" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Indonesian President Joko Widodo appeals to U.S. President Joe Biden for the U.S. to push for a cease-fire in the ongoing conflict between Israel and the Palestinian Islamist group Hamas during a meeting in the Oval Office at the White House in Washington, U.S., November 13, 2023. REUTERS/Leah Millis翻译:11月13日，印度尼西亚总统佐科·维多多在美国华盛顿白宫椭圆形办公室举行会议，呼吁美国总统乔·拜登推动以色列和巴勒斯坦伊斯兰组织哈马斯之间持续冲突的停火。 ，2023。路透社/Leah Millis</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/PSKeTsAiY_kHlpDJwf2bN9JCjeU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/W7EKD7SNCZN47NSAPLG7ELANJ4.jpg" alt="U.S. President Biden&nbsp;meets with Indonesian President Widodo in Washington, U.S.翻译:美国总统拜登在美国华盛顿会见印度尼西亚总统维多多" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Indonesian President Joko Widodo for talks on regional security and clean-energy transition, among other things, in the Oval Office at the White House in Washington, U.S., November 13, 2023. REUTERS/Leah Millis翻译:2023 年 11 月 13 日，美国总统乔·拜登在美国华盛顿白宫椭圆形办公室会见印度尼西亚总统佐科·维多多，就地区安全和清洁能源转型等问题进行会谈。 REUTERS/Leah Millis</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ic2g_qbhZLJnH6AHYfCNfuDFCvY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BN7OOYGFMJO35MLBA5W4ZMCABM.jpg" alt="U.S. President Biden&nbsp;meets with Indonesian President Widodo in Washington, U.S.翻译:美国总统拜登在美国华盛顿会见印度尼西亚总统维多多" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Indonesian President Joko Widodo for talks on regional security and clean-energy transition, among other things, in the Oval Office at the White House in Washington, U.S., November 13, 2023. REUTERS/Leah Millis翻译:2023 年 11 月 13 日，美国总统乔·拜登在美国华盛顿白宫椭圆形办公室会见印度尼西亚总统佐科·维多多，就地区安全和清洁能源转型等问题进行会谈。 REUTERS/Leah Millis</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Padu4jxUFmo1zVe-PIxblR9Jo9o=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GDUKCUODZRN6TBYH5IXMZJMRE4.jpg" alt="G20 summit in Bali翻译:G20巴厘岛峰会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Indonesian President Joko Widodo greets U.S. President Joe Biden upon his arrival for a mangrove planting event at Ngurah Rai Forest Park, on the sidelines of the G20 summit in Denpasar, Bali, Indonesia November 16, 2022. Dita Alangkara/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:2022 年 11 月 16 日，在印度尼西亚巴厘岛登巴萨举行的 G20 峰会期间，印度尼西亚总统佐科·维多多在美国总统乔·拜登抵达伍拉·赖森林公园参加红树林种植活动时向他致意。Dita Alangkara/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>                     <p>Leaders from the United States and Indonesia were in discussions on Monday that will set the stage for U.S. President Joe Biden's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/">first in person meeting</a> in a year with Chinese leader Xi Jinping.翻译:美国和印度尼西亚领导人周一进行了讨论，这将为美国总统乔·拜登与中国领导人习近平一年内的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/">首次会面</a>奠定基础。</p>   <p>Biden greeted Indonesian President Joko Widodo at the White House as the two leaders prepare for a Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit in San Francisco, where Washington hopes to reduce friction with Beijing. Biden is due to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/">meet Xi</a> on Wednesday.翻译:拜登在白宫迎接印度尼西亚总统佐科·维多多，两国领导人正在筹备在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织（APEC）峰会，华盛顿希望减少与北京的摩擦。拜登定于周三与<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/">习近平会面</a>。</p>   <p>Biden and Widodo are expected to agree to new cooperation in defense areas including cybersecurity, space, combined exercises and nuclear threats, according to a senior Biden administration official who declined to be identified.翻译:一位不愿透露姓名的拜登政府高级官员表示，预计拜登和维多多将同意在网络安全、太空、联合演习和核威胁等国防领域开展新的合作。</p>   <p>On climate, the United States will announce steps with the Southeast Asian country on carbon capture and storage, supporting the electrical grid and improving air quality.翻译:在气候方面，美国将宣布与东南亚国家在碳捕获和储存、支持电网和改善空气质量方面采取措施。</p>   <p>Reuters reported on Sunday that the two countries <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/us-indonesia-discuss-potential-deal-ev-minerals-sources-2023-11-12/">are working to advance</a> a potential minerals partnership focused on the electric vehicle (EV) battery metal nickel, citing three people with direct knowledge of the conversations.翻译:路透社周日援引三名直接了解对话情况的人士的话报道称，两国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/us-indonesia-discuss-potential-deal-ev-minerals-sources-2023-11-12/">正在努力推进</a>潜在的矿物合作伙伴关系，重点关注电动汽车（EV）电池金属镍。</p>   <p>But the Biden administration is still concerned about environmental, social and governance (ESG) standards in Indonesia and is examining how such a deal might work. The two sides will unveil a plan that will prepare the countries for negotiations on the issue, said one of the U.S. officials.</p>    <h 1="">INDONESIA MAKES APPEAL TO U.S. ON GAZA</h>  <p>Jokowi, as the president is known, is also expected to press Biden on steps to end <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/indonesia-president-will-convey-biden-that-hamas-israel-war-should-be-stopped-2023-11-09/">Israel's war with Hamas</a>.翻译:预计佐科威总统还将向拜登施压，要求其采取措施结束<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/indonesia-president-will-convey-biden-that-hamas-israel-war-should-be-stopped-2023-11-09/">以色列与哈马斯的战争</a>。</p>   <p>"Indonesia appeals to the U.S. to do more to stop the atrocities in Gaza. Ceasefire is a must for the sake of humanity," Widodo said in the Oval Office before talks with Biden.翻译:“印度尼西亚呼吁美国采取更多措施制止加沙的暴行。为了人类的利益，停火是必须的，”维多多在与拜登会谈前在椭圆形办公室表示。</p>   <p>Indonesia, an archipelago of 270 million people, is the largest Muslim-majority nation. Many Muslims have been outraged by Biden's support for Israel after Hamas militants killed about 1,200 people and took more than 200 hostages on Oct. 7, according to Israeli officials. Palestinian officials have said Israeli strikes have killed more than 11,000 Gaza residents.翻译:印度尼西亚是一个拥有 2.7 亿人口的群岛国家，是最大的穆斯林占多数的国家。据以色列官员称，哈马斯武装分子于 10 月 7 日杀害了约 1,200 人并劫持了 200 多人质，之后许多穆斯林对拜登对以色列的支持感到愤怒。巴勒斯坦官员表示，以色列的空袭已造成超过 11,000 名加沙居民死亡。</p>   <p>"The president will look to ask Indonesia to a play a larger role and to assist us," in the Middle East, the U.S. official said, without elaborating on what such an expanded role might entail.翻译:这位美国官员表示，“总统将要求印度尼西亚在中东发挥更大的作用并协助我们”，但没有详细说明这种扩大的作用可能意味着什么。</p>   <p>Like several of its neighbors in Southeast Asia, Indonesia is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-xi-wants-expand-cooperation-with-indonesia-several-key-markets-2023-10-17/">economically intertwined with China</a> as it navigates territorial disputes with its larger neighbor and wants to avoid getting caught in the middle by hostile Washington-Beijing relations.翻译:与东南亚的几个邻国一样，印度尼西亚在处理与其较大邻国的领土争端时<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-xi-wants-expand-cooperation-with-indonesia-several-key-markets-2023-10-17/">与中国在经济上紧密相连</a>，并希望避免因华盛顿与北京的敌对关系而陷入困境。</p>   <p>Jakarta is expected to formally upgrade relations with Washington to the highest diplomatic tier at the meeting. Biden will also announce new funding for Indonesia's semiconductor industry, the people said.翻译:预计雅加达将在此次会议上正式将与华盛顿的关系提升至最高外交级别。知情人士称，拜登还将宣布为印度尼西亚半导体行业提供新的资金。</p>   <p>The two leaders will also discuss Indonesia's diplomatic efforts to resolve the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/myanmar-president-country-risk-breaking-apart-due-border-violence-2023-11-09/">conflict in Myanmar</a>, where the military took control in a 2021 coup and has been engaged in clashes with rebel alliances, one of the officials said.翻译:一位官员表示，两位领导人还将讨论印度尼西亚为解决<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/myanmar-president-country-risk-breaking-apart-due-border-violence-2023-11-09/">缅甸冲突</a>而做出的外交努力。缅甸军方在 2021 年的政变中控制了缅甸，并一直与叛军联盟发生冲突。</p>   <p>"It's going to be time soon for us to think about what our next steps are together to deal with a situation that is untenable," the person said.翻译:这位人士表示：“我们很快就会考虑下一步应该采取什么措施来应对这种难以维持的局面。”</p>   <p>Jokowi, first elected in 2014, is constitutionally required to leave office next year after serving the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/even-indonesian-presidents-loyalists-outraged-over-election-moves-sources-2023-11-10/">maximum two terms</a>.翻译:佐科维于 2014 年首次当选，根据宪法规定，他必须在任期<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/even-indonesian-presidents-loyalists-outraged-over-election-moves-sources-2023-11-10/">最多两届</a>后于明年离任。</p>    <span>Reporting by Trevor Hunnicutt and Steve Holland; Editing by Michael Perry and Grant McCool翻译:特雷弗·亨尼卡特和史蒂夫·霍兰德报道；迈克尔·佩里和格兰特·麦库尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 22:26:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CWVRAA2KLRLTXAIACKKB32TCJU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-with-indonesia-president-ahead-xi-summit-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Trevor Hunnicutt, Steve Holland]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>INDONESIA/ (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[参议员要求财政部禁止中国电池公司和矿产参与美国电动汽车税收抵免]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/DfvIyGQt_l9BR69BZ1Eva-9KYDE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/RTLZVQKO5FME5F2XSLHTSL7TJ4.jpg" alt="Illustration shows Car miniature, &quot;Electric vechicles (EVs)&quot; words, U.S. and Chinese flags翻译:插图显示汽车微型模型、“电动车 (EV)”字样、美国和中国国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Car miniature, "Electric vechicles (EVs)" words, U.S. and Chinese flags are seen in this illustration taken, September 26, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration翻译:这张摄于 2023 年 9 月 26 日的插图中可以看到微型汽车、“电动汽车 (EV)”字样、美国和中国国旗。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/插图</figcaption></figure>       <p>Democratic Senator Joe Manchin urged the U.S. Treasury on Monday to adopt the "strictest possible standards" to prevent Chinese-produced minerals or Chinese battery companies from winning electric vehicle tax credits.翻译:民主党参议员乔·曼钦周一敦促美国财政部采取“尽可能严格的标准”，以阻止中国生产的矿物或中国电池公司获得电动汽车税收抵免。</p>   <p>Manchin, who chairs the Senate Energy Committee, raised concerns in a letter to Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen about reports Chinese battery companies are actively pursuing business opportunities to take advantage of the credits, adding U.S. tax credits "cannot be allowed to be hijacked by adversaries engaging in mineral laundering."翻译:参议院能源委员会主席曼钦在致财政部长珍妮特·耶伦的一封信中对中国电池公司正在积极寻求商机以利用税收抵免的报道表示担忧，并补充说美国税收抵免“不能被对手劫持”在洗矿过程中。”</p>   <p>In 2022, Congress passed the Inflation Reduction Act barring $7,500 in future consumer EV tax credits if any battery components are manufactured or assembled by a "foreign entity of concern."翻译:2022 年，国会通过了《通货膨胀削减法案》，如果任何电池组件是由“相关外国实体”制造或组装的，则未来的消费者电动汽车税收抵免将被禁止 7,500 美元。</p>   <p>The rules were aimed at weaning U.S. battery supply chains away from China, which Manchin noted is currently responsible for 74% of the world’s cathode production, 92% of anode production, and 76% of lithium-ion battery cell production.翻译:这些规则旨在使美国电池供应链脱离中国，曼钦指出，中国目前占全球正极产量的 74%、负极产量的 92% 和锂离子电池产量的 76%。</p>   <p>The auto industry awaiting detailed guidance from the Treasury on what is considered a "foreign entity of concern" as they make investment decisions on producing batteries for their transition to electric vehicles.翻译:汽车行业在做出向电动汽车过渡的电池生产投资决策时，正在等待财政部关于“受关注外国实体”的详细指导。</p>   <p>The foreign entity of concern rules come into effect in 2024 for completed batteries and 2025 for critical minerals used to produce them. The Treasury did not immediately comment.翻译:外国实体关注规则对于成品电池将于 2024 年生效，对于用于生产电池的关键矿物则于 2025 年生效。财政部没有立即发表评论。</p>   <p>Manchin said the law does not allow for a "value added test" exception and it "would be unconscionable to reward bad actors through a loose or deliberately weak interpretation."翻译:曼钦表示，法律不允许“增值测试”例外，“通过宽松或故意薄弱的解释来奖励不良行为者是不合理的”。</p>   <p>A key decision in the guidance is whether Ford Motor Co's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/F.N" target="_blank">(F.N)</a> deal to license the technology of Chinese battery manufacturer CATL <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300750.SZ" target="_blank">(300750.SZ)</a> for use in Ford-owned U.S. battery plants will meet the Treasury's standards to access the tax credits. The arrangement has raised concerns among U.S. lawmakers.翻译:该指南的一个关键决定是，福特汽车公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/F.N" target="_blank">（FN）</a>授权中国电池制造商CATL <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300750.SZ" target="_blank">（300750.SZ）</a>技术用于福特旗下美国电池工厂的交易是否符合财政部获得税收抵免的标准。这一安排引起了美国立法者的担忧。</p>   <p>Ford put its planned $3.5 billion Michigan battery plant on hold in September and said it was awaiting "final language" from the Treasury on whether batteries made using Chinese technology will qualify for tax credits.翻译:福特9月份搁置了其计划投资35亿美元的密歇根电池工厂，并表示正在等待财政部关于使用中国技术制造的电池是否有资格获得税收抵免的“最终语言”。</p>   <p>Manchin said Yellen should "use the strictest metrics possible to ensure there are no loopholes that will lead to the laundering of minerals and materials from China or other nations of concern."翻译:曼钦表示，耶伦应该“使用尽可能严格的衡量标准，以确保不存在导致中国或其他相关国家的矿物和材料被洗钱的漏洞。”</p>    <span>Reporting by David Shepardson; Editing by Chris Reese and Jonathan Oatis翻译:大卫·谢泼德森报道；克里斯·里斯和乔纳森·奥蒂斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 22:23:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">HZDMT4LP2VMTFKHXFS2DHWKI7I</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/senator-asks-treasury-bar-chinese-battery-firms-minerals-us-ev-tax-credits-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Shepardson]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>AUTOS/CHINA (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[甘表示，中国工商银行因黑客扰乱美国国债市场而支付了赎金]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/gO-7sXRlWoFNmq514tavMntaIoo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZRARQYIHXVJBJJNFINWZ6AATCI.jpg" alt="The logo of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China (ICBC) is pictured at the entrance to its branch in Beijing翻译:中国工商银行（ICBC）北京分行入口处的标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China (ICBC) is pictured at the entrance to its branch in Beijing翻译:中国工商银行（ICBC）北京分行入口处的标志, China April 1, 2019. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo翻译:2019年4月1日，中国工商银行（ICBC）的标志出现在中国北京分行的入口处。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's biggest lender, the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, paid a ransom after it was hacked last week, a Lockbit ransomware gang representative said on Monday in a statement which Reuters was unable to independently verify.翻译:Lockbit 勒索软件团伙代表周一在一份声明中表示，中国最大的银行中国工商银行在上周遭到黑客攻击后支付了赎金，但路透社无法独立核实该声明。</p>   <p>ICBC, whose U.S. arm was hit by a ransomware attack that disrupted trades in the U.S. Treasury market on Nov. 9, did not immediately respond to a request for comment.翻译:11月9日，中国工商银行美国分行遭受勒索软件攻击，美国国债市场交易中断，该行没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>"They paid a ransom, deal closed," the Lockbit representative told Reuters via Tox, an online messaging app.翻译:Lockbit 代表通过在线消息应用程序 Tox 告诉路透社：“他们支付了赎金，交易完成。”</p>   <p>The blackout at ICBC's U.S. broker-dealer left it <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/icbc-ransomware-attack-triggers-global-regulator-trader-scrutiny-2023-11-10/">temporarily owing BNY Mellon BK.N $9 billion</a>, an amount many times larger than its net capital.翻译:工商银行美国经纪自营商停电使其<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/icbc-ransomware-attack-triggers-global-regulator-trader-scrutiny-2023-11-10/">暂时欠纽约梅隆银行 (BK.N) 90 亿美元</a>，这一数额是其净资本的数倍。</p>   <p>The hack was so extensive that <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/market-inside-wall-streets-scramble-after-icbc-hack-2023-11-13/">even corporate email at the firm ceased to function, forcing employees to switch to Google mail, Reuters reported</a>.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/market-inside-wall-streets-scramble-after-icbc-hack-2023-11-13/">据路透社报道，这次黑客攻击的范围如此之大，以至于该公司的企业电子邮件都停止运行，迫使员工改用谷歌邮件。</a></p>   <p>"The market is mostly back to normal now," said Zhiwei Ren, a portfolio manager at Penn Mutual Asset Management.翻译:佩恩互惠资产管理公司投资组合经理任志伟表示：“市场现在基本恢复正常。”</p>   <p>The ransomware attack came at a time of heightened worries about the resiliency of the $26 trillion Treasury market, essential to the plumbing of global finance, and is likely to draw scrutiny from regulators.翻译:此次勒索软件攻击发生之际，人们对 26 万亿美元的国债市场的弹性更加担忧，该市场对于全球金融管道至关重要，并且可能会引起监管机构的审查。</p>   <p>A spokesperson for the U.S. Treasury Department did not immediately provide comment on Monday.翻译:美国财政部发言人周一没有立即发表评论。</p>   <p>The Financial Services Information Sharing and Analysis Center, a financial industry cybersecurity group, said financial firms have well-established protocols for sharing information on such incidents.翻译:金融业网络安全组织金融服务信息共享和分析中心表示，金融公司拥有完善的协议来共享此类事件的信息。</p>   <p>"We are reminding members to stay current on all protective measures and patch critical vulnerabilities immediately," a spokesperson said in a statement, adding: "Ransomware remains one of the top threat vectors facing the financial sector."</p>    <h 1="">WHY PAY?</h>  <p>Lockbit has hacked some of the world's largest organisations in recent months, stealing and leaking sensitive data in cases where victims refused to pay ransom.翻译:近几个月来，Lockbit 对世界上一些最大的组织进行了黑客攻击，在受害者拒绝支付赎金的情况下窃取和泄露敏感数据。</p>   <p>In just three years, it has become <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/what-is-lockbit-digital-extortion-gang-cybercrime-spree-2023-11-10/">the world's top ransomware threat</a>, according to U.S. officials.翻译:据美国官员称，在短短三年内，它已成为<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/what-is-lockbit-digital-extortion-gang-cybercrime-spree-2023-11-10/">全球最大的勒索软件威胁</a>。</p>   <p>Nowhere has it been more disruptive than in the United States, hitting more than 1,700 American organisations in nearly every sector from financial services and food to schools, transportation and government departments.翻译:没有哪个地方比美国更具破坏性，影响了从金融服务、食品到学校、交通和政府部门等几乎各个领域的 1,700 多个美国组织。</p>   <p>Authorities have long advised against paying ransomware gangs in a bid to break the criminals' business model. Ransom is usually demanded in the form of cryptocurrency, which is harder to trace and gives the receiver anonymity.翻译:当局长期以来一直建议不要向勒索软件团伙支付费用，以打破犯罪分子的商业模式。赎金通常以加密货币的形式提出，这种形式更难以追踪，并且可以让接收者匿名。</p>   <p>Some companies have quietly paid up in a bid to get back online quickly and avoid the reputational damage of having their sensitive data publicly leaked. Victims who do not have digital backups that allow them to restore their systems without the need of a decryption key sometimes have no choice but to pay.翻译:一些公司已经悄悄付款，以求尽快恢复正常运营，并避免因敏感数据公开泄露而造成声誉受损。没有数字备份而无需解密密钥即可恢复系统的受害者有时别无选择，只能付费。</p>   <p>Last week, Lockbit hackers <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/boeing-data-published-by-lockbit-hacking-gang-2023-11-10/">published internal data from aerospace giant Boeing BA.N</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/law-firm-allen-overy-hit-by-data-incident-2023-11-09/">said on their website</a> they had infected computer systems at law firm Allen &amp; Overy.翻译:上周，Lockbit 黑客<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/boeing-data-published-by-lockbit-hacking-gang-2023-11-10/">公布了航空航天巨头波音 BA.N 的内部数据</a>，并 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/law-firm-allen-overy-hit-by-data-incident-2023-11-09/">在其网站上表示，</a>他们已经感染了 Allen &amp; Overy 律师事务所的计算机系统。</p>    <span>Reporting by James Pearson in London; Additional reporting by Davide Barbuscia, Carolina Mandl and Tatiana Bautzer in New York, and Pete Schroeder in Washington DC; Editing by Michelle Price, David Goodman, Jonathan Oatis and Alexander Smith翻译:詹姆斯·皮尔森在伦敦的报道； Davide Barbuscia、Carolina Mandl 和 Tatiana Bautzer 在纽约以及 Pete Schroeder 在华盛顿特区的补充报道；编辑：米歇尔·普莱斯、大卫·古德曼、乔纳森·奥蒂斯和亚历山大·史密斯</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 21:30:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">AASG7K33HZNHBMQKFV7K6X6LSE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/icbc-paid-ransom-after-hack-that-disrupted-markets-cybercriminals-say-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[James Pearson]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ICBC</category>
                
                <category>CYBER/RANSOM (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[波音股价因中国可能解除 737 订单冻结、迪拜订单激增而上涨]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/EdI1wQPoG-DV-GvusBM7D-3jYZ4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/APXLMEGMCFLCFNS45XMP4GGMVQ.jpg" alt="54th Paris Air Show at Le Bourget Airport near Paris翻译:第 54 届巴黎航空展在巴黎附近的布尔歇机场举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Boeing logo is seen on a 777-9 aircraft on display during the 54th International Paris Airshow at Le Bourget Airport near Paris, France, June 18, 2023. REUTERS/Benoit Tessier翻译:2023 年 6 月 18 日，在法国巴黎附近的布尔歇机场举行的第 54 届国际巴黎航展上，一架 777-9 飞机上展示了波音标志。 REUTERS/Benoit Tessier</figcaption></figure>       <p>Shares of Boeing <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BA.N" target="_blank">(BA.N)</a> rose on Monday after a report said China was considering ending its freeze on purchases of the planemaker's best-selling 737 MAX aircraft after more than four years.翻译:波音公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BA.N" target="_blank">(BA.N)</a>股价周一上涨，此前有报道称，中国正在考虑结束四年多以来对该飞机制造商最畅销 737 MAX 飞机的采购冻结。</p>   <p>This, coupled with bumper jet orders from Middle Eastern airlines at the Dubai Airshow, sent Boeing shares up 4%. Supplier Spirit Aerosystems <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SPR.N" target="_blank">(SPR.N)</a> also rose 2.7%.翻译:再加上中东航空公司在迪拜航展上获得大量飞机订单，波音股价上涨 4%。供应商 Spirit Aerosystems <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SPR.N" target="_blank">(SPR.N)</a>也上涨 2.7%。</p>   <p>China is considering resuming <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/china-weighs-ending-freeze-boeing-purchases-with-737-max-deal-us-bloomberg-news-2023-11-13/">purchases</a> of Boeing's 737 MAX aircraft when the U.S. and Chinese presidents meet this week at the APEC summit, Bloomberg News reported on Sunday, citing people familiar with the matter.翻译:彭博新闻周日援引知情人士的话报道称，中国正在考虑在美国和中国国家元首本周在亚太经合组织峰会上会晤时恢复<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/china-weighs-ending-freeze-boeing-purchases-with-737-max-deal-us-bloomberg-news-2023-11-13/">购买</a>波音 737 MAX 飞机。</p>   <p>The resumption of 737 orders from China would be meaningful to Boeing's bottom line over the next six to 18 months, said Thomas Hayes, chairman of hedge fund Great Hill Capital.翻译:对冲基金 Great Hill Capital 董事长托马斯·海耶斯 (Thomas Hayes) 表示，中国恢复 737 订单将对波音未来 6 至 18 个月的盈利产生重大影响。</p>   <p>Deliveries of Boeing's bestselling 737 MAX to Chinese airlines were halted following two deadly crashes.翻译:在发生两起致命空难后，波音最畅销的 737 MAX 飞机已停止向中国航空公司交付。</p>   <p>Boeing also secured <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/looming-emirates-777x-deal-kickstart-dubai-airshow-sources-2023-11-12/">orders</a> for 125 widebody jets worth more than $50 billion from Emirates and its sister airline flydubai at the opening of the Dubai Airshow on Monday.翻译:波音公司还在周一迪拜航展开幕式上从阿联酋航空及其姊妹航空公司迪拜航空获得了价值超过 500 亿美元的 125 架宽体飞机<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/looming-emirates-777x-deal-kickstart-dubai-airshow-sources-2023-11-12/">订单</a>。</p>   <p>Demand for the industry's biggest jets that dominated the region's airports is humming after a prolonged cyclical downturn followed by the damaging effect of COVID-19 on long-haul travel.翻译:在经历了长期的周期性低迷以及新冠肺炎 (COVID-19) 对长途旅行的破坏性影响之后，对该地区机场主导的业界最大喷气式飞机的需求正在蓬勃发展。</p>   <p>Carriers have been placing orders with urgency as planemakers' backlogs have grown and as jet deliveries have been pushed out toward the end of the decade.翻译:由于飞机制造商的积压订单不断增加，而且喷气式飞机的交付时间被推迟到本世纪末，航空公司一直在紧急下订单。</p>   <p>"Potential reopening of the 737 in China for Boeing and the contracts at the Dubai Airshow is all kind of the perfect combination of optimism and positive outlook that the stock has been needing for many months where it has underperformed," Hayes added.翻译:海耶斯补充道：“波音公司在中国重新开放 737 飞机的可能性以及迪拜航展上的合同都是乐观情绪和积极前景的完美结合，而这正是该股几个月来表现不佳所需要的。”</p>      <p>Boeing shares were trading at $205.15, compared with analysts' current median price target of $250, according to LSEG data.翻译:根据 LSEG 的数据，波音股价目前交易价格为 205.15 美元，而分析师目前的目标中值目标价为 250 美元。</p>    <span>Reporting by Shivansh Tiwary and Ananya Mariam Rajesh in Bengaluru; Editing by Shilpi Majumdar翻译:Shivansh Tiwary 和 Ananya Mariam Rajesh 在班加罗尔的报道；希尔皮·马宗达尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 21:29:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7WK3HIXBLRLOZGZRH6O2URMKX4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/boeing-shares-take-off-report-that-china-may-lift-737-freeze-bumper-dubai-orders-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>STOCKS/BOEING</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[全球股市因通胀和利率担忧而受挫]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Sx1H-f0CzypEzBufRSC-4CPaJ5c=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CIETXDQIAJM2RNQLNBHQOFIF4E.jpg" alt="Traders work on the floor of the NYSE in New York翻译:交易员在纽约证券交易所工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Traders work on the floor at the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) in New York City, U.S., October 27, 2023.  REUTERS/Brendan McDermid翻译:2023 年 10 月 27 日，交易员在美国纽约市纽约证券交易所 (NYSE) 的交易大厅工作。REUTERS/Brendan McDermid</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/FAs5FCgg2yQsUgUnTIPhaZ6rQRQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FQCY5PVVXNKGLKXZYLJNDYCEUU.jpg" alt="German share price index DAX graph is pictured at the stock exchange in Frankfurt翻译:德国股价指数 DAX 图为法兰克福证券交易所" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The German share price index DAX graph is pictured at the stock exchange in Frankfurt翻译:德国股价指数 DAX 图为法兰克福证券交易所, Germany, November 8, 2023.    REUTERS/Staff/File Photo翻译:德国股价指数DAX图拍摄于2023年11月8日德国法兰克福证券交易所。REUTERS/Staff/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/PmoMGVBFmF6801QYlY199bWN2vo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NCHVEVWNNVPLVHULYVRKT3SYNA.jpg" alt="Passersby are reflected on an electric stock quotation board outside a brokerage in Tokyo翻译:东京一家经纪公司外的电子股票报价板上反映了路人的情况" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Passersby are reflected on an electric stock quotation board outside a brokerage in Tokyo翻译:东京一家经纪公司外的电子股票报价板上反映了路人的情况, Japan April 18, 2023.  REUTERS/Issei Kato/File Photo</figcaption></figure>                 <p>Global stocks traded in a narrow range on Monday as the market focused on U.S. inflation data for more clues on whether global interest rates really have peaked.翻译:周一全球股市窄幅波动，市场关注美国通胀数据，以寻找更多关于全球利率是否真正见顶的线索。</p>   <p>After two weeks of gains, MSCI's gauge of global equities <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIWD00000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIWD00000PUS)</a> whipsawed between modest gains and losses, and finished up 0.19%. Wall Street's benchmark S&amp;P 500 share index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a> was flat, the Dow Jones Industrial Index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DJI" target="_blank">(.DJI)</a> was up 0.16%, while the Nasdaq Composite lost 0.22%.翻译:经过两周的上涨后，MSCI 全球股市指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIWD00000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIWD00000PUS)</a>在小幅上涨和下跌之间摇摆，最终上涨 0.19%。华尔街基准标准普尔 500 指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a>持平，道琼斯工业指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DJI" target="_blank">(.DJI)</a>上涨 0.16%，而纳斯达克综合指数下跌 0.22%。</p>   <p>The index for world equities has gained almost 5% so far this month, after risk aversion in October caused by the Israel-Hamas war was soothed by bets that major central banks have ended their lengthy run of interest rate hikes.翻译:10月份以色列-哈马斯战争引发的避险情绪因主要央行已结束长期加息的押注而得到缓解，本月迄今为止，世界股市指数已上涨近5%。</p>   <p>Still, the week ahead is packed with market risk events, with consumer inflation and retail sales figures from the United States on Tuesday and Wednesday, respectively, the most likely to shift the economic narrative.翻译:尽管如此，未来一周仍将充满市场风险事件，美国周二和周三分别公布的消费者通胀和零售销售数据最有可能改变经济形势。</p>   <p>"Top of mind this week will be Tuesday's October Consumer Price Index report where we are looking for core inflation to have gained additional speed for a third straight month," analysts at TD Securities said in a note. They forecast core inflation to have accelerated to 0.4% from 0.3% in September.翻译:道明证券分析师在一份报告中表示：“本周最重要的是周二公布的十月消费者价格指数报告，我们预计核心通胀将连续第三个月加速增长。”他们预测核心通胀率将从 9 月份的 0.3% 加速至 0.4%。</p>   <p>Economists polled by Reuters expect headline U.S. consumer price inflation slowed to 3.3% in October from 3.7% the month before, with the so-called core inflation rate that strips out volatile components unchanged.翻译:路透社调查的经济学家预计，10 月份美国总体消费者价格通胀率将从上月的 3.7% 放缓至 3.3%，剔除波动性成分的所谓核心通胀率保持不变。</p>   <p>"While a continuation of the (stocks) rally into year-end is definitely possible, it may be muted by bearish equity sentiment driven by both heightened geopolitical and financial market risk," research house BCA also cautioned in a note to clients on Monday.翻译:研究机构 BCA 在周一给客户的一份报告中也警告说：“虽然（股市）涨势肯定有可能持续到年底，但地缘政治和金融市场风险加剧所驱动的看跌股市情绪可能会削弱这种涨势。”</p>   <p>That combination of rate hike worries and risk aversion helped send the dollar to a fresh one-year high against the yen on Monday.翻译:加息担忧和避险情绪结合在一起，推动美元兑日元周一创下一年新高。</p>   <p>Benchmark 10-year Treasury yields , which rise when prices fall, also touched a one-week high of 4.6960% early Monday, as concerns about inflation reduced the appeal of fixed interest-paying debt instruments.翻译:随着价格下跌而上涨的基准10年期国债收益率周一早些时候也触及一周高点4.6960%，原因是对通胀的担忧降低了固定付息债务工具的吸引力。</p>   <p>Moody's cut its U.S. AAA credit rating outlook to "negative" from "stable" on Friday, citing large fiscal deficits and a decline in debt affordability. Fitch downgraded the United States to AA+ from AAA in August after months of political brinkmanship around the U.S. debt ceiling.翻译:周五，穆迪将美国 AAA 信用评级前景从“稳定”下调至“负面”，理由是财政赤字巨大且债务承受能力下降。经过数月围绕美国债务上限的政治边缘政策后，惠誉于 8 月将美国评级从 AAA 下调至 AA+。</p>   <p>The U.S. faces another partial government shutdown beginning Saturday if Congress does not pass a stopgap spending bill.翻译:如果国会不通过权宜之计的支出法案，美国将从周六开始面临另一次部分政府关门。</p>   <p>The dollar hit 151.90 yen on Monday for the first time since mid-October last year, and was still hovering at 151.59 near those highs at 2110 GMT. The dollar index, which tracks the U.S. currency against six others, was flat at 105.61, within distance of its year-to-date high reached Oct. 3.翻译:周一，美元兑日元汇率自去年10月中旬以来首次触及151.90日元，并且在格林尼治标准时间2110时仍徘徊在151.59附近的高位。追踪美元兑其他六种货币的美元指数持平于 105.61，距离 10 月 3 日触及的今年迄今高点不远。</p>   <p>Nomura Securities strategist Naka Matsuzawa said global equities were now likely close to a peak.翻译:野村证券(Nomura Securities)策略师Naka Matsuzawa表示，全球股市目前可能已接近峰值。</p>   <p>"Up until now, the market has been taking bad economic news as good news, because that would mean a pause in Fed rate hikes," he said.翻译:“到目前为止，市场一直将坏经济消息视为好消息，因为这将意味着美联储加息的暂停，”他表示。</p>   <p>"But now, the Treasury market has already priced in a pause, so there's not much room for Treasury yields to fall further," removing a support for the stock market. "In short, I don't think the stock market rally is going to continue."翻译:“但现在，国债市场已经消化了暂停的定价，因此国债收益率进一步下跌的空间不大，”这消除了对股市的支撑。 “简而言之，我认为股市上涨不会持续。”</p>   <p>Adding to short-term market tensions, U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese leader Xi Jinping will meet this week on the sidelines of an Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit in San Francisco.翻译:美国总统乔·拜登和中国领导人习近平将于本周在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织（APEC）峰会期间会面，这加剧了短期市场的紧张局势。</p>   <p>Crude oil prices also eased as demand worries trumped supply concerns ahead of Chinese retail sales data later in the week that may darken an outlook already dimmed by <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/global-economy-asias-factories-squeezed-chinas-nascent-recovery-teeters-2023-11-01/">declining industrial activity</a> in the world's second-largest economy.翻译:原油价格也有所回落，因为在本周晚些时候中国零售销售数据公布之前，需求担忧超过了供应担忧，这可能使已经因全球第二大经济体<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/global-economy-asias-factories-squeezed-chinas-nascent-recovery-teeters-2023-11-01/">工业活动下降</a>而黯淡的前景变得更加黯淡。</p>   <p>Brent crude futures for January and U.S. West Texas Intermediate (WTI) crude futures for December edged higher, both up around $1.30 at $82.75 and $78.53 a barrel.翻译:1 月布伦特原油期货和 12 月美国西德克萨斯中质原油 (WTI) 原油期货小幅走高，均上涨约 1.30 美元，至每桶 82.75 美元和 78.53 美元。</p>   <p>Both benchmarks gained nearly 2% on Friday as Iraq voiced support for oil cuts by OPEC+.翻译:由于伊拉克表示支持 OPEC+ 减产，两个基准周五均上涨近 2%。</p>    <span>Reporting by Naomi Rovnick and Nell Mackenzie in London; additional reporting by Kevin Buckland in Tokyo; editing by Jacqueline Wong, Mark Heinrich and Richard Chang翻译:Naomi Rovnick 和 Nell Mackenzie 在伦敦的报道；凯文·巴克兰 (Kevin Buckland) 在东京的补充报道；编辑：Jacqueline Wong、Mark Heinrich 和 Richard Chang</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 21:22:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5F476R5UYBJJZDYEJJXOXCRBBI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/global-markets-wrapup-1-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Koh Qing, Naomi Rovnick]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/ (WRAPUP 7, GRAPHICS)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国商务部长雷蒙多将在APEC期间会见中国商务部长王毅]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/x38bsq0scgpQvIQHzHuqQ4s44Y0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WYEWEGFWU5JKJF3CN2SSXWQGKY.jpg" alt="AI Safety Summit in Bletchley翻译:布莱切利人工智能安全峰会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo speaks on Day 1 of the AI Safety Summit at Bletchley Park in Bletchley, Britain on November 1, 2023.  Leon Neal/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:美国商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多 (Gina Raimondo) 于 2023 年 11 月 1 日在英国布莱切利布莱切利公园举行的人工智能安全峰会第一天发表讲话。 Leon Neal/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TUyCIsg1eQU63Tz2J0_Opaup0Q0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VZRZH3DP4ZMJJJ2ZDYK4X6A6SQ.jpg" alt="BRICS Summit in Johannesburg翻译:金砖国家领导人约翰内斯堡峰会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Commerce Minister Wang Wentao arrives at the BRICS Summit in Johannesburg翻译:金砖国家领导人约翰内斯堡峰会, South Africa August 23, 2023. REUTERS/Alet Pretorius/Pool/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>The commerce chiefs of the United States and China will meet at the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC)</a> forum this week, one of a series of cabinet-level engagements surrounding high-stakes talks between U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping.翻译:美国和中国商务主管将于本周在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">亚太经济合作组织（APEC）</a>论坛上会面，这是围绕美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平之间的高风险会谈举行的一系列内阁级活动之一。</p>   <p>A U.S. Commerce Department spokesperson confirmed that U.S. Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo and Chinese Commerce Minister Wang Wentao planned to meet but was not able to provide details and timing.翻译:美国商务部发言人证实，美国商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多和中国商务部部长王文涛计划会面，但未能提供细节和时间。</p>   <p>Raimondo is participating in ministerial meetings for APEC and the Biden administration's Indo-Pacific Economic Framework discussions.翻译:雷蒙多正在参加亚太经合组织部长级会议和拜登政府的印太经济框架讨论。</p>   <p>Biden and Xi are expected to meet in the San Francisco Bay area on Wednesday in an effort to calm a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/">tense relationship</a> between the world's two largest economies.翻译:拜登和习近平预计将于周三在旧金山湾区会面，以缓和世界最大两个经济体之间的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/">紧张关系</a>。</p>   <p>Raimondo first mentioned the meeting with Wang, their third in person in less than six months, in an interview with CNN that aired on Sunday.翻译:雷蒙多在周日播出的美国有线电视新闻网采访中首次提到了与王的会面，这是他们在不到六个月内的第三次会面。</p>   <p>She said it was time to "ratchet down the temperature" of the U.S.-China relationship. She added that she would not "sugarcoat anything, not to pretend that this isn't a great competition, but to be direct and be honest and also to ... responsibly manage this relationship."翻译:她表示，现在是美中关系“降温”的时候了。她补充说，她不会“粉饰一切，也不会假装这不是一场伟大的竞争，而是要直接、诚实，并且……负责任地管理这种关系。”</p>   <p>Her meeting with Wang follows U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen's meetings last week with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng, during which the two sides agreed to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/yellen-chinas-he-intensify-communication-after-pre-apec-meetings-2023-11-10/">"intensify communication"</a> - including with a return trip for Yellen to China next year.翻译:在她与王的会面之前，美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦上周与中国国务院副总理何立峰会面，双方同意<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/yellen-chinas-he-intensify-communication-after-pre-apec-meetings-2023-11-10/">“加强沟通”</a> ，包括耶伦明年重返中国。</p>   <p>Raimondo has a more difficult China portfolio than Yellen, as Commerce oversees contentious U.S. export controls on advanced semiconductors and chip manufacturing equipment, and other sensitive technologies that could have military applications. She said there can be "no negotiation" over these.翻译:雷蒙多在中国的投资组合比耶伦更为困难，因为商务部负责监督美国对先进半导体和芯片制造设备以及其他可能具有军事应用的敏感技术的有争议的出口管制。她表示，对于这些问题“没有任何谈判”。</p>   <p>During her visit to Beijing in late August, during which she met with Wang, Raimondo agreed to set up a dialogue with Chinese officials on export controls to avoid misunderstandings about the measures.翻译:8月下旬访问北京期间，雷蒙多会见了王毅，同意与中国官员就出口管制问题进行对话，以避免对这些措施产生误解。</p>   <p>She also said during the trip that U.S. businesses had told her that China was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/china-response-uss-raimondo-says-it-is-easing-market-access-foreign-firms-2023-08-30/">becoming "uninvestible" for U.S. firms</a>. She repeated the comment to CNN, citing China's new anti-espionage law, unpredictable regulations and government raids on U.S. firms.翻译:她还表示，在访问期间，美国企业告诉她，中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/china-response-uss-raimondo-says-it-is-easing-market-access-foreign-firms-2023-08-30/">对于美国企业来说正变得“无法投资”</a> 。她向美国有线电视新闻网（CNN）重复了这一评论，并列举了中国新的反间谍法、不可预测的法规以及政府对美国公司的突击搜查。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Lawder; editing by Grant McCool翻译:大卫·劳德报道；格兰特·麦库尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 21:20:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">QJX63QAXCJPNTCJE2RS4OMIKOE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us-commerce-chief-raimondo-meet-chinese-counterpart-wang-during-apec-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Lawder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>RAIMONDO (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美元兑日元触及一年高点后下滑]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/aHYazDkXx_d6S9K2TwEX6IR-u8g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6YQVC6EVY5N3ZPCDVI763CKEPY.jpg" alt="Illustration shows Japanese Yen and U.S. dollar banknotes翻译:插图显示日元和美元纸币" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Japanese Yen and U.S. dollar banknotes are seen in this illustration taken March 10, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo/File Photo翻译:这张摄于 2023 年 3 月 10 日的插图中可以看到日元和美元纸币。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/档案照片/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Wsvb4Wss1_AbBwG1i_Ytog7yVVk=/800x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TYUFM65KM5M2FKWLPPW3UQLOUQ.jpg" alt="U.S. one dollar banknotes are seen in front of displayed stock graph in this illustration taken翻译:在这张插图中，可以在显示的库存图前面看到一美元纸币" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. one dollar banknotes are seen in front of displayed stock graph in this illustration taken翻译:在这张插图中，可以在显示的库存图前面看到一美元纸币, February 8, 2021. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>The dollar climbed to its highest level in more than a year against the Japanese yen on Monday, near the key psychological level of 152, before falling sharply in a flurry of trading in $3.45 billion of options that come due this week.翻译:美元兑日元周一攀升至一年多来的最高水平，接近152的关键心理水平，随后在本周到期的34.5亿美元期权交易中大幅下跌。</p>   <p>The dollar later traded little changed on expectations a soft reading of the U.S. consumer price index (CPI) on Tuesday will keep Treasury yields trending lower as the market perceives the Federal Reserve is done hiking interest rates.翻译:由于市场认为美联储已经完成加息，周二美国消费者价格指数（CPI）的疲弱读数将使美国国债收益率继续走低，因此美元随后走势几乎没有变化。</p>   <p>The dollar early in the session shot to 151.92 yen , the highest since October 2022, about 20 minutes before some $1.25 billion in options contracts were set to expire with a 152 strike price, analysts said.翻译:分析师表示，美元兑日元早盘飙升至 151.92 日元，为 2022 年 10 月以来的最高水平，大约 20 分钟后，价值约 12.5 亿美元的期权合约将以 152 的执行价到期。</p>   <p>The dollar suddenly dropped to 151.20, minutes after a 10 a.m. ET (1500 GMT) strike price deadline. Another $2.2 billion are set to expire on Wednesday, the analysts said.翻译:美元突然跌至 151.20，距离美国东部时间上午 10 点（格林尼治标准时间 1500）执行价格截止时间仅几分钟。分析师称，另有 22 亿美元将于周三到期。</p>   <p>The yen's sharp rebound against the dollar was not due to Bank of Japan intervention, said Marc Chandler, chief market strategist at Bannockburn Global Forex in New York.翻译:纽约Bannockburn Global Forex首席市场策略师Marc Chandler表示，日元兑美元大幅反弹并非由于日本央行干预。</p>   <p>"The dollar/yen came off after almost reaching last year's high at 10 a.m." he said. "The same thing happened in early October."翻译:“美元/日元上午 10 点几乎触及去年高点后开始下跌，”他表示。 “十月初也发生了同样的事情。”</p>   <p>Markets have been alert to potential intervention from Tokyo to shore up the battered yen. Earlier in Japan, Finance Minister Shunichi Suzuki said the government would keep monitoring the currency market and respond appropriately.翻译:市场一直对东京可能采取的干预行动保持警惕，以支撑遭受重创的日元。早些时候，日本财务大臣铃木俊一表示，政府将继续监控货币市场并做出适当反应。</p>   <p>The dollar was last up 0.12% at 151.680 yen. The yen has fallen almost 14% against the dollar so far this year.翻译:美元兑日元最新上涨0.12%至151.680。今年迄今为止，日元兑美元汇率已下跌近14%。</p>   <p>Fed Chief Jerome Powell and policymakers want markets to be wary in the hope rates stay high and keep monetary policy tight without the need to raise the Fed's lending rate further, said Joseph Trevisani, senior analyst at FXStreet.com.翻译:FXStreet.com高级分析师约瑟夫·特雷维萨尼(Joseph Trevisani)表示，美联储主席杰罗姆·鲍威尔和政策制定者希望市场保持警惕，希望利率保持在高位并保持货币政策紧缩，而不需要进一步提高美联储的贷款利率。</p>   <p>"That's why their rhetoric is much stronger than their actions right now," Trevisani said. "Rates are going to go down, bond prices are going to go up" if credit markets really think that the Fed is done raising rates, he said.翻译:特雷维萨尼说：“这就是为什么他们现在的言论比他们的行动更强烈。”他表示，如果信贷市场真的认为美联储已经完成加息，“利率将会下降，债券价格将会上涨”。</p>   <p>"That'll take the dollar lower because I do think the Fed is pretty much done raising rates."翻译:“这将导致美元走低，因为我确实认为美联储已经基本完成了加息。”</p>   <p>The dollar index , a measure of the U.S. currency against six others, 
 fell 0.09%
 at 
 105.64
 .翻译:衡量美元兑其他六种货币的美元指数下跌 0.09%，至 105.64。</p>   <p>The reaction to a subdued CPI number is likely to be shallow because U.S. retail sales on Wednesday will be more important as they should better reveal the economy's strength, said Paresh Upadhyaya, director of fixed income and currency strategy at Amundi US in Boston.翻译:波士顿Amundi US固定收益和货币策略总监帕雷什·乌帕迪亚亚(Paresh Upadhyaya)表示，对CPI数据低迷的反应可能会很浅，因为周三的美国零售销售数据将更加重要，因为它们应该更好地揭示经济实力。</p>   <p>"All the signs have been pointing to continued momentum on consumption," Upadhyaya said. "If we see an upside surprise ... the markets are going to begin to price in a rate hike in December."翻译:“所有迹象都表明消费势头持续强劲，”乌帕迪亚亚说。 “如果我们看到意外的上行……市场将开始消化 12 月份加息的影响。”</p>   <p>The market barely reacted to news late on Friday that Moody's cut the outlook for U.S. credit to negative from stable.翻译:市场对周五晚间穆迪将美国信贷前景从稳定下调至负面的消息几乎没有做出反应。</p>   <p>The euro rose
 up 0.15% to
 $
 1.0697
 as sterling strengthened after a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/uk-pm-sunak-sacks-interior-minister-braverman-2023-11-13/">reshuffle of key posts</a> in the British government by Prime Minister Rishi Sunak.翻译:欧元上涨0.15%至1.0697美元，因英国首相里希·苏纳克(Rishi Sunak)对英国政府<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/uk-pm-sunak-sacks-interior-minister-braverman-2023-11-13/">关键职位进行改组</a>后英镑走强。</p>   <p>Britain's currency rose about 0.44% at $1.2279 and about 0.27% firmer against the euro at around 87.14 pence after news of changes to the make-up of the UK government.翻译:英国政府组成变动的消息传出后，英镑兑欧元汇率上涨约0.44%至1.2279美元，兑欧元汇率上涨约0.27%至87.14便士左右。</p>   <p>Sunak brought back former leader David Cameron as foreign minister in a reshuffle triggered by his firing of Interior Minister Suella Braverman after her criticism of the police threatened his authority.翻译:苏纳克重新任命前领导人戴维·卡梅伦为外交部长，这是由于内政部长苏埃拉·布拉弗曼因批评警察威胁到他的权威而被解雇而引发的一次改组。</p>    <span>Reporting by Herbert Lash, additional reporting by Dhara Ranasinghe in London, Brigid Riley in Tokyo; editing by Emelia Sithole-Matarise, Sharon Singleton, Jonathan Oatis and Richard Chang翻译:赫伯特·拉什 (Herbert Lash) 报道，伦敦达拉·拉纳辛格 (Dhara Ranasinghe) 和东京布里吉德·莱利 (Brigid Riley) 补充报道；编辑：Emelia Sithole-Matarise、Sharon Singleton、Jonathan Oatis 和 Richard Chang</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 21:16:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ASBIBXZHWZNCXMFGOGZOTPCPBI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/dollar-firm-ahead-us-inflation-data-yen-hovers-near-one-year-low-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Herbert Lash]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>FOREX/ (UPDATE 5)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[欧盟同意矿产供应目标以减少对中国的依赖]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Critical minerals law likely to enter force early 2024</li>  <li>Deal increases ambitions on recycling</li>  <li>Aluminium and synthetic graphite added to key minerals</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>重要矿产法可能于 2024 年初生效</li><li>交易增加了回收的雄心</li><li>铝和合成石墨添加到关键矿物中</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/-k97Hbg_OkdopPRGeheSziV7RAk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/EJ5ZD7MJYZOI7JFXRKN7RES33U.jpg" alt="EU flags fly outside the European Commission in Brussels翻译:欧盟旗帜在布鲁塞尔欧盟委员会外飘扬" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>European Union flags fly outside the European Commission in Brussels, Belgium November 8, 2023. REUTERS/Yves Herman翻译:2023 年 11 月 8 日，欧盟旗帜在比利时布鲁塞尔欧盟委员会外飘扬。REUTERS/Yves Herman</figcaption></figure>       <p>Negotiators for EU governments and lawmakers reached a deal on Monday on targets for domestic supply of critical minerals such as lithium and nickel to reduce its reliance on third countries, principally China.翻译:欧盟各国政府谈判代表和立法者周一就锂和镍等关键矿产的国内供应目标达成协议，以减少对第三国（主要是中国）的依赖。</p>   <p>The European Commission proposed the Critical Raw Materials Act in March, a centrepiece of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/eu-unveil-plans-leadership-green-industrial-revolution-2023-03-16/">EU strategy</a> to allow it to compete with the United States and China in making clean tech products.翻译:欧盟委员会于三月份提出了《关键原材料法案》，这是<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/eu-unveil-plans-leadership-green-industrial-revolution-2023-03-16/">欧盟战略</a>的核心，旨在使其能够在清洁技术产品的制造方面与美国和中国竞争。</p>   <p>The proposal said the European Union should extract 10%, recycle 15% and process 40% of its annual needs by 2030 for 16 "strategic raw materials".翻译:该提案称，到2030年，欧盟应提取10%、回收15%并加工16种“战略原材料”年度需求的40%。</p>   <p>The European Parliament and the Council, the grouping of EU governments, needed to agree on a common text. They did this on Monday, parties from both sides said, paving the way for the law to enter force in early 2024.翻译:欧洲议会和理事会（欧盟各国政府组成的组织）需要就共同文本达成一致。双方表示，他们于周一这样做了，为该法律于 2024 年初生效铺平了道路。</p>   <p>Negotiators upgraded the recycling target to at least 25%. Parliament negotiators also said the European Commission would pass a related act in 2027 that set a recycling target related to annual waste collected, rather than consumption.翻译:谈判人员将回收目标提高到至少 25%。议会谈判代表还表示，欧盟委员会将在 2027 年通过一项相关法案，设定与每年收集的废物相关的回收目标，而不是消费量。</p>   <p>The negotiators also agreed to add aluminium to the list of strategic raw materials as well as synthetic graphite. Natural graphite was already in the list.翻译:谈判代表还同意将铝以及合成石墨添加到战略原材料清单中。天然石墨已经在名单中。</p>   <p>The latter inclusion reflects China's plan to tighten export controls for graphite. China refines over 90% of the world's graphite into material that is used in almost all electric vehicle anodes, the negatively charged portion of the battery.翻译:后者的列入反映了中国计划加强石墨出口管制。中国将全球 90% 以上的石墨精炼成几乎所有电动汽车阳极（电池的带负电部分）所用的材料。</p>   <p>The EU is also heavily reliant on China for rare earths and lithium, other vital materials for its green transition.翻译:欧盟还严重依赖中国的稀土和锂以及其他绿色转型的重要材料。</p>   <p>The act's aim is that no third country should provide more than 65% of any strategic raw material, which also includes cobalt, copper, magnesium and titanium.翻译:该法案的目标是，任何第三国都不得提供超过 65% 的战略原材料，其中还包括钴、铜、镁和钛。</p>   <p>The act sets time limits on granting permits for strategic mining, recycling and processing projects, and requires large companies needing strategic materials in key technologies to do regular risk assessments of their supply chains.翻译:该法案规定了授予战略采矿、回收和加工项目许可证的时间限制，并要求需要关键技术中战略材料的大公司定期对其供应链进行风险评估。</p>   <p>It also has provisions designed to moderate consumption.翻译:它还制定了旨在调节消费的规定。</p>   <p>EU industry chief Thierry Breton said in a statement that, without action, Europe risked shortages and unwanted dependencies, and that the law would ensure high environmental and social standards.翻译:欧盟工业负责人蒂埃里·布雷顿(Thierry Breton)在一份声明中表示，如果不采取行动，欧洲将面临短缺和不必要的依赖的风险，而该法律将确保高环境和社会标准。</p>   <p>The bloc will work with EU members to identify strategic projects that will benefit from shorter and more efficient permitting procedures and easier access to finance, he added.翻译:他补充说，欧盟将与欧盟成员国合作，确定战略项目，这些项目将受益于更短、更高效的许可程序和更容易获得融资。</p>    <span>Reporting by Foo Yun Chee and Philip Blenkinsop; Editing by David Goodman, Jan Harvey and Jonathan Oatis翻译:Foo Yun Chee 和 Philip Blenkinsop 的报道；编辑：大卫·古德曼、扬·哈维和乔纳森·奥蒂斯</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 20:48:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">AMBUKYJUNRM5HAAE7MNX26N2D4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/eu-set-okay-rules-secure-critical-raw-materials-eu-official-says-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Foo Yun Chee, Philip Blenkinsop]]></author>
            
                
                <category>EU</category>
                
                <category>INDUSTRY/ (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[工行黑客事件后华尔街的混乱]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/We1zSRXyn0zS_k6zWUmv-O7Ftg4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/P76UAD6Q65LQZOQX45B5PMQ4BU.jpg" alt="The logo of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China is seen at its branch at its headquarters in Beijing翻译:中国工商银行北京总部分行的标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China (ICBC) is seen at its branch at its headquarters in Beijing, China, March 30, 2016.  REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/File Photo/File Photo翻译:2016 年 3 月 30 日，中国工商银行 (ICBC) 标志出现在中国北京总部分行。 REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/资料照片/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The cyber hack of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China's U.S. broker-dealer was so extensive on Wednesday, even the corporate email stopped working and forced employees to switch to Google mail, according to two people familiar with the situation.翻译:据两位知情人士透露，中国工商银行美国经纪自营商周三遭受的网络黑客攻击范围非常广泛，甚至连公司电子邮件都停止工作，迫使员工改用谷歌邮件。</p>   <p>The blackout left the brokerage <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/icbc-ransomware-attack-triggers-global-regulator-trader-scrutiny-2023-11-10/">temporarily owing BNY Mellon BK.N $9 billion</a>, an amount many times larger than its net capital, a measure of resources at hand to promptly satisfy claims.翻译:停电导致该经纪公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/icbc-ransomware-attack-triggers-global-regulator-trader-scrutiny-2023-11-10/">暂时欠纽约梅隆银行 90 亿美元</a>，这一数额比其净资本高出许多倍，而净资本是衡量其手头资源以迅速满足索赔要求的指标。</p>   <p>Those details and what happened next, some of which are reported here for the first time, show how the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-largest-bank-icbc-hit-by-ransomware-software-ft-2023-11-09/">ransomware attack</a> pushed the firm owned by China’s largest bank close to the brink. And they serve as a wakeup call for the financial sector and raise some concerns about the resilience of the $26 trillion Treasury market.翻译:这些细节以及接下来发生的事情（其中一些是首次在此报道）表明， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-largest-bank-icbc-hit-by-ransomware-software-ft-2023-11-09/">勒索软件攻击</a>如何将中国最大银行旗下的公司推向崩溃的边缘。它们给金融部门敲响了警钟，并引发了人们对 26 万亿美元国债市场弹性的担忧。</p>   <p>ICBC's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601398.SS" target="_blank">(601398.SS)</a> New York-based unit, called ICBC Financial Services, got a cash injection from its Chinese parent to help pay back BNY, and it manually processed trades with the custody bank's help, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/icbc-ransomware-attack-triggers-global-regulator-trader-scrutiny-2023-11-10/">Reuters reported on Friday</a>.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/icbc-ransomware-attack-triggers-global-regulator-trader-scrutiny-2023-11-10/">据路透社周五报道，</a>中国工商银行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601398.SS" target="_blank">（601398.SS）</a>总部位于纽约的子公司工银金融服务公司从其中国母公司获得了现金注入，以帮助偿还纽约银行的资金，并在托管银行的帮助下手动处理交易。</p>   <p>ICBC told market participants on an industry call on Friday afternoon that it was working with a cybersecurity firm, called MoxFive, to set up secure systems that would allow it to resume normal business on Wall Street, according to the sources. But ICBC expected that process to take at least until Monday, they said.翻译:据消息人士透露，中国工商银行在周五下午的行业电话会议上告诉市场参与者，它正在与一家名为 MoxFive 的网络安全公司合作，建立安全系统，使其能够在华尔街恢复正常业务。但他们表示，工行预计这一过程至少要持续到周一。</p>   <p>In the interim, the firm had asked its clients to temporarily suspend business and clear trades elsewhere, the sources said. Other market participants, meanwhile, looked through their own books to see whether they had any exposure and sought to reroute trades, one of the sources said.翻译:消息人士称，在此期间，该公司已要求其客户暂时停止业务并在其他地方清算交易。一位消息人士称，与此同时，其他市场参与者也在查看自己的账簿，看看自己是否有任何风险敞口，并试图改变交易路线。</p>   <p>ICBC Financial Services could not be reached for comment. ICBC did not respond to a request for comment.翻译:未能联系到工银金融服务部置评。中国工商银行没有回应置评请求。</p>   <p>On a notice on its website, the brokerage said it has been "progressing its recovery efforts with the support of its professional team of information security experts." It said it had cleared Treasury trades executed on Wednesday and repo financing trades done on Thursday.翻译:该券商在其网站上发布的通知中表示，“在信息安全专家专业团队的支持下，其一直在推进恢复工作”。该公司表示，已清算了周三执行的国债交易和周四执行的回购融资交易。</p>   <p>Moxfive executives did not respond to requests for comment.翻译:Mox Five 高管没有回应置评请求。</p>   <p>The ransomware attack, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/what-is-lockbit-digital-extortion-gang-cybercrime-spree-2023-11-10/">claimed by cybercrime gang Lockbit</a>, comes at a time of heightened worries about the resiliency of the Treasury market, which is essential to the plumbing of global finance. After upheavals there - most recently during the pandemic in March 2020 - threatened financial stability, U.S. authorities launched a broad review of its functioning.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/what-is-lockbit-digital-extortion-gang-cybercrime-spree-2023-11-10/">网络犯罪团伙 Lockbit 声称发动了</a>这起勒索软件攻击，而此时人们对美国国债市场的弹性更加担忧，而美国国债市场对于全球金融管道至关重要。那里的动荡（最近一次是在 2020 年 3 月的大流行期间）威胁到金融稳定后，美国当局对其运作进行了广泛的审查。</p>   <p>While market participants and officials have said the impact of the ICBC hack on Treasury market functioning was limited, the full extent of it is not yet understood. There is some debate, for example, about whether it had affected a major auction of Treasury bonds on Thursday.翻译:尽管市场参与者和官员表示，中国工商银行黑客事件对国债市场运作的影响有限，但其影响的全部程度尚不清楚。例如，关于这是否影响了周四国债的大型拍卖，存在一些争论。</p>   <p>Nevertheless, market participants said the attack is likely to add a new aspect to the regulatory review, as it brings cyber threats into sharper focus. It could also boost a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/market-treasury-market-braces-seismic-sec-rule-2023-10-30/">Securities and Exchange Commission's push</a> to have more Treasury trades go through central clearing, where a third-party acts as a seller to every buyer, and buyer to every seller.翻译:尽管如此，市场参与者表示，这次攻击可能会为监管审查增加一个新的方面，因为它使网络威胁更加受到关注。它还可能推动<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/market-treasury-market-braces-seismic-sec-rule-2023-10-30/">美国证券交易委员会推动</a>更多国债交易通过中央清算，其中第三方充当每个买家的卖家，以及每个卖家的买家。</p>   <p>Darrell Duffie, a Stanford finance professor who has studied the market in depth and consults with regulators, said other firms in ICBC's situation might not have enough capital readily available to meet a large shortfall and default.翻译:斯坦福大学金融学教授达雷尔·杜菲(Darrell Duffie)对市场进行了深入研究，并与监管机构进行了咨询，他表示，像工行这样的其他公司可能没有足够的可用资金来应对巨额缺口和违约。</p>   <p>"Any default that could follow an event like this, if not centrally cleared, could propagate into a chain reaction of default events," Duffie said. "This hack makes even more evident the important financial stability benefits of broader central clearing."翻译:达菲表示：“此类事件发生后可能出现的任何违约，如果不进行集中清算，都可能会引发违约事件的连锁反应。” “这次黑客攻击使得更广泛的中央清算对金融稳定的重要好处更加明显。”</p>   <p>The hack is likely to become a key topic of conversation at a major Treasury market conference on Nov. 16.</p>    <h 1="">MID-SIZE BROKER</h>  <p>ICBC Financial Services is not huge by Wall Street's standards. The company had about $24.5 billion in assets as of June 30, with $480.7 million of net capital, according to financial information posted on its website. It also had credit lines from affiliates of $450 million as well as the ability to borrow overnight funds from an affiliate.翻译:按照华尔街的标准，工银金融服务公司规模并不大。根据其网站上发布的财务信息，截至 6 月 30 日，该公司拥有约 245 亿美元的资产，净资本为 4.807 亿美元。它还从附属公司获得了 4.5 亿美元的信贷额度，并能够从附属公司借入隔夜资金。</p>   <p>It mainly offers settlement and financing services for fixed-income securities, such as repurchase agreement (repo), where assets such as Treasuries are used as collateral to raise short-term cash.翻译:它主要为固定收益证券提供结算和融资服务，例如回购协议（repo），其中使用国债等资产作为抵押品筹集短期现金。</p>   <p>It told market participants on Friday's call that its clients include four independent brokers and half a dozen algorithmic traders, according to the sources. Reuters could not learn the identity of its clients.翻译:据消息人士透露，该公司在周五的电话会议上告诉市场参与者，其客户包括四名独立经纪人和六名算法交易员。路透社无法得知其客户的身份。</p>   <p>One of the sources described the business as mid-sized, explaining that "the biggest players in Treasuries are not clearing at a firm like that."翻译:其中一位消息人士将该业务描述为中等规模，并解释说“国债领域最大的参与者并没有在这样的公司进行清算。”</p>   <p>Even so, the attack that paralyzed its systems threw a wrench in the market's gears when word of the hack spread through Wall Street. One of the sources said some market participants scrambled to sort out whether they had any exposure and rerouted their trades to other firms.</p>    <h 1="">$9 BLN OVERDRAFT</h>  <p>When ICBC's trades got stuck, it became BNY Mellon's issue, too, since it is the sole settlement agent for Treasury securities. The bank played a crucial role in helping sort through the mess, deploying a manual process to clear trades one by one, the market participants said.翻译:当中国工商银行的交易陷入困境时，它也成为纽约梅隆银行的问题，因为它是美国国债的唯一结算代理。市场参与者表示，该银行在帮助理清混乱局面方面发挥了至关重要的作用，部署了手动流程来逐笔清算交易。</p>   <p>ICBC's inability to access its systems meant securities from the Chinese firm's repo trades were getting delivered to BNY for settlement, but no cash was coming in from the broker-dealer, one of the sources said.翻译:其中一位消息人士称，中国工商银行无法访问其系统，这意味着这家中国公司的回购交易中的证券将被交付给纽约银行进行结算，但经纪自营商并没有收到任何现金。</p>   <p>That effectively meant BNY was loaning ICBC the cash, secured by Treasuries, according to the source. That's when ICBC's parent injected capital into the unit, allowing BNY to be paid, the source said.翻译:消息人士称，这实际上意味着纽约银行向中国工商银行借出了以国债作为担保的现金。消息人士称，当时中国工商银行的母公司向该部门注资，允许纽约银行付款。</p>   <p>ICBC told market participants on the call, which was organized by the industry group SIFMA, that the transfer had been more than what they expected was needed for current trading volumes, the source said.翻译:消息人士称，中国工商银行在行业组织 SIFMA 组织的电话会议上告诉市场参与者，此次转账金额超出了他们对当前交易量的预期。</p>   <p>SIFMA declined to comment.翻译:SIFMA拒绝发表评论。</p>   <p>Once the firm gets its new system up and running, others on the Street are likely to do their own review to make sure it is safe, which might add time for the business to return to normal, the sources said.翻译:消息人士称，一旦该公司的新系统启动并运行，华尔街的其他人可能会进行自己的审查，以确保其安全，这可能会增加该公司恢复正常的时间。</p>   <p>ICBC told market participants Friday that they were also hoping to have a secondary email system set up soon.翻译:中国工商银行周五告诉市场参与者，他们还希望尽快建立辅助电子邮件系统。</p>    <span>Reporting by Paritosh Bansal; editing by Edward Tobin翻译:帕里托什·班萨尔 (Paritosh Bansal) 报道；爱德华·托宾编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 19:46:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BOVWQW4K7VIYPBPIE4EXUR2GSE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/market-inside-wall-streets-scramble-after-icbc-hack-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Paritosh Bansal]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ICBC</category>
                
                <category>CYBER/BNY (REPEAT, EXCLUSIVE, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国表示正在努力在APEC领导人宣言上达成强有力的共识]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The United States is working hard to try to get a strong consensus leaders' statement at this week's Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation forum (APEC) summit this week, the senior U.S. official for APEC, Matt Murray, told reporters on Monday.翻译:美国亚太经合组织高级官员马特·默里周一对记者表示，美国正在努力争取在本周举行的亚太经济合作论坛（APEC）峰会上达成强有力的共识领导人声明。</p>   <p>Leaders from the 21-member APEC forum <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">are due to gather</a> in San Francisco from Wednesday until Friday. The wars in the Middle East and Ukraine have divided opinion among APEC members, making drafting a summit declaration difficult.翻译:由 21 个成员组成的 APEC 论坛领导人<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">将于周三至周五齐聚</a>旧金山。中东和乌克兰战争导致APEC成员意见分歧，给峰会宣言的起草带来困难。</p>   <p>"We're certainly working toward having a strong consensus statement in APEC for the leaders to be able to release at the end of the week," Murray said in a briefing call, while acknowledging there had been "a lot of friction over the last couple of years over statements, primarily due to the Russia-Ukraine conflict."翻译:默里在一次新闻发布会上表示：“我们当然正在努力在亚太经合组织会议上达成强有力的共识声明，以便领导人能够在本周末发布。”他同时承认“过去一段时间存在很多摩擦”。多年来的声明，主要是由于俄罗斯和乌克兰的冲突。”</p>   <p>"But last year Thailand hosted APEC and was able to announce a consensus leaders’ declaration, and we certainly want to try to do the same thing this year," Murray said.翻译:“但去年泰国主办了亚太经合组织，并能够宣布领导人共识宣言，我们当然希望今年尝试做同样的事情，”穆雷说。</p>   <p>"And we're working very hard with all of our like-minded partners and economies, economic partners throughout APEC, to try to deliver that kind of result."翻译:“我们正在与所有志同道合的伙伴和经济体、整个亚太经合组织的经济伙伴努力合作，努力实现这样的结果。”</p>   <p>Russia is a member of APEC and last year in Bangkok leaders endorsed a text vowing to uphold and strengthen a rules-based multilateral trading system while noting "most" of them condemned Russia's war in Ukraine.翻译:俄罗斯是亚太经合组织成员，去年领导人在曼谷签署了一份文本，誓言维护和加强基于规则的多边贸易体系，同时指出“大多数”领导人谴责俄罗斯在乌克兰的战争。</p>   <p>This year the war in the Middle East is an added complication with Muslim majority APEC members Indonesia and Malaysia, for example, backing the Palestinian cause, while the United States and others lean toward Israel.翻译:今年的中东战争变得更加复杂，例如，穆斯林占多数的亚太经合组织成员国印度尼西亚和马来西亚支持巴勒斯坦事业，而美国和其他国家则倾向于以色列。</p>   <p>The United State as host is in charge of the APEC guest list and says Russian President Vladimir Putin will not be attending the San Francisco summit. Murray said Russia would be represented by a deputy prime minister and other officials not subject to U.S. sanctions.翻译:美国作为东道主负责亚太经合组织嘉宾名单，并表示俄罗斯总统普京将不会出席旧金山峰会。默里表示，俄罗斯将由一名副总理和其他不受美国制裁的官员代表。</p>   <p>APEC accounts for about 62% of global GDP and almost half of global trade. It is unique in grouping economies rather than nations, allowing participation of Chinese-ruled Hong Kong and democratically governed Taiwan, which China claims as its own. It does not, however, include India, the world's most populous country.翻译:APEC约占全球GDP的62%，几乎占全球贸易的一半。它的独特之处在于将经济体而不是国家分组，允许中国统治的香港和民主统治的台湾参与其中，中国声称台湾是自己的领土。然而，它不包括世界上人口最多的国家印度。</p>   <p>Murray said India would be represented at ministerial-level APEC meetings this week as a "guest economy."翻译:穆雷表示，印度将作为“客座经济体”出席本周的亚太经合组织部长级会议。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Brunnstrom and Simon Lewis; editing by Jonathan Oatis翻译:大卫·布伦斯特罗姆和西蒙·刘易斯报道；乔纳森·奥蒂斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 17:30:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">36GMOKFWOJJZ5N3UFKUUXBFB3Y</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us-says-its-working-hard-have-strong-consensus-leaders-declaration-apec-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Brunnstrom, Simon Lewis]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/STATEMENT (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[英国审查对外国收购的审查]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/zjdOl-ETkpEHH8wWZc3p3uJImUo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BJ7R7UFSH5O5RLIEMPWELIDCNU.jpg" alt="A view of the main entrance of Nexperia owned site of microchip producer Newport Wafer Fab, Newport, Wales,翻译:Nexperia 拥有的微芯片生产商纽波特晶圆厂（威尔士纽波特）的主入口视图，" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view of the main entrance of Nexperia owned site of microchip producer Newport Wafer Fab, Newport, Wales,翻译:Nexperia 拥有的微芯片生产商纽波特晶圆厂（威尔士纽波特）的主入口视图， Britain, November 22, 2022. REUTERS/Rebecca Naden/File photo翻译:2022 年 11 月 22 日，英国威尔士纽波特，Nexperia 拥有的微芯片生产商纽波特晶圆厂 (Newport Wafer Fab) 的主入口视图。路透社/Rebecca Naden/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Britain is reviewing how it screens foreign takeovers for national security concerns to reduce the burden on businesses, less than two years after tougher rules were introduced, deputy prime minister Oliver Dowden said on Monday.翻译:英国副首相奥利弗·道登周一表示，在出台更严格的规定不到两年后，英国正在审查如何出于国家安全考虑筛选外国收购，以减轻企业负担。</p>   <p>The government, under the 2022 National Security and Investment Act, has the power to scrutinise investment and take action to protect assets that are vital to Britain's national security.翻译:根据《2022 年国家安全和投资法案》，政府有权审查投资并采取行动保护对英国国家安全至关重要的资产。</p>   <p>Companies, however, have criticised the breadth of the act, which requires the notification of deals in 17 areas, ranging from advanced materials to transport.翻译:然而，公司批评了该法案的广度，该法案要求通报从先进材料到运输等 17 个领域的交易。</p>   <p>In the first full year of the act coming into effect, China-linked takeovers <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-opposes-uks-discriminatory-actions-against-china-linked-deals-2023-07-12/">accounted</a> for eight of the 15 interventions made, prompting criticism from the Chinese embassy in London.翻译:该法案生效的第一年，15 项干预措施中， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-opposes-uks-discriminatory-actions-against-china-linked-deals-2023-07-12/">有</a>8 项是与中国相关的收购，这引发了中国驻伦敦大使馆的批评。</p>   <p>Notably, the law was used to force Chinese-owned technology company Nexperia to sell Britain's biggest microchip factory, Newport Wafer Fab, which it had bought in 2021.翻译:值得注意的是，该法律被用来迫使中国科技公司 Nexperia 出售其于 2021 年收购的英国最大的微芯片工厂 Newport Wafer Fab。</p>   <p>Dowden said he needed to ensure the screening powers remained "up to date, proportionate and transparent", while protecting national security.翻译:道登表示，他需要确保筛查权力保持“最新、适当和透明”，同时保护国家安全。</p>   <p>Semiconductors and critical minerals could be carved out as standalone sectors under the act, he said, reflecting their growing importance.翻译:他说，根据该法案，半导体和关键矿物可以被划分为独立的部门，这反映出它们日益增长的重要性。</p>   <p>He said businesses, investors and advisors would now be consulted to ensure the process remained as frictionless and effective as possible.翻译:他表示，现在将咨询企业、投资者和顾问，以确保这一过程尽可能保持无摩擦和有效。</p>   <p>Evidence can be submitted to the government until Jan. 15.翻译:证据可以在 1 月 15 日之前提交给政府。</p>   <p>"The best way to foster economic security is through a strong and open economy," Dowden said. "That's why we've been using the powers effectively so far, only intervening when absolutely necessary to protect national security."翻译:道登说：“促进经济安全的最佳途径是通过强大和开放的经济。” “这就是为什么我们迄今为止一直有效地使用这些权力，只有在绝对必要时才进行干预以保护国家安全。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Paul Sandle; Editing by Susan Fenton翻译:保罗·桑德尔报道；苏珊·芬顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 16:57:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6GXE3XGJ2VOKBO67XKKFMAW6UM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/britain-reviews-scrutiny-foreign-takeovers-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>BRITAIN</category>
                
                <category>M&#38;A/SCRUTINY</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[托克将澳大利亚开采的铜带回中国——消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Standard Australian copper concentrate shipment en route to China</li>  <li>Trafigura unit to assist with customs clearance</li>  <li>Entry of the cargo points to end of informal ban</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>标准澳大利亚铜精矿运往中国</li><li>托克部门协助清关</li><li>货运点进入以结束非正式禁令</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/KKXORVjoBxqs8LvZMQ9qO0bmi0A=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XKUEPGG2TRPS3D33TDD4M3WF3Q.jpg" alt="Employees work at a copper smelter in Yantai翻译:烟台一家铜冶炼厂的员工在工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Employees work at a copper smelter in Yantai翻译:烟台一家铜冶炼厂的员工在工作, Shandong province, China April 26, 2023. REUTERS/Siyi Liu翻译:2023 年 4 月 26 日，中国山东省烟台市一家铜冶炼厂的员工在工作。路透社/Siyi Liu</figcaption></figure>       <p>Swiss commodity trader Trafigura has agreed to help Chinese smelters clear imports of copper concentrate from Australia, suggesting an informal ban has been lifted if the cargo clears customs, three sources familiar with the matter told Reuters.翻译:三名知情人士告诉路透社，瑞士大宗商品贸易商托克已同意帮助中国冶炼厂清关从澳大利亚进口的铜精矿，这表明如果货物清关，非正式禁令将被解除。</p>   <p>China has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/chinese-buyers-anticipate-end-soft-ban-australian-copper-2023-05-10/">gradually been easing</a> a raft of unofficial curbs and tariffs on Australian imports, including copper concentrate and coal, that were imposed in 2020 at the height of a diplomatic spat over trade and security.翻译:中国正在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/chinese-buyers-anticipate-end-soft-ban-australian-copper-2023-05-10/">逐步放松</a>对澳大利亚进口商品（包括铜精矿和煤炭）的一系列非正式限制和关税，这些限制和关税是在 2020 年贸易和安全外交争端最严重时实施的。</p>   <p>Despite a wider informal easing, state-owned Chinese smelters that turn concentrate into copper metal, have been reluctant to buy from Australia, which accounted for 5%, or 1.1 million tonnes, of China's total copper concentrate imports in 2019.翻译:尽管有更广泛的非正式宽松政策，但将精矿转变成金属铜的中国国有冶炼厂一直不愿从澳大利亚购买，澳大利亚占2019年中国铜精矿进口总量的5%，即110万吨。</p>   <p>However a shipment of around 10,000 metric tonnes of copper concentrate mined from Western Australia's Golden Grove, owned by 29Metals <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/29M.AX" target="_blank">(29M.AX)</a>, is on its way to Shandong province, where many major Chinese smelters are located, the sources said.翻译:然而，消息人士称，29Metals <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/29M.AX" target="_blank">(29M.AX)</a>旗下西澳大利亚 Golden Grove 开采的约 10,000 吨铜精矿正在运往中国许多主要冶炼厂所在地的山东省。</p>   <p>The passage of a large cargo of Australian concentrate through customs in China will ease smelters' concerns about a political backlash, the sources said.翻译:消息人士称，大批澳大利亚精矿通过中国海关将缓解冶炼厂对政治反弹的担忧。</p>   <p>"We have been waiting for others to be the first to resume buying Australia-origin concentrate," a source at a major Chinese copper concentrates importer said.翻译:“我们一直在等待其他人率先恢复购买澳大利亚原产精矿，”中国一家主要铜精矿进口商的消息人士表示。</p>   <p>Copper is vital for the power industry due to its conductivity. China consumes nearly half of the global mined copper supply estimated at around 25 million tonnes this year.翻译:由于其导电性，铜对于电力工业至关重要。中国今年消耗了全球矿铜供应量的近一半，估计约为 2500 万吨。</p>   <p>Trafigura's Chinese affiliate will be responsible for clearing customs on behalf of domestic consumers once the cargo arrives at Shandong's Qingdao port, two of the sources said.翻译:两名消息人士称，一旦货物抵达山东青岛港，托克的中国子公司将负责代表国内消费者清关。</p>   <p>"Once Trafigura gets the clearance, it is official that the soft ban has come to an end," the source added.翻译:消息人士补充道：“一旦托克获得许可，软禁令就正式结束。”</p>   <p>Trafigura declined to comment. 29Metals did not respond to a request for comment.翻译:托克拒绝置评。 29Metals 没有回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Australian trade data <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/chinese-buyers-anticipate-end-soft-ban-australian-copper-2023-05-10/">shows exports worth </a>A$60.5 million ($38.52 million) of copper ore and concentrate to China in January.翻译:澳大利亚贸易数据<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/chinese-buyers-anticipate-end-soft-ban-australian-copper-2023-05-10/">显示，1 月份向中国出口了价值</a>6050 万澳元（合 3852 万美元）的铜矿石和精矿。</p>   <p>However, the cargo was not logged in Chinese data, which officially shows that in the first nine months of this year, only $10 worth of copper ore and concentrate were imported.翻译:然而，中国数据并未记录这批货物，官方数据显示，今年前9个月，仅进口了价值10美元的铜矿石和精矿。</p>   <p>Australia produced 818,800 tonnes of copper in ore and concentrates last year and is, according International Copper Study Group, the world's eighth-largest producer of the metal.翻译:据国际铜业研究组织称，澳大利亚去年以矿石和精矿的形式生产了 818,800 吨铜，是世界第八大金属生产国。</p>   <p>The shipments from Australia come at a critical time, when Chinese smelters are starting annual negotiations with major miners on annual treatment charges and refining charges (TC/RC).翻译:来自澳大利亚的发货正值关键时刻，当时中国冶炼厂正开始与主要矿商就年度处理费和精炼费（TC/RC）进行年度谈判。</p>   <p>TC/RC is the income received by smelters for turning concentrates into refined copper, which typically rises with higher supply and falls during times of shortages.翻译:TC/RC 是冶炼厂将精矿转化为精炼铜所获得的收入，通常随着供应量的增加而增加，并在短缺时减少。</p>   <p>($1 = 1.5706 Australian dollars)翻译:(1 美元 = 1.5706 澳元)</p>    <span>Reporting by Julian Luk; Editing by Veronica Brown and Sharon Singleton翻译:Julian Luk 报道；维罗妮卡·布朗和莎朗·辛格尔顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 13:20:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">HGDJKNIPAJMDZNLKPBACSUV3IY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/trafigura-brings-australian-mined-copper-back-china-sources-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Julian Luk]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA/COPPER</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[向太平洋提供安置方案是澳大利亚战胜中国的胜利]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/MW8CPfFcXuCucc5M0_Fx9dRDul8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VY6BM7XQAFMPZAHN2OYWPKPMFA.jpg" alt="FILE PHOTO: Tuvalu Prime Minister Kausea Natano,speaks during the U.N. Climate Conference (COP26) in Glasgow, Scotland.翻译:资料照片：图瓦卢总理考西亚·纳塔诺在苏格兰格拉斯哥举行的联合国气候会议 (COP26) 上发表讲话。" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>FILE PHOTO: Tuvalu Prime Minister Kausea Natano speaks during the U.N. Climate Conference (COP26) in Glasgow, Scotland. November 2021. REUTERS/Hannah McKay/Pool/File Photo翻译:文件照片：图瓦卢总理考西亚·纳塔诺在苏格兰格拉斯哥举行的联合国气候会议 (COP26) 上发表讲话。 2021 年 11 月。路透社/Hannah McKay/Pool/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Australia scored a significant win for influence in the Pacific Islands region with a trump card that China, seeking to expand security ties, doesn't have: the opportunity of resettlement.翻译:澳大利亚凭借一张寻求扩大安全关系的中国所没有的王牌，在太平洋岛屿地区的影响力上取得了重大胜利：重新安置的机会。</p>   <p>Under a security guarantee to the remote atoll nation of Tuvalu, which is threatened by rising sea levels, Australia will offer permanent residency to 280 Tuvalu citizens each year.翻译:根据对受到海平面上升威胁的偏远环礁国家图瓦卢的安全保障，澳大利亚每年将向 280 名图瓦卢公民提供永久居留权。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australia-offer-climate-refuge-all-residents-tuvalu-report-2023-11-10/">The treaty</a>, signed on Friday by Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and his counterpart Kausea Natano, could transform Australia's relationship with the Pacific, analysts say.翻译:分析人士称， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australia-offer-climate-refuge-all-residents-tuvalu-report-2023-11-10/">该条约</a>由总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞和总理考西亚·纳塔诺于周五签署，可能会改变澳大利亚与太平洋地区的关系。</p>   <p>"It is something China can't do," said Australian National University Pacific expert Graeme Smith.翻译:“这是中国做不到的，”澳大利亚国立大学太平洋分校专家格雷姆·史密斯说。</p>   <p>The treaty was announced after parliament recently passed legislation for a wider scheme offering permanent settlement for 3,000 Pacific Islanders annually in a ballot from next year.翻译:该条约是在议会最近通过立法制定一项更广泛的计划后宣布的，该计划从明年开始每年投票为 3,000 名太平洋岛民提供永久定居。</p>   <p>Defence Minister Richard Marles called the treaty with Tuvalu a "watershed in our relationship with the Pacific", representing a "much greater commitment for Australia to be providing more of Tuvalu's defence".翻译:国防部长理查德·马尔斯称与图瓦卢的条约是“我们与太平洋地区关系的分水岭”，代表“澳大利亚为图瓦卢提供更多防务做出了更大的承诺”。</p>   <p>The sequencing of Albanese's whirlwind of diplomatic visits - <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-us-leaders-discuss-pacific-infrastructure-critical-minerals-2023-10-24/">Washington</a>, Beijing a week later, and then directly to a Pacific Islands leaders meeting in Rarotonga, sent "clear signals to everyone involved", said Peter Dean, director of foreign policy and defence at the United States Studies Centre in Sydney.翻译:联合国外交政策和防务主任彼得·迪恩表示，阿尔巴尼亚旋风式的外交访问——一周后访问<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-us-leaders-discuss-pacific-infrastructure-critical-minerals-2023-10-24/">华盛顿</a>、北京，然后直接前往拉罗汤加举行太平洋岛屿领导人会议，向所有相关人员发出了“明确的信号”。悉尼国家研究中心。</p>   <p>"The number one strategic objective of Australian governments since federation in this region has been to ensure another great power whose interests are not aligned to its own doesn't get a foothold in the region," he said.翻译:他说：“自该地区联邦成立以来，澳大利亚政府的首要战略目标就是确保另一个与其利益不一致的大国无法在该地区立足。”</p>   <p>"China can turn up and offer more infrastructure money... they can't turn up and offer this kind of resettlement relationship. It serves as a model for the region."翻译:“中国可以出现并提供更多的基础设施资金……他们不能出现并提供这种安置关系。它可以成为该地区的典范。”</p>   <p>Despite the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-australia-restart-annual-meetings-trade-resumes-2023-11-07/">improved diplomatic tone</a> between Australia and China after Albanese's tour last week, the first in seven years by an Australian leader, security tensions remain as Beijing expands its role in the Pacific Islands.翻译:尽管阿尔巴内斯上周出访（澳大利亚领导人七年来首次出访）后，澳大利亚和中国之间的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-australia-restart-annual-meetings-trade-resumes-2023-11-07/">外交气氛有所改善</a>，但随着北京扩大其在太平洋岛屿的作用，安全紧张局势依然存在。</p>   <p>Australia has sent 450 police and military officers to Solomon Islands, which signed a security pact with China last year, to provide security for the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-sends-100-police-solomon-islands-pacific-games-2023-11-08/">Pacific Games which open</a> on Sunday, joining regional forces from Fiji and Papua New Guinea, to ensure there is no gap for Chinese police to fill.翻译:澳大利亚已向去年与中国签署安全协议的所罗门群岛派遣了 450 名警察和军官，为周日<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-sends-100-police-solomon-islands-pacific-games-2023-11-08/">开幕的太平洋运动会</a>提供安全保障，并与斐济和巴布亚新几内亚的地区部队一道，确保不存在任何差距。供中国警方填写。</p>   <p>Australia also will be able to block any policing deal between China and Tuvalu - as well as any telecommunications, energy or port deal - under its treaty.翻译:根据其条约，澳大利亚还可以阻止中国与图瓦卢之间的任何警务协议以及任何电信、能源或港口协议。</p>   <p>State-owned China Civil Engineering Construction Corporation (CCECC) had built Tuvalu's harbour in 2019, to the concern of diplomatic ally Taiwan which lost Solomon Islands and Kiribati to Beijing's overtures in the same year.翻译:国有的中国土木工程建设公司（CCECC）于 2019 年建造了图瓦卢港口，这引起了外交盟友台湾的担忧，台湾在同年因北京的示好而失去了所罗门群岛和基里巴斯。</p>   <p>"The game is not going to pause because Australia and China relations are a bit warmer, or even if China-U.S. competition somehow diminishes a bit," said Smith.翻译:史密斯表示：“比赛不会因为澳大利亚和中国关系回暖而暂停，或者即使中美竞争在某种程度上减弱。”</p>   <p>Wang Yiwei, an international relations professor at the Renmin University in Beijing, said rivalry between China and the United States in the Pacific Islands, with each seeking to block the other, had heightened Australia's sensitivity to every Chinese move.翻译:北京人民大学国际关系教授王义伟表示，中美在太平洋岛屿上的竞争，双方都试图阻止对方，这提高了澳大利亚对中国一举一动的敏感度。</p>   <p>The "strategic game" between China and the U.S. was now on Australia's doorstep, he said.翻译:他说，中美之间的“战略博弈”现在已经到了澳大利亚家门口。</p>   <p>"Cooperation in the Pacific region tends to focus on non-traditional security, including maintenance of public security and infrastructure to deal with climate change," he added.翻译:他补充说：“太平洋地区的合作往往侧重于非传统安全，包括维护公共安全和应对气候变化的基础设施。”</p>   <p>"These should not be considered too security-related, but the United States is still relatively sensitive, and Australia is also more sensitive."翻译:“这些不应该被认为太与安全相关，但美国还是比较敏感的，澳大利亚也比较敏感。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Kirsty Needham in Sydney and Martin Pollard in Beijing; Editing by Miral Fahmy翻译:悉尼的 Kirsty Needham 和北京的 Martin Pollard 报道；米拉尔·法赫米编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 08:24:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Z4GXBP6MKZORVL3X2MPH4KLGTE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/resettlement-offer-pacific-win-australia-over-china-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Kirsty Needham, Martin Pollard]]></author>
            
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/PACIFIC (ANALYSIS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[埃赫曼押注锂，加大对大型矿山的投资]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/i2wtNX87qjBXVqVBBYQ5Cwx6pAA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/A6WVQHAGANN7VBMAALCX5NZMLU.jpg" alt="Atacama Desert salt flats, lithium deposit spots, in Chile翻译:智利阿塔卡马沙漠盐滩、锂矿床" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A geological monolith is seen close to Tara salt flat at Los Flamencos National Reserve, in Antofagasta region, Chile, May 5, 2023. REUTERS/Ivan Alvarado/File Photo翻译:2023 年 5 月 5 日，智利安托法加斯塔地区洛斯弗拉门科斯国家保护区塔拉盐滩附近看到一块地质巨石。路透社/Ivan Alvarado/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/1UsgCY0vuWmlTNEDyHrZO7it_Mc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MZU3U37FVZIKNDB4SWBDKRTOVA.jpg" alt="Atacama Desert salt flats, lithium deposit spots, in Chile翻译:智利阿塔卡马沙漠盐滩、锂矿床" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Cristian Espindola, Atacama Indigenous council member, shows a rock painting on the hillside of a rock formation known as La Catedral of the Tara salt flat, in Los Flamencos National Reserve, in Antofagasta region, Chile, May 5, 2023. REUTERS/Ivan Alvarado/File Photo翻译:2023 年 5 月 5 日，阿塔卡马土著委员会成员克里斯蒂安·埃斯平多拉 (Cristian Espindola) 在智利安托法加斯塔地区洛斯弗拉门科斯国家保护区的塔拉盐滩大教堂岩层山坡上展示了一幅岩画。 REUTERS/Ivan Alvarado /档案照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>Eramet <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ERMT.PA" target="_blank">(ERMT.PA)</a> will go ahead with plans to add more capacity in Argentina for the battery mineral lithium and aims to double nickel mine output in Indonesia, in an investment push it sees withstanding a faltering global economy.翻译:Eramet <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ERMT.PA" target="_blank">(ERMT.PA)</a>将继续实施在阿根廷增加电池矿物锂产能的计划，并计划将印度尼西亚的镍矿产量增加一倍，该公司认为，在全球经济步履蹒跚的情况下，这是一项投资举措。</p>   <p>The French mining group forecast on Monday capital expenditure of about 1.9 billion euros ($2.03 billion) over 2024-2026, an increase in annual investment from 550 million euros expected this year.翻译:法国矿业集团周一预测，2024-2026 年的资本支出约为 19 亿欧元（20.3 亿美元），比今年预期的 5.5 亿欧元增加了年度投资。</p>   <p>"These investments are being made in areas with very high growth," Christel Bories, Eramet's chair and CEO, told Reuters. "Lithium is not tied to world economic growth, it's tied to the development of batteries and the energy transition."翻译:埃赫曼董事长兼首席执行官克里斯特尔·博里斯 (Christel Bories) 告诉路透社：“这些投资是在增长非常快的领域进行的。” “锂与世界经济增长无关，它与电池的发展和能源转型有关。”</p>   <p>The group said it had approved a second phase for its Centenario lithium project in Argentina to produce about 30,000 metric tons annually of lithium carbonate equivalent (LCE), on top of the 24,000 tons targeted in a first tranche that will enter production in the second quarter of 2024.翻译:该集团表示，已批准其位于阿根廷的 Centenario 锂项目第二阶段，每年生产约 30,000 吨碳酸锂当量 (LCE)，第一阶段的目标产量为 24,000 吨，将于第二季度投入生产2024 年。</p>   <p>As well as studying a possible third tranche at Centenario, the firm is exploring the nearby Arizaro deposit, Bories said before Eramet's first capital markets day.翻译:Bories 在 Eramet 首个资本市场日之前表示，除了研究 Centenario 可能的第三批矿藏外，该公司还在勘探附近的 Arizaro 矿床。</p>   <p>Eramet is developing Centenario with Chinese steel giant Tsingshan. A $400 million deal with Glencore <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GLEN.L" target="_blank">(GLEN.L)</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/eramet-says-it-secured-400-mln-lithium-deal-with-glencore-2023-07-26/">to market lithium</a> from the project's first stage will mostly cover Eramet's financing needs for the next tranche, Bories said.翻译:Eramet 正在与中国钢铁巨头青山钢铁共同开发 Centenario。 Bories 表示，与 Glencore <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GLEN.L" target="_blank">(GLEN.L)</a>达成的一项价值 4 亿美元的协议<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/eramet-says-it-secured-400-mln-lithium-deal-with-glencore-2023-07-26/">，用于销售该项目第一阶段的锂</a>，将主要满足 Eramet 下一阶段的融资需求。</p>   <p>In Chile, meanwhile, the group said it had acquired for an initial $95 million a 120,000-hectare lithium concession in the Atacama region.翻译:与此同时，在智利，该集团表示已以 9500 万美元的初始价格收购了阿塔卡马地区 12 万公顷的锂矿特许权。</p>   <p>Eramet wants to bring output at Weda Bay in Indonesia, the world's largest nickel mine that it also operates with Tsingshan, to 60 million wet metric tons in 2026 from 30 million anticipated this year.翻译:埃赫曼希望将印度尼西亚 Weda Bay 的产量从今年预计的 3,000 万湿吨增至 2026 年。Weda Bay 是该公司与青山共同运营的全球最大镍矿。</p>   <p>The group aims to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/basf-eramet-finalise-partnership-indonesia-nickel-smelter-indonesia-2023-01-18/">process</a> some of the Weda Bay ore into battery-grade nickel and cobalt in a joint venture with German chemical group BASF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BASFn.DE" target="_blank">(BASFn.DE)</a>, with a decision due next year.翻译:该集团计划与德国化工集团巴斯夫<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BASFn.DE" target="_blank">(BASFn.DE)</a>成立合资企业，将韦达湾的部分矿石<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/basf-eramet-finalise-partnership-indonesia-nickel-smelter-indonesia-2023-01-18/">加工</a>成电池级镍和钴，并将于明年做出决定。</p>   <p>It also plans to increase ore output in Gabon, where it operates the world's largest manganese mine, to 8.5 million tons in 2026 from about 7 million expected in 2023, mainly through improvements to a rail transport link.翻译:该公司还计划主要通过改善铁路运输线路，将加蓬的矿石产量从 2023 年预计的约 700 万吨增加到 2026 年的 850 万吨。该公司在加蓬运营着世界上最大的锰矿。</p>   <p>The competitiveness of its top mines and the sale of less profitable metallurgical businesses allows Eramet to invest in a weaker cycle marked by economic uncertainty in commodity powerhouse China, Bories said.翻译:博里斯表示，其顶级矿山的竞争力以及利润较低的冶金业务的出售，使埃赫曼能够在大宗商品大国中国经济不确定性的疲软周期中进行投资。</p>   <p>"The outlook for 2024 is not very favourable," she said. "But despite the very sharp fall in metal prices we are managing to hold up."翻译:“2024 年的前景不太乐观，”她说。 “但尽管金属价格大幅下跌，我们仍设法坚持住。”</p>   <p>However, in New Caledonia its nickel subsidiary SLN remains in financial difficulties, and has entered another court conciliation process after using up the latest <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/france-grants-loan-eramets-sln-nickel-unit-avert-collapse-2023-02-13/">loan</a> from the French government, Bories said.翻译:然而，Bories 表示，其在新喀里多尼亚的镍子公司 SLN 仍面临财务困难，并在用完法国政府的最新<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/france-grants-loan-eramets-sln-nickel-unit-avert-collapse-2023-02-13/">贷款</a>后已进入另一场法院调解程序。</p>   <p>With Eramet refusing to inject more money into SLN and Glencore only providing funding to end-February for the Koniambo Nickel SAS (KNS) operation it co-owns, the authorities need to agree measures in the coming weeks to salvage a nickel industry depleted by energy costs and political tensions, she said.翻译:由于 Eramet 拒绝向 SLN 注入更多资金，而嘉能可仅在 2 月底前为其共同拥有的 Koniambo Nickel SAS (KNS) 业务提供资金，当局需要在未来几周内就拯救能源枯竭的镍行业达成一致。她说，成本和政治紧张局势。</p>    <span>Reporting by Gus Trompiz, Editing by Charlotte Van Campenhout and Louise Heavens翻译:格斯·特罗姆皮兹报道，夏洛特·范坎彭豪特和路易丝·天堂编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 07:51:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7SDEZVBMJBMN3NCEYJDDL56SGA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/eramet-bets-lithium-boom-big-mines-investment-push-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Gus Trompiz]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ERAMET</category>
                
                <category>MINING/STRATEGY (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着监管困境的缓解，中国滴滴出行首次实现 2021 年以来的季度盈利]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/hl2VdQ0OVqS9sN74A37sYrrbkQw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4FSUCMTIEBPHHK4B6B4JMUU3FE.jpg" alt="People walk past the headquarters of the Chinese ride-hailing service Didi in Beijing翻译:人们走过中国叫车服务公司滴滴在北京的总部" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk past the headquarters of the Chinese ride-hailing service Didi in Beijing翻译:人们走过中国叫车服务公司滴滴在北京的总部, China, December 3, 2021. REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2021 年 12 月 3 日，人们走过位于中国北京的中国叫车服务滴滴总部。路透社/Thomas Peter/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Didi Global, China's largest ride-hailing company, on Monday reported its first quarterly profit since 2021, adding to signs of its comeback from regulatory challenges as domestic demand for mobility services continues to recover.翻译:中国最大的网约车公司滴滴出行周一公布了自 2021 年以来的首个季度盈利，随着国内出行服务需求持续复苏，该公司从监管挑战中恢复过来的迹象进一步增加。</p>   <p>Didi Global reported net income attributable to shareholders of 107 million yuan ($14.66 million) in the three-month period ended Sept. 30, versus a loss of 2 billion yuan a year ago. Revenue in the reported quarter jumped 25% to 51.40 billion yuan.翻译:滴滴全球公布，截至 9 月 30 日的三个月内，归属于股东的净利润为 1.07 亿元人民币（合 1,466 万美元），而去年同期为亏损 20 亿元人民币。报告季度收入增长 25% 至 514 亿元人民币。</p>   <p>The ride-hailing firm, which is backed by Alibaba <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">(9988.HK)</a>, Tencent <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0700.HK" target="_blank">(0700.HK)</a> and SoftBank Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9984.T" target="_blank">(9984.T)</a>, did not report its quarterly results in 2022, but recorded an annual <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-didi-sees-2022-revenue-hit-by-covid-net-loss-narrows-2023-04-29/">net loss</a> of 23.78 billion yuan.翻译:这家由阿里巴巴<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">（9988.HK）</a> 、腾讯<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0700.HK" target="_blank">（0700.HK）</a>和软银集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9984.T" target="_blank">（9984.T）</a>支持的网约车公司没有公布2022年季度业绩，但全年<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-didi-sees-2022-revenue-hit-by-covid-net-loss-narrows-2023-04-29/">净亏损</a>237.8亿美元元。</p>   <p>The company on Monday announced plans to repurchase up to $1 billion shares over the next 24 months and said it will boost marketing to aid further business growth.翻译:该公司周一宣布计划在未来 24 个月内回购至多 10 亿美元的股票，并表示将加强营销以帮助业务进一步增长。</p>   <p>Didi in 2021 came into the crosshairs of China's cyberspace regulator for pursuing a U.S. stock listing without an approval. This led to a regulatory investigation into the firm that barred it from signing up new users and caused dozens of its apps to be banned from major app stores.翻译:2021年，滴滴出行因未经批准赴美上市而成为中国网信监管机构的焦点。这导致对该公司进行监管调查，禁止其注册新用户，并导致其数十个应用程序被禁止在主要应用程序商店上架。</p>   <p>The company was delisted from the New York Stock Exchange last year.翻译:该公司去年从纽约证券交易所退市。</p>   <p>Didi was fined $1.2 billion in July 2022 over data-security breaches, but began to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-didi-q2-revenue-grows-regulatory-curbs-ease-2023-09-09/">emerge</a> from these regulatory troubles in January after it was allowed to restore its apps.翻译:2022 年 7 月，滴滴出行因数据安全漏洞被罚款 12 亿美元，但在 1 月份获准恢复其应用程序后，开始<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-didi-q2-revenue-grows-regulatory-curbs-ease-2023-09-09/">摆脱</a>这些监管问题。</p>   <p>The company has also taken steps to streamline its business operations and focus on its core ride-hailing services. In August, the company <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinas-xpeng-take-over-didis-autonomus-vehicle-unit-eyeing-2024-launch-2023-08-28/">announced</a> it would sell its electric vehicle business unit to leading Chinese electric vehicle startup Xpeng <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9868.HK" target="_blank">(9868.HK)</a> for up to $744 million.翻译:该公司还采取措施简化业务运营，并将重点放在核心的叫车服务上。 8月，该公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinas-xpeng-take-over-didis-autonomus-vehicle-unit-eyeing-2024-launch-2023-08-28/">宣布</a>将以高达7.44亿美元的价格将其电动汽车业务部门出售给中国领先的电动汽车初创公司小鹏汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9868.HK" target="_blank">（9868.HK）</a> 。</p>   <p>"In the future, we expect to continue expanding our core businesses while enhancing our product and service capabilities in order to provide better services to our consumers, drivers and ecosystem partners," Didi Chairman and CEO Wei Cheng said in a statement.翻译:滴滴董事长兼首席执行官程维在一份声明中表示：“未来，我们希望继续拓展核心业务，同时增强产品和服务能力，为消费者、司机和生态系统合作伙伴提供更好的服务。”</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2963 Chinese yuan)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2963 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Yelin Mo in Beijing and Sameer Manekar in Bengaluru; Editing by Kim Coghill and Sherry Jacob-Phillips翻译:莫叶琳在北京和 Sameer Manekar 在班加罗尔的报道； Kim Coghill 和 Sherry Jacob-Phillips 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 07:38:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">HDT3ZBC6WRLGFNHU5ZY2PEFVOE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-didi-swings-third-quarter-profit-buy-back-1-bln-worth-shares-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Yelin Mo, Sameer Kulkarni]]></author>
            
                
                <category>DIDI GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>RESULTS/ (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着北京加强做市计划，Citadel 证券探索中国牌照]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/xziCUszJOKBYyN0qFGymm8T8SCQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TH3CUPARSZKLPP5VQ3EWOKUADE.jpg" alt="Milken Institute Global Conference in Beverly Hills翻译:米尔肯研究所全球会议在比佛利山庄举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Peng Zhao, CEO, Citadel Securities speaks at the 2023 Milken Institute Global Conference in Beverly Hills翻译:米尔肯研究所全球会议在比佛利山庄举行, California, U.S., May 1, 2023. REUTERS/Mike Blake/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Citadel Securities, one of the world's biggest market-making firms, is "actively exploring" establishing a licensed onshore business in China, its chief executive Peng Zhao said.翻译:Citadel 证券首席执行官赵鹏表示，Citadel 证券是全球最大的做市商之一，正在“积极探索”在中国建立持牌境内业务。</p>   <p>If Citadel Securities were to obtain a licence, it would be the first foreign firm to formally foray into market-making in China outside interbank and foreign exchange market making.翻译:如果 Citadel 证券获得牌照，它将成为除银行间和外汇做市之外第一家正式涉足中国做市业务的外国公司。</p>   <p>Over the last two years, Chinese authorities have encouraged the development of market makers, approving more licences and pledging to roll out more types of derivatives as they seek to boost liquidity and draw in more long-term capital.翻译:过去两年，中国当局鼓励做市商的发展，批准了更多牌照，并承诺推出更多类型的衍生品，以提高流动性并吸引更多长期资本。</p>   <p>At least 16 domestic securities brokerage firms have been given the nod to act as market makers in China A shares as of mid-September, official records show.翻译:官方记录显示，截至9月中旬，至少有16家国内券商获准担任中国A股做市商。</p>   <p>"We are pleased to see the introduction of the market-making program in China," Zhao told Reuters in an interview in Hong Kong. He declined to disclose the specific licence the company might seek.翻译:“我们很高兴看到中国推出做市计划，”赵在香港接受路透社采访时表示。他拒绝透露该公司可能寻求的具体许可。</p>   <p>"As the Chinese capital market continues to grow beyond simple stock trading and into more complex products, the concept of market making not only will come naturally but also becomes necessary instead of just adding value from a liquidity perspective," Zhao said.翻译:“随着中国资本市场不断从简单的股票交易发展到更复杂的产品，做市的概念不仅会自然而然地出现，而且变得必要，而不仅仅是从流动性角度增加价值，”赵说。</p>   <p>Billionaire Ken Griffin's Citadel Securities, which handles about $390 billion in trades per day, is one of the top market makers by trading volume in the United States.翻译:亿万富翁 Ken Griffin 的 Citadel 证券每天处理约 3900 亿美元的交易，是美国交易量最大的做市商之一。</p>   <p>Market makers quote both buy and sell prices for assets and are constant trading participants in the market, earning profit through the spread of bid and offer prices.翻译:做市商提供资产的买入和卖出价格，并且是市场上的持续交易参与者，通过买入价和卖出价的价差赚取利润。</p>   <p>China's nascent market-making sector could grow to be worth 250 billion yuan ($34 billion) in revenues in 2032, compared with an estimated 40 billion yuan last year, according to Chinese brokerage Haitong.翻译:据中国券商海通称，中国新兴的做市行业到 2032 年的收入可能会增长到 2500 亿元人民币（340 亿美元），而去年估计为 400 亿元人民币。</p>   <p>Market-making was first introduced in China in 2014. In February, Beijing started to allow licenced securities brokerage firms to act as market makers for its newest board Beijing Stock Exchange, following a similar move in May 2022 for its Nasdaq-style <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-launch-market-making-star-market-2022-01-07/">STAR</a> Market.翻译:中国于 2014 年首次引入做市制度。今年 2 月，北京开始允许持牌证券经纪公司担任其最新主板北京证券交易所的做市商，继 2022 年 5 月在纳斯达克风格的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-launch-market-making-star-market-2022-01-07/">科创板</a>市场采取类似举措后。</p>   <p>Citadel Securities in July appointed Tony Tang, the former head of BlackRock's China business, to helm its China operations.翻译:Citadel 证券于 7 月任命贝莱德中国业务前负责人 Tony Tang 负责其中国业务。</p>   <p>In February, it became a "qualified foreign institutional investor" in China, a few months after the country allowed qualified foreign institutions to trade more broadly in domestic futures and options instruments.翻译:今年二月，在中国允许合格境外机构更广泛地进行国内期货和期权工具交易几个月后，该公司成为中国的“合格境外机构投资者”。</p>   <p>The wider access it gained with that licence covers bonds, futures and options in addition to stocks it traded via China's Stock Connect Programme.翻译:除了通过中国股市互联互通计划交易的股票之外，该公司获得了更广泛的准入范围，涵盖债券、期货和期权。</p>   <p>This year, Citadel Securities also launched an investment-grade corporate bond market-making business in the United States. It is now looking to bring that business to Asia. Currently, it focuses on helping clients in Asia trade in U.S. assets such as U.S. Treasuries and U.S. dollar interest rate swaps.翻译:今年，Citadel 证券还在美国推出了投资级公司债券做市业务。该公司现在正寻求将该业务带到亚洲。目前，它专注于帮助亚洲客户进行美国国债和美元利率掉期等美国资产交易。</p>   <p>Since 2020, the brokerage has more than doubled its Asia Pacific headcount to nearly 300 people, a contrast to the wider trend of Wall Street layoffs amid depressed deal activity due to high interest rates and geopolitical uncertainty.翻译:自 2020 年以来，该券商的亚太区员工人数增加了一倍多，达到近 300 人，这与高利率和地缘政治不确定性导致交易活动低迷导致华尔街裁员的更广泛趋势形成鲜明对比。</p>    <span>Reporting by Summer Zhen and Selena Li in Hong Kong; Editing by Sumeet Chatterjee and Edwina Gibbs翻译:甄夏和李赛琳在香港的报道；苏米特·查特吉和埃德温娜·吉布斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 07:34:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">VTMXHVAPSFNMBBNEFTG5F6GOCI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/citadel-securities-explores-china-licence-beijing-steps-up-market-making-program-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Selena Li, Summer Zhen]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CITADEL SECURITIES</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早盘竞价：芯片股欢呼雀跃，其他股则回落]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/LqyaWWGJm4xs_tyDkyawqOycy5I=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PP72QROYJZMBPM2C4NWXBOF7JI.jpg" alt="German share price index DAX graph is pictured at the stock exchange in Frankfurt翻译:德国股价指数 DAX 图为法兰克福证券交易所" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The German share price index DAX graph is pictured at the stock exchange in Frankfurt翻译:德国股价指数 DAX 图为法兰克福证券交易所, Germany, October 30, 2023.    REUTERS/Staff/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>A look at the day ahead in European and global markets from Kevin Buckland翻译:凯文·巴克兰 (Kevin Buckland) 对欧洲和全球市场未来一天的展望</p>   <p>Chip stocks gave Asian equity investors some small bit of cheer to start the week, picking up where Wall Street left off while U.S. yields stayed subdued, which kept a lid on the dollar, too.翻译:本周伊始，芯片股给亚洲股市投资者带来了一些小小鼓舞，在华尔街股市停顿的情况下有所回升，而美国收益率依然低迷，这也限制了美元的走势。</p>   <p>But elsewhere, bears were firmly in control.翻译:但在其他地方，空头牢牢控制着局面。</p>   <p>A lot of that can likely be traced to China, rather than to the Moody's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/moodys-changes-outlook-united-states-ratings-negative-2023-11-10/">downgrade</a> to the outlook for the U.S. sovereign debt rating, which investors have taken in stride.翻译:其中很大一部分原因很可能是中国造成的，而不是穆迪对美国主权债务评级前景<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/moodys-changes-outlook-united-states-ratings-negative-2023-11-10/">的下调</a>，投资者对此泰然处之。</p>   <p>The Chinese consumer has so far refused to ride to the rescue of the world's second-largest economy. Monthly retail sales data is due on Wednesday but the country's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-singles-day-sales-festival-wraps-up-with-e-commerce-giants-reporting-2023-11-12/">Singles Day</a> shopping extraganza over the weekend - equivalent to Black Friday sales elsewhere - recorded only meagre growth.翻译:迄今为止，中国消费者拒绝出手拯救世界第二大经济体。月度零售销售数据将于周三公布，但该国周末的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-singles-day-sales-festival-wraps-up-with-e-commerce-giants-reporting-2023-11-12/">双十一</a>购物狂欢——相当于其他地方的黑色星期五销售——仅录得微弱增长。</p>      <p>Looking across the region, Japan's tech-heavy Nikkei managed to keep its head above water, buoyed by gains for its two biggest chip-related shares; Taiwan's benchmark advanced 0.8%.翻译:纵观整个地区，日本以科技股为主的日经指数在其两只最大的芯片相关股票上涨的提振下成功保持了水面。台湾股市基准上涨 0.8%。</p>   <p>But Hong Kong flipped from early gains to a loss of about 0.15%. A sub-index of tech shares remained firmly positive but another of mainland property developers slumped more than 1%.翻译:但香港股市从早盘上涨转为下跌约 0.15%。科技股分类指数依然坚挺，但另一家内地房地产开发商则下跌超过 1%。</p>   <p>China's blue chips fell 0.5%.翻译:中国蓝筹股下跌0.5%。</p>   <p>U.S. retail sales data is also due on Wednesday, preceded by CPI a day earlier. The figures could be key in helping the Federal Reserve to plot the path ahead for interest rates, including whether another hike is needed.翻译:美国零售销售数据也将于周三公布，消费者物价指数 (CPI) 早于前一天公布。这些数据可能是帮助美联储规划未来利率路径的关键，包括是否需要再次加息。</p>   <p>The Fed's rhetoric has taken a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/feds-powell-not-confident-policy-is-tight-enough-supply-side-help-may-be-2023-11-09/">hawkish turn</a> recently, but markets so far are more focused on the data, particularly the soft non-farm payrolls numbers at the start of this month.翻译:美联储的言论最近<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/feds-powell-not-confident-policy-is-tight-enough-supply-side-help-may-be-2023-11-09/">转向鹰派</a>，但迄今为止市场更关注数据，尤其是本月初疲软的非农就业数据。</p>   <p>ECB President Christine Lagarde last week <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/ecb-rates-held-long-enough-could-get-inflation-target-lagarde-2023-11-10/">said</a> that rates will stay restrictive at least for several quarters. Lagarde deputy Luis de Guindos has his say a little later today, giving the keynote speech to kick off Euro Finance Week.翻译:欧洲央行行长拉加德上周<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/ecb-rates-held-long-enough-could-get-inflation-target-lagarde-2023-11-10/">表示</a>，利率将至少在几个季度内保持限制性。拉加德副手路易斯·德金多斯今天晚些时候发表讲话，为欧洲金融周拉开序幕。</p>   <p>Elswhere, Bank of England board member Catherine L. Mann will take the podium, after the bank's chief economist, Huw Pill, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/bank-england-isnt-making-promises-rates-pill-says-2023-11-09/">said</a> last week its projection that monetary policy will need to remain restrictive for an extended period should not be taken as a promise.翻译:在其他地方，英格兰银行董事会成员凯瑟琳·L·曼(Catherine L. Mann)将走上讲台，此前该行首席经济学家休·皮尔(Huw Pill)上周<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/bank-england-isnt-making-promises-rates-pill-says-2023-11-09/">表示</a>，其关于货币政策将需要在较长时期内保持限制性的预测不应被视为承诺。</p>   <p>Key developments that could influence markets on Monday:翻译:可能影响周一市场的主要事态发展：</p>   <p>-ECB's de Guindos, BoE's Mann speak翻译:-欧洲央行德金多斯、英国央行曼恩讲话</p>   <p>-UK Rightmove house prices翻译:-英国Rightmove房价</p>   <p>-Sweden SEB housing翻译:-瑞典SEB住房</p>   <p>-New York Fed consumer expectations survey翻译:-纽约联储消费者预期调查</p>    <span>Reporting by Kevin Buckland; Editing by Edmund Klamann翻译:凯文·巴克兰报道；编辑：埃德蒙·克拉曼</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 06:57:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">P6JUSTZOC5PHDLMYB3STM65H7U</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/global-markets-view-europe-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>EUROPE</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[亚太经合组织经济增长将因持续通胀和中美紧张局势而放缓]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/eCDSPyh1pU77A1KvPmnvd6LoPxo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/F2QY5RM6CROSTKNVQBQ2KNRM5Q.jpg" alt="U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen visits China翻译:美国财长耶伦访华" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. and Chinese flags are set up before a meeting between U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen and Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng in Beijing, China, Saturday, July 8, 2023. Mark Schiefelbein/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:2023 年 7 月 8 日星期六，美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦与中国国务院副总理何立峰在中国北京会晤之前，美国和中国国旗已升起。Mark Schiefelbein/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Economic growth among Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation countries is expected to decline next year and remain below the global average as higher interest rates slow U.S. growth, as China continues to struggle with its recovery and tensions between the two hamper trade, the body said on Sunday.翻译:亚太经合组织周日表示，由于美国经济增长放缓，中国继续在复苏中苦苦挣扎，以及两国之间的紧张关系阻碍了贸易，亚太经济合作组织国家的经济增长预计明年将下降，并仍低于全球平均水平。</p>   <p>The APEC Secretariat's Policy Support Unit issued <a href="https://www.apec.org/docs/default-source/publications/2023/11/223_psu_arta-november-2023.pdf?sfvrsn=46d01f79_2" target="_blank">new forecasts</a> on the eve of the APEC leaders' summit in San Francisco, showing that the 21-country region's growth rate would dip to 2.8% in 2024 from 3.3% in 2023.翻译:APEC秘书处政策支持小组在旧金山APEC领导人峰会前夕发布<a href="https://www.apec.org/docs/default-source/publications/2023/11/223_psu_arta-november-2023.pdf?sfvrsn=46d01f79_2" target="_blank">新预测</a>，显示21国地区的增长率将从2023年的3.3%降至2024年的2.8%。</p>   <p>The APEC GDP growth rate will average 2.9% in 2025 and 2026, below the global average of 3.2% and 3.5-3.6% in the rest of the world.翻译:2025年和2026年APEC GDP增长率平均为2.9%，低于全球平均水平3.2%和世界其他地区3.5-3.6%。</p>   <p>Among key downside risks for the Pacific Rim region are persistent inflation associated with export restrictions, weather conditions that have raised the price of rice and other agricultural products, and disruptions in the fertilizer supply chain. Taming inflation could require more monetary policy tightening, slowing growth further.翻译:环太平洋地区的主要下行风险包括与出口限制相关的持续通货膨胀、导致大米和其他农产品价格上涨的天气条件以及化肥供应链的中断。抑制通胀可能需要进一步收紧货币政策，从而进一步放缓经济增长。</p>   <p>Trade volume growth for goods is set to rebound next year among APEC countries after a largely flat 2023 due to China's sluggish growth, rising to 4.3% for goods exports and 3.5% for goods imports. But growth of both exports and imports are forecast to peak at 4.4% in 2025, declining slightly in 2026 due to geo-political fragmentation that is disrupting longstanding supply relationships.翻译:由于中国增长乏力，APEC 国家的货物贸易量增长在 2023 年基本持平后，明年将出现反弹，货物出口增长至 4.3%，货物进口增长至 3.5%。但预计出口和进口增长将在 2025 年达到 4.4% 的峰值，并在 2026 年因地缘政治分裂破坏长期供应关系而略有下降。</p>   <p>Carlos Kuriyama, director of the APEC policy support unit, said the data show that it was important for the U.S. and China to patch up their differences after years of tariff battles and national security export restrictions.翻译:APEC政策支持部门主任卡洛斯·栗山表示，数据显示，经过多年的关税战和国家安全出口限制，美国和中国弥合分歧非常重要。</p>   <p>U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping are <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/">expected to meet in-person</a> for the first time in a year on Wednesday in a high-stakes session aimed at curbing tensions between the world's two largest economies.翻译:美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/">预计将于周三举行一年来首次面对面会面，这是</a>一场旨在遏制世界最大两个经济体之间紧张关系的高风险会议。</p>   <p>Kuriyama said that national security-driven export controls and other restrictions between the U.S. and China are driving up costs in supply chains that were previously optimized for efficiency. While a full return to pre-COVID-19 trading patterns is not possible, avoiding further fragmentation is important, he added.翻译:栗山表示，美国和中国之间以国家安全为导向的出口管制和其他限制正在推高供应链的成本，而此前这些供应链是为了提高效率而优化的。他补充说，虽然不可能完全恢复到 COVID-19 之前的交易模式，但避免进一步的碎片化很重要。</p>   <p>The data shows "how important it is to re-engage, de-risk and avoid decoupling" of the U.S. and Chinese economies. "I think a stable relationship within U.S. and China is a win-win situation for everyone," Kuriyama said.翻译:这些数据显示了中美经济“重新接触、降低风险和避免脱钩的重要性”。 “我认为中美之间稳定的关系对每个人来说都是双赢的局面，”栗山说。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Lawder Editing by Stephen Coates翻译:大卫·劳德报道 斯蒂芬·科茨编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 06:56:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">XTMQBXJEWZOMNKIRGWPEZSGYNA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/apecs-growth-slow-persistent-inflation-us-china-tensions-weigh-report-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Lawder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/FORECASTS</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国高科技制造业贷款引发廉价出口浪潮担忧]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/3OdFEr3NfWGFFjMhns-jzWXYU4Q=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CUXMDL47M5M57BNN4BJGSVBJBI.jpg" alt="Production line of a semiconductor chip company in Suqian翻译:宿迁某半导体芯片公司生产线" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An employee works on the production line of a semiconductor chip company in Suqian, Jiangsu province, China February 28, 2023. China Daily via REUTERS  ATTENTION EDITORS - THIS IMAGE WAS PROVIDED BY A THIRD PARTY. CHINA OUT./File Photo翻译:2023 年 2 月 28 日，一名员工在中国江苏省宿迁市一家半导体芯片公司的生产线上工作。《中国日报》（路透社）注意编辑 - 此图片由第三方提供。中国出局。/资料图</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/byuWSFDkV50_zbWKff4NZnQl1DU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2MDHXGR2JJIP7MJAVIHQ5WY7X4.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of semiconductor chips and Chinese flag翻译:半导体芯片和中国国旗插画图片" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Worker miniatures are placed among the flag of China and printed circuit boards with semiconductor chips, in this illustration picture taken July 5, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张摄于 2023 年 7 月 5 日的插图中，工人的微缩模型被放置在中国国旗和带有半导体芯片的印刷电路板之间。REUTERS/Florence Lo/插图/档案照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>China's leaders, determined to upgrade manufacturing, are steering money toward makers of high-tech products, from semiconductors to EVs, raising fears that overcapacity will fuel a new wave of cheap exports.翻译:中国领导人决心升级制造业，正在将资金转向从半导体到电动汽车等高科技产品制造商，这引发了人们对产能过剩将助长新一轮廉价出口浪潮的担忧。</p>   <p>Lending data from China's central bank offers a glimpse of government priorities: as of the end of September, outstanding loans to the troubled property sector fell 0.2% year-on-year but lending to the manufacturing sector jumped 38.2%.翻译:中国央行的贷款数据让我们一睹政府的优先事项：截至9月底，陷入困境的房地产行业的未偿还贷款同比下降0.2%，但制造业的贷款猛增38.2%。</p>   <p>Economists caution that this wave of investment differs in key respects from an earlier capital investment surge that, among other effects, inflated China's solar panel industry, triggered a trade fight and put scores of companies out of business.翻译:经济学家警告说，这波投资浪潮在关键方面与之前的资本投资激增有所不同，后者的影响之一是使中国太阳能电池板行业膨胀，引发贸易战并使数十家公司破产。</p>   <p>But the trend has alarmed some key trading partners, particularly in Europe where an investigation into Chinese EV subsidies is underway.翻译:但这一趋势引起了一些主要贸易伙伴的警惕，特别是在欧洲，那里正在对中国电动汽车补贴进行调查。</p>   <p>"There is lower consumption in China right now but you have massive overcapacity that is being pushed out to the world, including in batteries, solar and chemicals," said Jens Eskelund, president of the European Chamber of Commerce in Beijing.翻译:北京欧盟商会会长延斯·埃斯克伦德表示：“目前中国的消费量有所下降，但大量产能过剩正在被推向世界各地，包括电池、太阳能和化学品领域。”</p>   <p>"Europe and China are like two trains that are going to collide," Eskelund said, referring to trade.翻译:“欧洲和中国就像两列即将相撞的火车，”埃斯凯伦德在谈到贸易时表示。</p>   <p>China's industrial policy will be on the agenda at this week's meeting of the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum in San Francisco, where Chinese President Xi Jinping is expected to meet U.S. President Joe Biden.翻译:中国的产业政策将成为本周在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织（APEC）论坛会议的议程，预计中国国家主席习近平将在会上会见美国总统乔·拜登。</p>   <p>Under Xi, China has sought to make itself an advanced manufacturing powerhouse for high-end goods for the world, including EVs, wind turbines, aerospace components and advanced semiconductors. Critics say the push has come at the expense of another need - to get China to consume more and export less, a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/part-chinas-economic-miracle-was-mirage-reality-check-is-next-2023-09-03/">structural shift</a> many economists see as key to preserving high levels of growth.</p>       <h 1="">ADVANCED SECTORS</h>  <p>Policymakers have struggled with overcapacity before. Stimulus following the 2007-2008 global financial crisis triggered a boom in steel, solar and other areas, but also generated growth that ultimately helped absorb much of that new production, said Frederic Neumann, chief Asia economist at HSBC.翻译:政策制定者此前一直在与产能过剩作斗争。汇丰银行首席亚洲经济学家 Frederic Neumann 表示，2007-2008 年全球金融危机后的刺激措施引发了钢铁、太阳能和其他领域的繁荣，但也带来了增长，最终帮助吸收了大部分新产量。</p>   <p>This time, the government's focus is narrower, targeting high-tech and "advanced manufacturing", a goal laid out in 2021 in the 14th five-year plan.翻译:这一次，政府的关注重点更窄，瞄准了高科技和“先进制造业”，这是“十四五”规划中2021年制定的目标。</p>   <p>"China has adopted a strategy to shift investment spending from the real estate sector into manufacturing, which will drive up capacity further. Rather than boosting goods absorption via surging construction, China is opting to drive up the capacity of goods-producing industries," said Neumann.翻译:“中国采取了将投资支出从房地产行业转向制造业的战略，这将进一步提高产能。中国没有通过激增的建设来促进商品吸收，而是选择提高商品生产行业的产能，”他表示。诺依曼。</p>   <p>"Global markets, unfortunately, are not in a position to absorb the additional capacity."翻译:“不幸的是，全球市场无法吸收额外的产能。”</p>   <p>Another difference from previous episodes of overcapacity: the sums are smaller.翻译:与以往产能过剩时期的另一个不同之处是：总额较小。</p>   <p>The headline growth rate for financing into manufacturing is likely close to 18%, said Tao Wang, chief China economist at UBS, because the other major source of financing for companies - bonds - is down sharply, meaning a more modest combined increase.翻译:瑞银首席中国经济学家王涛表示，制造业融资的总体增长率可能接近18%，因为企业的另一个主要融资来源——债券——大幅下降，这意味着综合增长将更为温和。</p>   <p>And overall investment growth in Chinese manufacturing has been slowing as producers respond to a weak market.翻译:由于生产商应对疲软的市场，中国制造业的整体投资增长一直在放缓。</p>   <p>"Orders and profits are down and they tend to react to that," said Wang.翻译:“订单和利润下降，他们往往会对此做出反应，”王说。</p>   <p>Still, investment in high-tech manufacturing outpaces the rest of the sector. It grew 11.3% in the first nine months of 2023 year-on-year, compared with 6.3% for overall manufacturing investment, according to data from China's National Bureau of Statistics.翻译:尽管如此，对高科技制造业的投资仍然超过了该行业的其他领域。中国国家统计局的数据显示，2023 年前 9 个月，制造业投资同比增长 11.3%，而整体制造业投资增长 6.3%。</p>      <p>A Reuters review of more than 100 publicly available policy documents and state media reports found that dozens of provincial and municipal governments are increasing the proportion of government loans directed to green development, advanced manufacturing and strategic industries.翻译:路透社对100多份公开政策文件和官方媒体报道的审查发现，数十个省市政府正在提高针对绿色发展、先进制造业和战略性产业的政府贷款比例。</p>   <p>For example, Guangdong province has increased lending to both high-tech and advanced manufacturing by about 45%, state media reported. During the first half of 2023, outstanding loans to the high-tech manufacturing sector in the eastern province of Shandong jumped 67%.翻译:例如，据官方媒体报道，广东省已将高科技和先进制造业的贷款增加了约 45%。 2023年上半年，东部省份山东省高科技制造业的贷款余额猛增67%。</p>   <p>By the end of September, Dongguan, a southern manufacturing city of 7.5 million people, had a total outstanding loan balance to high-tech companies of 246 billion yuan ($33.7 billion), about a fifth of its economy.</p>    <h 1="">OVERCAPACITY</h>  <p>Signs of excess capacity are appearing.翻译:产能过剩的迹象正在显现。</p>   <p>Forecasts indicate China will soon be able to meet all global demand for lithium-ion batteries, said Duo Fu, vice president of Rystad Energy.翻译:Rystad Energy副总裁多夫表示，预测表明中国很快就能满足全球对锂离子电池的所有需求。</p>   <p>Similarly, its automakers, including EV producers, had the capacity to produce 43 million cars a year at the end of 2022, with plants operating at just 54.5% capacity, China Passenger Car Association (CPCA) data show.翻译:同样，中国乘用车协会 (CPCA) 的数据显示，到 2022 年底，包括电动汽车生产商在内的中国汽车制造商的年产量为 4300 万辆，但工厂开工率仅为 54.5%。</p>   <p>Unfortunately, sluggish economic growth and stunted consumption limits what can be purchased domestically.翻译:不幸的是，经济增长乏力和消费低迷限制了国内购买。</p>   <p>After decades of prioritising supply, household consumption accounted for only 38% of gross domestic product in 2021 - even before the harshest COVID-19 lockdowns - compared with 68% for the U.S. and 55% the world average, World Bank data showed.翻译:世界银行的数据显示，经过几十年的优先供应，到 2021 年，即使在最严厉的 COVID-19 封锁之前，家庭消费仅占国内生产总值 (GDP) 的 38%，而美国的这一比例为 68%，世界平均水平为 55%。</p>      <p>In some ways, the race to invest in advanced sectors is helpful for China, said Lu Zhengwei, chief economist at Industrial Bank in Shanghai.翻译:上海兴业银行首席经济学家陆正伟表示，从某些方面来说，投资先进行业的竞赛对中国是有帮助的。</p>   <p>"Generally speaking, I think the investment in the new sectors is healthy and will support the sectors’ long-term development. They are investing while seeing overcapacity, which drives technological development."翻译:“总的来说，我认为对新行业的投资是健康的，将支持这些行业的长期发展。他们在产能过剩的情况下进行投资，这推动了技术发展。”</p>   <p>For the global economy, Chinese production could help curb inflation.翻译:对于全球经济而言，中国的生产可能有助于抑制通胀。</p>   <p>"Far from losing global export market shares, Chinese produces may gain competitiveness," said Neumann. "In turn, this could raise disinflationary pressures in global goods markets, helping to curtail inflation."翻译:“中国产品非但不会失去全球出口市场份额，反而可能会获得竞争力，”诺伊曼说。 “反过来，这可能会增加全球商品市场的通货紧缩压力，有助于抑制通胀。”</p>   <p>Neither point will mitigate trade tensions, particularly as many countries push plans to favour domestic high-tech industries.翻译:这两点都不会缓解贸易紧张局势，特别是在许多国家推行有利于国内高科技产业的计划的情况下。</p>   <p>"Over the long term, we need to have an adjustment process," said a Chinese government trade adviser, speaking on condition of anonymity. "We should let market forces eliminate some firms."翻译:“从长远来看，我们需要一个调整过程，”一位不愿透露姓名的中国政府贸易顾问表示。 “我们应该让市场力量淘汰一些企业。”</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2921 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2921 人民币）</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Siyi Liu; Graphics by Kripa Jayaram; Editing by Robert Birsel翻译:刘思怡补充报道；制图：Kripa Jayaram；罗伯特·伯塞尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 23:09:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RP7DTOXTU5O67M6EW54T7BSSYE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/with-manufacturing-loans-rising-can-china-avoid-new-supply-glut-2023-11-12/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Don Durfee, Kevin Yao, Eduardo Baptista]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>MANUFACTURING (ANALYSIS, GRAPHICS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
