<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 07:27:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[在中国和俄罗斯遭受痛苦之后，投资者窥探廉价芬兰股票的价值]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Finnish industrials premium at 14-year low</li>  <li>NATO membership has reduced Russia risk</li>  <li>OMX Helsinki 25 down 10% in 2023 vs 8% rally for STOXX 600</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>芬兰工业溢价创14年新低</li><li>加入北约降低了俄罗斯的风险</li><li>OMX 赫尔辛基 25 指数 2023 年下跌 10%，而 STOXX 600 指数则上涨 8%</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/350_R-PfE_fc8bsg7-bagS0KJXg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZOYROKUOQVI3RI3QTQ5GJ2WV5A.jpg" alt="Finnish company KONE flag flutters at their headquarters in Espoo翻译:芬兰通力公司旗帜在埃斯波总部飘扬" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Finnish company KONE flag flutters at their headquarters in Espoo翻译:芬兰通力公司旗帜在埃斯波总部飘扬, Finland July 17, 2018. REUTERS/Ints Kalnins</figcaption></figure>       <p>Finland's beaten-down stock market may offer value for investors next year, money managers say, with a potential global economic recovery set to lift the cyclical stocks that dominate the index and NATO membership easing perceived Russia risks.翻译:基金经理表示，芬兰遭受重创的股市明年可能会为投资者带来价值，全球经济潜在复苏将提振主导该指数的周期性股票，而北约成员国身份也将缓解俄罗斯面临的风险。</p>   <p>Finnish stocks are Europe's biggest laggards this year, as risks stemming from tensions with Russia and concerns over China's stuttering recovery have hurt its exporters. In addition, big funds have favoured global mega caps over smaller firms, which make up a large portion of the Nordic country's equity landscape.翻译:芬兰股市是今年欧洲股市中表现最差的，因为与俄罗斯的紧张关系带来的风险以及对中国复苏乏力的担忧损害了其出口商。此外，大型基金更青睐全球大型企业而不是小型企业，而小型企业在北欧国家的股票格局中占很大一部分。</p>   <p>The top 25 stocks in Helsinki are worth a combined $150 billion. Europe's most valuable firm Novo Nordisk <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NOVOb.CO" target="_blank">(NOVOb.CO)</a>, alone, is worth three times that. The OMX Helsinki 25 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.OMXH25" target="_blank">(.OMXH25)</a> has lost 10% this year, versus the STOXX 600's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.STOXX" target="_blank">(.STOXX)</a> 8% rally.翻译:赫尔辛基排名前 25 的股票总价值达 1,500 亿美元。仅欧洲市值最高的公司诺和诺德公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NOVOb.CO" target="_blank">(NOVOb.CO)</a>的市值就达到了这个数字的三倍。 OMX 赫尔辛基 25 指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.OMXH25" target="_blank">(.OMXH25)</a>今年下跌了 10%，而 STOXX 600 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.STOXX" target="_blank">(.STOXX)</a>则上涨了 8%。</p>   <p>Tomas Hildebrandt, senior portfolio manager at Nordic fund manager EVLI, sees Finnish stocks as cheaply valued and likely to benefit from an economic recovery he expects could gain traction in 2024.翻译:北欧基金管理公司 EVLI 的高级投资组合经理托马斯·希尔德布兰特 (Tomas Hildebrandt) 认为，芬兰股票估值低廉，并可能受益于经济复苏，他预计 2024 年经济复苏可能会获得牵引力。</p>   <p>"I don't see any structural issues at the moment that would really spin the global economy into a deeper recession. Hence, I think that the bottom will be reached at some point," said Hilderbrant, who is overweight Finland, but underweight Europe.翻译:希尔德布兰特表示，“目前我认为没有任何结构性问题会真正让全球经济陷入更严重的衰退。因此，我认为在某个时候会触底。”希尔德布兰特增持芬兰，但减持欧洲。 。</p>   <p>"We might be early in our call, but with the outlook of a shallow recession, markets will start to look for a cyclical recovery sometime during next year".</p>    <h 1="">GLOBAL DOWNTURN</h>  <p>Industrial stocks have suffered from a global manufacturing downturn that started in 2022 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/XWPMIM=ECI" target="_blank">(XWPMIM=ECI)</a>. A recent Deutsche Bank study, however, showed some leading indicators -- like South Korean semiconductor exports, which rose in October for the first time in 16 months -- are pointing upwards.翻译:工业股受到 2022 年开始的全球制造业低迷的影响<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/XWPMIM=ECI" target="_blank">(XWPMIM=ECI)</a> 。然而，德意志银行最近的一项研究显示，一些领先指标（例如 10 月份韩国半导体出口 16 个月来首次增长）正在上升。</p>   <p>A recovery should benefit other export-driven markets in Europe, although Finnish equities look more of a bargain. They suffered a harsher derating due to their greater exposure to China and selling linked to concerns over tensions with Russia.翻译:尽管芬兰股市看起来更便宜，但复苏应该有利于欧洲其他出口驱动型市场。由于对中国的敞口加大以及对与俄罗斯紧张关系的担忧导致抛售，它们的评级遭受了更严重的下调。</p>   <p>In April, Finland joined NATO, ending seven decades of military non-alignment and roughly doubling the length of the border the organisation shares with Russia.翻译:4月，芬兰加入北约，结束了长达七年的军事不结盟状态，并将该组织与俄罗斯的边界长度大致增加了一倍。</p>   <p>"Some foreign investors have been selling Finnish stocks after the Ukraine war started due to Russian proximity, but the country risk has declined after Finland joined NATO," said Hertta Alava, senior strategist at the country's top bank Nordea.翻译:芬兰最大银行北欧联合银行高级策略师赫塔·阿拉瓦表示，“乌克兰战争爆发后，由于靠近俄罗斯，一些外国投资者一直在抛售芬兰股票，但芬兰加入北约后，该国风险有所下降。”</p>   <p>Elevator maker Kone <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/KNEBV.HE" target="_blank">(KNEBV.HE)</a>, Helsinki's biggest industrial stock, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finnish-elevator-maker-kone-sells-russian-assets-s8-capital-2023-10-24/">sold its Russian assets</a> in October, 20 months after Russia invaded Ukraine. It has struggled because of its large exposure to China's property sector.翻译:赫尔辛基最大的工业股票电梯制造商通力<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/KNEBV.HE" target="_blank">(KNEBV.HE)</a>在俄罗斯入侵乌克兰 20 个月后，于 10 月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finnish-elevator-maker-kone-sells-russian-assets-s8-capital-2023-10-24/">出售了其俄罗斯资产</a>。由于其在中国房地产行业的投资规模较大，该公司一直在苦苦挣扎。</p>   <p>Kone's update to end-September saw orders falling less than expected thanks to what CEO Henrik Ehrnrooth called a "fantastic quarter" <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/elevator-maker-kones-third-quarter-orders-beat-expectations-strong-china-2023-10-25/">in China</a>. Following a 14% slide this year, the stock is 10% cheaper than rivals Zurich-listed Schindler <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SCHP.S" target="_blank">(SCHP.S)</a> and Otis <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/OTIS.N" target="_blank">(OTIS.N)</a> in the U.S., having traded at a premium of around the same size to both in the last 5 years, according to LSEG data.翻译:通力截至 9 月底的最新数据显示，由于首席执行官 Henrik Ehrnrooth 所说的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/elevator-maker-kones-third-quarter-orders-beat-expectations-strong-china-2023-10-25/">中国</a>“出色的季度”，订单下降幅度低于预期。继今年下跌 14% 后，该股比在苏黎世上市的迅达<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SCHP.S" target="_blank">(SCHP.S)</a>和美国奥的斯<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/OTIS.N" target="_blank">(OTIS.N)</a>的竞争对手便宜 10%，其交易价格与这两家公司在美国的溢价大致相同。根据 LSEG 数据，过去 5 年。</p>   <p>Other underperformers include cyclical material companies such as forestry firms Metsa Board <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/METSB.HE" target="_blank">(METSB.HE)</a> and Stora Enso <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/STERV.HE" target="_blank">(STERV.HE)</a>, and stainless steelmaker Outokumpu <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/OUT1V.HE" target="_blank">(OUT1V.HE)</a>.</p>    <h 1="">"A LOT IS PRICED IN"</h>  <p>Finnish industrials <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.dMIFI0IN00PUS" target="_blank">(.dMIFI0IN00PUS)</a> have commanded an average premium of 28% over European peers <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIEU0IN00PEU" target="_blank">(.MIEU0IN00PEU)</a> in the last decade. That gap has narrowed to a 14-year low of 6%, LSEG data shows.翻译:过去十年，芬兰工业股<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.dMIFI0IN00PUS" target="_blank">(.dMIFI0IN00PUS) 的</a>平均溢价比欧洲同行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIEU0IN00PEU" target="_blank">(.MIEU0IN00PEU)</a>高出 28%。 LSEG 数据显示，这一差距已缩小至 6%，为 14 年来的最低点。</p>   <p>Nordea's Alava said this group had potential to outperform Swedish and French industrials over the next two years, while the broader Finnish market had stronger earnings upside.翻译:北欧联合银行的阿拉瓦表示，该集团有潜力在未来两年超越瑞典和法国工业企业，而更广泛的芬兰市场的盈利上涨空间也更大。</p>   <p>According to LSEG, OMX Helsinki 25 earnings are seen growing 12% in 2024, faster than the 6.7% rise seen for the STOXX, after falling 16% and 1.2% respectively this year.翻译:根据 LSEG 的数据，OMX Helsinki 25 的盈利预计在 2024 年增长 12%，高于 STOXX 6.7% 的涨幅，而今年分别下跌 16% 和 1.2%。</p>   <p>"Finnish stocks are attractively valued and a lot of bad news is priced in," Alava said.翻译:阿拉瓦表示：“芬兰股市估值颇具吸引力，许多坏消息已被消化。”</p>   <p>"If the European economy recovers in 2024 as I expect, Finnish cyclical stocks should recover too... this could be a good time for long-term investors to increase holdings".翻译:“如果欧洲经济如我预期的那样在2024年复苏，芬兰周期性股票也应该复苏……这可能是长期投资者增持的好时机”。</p>    <span>Reporting by Danilo Masoni; Editing by Christina Fincher翻译:达尼洛·马索尼 (Danilo Masoni) 报道；克里斯蒂娜·芬奇编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 07:11:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BFLRGREX5BLKZHYL3RJQV27YF4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/investors-spy-value-cheap-finnish-stocks-after-china-russia-pain-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Danilo Masoni]]></author>
            
                
                <category>EUROPE</category>
                
                <category>STOCKS/FINLAND (ANALYSIS)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[具有里程碑意义的香港国家安全案预计将在3至4个月内判决 - 法官]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/E4zxYUNfo3AAFMiLfKH7MXjMWJY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SWJHBNZIGBNPZBRLDTM37QRCUM.jpg" alt="Owen Chow Ka-shing arrives at West Kowloon Magistrates' Courts building to take part in a hearing, in Hong Kong翻译:周嘉诚抵达香港西九龙裁判法院大楼参加听证会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Owen Chow Ka-shing, one of the 47 pro-democracy activists charged with conspiracy to commit subversion under the national security law, arrives at West Kowloon Magistrates' Courts building, in Hong Kong, China November 29, 2021. REUTERS/Lam Yik/File photo翻译:2021 年 11 月 29 日，被指控串谋颠覆国家安全法的 47 名民主活动人士之一周嘉诚抵达中国香港西九龙裁判法院大楼。 REUTERS/Lam Yik/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>(This story has been refiled to add the dropped word 'were' in paragraph 1)翻译:（这个故事已重新归档，添加了第 1 段中删除的单词“were”）</p>   <p>A landmark national security trial for 16 Hong Kong democracy activists entered its final stretch on Wednesday, with a verdict expected in early 2024, nearly two years after they were charged with conspiracy to commit subversion.翻译:对 16 名香港民主活动人士进行的具有里程碑意义的国家安全审判于周三进入最后阶段，预计将于 2024 年初作出判决，距离他们被指控阴谋颠覆已近两年。</p>   <p>On the first day of closing submissions, one of the handpicked national security judges, Andrew Chan, said a verdict would "tentatively" come in three to four months, with 10 days set aside for closing submissions.翻译:在结案陈词的第一天，精心挑选的国家安全法官安德鲁·陈 (Andrew Chan) 表示，裁决将“暂定”在三到四个月内做出，其中有 10 天的时间用于结案陈词。</p>   <p>This is the first official indication of a potential end point for the legal proceedings, which have already stretched over 100 days in court since the trial began on Feb. 6.翻译:这是该法律诉讼程序可能结束的首次正式迹象，自 2 月 6 日审判开始以来，该诉讼程序已经在法庭上持续了 100 多天。</p>   <p>The legal saga began with police raids on more than 50 of the city's leading democrats in early 2021 under a sweeping China-imposed national security law, which has been criticised as a tool of repression by some Western governments, including the United States.翻译:这场法律传奇始于2021年初，警方根据中国实施的一项全面的国家安全法突袭了该市50多名主要民主党人，该法被包括美国在内的一些西方政府批评为镇压工具。</p>   <p>Beijing says the national security law brought stability to the city after monthslong pro-democracy protests in 2019.翻译:北京表示，在 2019 年长达数月的民主抗议活动之后，国家安全法给这座城市带来了稳定。</p>   <p>The court case could see many leading democrats jailed for life, and is being monitored by Western diplomats in the courtroom.翻译:此案可能导致许多民主党领袖被判终身监禁，法庭上正受到西方外交官的监视。</p>   <p>Throughout the trial, government prosecutors have accused the democrats of hatching a conspiracy to cause a constitutional crisis and to subvert the government by unlawful means: organising a primary election aimed at maximising the democratic opposition's chances of a majority in the legislature.翻译:在整个审判过程中，政府检察官指控民主党密谋引发宪法危机并通过非法手段颠覆政府：组织初选，旨在最​​大限度地提高民主反对派在立法机构中获得多数席位的机会。</p>   <p>The prosecutors alleged the democrats would then seek to "indiscriminately veto" government budgets to push the government to respond to the demands of democratic protesters, with a view to subvert state power, or force Hong Kong's leader to resign.翻译:检方称，民主党人随后将寻求“不加区别地否决”政府预算，以迫使政府回应民主抗议者的要求，以颠覆国家政权，或迫使香港领导人辞职。</p>   <p>During the closing submission, prosecutor Jonathan Man argued that it was quite clear that acts of subversion had taken place, even without actual violence.翻译:在结案陈词中，检察官乔纳森·曼 (Jonathan Man) 辩称，即使没有实际的暴力，也很明显发生了颠覆行为。</p>   <p>"Nowadays physical violence would not be necessary," to conduct subversion, Man told the court, saying such acts were often carried out through digital means including social media.翻译:曼告诉法庭，“现在不再需要身体暴力”来进行颠覆，并表示此类行为通常是通过包括社交媒体在内的数字手段进行的。</p>   <p>"Communication with the public is much easier, (it's) easy to manipulate those means in order to endanger national security," he added.翻译:他补充说：“与公众的沟通更加容易，很容易操纵这些手段来危害国家安全。”</p>   <p>Most of the democrats have been detained for more than 1,000 days since Feb. 28, 2021, on national security grounds, and were subjected to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/hongkong-security-bail/">marathon bail hearings</a>. The case has been repeatedly delayed as prosecutors requested more time to prepare. Only 13 of the original 47 democrats were granted bail.翻译:自2021年2月28日以来，大多数民主党人以国家安全为由被拘留超过1000天，并接受了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/hongkong-security-bail/">马拉松式的保释听证会</a>。由于检察官要求更多时间准备，此案一再被推迟。最初的 47 名民主党人中只有 13 人获准保释。</p>   <p>Thirty-one of the 47 charged have pleaded guilty - which could qualify them for reduced sentences. Only 16 are not pleading guilty, including former journalist Gwyneth Ho; activists Owen Chow and Gordon Ng; and ex-democratic lawmakers Leung Kwok-hung, Lam Cheuk-ting and Helena Wong.翻译:47 名被指控的人中有 31 人已认罪，这可能使他们有资格获得减刑。只有 16 人没有认罪，其中包括前记者 Gwyneth Ho；活动家 Owen Chow 和 Gordon Ng；以及前民主派议员梁国雄、林卓婷和黄海伦。</p>   <p>Those who have pleaded guilty include former law professor Benny Tai and activist Joshua Wong, who will be sentenced after the trial. Four who pleaded guilty have become prosecution witnesses.翻译:已认罪的人包括前法学教授戴耀廷和活动人士黄之锋，他们将在审判后被判刑。四名认罪者已成为控方证人。</p>   <p>(This story has been refiled to add the dropped word 'were' in paragraph 1)翻译:（这个故事已重新归档，添加了第 1 段中删除的单词“were”）</p>    <span>Editing by Gerry Doyle翻译:格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 06:48:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CYYTZNHFQVN5PKY4KP5OEYVCAI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/landmark-hong-kong-national-security-case-verdict-expected-3-4-months-judge-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jessie Pang, James Pomfret]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HONGKONG</category>
                
                <category>SECURITY/ (CORRECTED, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：华为新智能汽车公司在高级股权谈判中估值高达 350 亿美元 - 消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/EB37Lxdi-zvEXw3TlxUATZvRW7o=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CZYX7KX6PVN7FBKH7FCYPMIGAY.jpg" alt="A Chinese flag flutters near a Huawei store in Shanghai翻译:上海一家华为专卖店附近飘扬着中国国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Chinese flag flutters near a Huawei store in Shanghai翻译:上海一家华为专卖店附近飘扬着中国国旗, China, Sept. 8, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Huawei Technologies' (HWT.UL) new smart car software and components firm is set for a valuation of up to 250 billion yuan ($34.67 billion) after it sells stakes to investors including Changan Auto, three people with knowledge of the matter said.翻译:三名知情人士表示，华为技术有限公司 (HWT.UL) 的新智能汽车软件和零部件公司在向长安汽车等投资者出售股份后，估值将高达 2500 亿元人民币（346.7 亿美元）。</p>   <p>The Chinese company said on Sunday it will spin off its four-year-old Intelligent Automotive Solution (IAS) business unit - which aimed to become the equivalent of German automotive supplier Bosch of the intelligent electric vehicle (EV) era - into a new company which will receive the unit's core technologies and resources.翻译:这家中国公司周日表示，将把成立四年的智能汽车解决方案（IAS）业务部门分拆为一家新公司，该部门旨在成为智能电动汽车（EV）时代的德国汽车供应商博世（Bosch）。它将获得该单位的核心技术和资源。</p>   <p>Main auto partner Chongqing Changan Automobile <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/000625.SZ" target="_blank">(000625.SZ)</a> and relevant parties will own up to 40% of the new firm, a Changan Auto <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-huawei-changan-auto-form-joint-auto-systems-venture-2023-11-26/">statement</a> showed on Sunday. Neither Changan Auto nor Huawei disclosed financial details.翻译:长安汽车周日发布<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-huawei-changan-auto-form-joint-auto-systems-venture-2023-11-26/">声明</a>称，主要汽车合作伙伴重庆长安汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/000625.SZ" target="_blank">（000625.SZ）</a>及相关方将持有新公司最多40%的股份。长安汽车和华为均未透露财务细节。</p>   <p>Changan Auto and its ultimate parent, state-owned China Ordnance Equipment Group - also known as China South Industries Group - are considering acquiring about 35% and 5% respectively of the new firm, which could be valued at 200 billion to 250 billion yuan, two of the people said.翻译:长安汽车及其最终母公司、国有的中国兵器装备集团（又称中国兵器装备集团）正在考虑分别收购新公司约35%和5%的股份，估值可能达到2000亿至2500亿元人民币。两个人说道。</p>   <p>Potential minority shareholders include state-owned automakers FAW Group (SASACJ.UL) and Dongfeng Motor Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0489.HK" target="_blank">(0489.HK)</a>, which are also in advanced talks with Huawei to acquire up to 5% each, said the three people.翻译:三名知情人士表示，潜在的少数股东包括国有汽车制造商一汽集团(SASACJ.UL)和东风汽车集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0489.HK" target="_blank">(0489.HK)</a> ，它们也在与华为进行深入谈判，以分别收购最多5%的股份。</p>   <p>Huawei will likely remain the single largest shareholder with 40% to 50% for at least the next two-to-three years, said two of the people.翻译:两位知情人士表示，至少在未来两到三年内，华为可能仍将保持 40% 至 50% 的单一最大股东地位。</p>   <p>Deal details - notably the ownership split and valuation - have not been finalised and are subject to change, the three people said. The transaction will also be subject to regulatory approval, said one of the people as well as a fourth person with knowledge of the matter.翻译:三人表示，交易细节——尤其是所有权分割和估值——尚未最终确定，并且可能会发生变化。一位知情人士和第四位知情人士表示，该交易还将获得监管部门的批准。</p>   <p>The people declined to be identified as the matter is private.翻译:由于此事属于私事，知情人士拒绝透露姓名。</p>   <p>Changan Auto referred Reuters to its Sunday statement and declined to comment further. Huawei and other companies involved did not immediately respond to requests for comment.翻译:长安汽车向路透社提及其周日的声明，但拒绝进一步置评。华为和其他相关公司没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>The spin-off is rare for Huawei whose businesses including telecommunications and consumer electronics have been owned by founder Ren Zhengfei and close to 100,000 shareholding employees since the firm's 1987 founding. In 2020, a year after it was subjected to U.S. sanctions on security grounds, it sold budget smartphone brand Honor to keep the brand alive.翻译:此次分拆对于华为来说是罕见的，自1987年成立以来，华为的电信和消费电子等业务一直由创始人任正非和近10万名持股员工拥有。 2020年，也就是该公司因安全原因受到美国制裁一年后，该公司出售了廉价智能手机品牌荣耀，以维持该品牌的活力。</p>   <p>Three of the people said one reason for the planned sale is that Huawei has struggled to grow the smart car business and needs to recoup capital to cover research and development (R&amp;D) spending.翻译:三名知情人士表示，计划出售的原因之一是华为一直在努力发展智能汽车业务，需要收回资金来支付研发（R&amp;D）支出。</p>   <p>Huawei senior executives including Ren initially pinned high hopes on the unit to be a new growth driver, said the people.翻译:知情人士称，任正非等华为高管最初对该部门寄予厚望，希望该部门成为新的增长动力。</p>   <p>It has invested $3 billion in the unit since its inception and grown its R&amp;D team to 7,000 people, showed the company's 2022 annual report.翻译:该公司2022年年报显示，自该部门成立以来，该公司已向该部门投资30亿美元，并将研发团队扩大到7000人。</p>   <p>Ren did not immediately respond to a Reuters query via the company.翻译:任正非没有立即回复路透社通过该公司提出的询问。</p>   <p>But it was the only money-losing unit among Huawei's main six and brought in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/huawei-backed-aito-says-gets-50000-orders-m7-car-since-relaunch-2023-10-09/">one billion yuan revenue</a> in the first half of 2023, a fraction of the company's 310.9 billion yuan total, Huawei said in August.翻译:但华为在 8 月份表示，它是华为六大业务中唯一亏损的部门，2023 年上半年实现<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/huawei-backed-aito-says-gets-50000-orders-m7-car-since-relaunch-2023-10-09/">收入 10 亿元人民币</a>，仅占该公司 3109 亿元人民币总收入的一小部分。</p>   <p>Huawei has partnerships with other auto companies, including Seres Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601127.SS" target="_blank">(601127.SS)</a> and Jianghuai Automobile <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/600418.SS" target="_blank">(600418.SS)</a>, as well as with Changan Auto involving EV brands Avatr and Deepal.翻译:华为与其他汽车公司建立了合作伙伴关系，包括塞雷斯集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601127.SS" target="_blank">（601127.SS）</a>和江淮汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/600418.SS" target="_blank">（600418.SS）</a> ，以及涉及电动汽车品牌Avatr和Deepal的长安汽车。</p>   <p>The new firm - which Huawei has said will engage in R&amp;D, production, sales and service of intelligent automotive systems and component solutions - will also absorb the group's other auto-related assets and resources outside the IAS business unit, said one of the three people.翻译:其中一位人士表示，华为表示，新公司将从事智能汽车系统和零部件解决方案的研发、生产、销售和服务，还将吸收该集团在IAS业务部门之外的其他汽车相关资产和资源。 。</p>   <p>Huawei is considering locating the new firm's headquarters in Chongqing, a sprawling southwestern municipality where Changan is based, said two of the people. The unit is currently headquartered in Shanghai.翻译:两位知情人士表示，华为正在考虑将新公司总部设在重庆，这是一个庞大的西南直辖市，也是长安汽车的总部所在地。该单位目前总部位于上海。</p>   <p>The proposed deal will also smooth the way for the business' listing, as Huawei had planned, said two of the people.翻译:两位知情人士表示，拟议中的交易还将为华为原计划的上市铺平道路。</p>   <p>Richard Yu, head of Huawei's consumer business and who has overseen the smart car unit for years, is unlikely to lead the new firm, one of the people said without elaborating.翻译:一位知情人士表示，华为消费者业务负责人、多年来负责智能汽车部门的余承东不太可能领导这家新公司，但没有详细说明。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2111 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2111 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Julie Zhu and Zhuzhu Cui; Additional reporting by David Kirton; Editing by Brenda Goh and Christopher Cushing翻译:朱莉朱、崔朱朱报道；大卫·科顿 (David Kirton) 的补充报道；布伦达·吴和克里斯托弗·库欣编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 06:43:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">GODDPHVY5FKJDGVFSI2BRY4RDU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/huaweis-new-smart-car-firm-valued-up-35-bln-amid-advanced-stake-talks-sources-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Julie Zhu, Zhuzhu Cui]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HUAWEI</category>
                
                <category>AUTOS/ (EXCLUSIVE, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[债券为美联储削减开支的言论欢呼雀跃；猕猴桃苍蝇]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Two-year Treasury yields hit 4-month low</li>  <li>Dollar slides broadly; Gold hits 7-month high</li>  <li>China, Hong Kong stocks sink</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>两年期国债收益率创4个月新低</li><li>美元全面下滑；金价创7个月新高</li><li>中国内地、香港股市下跌</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ATcJg9p9txuNGT_jE7iAFeQTFag=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SOYPWW527ZKYHKNPZB2O6HCXAI.jpg" alt="Pedestrians walk past an electronic board displaying Nikkei share average, outside a brokerage in Tokyo翻译:东京一家经纪公司外，行人走过显示日经平均股价的电子板" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Pedestrians walk past an electronic board displaying Nikkei share average, outside a brokerage in Tokyo翻译:东京一家经纪公司外，行人走过显示日经平均股价的电子板, Japan, October 31, 2023. REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/File Photo翻译:2023 年 10 月 31 日，日本东京一家经纪公司外，行人走过显示日经平均股价的电子板。路透社/Kim Kyung-Hoon/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Treasury yields and the dollar hit multi-month lows on Wednesday after a Fed official made fresh hints of U.S. interest rate cuts, while the New Zealand dollar jumped after its central bank said another hike may be necessary if inflation proves stubborn.翻译:在美联储官员再次暗示美国降息后，美国国债收益率和美元周三触及数月低点，而在新西兰央行表示，如果通胀顽固，可能有必要再次加息后，新西兰元大幅上涨。</p>   <p>In Asia, MSCI's broadest index of Asia-Pacific shares outside Japan <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIAPJ0000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIAPJ0000PUS)</a> briefly hit a one-week high, before weakness in Hong Kong tech shares dragged it to a 0.3% loss.翻译:在亚洲，摩根士丹利资本国际(MSCI)日本以外最广泛的亚太股票指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIAPJ0000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIAPJ0000PUS)</a>短暂触及一周高点，随后香港科技股的疲软拖累该指数下跌0.3%。</p>   <p>Japan's Nikkei <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a> fell 0.3%.翻译:日本日经指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a>下跌 0.3%。</p>   <p>The New Zealand dollar was last up 0.9%, having blown past resistance to top 62 U.S. cents and make a four-month high.翻译:纽元兑美元最后上涨 0.9%，突破阻力位至 62 美分上方，创四个月新高。</p>   <p>The euro, yen, sterling, Australian dollar, yuan, Swiss franc and a host of Asian emerging market currencies also made fresh multi-month peaks on the dollar, while gold shot to a seven-month high above $2,501 an ounce.翻译:欧元、日元、英镑、澳元、人民币、瑞士法郎和一系列亚洲新兴市场货币兑美元汇率也创出新的数月高点，而金价则飙升至每盎司 2,501 美元以上，创七个月新高。</p>   <p>Federal Reserve Governor Christopher <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/feds-waller-increasingly-confident-policy-is-right-spot-2023-11-28/">Waller</a> - an influential and previously hawkish voice at the U.S. central bank - told the American Enterprise Institute on Tuesday that rate cuts could begin in a matter of months, provided inflation keeps easing.翻译:美联储理事克里斯托弗·沃勒（Christopher <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/feds-waller-increasingly-confident-policy-is-right-spot-2023-11-28/">Waller）</a>周二对美国企业研究所表示，如果通胀持续缓和，美联储可能会在几个月内开始降息。</p>   <p>Fed funds futures rallied on the remark to price more than hundred basis points (bps) of cuts in 2024 and a 40% chance they begin as soon as March. Two-year Treasury yields fell sharply and touched fresh lows in the Asia session.翻译:联邦基金期货价格因 2024 年降息幅度超过 100 个基点 (bps) 以及最早于 3 月份开始降息的可能性为 40% 的言论而上涨。两年期国债收益率大幅下跌，并在亚洲时段触及新低。</p>   <p>"The market clearly moved on Governor Waller's opening up the possibility of cuts," said Tapas Strickland, head of market economics at National Australia Bank in Sydney. Waller's remark echoed earlier comments made by Fed Chair Jerome Powell.翻译:悉尼澳大利亚国民银行市场经济主管塔帕斯·斯特里克兰表示，“沃勒州长开放降息的可能性，市场明显发生了变化。”沃勒的言论呼应了美联储主席杰罗姆·鲍威尔早些时候的言论。</p>   <p>The two-year yield hit its lowest since mid-July at 4.69% and the benchmark 10-year yield fell 6 bps to its lowest since September at 4.28%.翻译:两年期国债收益率触及7月中旬以来的最低点4.69%，基准10年期国债收益率下跌6个基点，降至9月以来的最低点4.28%。</p>   <p>The dollar was last down 0.2% at 147.15 yen , having earlier in the day traded at its lowest since Sept. 12 at 146.68. It touched a 3-1/2 month low at $1.1017 per euro .</p>    <h 1="">CONDITIONALITY</h>  <p>Waller's remarks extended what has been a two-week rally in stocks and bonds around the world since a benign U.S. inflation report two weeks ago -- except in China where doubts about the economy and a deepening property crisis have investors decidedly downbeat.翻译:沃勒的言论延续了自两周前美国通胀报告发布以来全球股市和债券已连续两周上涨的势头，但中国除外，对经济的疑虑和不断加深的房地产危机让投资者明显感到悲观。</p>   <p>Global stocks <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIWD00000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIWD00000PUS)</a> are up almost 9% in November and are tracking toward their best month in three years. The Hang Seng <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a> is down 0.4% and hasn't posted a positive month since July.翻译:全球股市<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIWD00000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIWD00000PUS)</a> 11 月份上涨近 9%，并正在朝着三年来最好的月份水平迈进。恒生指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a>下跌 0.4%，自 7 月份以来就没有出现过一个月的上涨。</p>   <p>The latest negative news came from <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/china-food-delivery-firm-meituans-q3-revenue-beats-estimates-2023-11-28/">Meituan</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3690.HK" target="_blank">(3690.HK)</a> which flagged slowing fourth-quarter growth for its mainstay food delivery business. Its shares collapsed 12% to a 3-1/2 year low on Wednesday, despite the company promising a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinas-meituan-launches-1-bln-share-buyback-program-2023-11-28/">$1 billion buyback</a>.翻译:最新负面消息来自<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/china-food-delivery-firm-meituans-q3-revenue-beats-estimates-2023-11-28/">美团点评</a><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3690.HK" target="_blank">（3690.HK）</a> ，该公司的支柱外卖业务第四季度增长放缓。尽管该公司承诺<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinas-meituan-launches-1-bln-share-buyback-program-2023-11-28/">回购 10 亿美元</a>，但其股价周三仍暴跌 12%，跌至 3-1/2 年低点。</p>   <p>The Hang Seng fell 2.4% on Wednesday. Hong Kong interbank rates are at 23-year highs , suggesting cash is draining out of the Asian financial hub and flagging pain for mortgage holders whose payments are often tied to one-month rates.翻译:恒生指数周三下跌 2.4%。香港银行同业拆息处于 23 年来的高位，表明现金正在从这个亚洲金融中心流失，而按揭贷款持有人的还款额通常与一个月利率挂钩，其痛苦也日渐减轻。</p>   <p>Mainland China blue chips <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI300" target="_blank">(.CSI300)</a> fell 1% and are heading for a fourth monthly decline in a row with a 2.5% fall in November.翻译:中国内地蓝筹股<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI300" target="_blank">(.CSI300)</a>下跌1%，并有望连续第四个月下跌，11月份下跌2.5%。</p>   <p>Some analysts are also wary that markets have run with parts of Fed officials' remarks -- flagging possible rate cuts -- even though the comments have been conditional on further declines in inflation and on financial conditions staying restrictive.翻译:一些分析师还对市场跟随美联储官员的部分言论（暗示可能降息）感到谨慎，尽管这些言论是以通胀进一步下降和金融状况保持限制性为条件的。</p>   <p>New Zealand sounded something of a warning note on Wednesday when the central bank <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/new-zealand-keeps-rates-hold-warns-hikes-may-not-be-over-2023-11-29/">slightly lifted its interest rate projections</a> and warned hikes may not be over.翻译:周三，新西兰央行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/new-zealand-keeps-rates-hold-warns-hikes-may-not-be-over-2023-11-29/">小幅上调利率预测</a>，并警告加息可能尚未结束，这听起来有点像警告。</p>   <p>"Bets ought to be guided by conditionality that policy is appropriately tight, not indulged with abandon on over-confidence that Fed is done (premised on linear projections of dis-inflation)," said Mizuho economist Vishnu Varathan.翻译:瑞穗银行经济学家 Vishnu Varathan 表示：“押注应该以政策适度紧缩为条件，而不是因对美联储行动的过度自信而放纵（以反通胀的线性预测为前提）。”</p>   <p>Elsewhere, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/australia-inflation-slows-more-than-expected-oct-2023-11-29/">Australian inflation eased</a> by more than expected.翻译:其他方面， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/australia-inflation-slows-more-than-expected-oct-2023-11-29/">澳大利亚通胀放缓</a>幅度超出预期。</p>   <p>In commodities, Brent crude futures steadied at $81.63 a barrel ahead of a crucial OPEC+ meeting on Thursday to decide output policy in the next months, but prices were set for a monthly drop, while Singapore iron ore futures are up 9.6% in November at $130.50 a tonne.翻译:大宗商品方面，布伦特原油期货稳定在每桶 81.63 美元，周四将召开关键的 OPEC+ 会议，决定未来几个月的产量政策，但价格预计每月下跌，而新加坡铁矿石期货 11 月上涨 9.6%，至 130.50 美元一吨。</p>    <span>Editing by Simon Cameron-Moore and Kim Coghill翻译:西蒙·卡梅伦-摩尔和金·科吉尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 06:25:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MZ2YCZSM6ZO5PLPOYXG3C5TLSY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/global-markets-wrapup-1-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Tom Westbrook]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/ (WRAPUP 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国支付宝将以近 4 亿美元的价格出售印度 Zomato 股份 - 条款清单]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/NEP7AGRbX4aT_mx-7eRcQC4yg_Y=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PQYPH46IEFMOLEI7CZ53HIBJRY.jpg" alt="A delivery worker of Zomato leaves to pick up an order from a restaurant in Mumbai翻译:Zomato 的一名送货员前往孟买一家餐厅领取订单" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A delivery worker of Zomato, an Indian food-delivery startup, prepares to leave to pick up an order from a restaurant in Mumbai, India, July 13, 2021. REUTERS/Francis Mascarenhas/File Photo翻译:2021 年 7 月 13 日，印度食品配送初创公司 Zomato 的一名送货员准备出发去印度孟买一家餐厅取订单。路透社/Francis Mascarenhas/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/rWcpwY0YA3HacZrl4t-8jJbhbQg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/AZI7HIUHWJJMXHHTANKU4KUARQ.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of Indian food delivery company Zomato翻译:印度外卖公司Zomato插画图" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of Indian food delivery company Zomato is seen on its app on a mobile phone displayed in front of its company website in this illustration picture taken July 14, 2021. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张 2021 年 7 月 14 日拍摄的插图图片中，可以在手机应用程序上看到印度食品配送公司 Zomato 的徽标，该应用程序显示在其公司网站前。REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>Chinese payments group Alipay launched a $400 million accelerated bookbuild to sell its stake in Indian food delivery giant Zomato <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ZOMT.NS" target="_blank">(ZOMT.NS)</a>, according to the deal's term sheet on Wednesday.翻译:根据周三的交易条款清单，中国支付集团支付宝启动了一项 4 亿美元的加速簿记建档计划，以出售其在印度食品配送巨头 Zomato <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ZOMT.NS" target="_blank">(ZOMT.NS)</a>的股份。</p>   <p>The deal comes after Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-alipay-plans-near-400-mln-stake-sale-indias-zomato-sources-2023-11-28/">reported</a> on Tuesday that Alipay was planning to sell its 3.4% in Zomato through block deals on the Indian stock exchanges.翻译:此前路透社周二<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-alipay-plans-near-400-mln-stake-sale-indias-zomato-sources-2023-11-28/">报道</a>称，支付宝计划通过印度证券交易所的大宗交易出售其所持 Zomato 3.4% 的股份。</p>   <p>(This story has been corrected to read that Alipay 'is selling', and not 'sells,' stake in Zomato in the headline)翻译:（这篇报道已更正为支付宝“正在出售”，而不是“出售”标题中的 Zomato 股份）</p>    <span>Reporting by Baranjot Kaur in Bengaluru; Editing by Rashmi Aich翻译:Baranjot Kaur 在班加罗尔的报道；拉什米·艾奇编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 06:01:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">W3PO5HKBLJJJZGPE72XLTFWYJM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinas-alipay-sells-stake-indias-zomato-nearly-400-mln-term-sheet-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ZOMATO</category>
                
                <category>INDIA/ANT</category>
                
                <category>STAKE (CORRECTED, URGENT, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[斯里兰卡与债权国达成债务重组协议——政府消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/5WbrX6hnu6ywzW2A-Ybfv2nqlx8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5K6QBZQJR5LLRDZK2E4IMRZST4.jpg" alt="A general view of the business district in Colombo翻译:科伦坡商业区全景" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A general view of the business district in Colombo翻译:科伦坡商业区全景, Sri Lanka, September 9, 2020. REUTERS/Dinuka Liyanawatte翻译:2020 年 9 月 9 日，斯里兰卡科伦坡商业区全景。REUTERS/Dinuka Liyanawatte</figcaption></figure>       <p>Sri Lanka has been informed that a debt-restructuring agreement with creditor nations has been reached but is yet to receive a letter of confirmation from the official creditor committee, a government source told Reuters on Wednesday.翻译:一位政府消息人士周三告诉路透社，斯里兰卡已获悉已与债权国达成债务重组协议，但尚未收到官方债权人委员会的确认函。</p>   <p>Sri Lanka, mired in its worst financial crisis in decades, has been trying to reach restructuring deals with creditors since last year, having being forced to default on its foreign debt in May 2022 after its foreign exchange dwindled to record lows.翻译:斯里兰卡深陷数十年来最严重的金融危机，自去年以来一直试图与债权人达成重组协议，并在2022年5月外汇跌至历史低点后被迫外债违约。</p>   <p>"Sri Lanka has been informed of an agreement," the source, who did not want to be identified, said. "It is confirmed that an agreement has been reached with bilateral lenders but we are still waiting on an official letter. We expect it soon."翻译:“斯里兰卡已获悉已达成协议，”这位不愿透露姓名的消息人士表示。 “已确认已与双边贷款机构达成协议，但我们仍在等待正式信函。我们预计很快就会收到。”</p>   <p>Japan co-chairs the official creditor committee, together with France and India. China is Sri Lanka's largest bilateral creditor and is an observer in the group, steering clear of joining the group as a formal member.翻译:日本与法国和印度共同担任官方债权人委员会主席。中国是斯里兰卡最大的双边债权国，也是该组织的观察员，但并未以正式成员身份加入该组织。</p>   <p>The agreement with the group of creditor nations comes about a month after the heavily indebted island nation reached a deal with the Export-Import Bank of China (EXIM) covering about <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/sri-lanka-says-it-has-deal-with-china-exim-bank-cover-42-bln-debt-2023-10-12/">$4.2 billion</a> of outstanding debt.翻译:与债权国集团达成协议大约一个月前，这个负债累累的岛国与中国进出口银行（EXIM）达成协议，涵盖约<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/sri-lanka-says-it-has-deal-with-china-exim-bank-cover-42-bln-debt-2023-10-12/">42 亿美元</a>的未偿债务。</p>   <p>The EXIM deal will help Sri Lanka clear the first review of an International Monetary Fund (MF) bailout, and secure a second IMF tranche of about $334 million, the country's finance ministry had said.翻译:斯里兰卡财政部表示，EXIM 协议将帮助斯里兰卡通过国际货币基金组织 (MF) 救助的首次审查，并获得国际货币基金组织 (IMF) 约 3.34 亿美元的第二笔援助。</p>   <p>Sri Lanka's total external debt is estimated at $36.6 billion, which includes $10.94 billion of bilateral debt, according to latest data released by its finance ministry.翻译:根据斯里兰卡财政部公布的最新数据，斯里兰卡外债总额估计为366亿美元，其中双边债务为109.4亿美元。</p>   <p>The country also needs to reach an agreement with bondholders who hold the bulk of the island's $12.5 billion worth of international sovereign bonds.翻译:该国还需要与持有该岛价值 125 亿美元国际主权债券大部分的债券持有人达成协议。</p>   <p>Sri Lanka's dollar bond maturing in July 2026 was last up 0.42 cents at 50.48 cents, according to Tradeweb data.翻译:根据 Tradeweb 数据，斯里兰卡于 2026 年 7 月到期的美元债券最后上涨 0.42 美分，至 50.48 美分。</p>    <span>Writing by Sudipto Ganguly; Editing by Jacqueline Wong and Kim Coghill翻译:苏迪普托·甘古利 (Sudipto Ganguly) 撰写；编辑：Jacqueline Wong 和 Kim Coghill</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:50:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2K5AHAIRCVIWVG5E6L7YBZ75XI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/sri-lanka-reaches-debt-restructuring-deal-with-creditor-nations-government-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Uditha Jayasinghe]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SRI LANKA</category>
                
                <category>CRISIS/DEBT (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国蔚来汽车与吉利汽车电池交换合作]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/nLK5jCNYkY_1yvWk9kwbKi1Och0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/L35EMSBM7BP5TIIR7NLSTHKP6Q.jpg" alt="Chinese EV brands face steep ramp-up in Europe翻译:中国电动汽车品牌在欧洲面临急剧增长" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of NIO seen on an EL6 car model is pictured at the NIO House, the showroom of the Chinese premium smart electric vehicle manufacture NIO Inc. in Berlin, Germany August 17, 2023. REUTERS/Annegret Hilse翻译:2023 年 8 月 17 日，德国柏林，中国高端智能电动汽车制造商蔚来公司 (NIO Inc.) 的展厅 NIO House 上的 EL6 车型上看到的 NIO 标志。 REUTERS/Annegret Hilse</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/w-xZRJ0qyHdGi-ASdMAXcmR_UJQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GUOAMZX7NNJ5JMWHHND4HCKERQ.jpg" alt="China International Supply Chain Expo in Beijing翻译:北京中国国际供应链博览会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk past a Geely sign at its booth during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing, China November 28, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo翻译:2023 年 11 月 28 日，在中国北京举行的首届中国国际供应链博览会 (CISCE) 上，人们走过吉利展位上的标志。路透社/Florence Lo</figcaption></figure>               <p>Chinese automakers Nio <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9866.HK" target="_blank">(9866.HK)</a> and Zhejiang Geely Holding Group said on Wednesday they had signed a strategic partnership agreement on battery swapping that would see them work together on standards, technology and model development.翻译:中国汽车制造商蔚来汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9866.HK" target="_blank">（9866.HK）</a>和浙江吉利控股集团周三表示，双方已签署换电战略合作协议，双方将在标准、技术和车型开发方面展开合作。</p>   <p>The deal makes Geely (GEELY.UL), whose brands range from Volvo to Zeekr, the second automaker to sign a battery swapping partnership with Chinese electric vehicle maker Nio.翻译:该交易使得吉利（GEELY.UL）（其品牌包括沃尔沃和Zeekr）成为第二家与中国电动汽车制造商蔚来签署电池更换合作伙伴关系的汽车制造商。</p>   <p>Nio, which has been looking to lower costs, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinas-nio-partner-with-changan-auto-developing-battery-swapping-evs-2023-11-21/">announced a tie-up</a> with Changan Automobile <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/000625.SZ" target="_blank">(000625.SZ)</a> last week.翻译:一直寻求降低成本的蔚来汽车上周宣布与长安汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/000625.SZ" target="_blank">（000625.SZ）</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinas-nio-partner-with-changan-auto-developing-battery-swapping-evs-2023-11-21/">合作</a>。</p>   <p>Battery swapping allows drivers to replace depleted packs quickly with fully charged packs, rather than plugging the vehicle into a charging point.翻译:电池更换允许驾驶员用充满电的电池组快速更换耗尽的电池组，而不是将车辆插入充电点。</p>   <p>Geely and Nio will adopt a "co-investment, co-construction, shared, co-operative" model, the companies said.翻译:双方表示，吉利与蔚来将采取“共投、共建、共享、合作”的模式。</p>   <p>They will look to establish an efficient battery asset management mechanism, build a unified battery swap operation and develop battery swappable vehicles compatible with each other's battery swap systems, the companies added.翻译:双方将建立高效的电池资产管理机制，建立统一的换电运营体系，开发与彼此换电系统兼容的换电汽车。</p>   <p>Nio has been looking to improve profitability. It has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinese-ev-upstart-nio-plans-eliminate-10-its-positions-2023-11-03/">trimmed its workforce</a> and deferred long-term investments to improve efficiency and reduce costs in the face of growing competition since U.S. auto maker Tesla <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a> kicked off a price war at the start of the year.翻译:蔚来一直在寻求提高盈利能力。自美国汽车制造商特斯拉<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a>年初掀起价格战以来，面对日益激烈的竞争，该公司已<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinese-ev-upstart-nio-plans-eliminate-10-its-positions-2023-11-03/">裁员</a>并推迟长期投资，以提高效率并降低成本。</p>   <p>Battery swapping could ease the strain on power grids at peak times when drivers recharge, but industry analysts and executives expect it would only become feasible if batteries become more standardised.翻译:电池更换可以缓解司机充电高峰时段电网的压力，但行业分析师和高管预计，只有电池变得更加标准化，这才变得可行。</p>   <p>Nio, with a plan to nearly double the total number of such stations in China this year, is one of a handful of EV makers betting on battery swapping as a major power option for EVs.翻译:蔚来汽车计划今年将中国此类充电站的总数增加近一倍，是少数押注电池更换作为电动汽车主要动力选择的电动汽车制造商之一。</p>   <p>In 2021, Geely said it aimed to set up 5,000 battery swapping stations for EVs <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-geely-set-up-5000-battery-swapping-stations-by-2025-2021-09-26/">globally by 2025</a>.翻译:2021年，吉利表示，目标是<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-geely-set-up-5000-battery-swapping-stations-by-2025-2021-09-26/">到2025年在全球</a>建立5000个电动汽车电池更换站。</p>   <p>Geely said it currently had 300 stations in operation and it would now continue to build stations alone as well as jointly with Nio.翻译:吉利表示，目前已运营 300 个加油站，并将继续单独以及与蔚来联合建设加油站。</p>    <span>Reporting by Beijing newsroom and Brenda Goh; Editing by Jacqueline Wong and Jamie Freed翻译:北京新闻编辑室和Brenda Goh报道；编辑：杰奎琳·黄和杰米·弗里德</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:48:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">H2DILSWXXRPS3LKEKAU5IGIFVE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-nio-teams-up-with-geely-battery-swapping-projects-media-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>NIO/ (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国最高外交官王毅将于周四访问越南 - 消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/8FaNuojFWh1xX5WXkMpRgTxOkeI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/45GFL7FAMRKDRPPRQQBJECYP7A.jpg" alt="Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi attends a press conference in Beijing翻译:中国外交部长王毅在北京出席记者会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi attends a press conference on the white paper on "A Global Community of Shared Future: China's Proposals and Actions", in Beijing, China September 26, 2023. REUTERS/Shubing Wang/File photo翻译:2023年9月26日，中国外交部长王毅在中国北京出席《构建人类命运共同体：中国的主张与行动》白皮书记者会。路透社/王书兵/资料图</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's top diplomat Wang Yi will visit Vietnam from Thursday, two Vietnamese sources with knowledge of trip said on Wednesday.翻译:两名越南消息人士周三表示，中国最高外交官王毅将从周四开始访问越南。</p>   <p>"He is expected to attend a Vietnam-China inter-government meeting in Hanoi on Friday," one of the sources said.翻译:一位消息人士称：“预计他将于周五出席在河内举行的越南-中国政府间会议。”</p>   <p>Vietnam's and China's foreign ministries did not immediately respond to a requests for comment.翻译:越南和中国外交部没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>China has had traditionally strong ties with Vietnam since diplomatic relations were established in 1950, despite a brief war in 1979.翻译:自 1950 年建交以来，中国与越南传统上一直保持着牢固的关系，尽管 1979 年发生了短暂的战争。</p>   <p>China is Vietnam's largest trading partner and a vital source of imports for its manufacturing sector.翻译:中国是越南最大的贸易伙伴，也是越南制造业的重要进口来源地。</p>   <p>China's Commerce Minister Wang Wentao on Monday during a visit to Vietnam pledged to further open the Chinese market to Vietnamese agricultural products as the two countries seek to deepen trade ties, according to Vietnam's Ministry of Industry and Trade.翻译:据越南工贸部称，中国商务部部长王文涛周一在访问越南期间承诺，随着两国寻求深化贸易关系，将进一步向越南农产品开放中国市场。</p>   <p>Reuters last month reported that Vietnamese and Chinese officials were preparing for a possible trip by Chinese President Xi Jinping to Hanoi. At the time, plans were for the trip to take place at the end of October or in early November. Three Hanoi-based diplomats subsequently said the visit was likely to be postponed to December.翻译:路透社上个月报道称，越南和中国官员正在为中国国家主席习近平可能访问河内做准备。当时计划在十月底或十一月初进行这次旅行。三名驻河内外交官随后表示，此次访问可能会推迟到 12 月。</p>   <p>Bilateral trade between Vietnam and China rose 5.5% last year to $175.5 billion, with shipments from China to Vietnam accounting for 67%, according to the ministry.翻译:据越南商务部称，去年越南和中国的双边贸易增长了5.5%，达到1755亿美元，其中中国对越南的出口额占67%。</p>    <span>Reporting by Hanoi bureau, additional reporting by Ryan Woo in Beijing; Editing by Kanupriya Kapoor翻译:河内分社报道，北京吴瑞安补充报道；卡努普里亚·卡普尔 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:02:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">P2GB2Q5GHNJQFDB5LSO5C2BZ7Q</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/chinas-top-diplomat-wang-yi-visit-vietnam-thursday-sources-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>VIETNAM</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国11月份工厂活动可能连续第二个月收缩]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ThZdlkaNrqi9xkIsprX5Fx04L5w=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MXX5ZK4ZHFIZXDB32HX222DIAQ.jpg" alt="Leapmotor's EV production line in Jinhua翻译:零跑汽车金华电动车生产线" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Robotic arms assemble cars in the production line for Leapmotor's electric vehicles at a factory in Jinhua, Zhejiang province, China, April 26, 2023. China Daily via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:2023 年 4 月 26 日，中国浙江省金华市一家工厂，机械臂在零跑电动汽车生产线上组装汽车。《中国日报》来自路透社/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's manufacturing activity likely contracted for a second consecutive month in November, a Reuters poll showed on Wednesday, keeping alive calls for further stimulus measures as factory owners struggle for orders both at home and abroad.翻译:路透社周三的一项民意调查显示，中国11月份制造业活动可能连续第二个月萎缩，在工厂主努力争取国内外订单之际，要求采取进一步刺激措施的呼声依然高涨。</p>   <p>While the official purchasing managers' index (PMI) is expected to have improved to 49.7 in November from last month's unexpected drop to 49.5, the median forecast of 31 economists in a Reuters poll has the index staying below the 50-point level demarcating contraction from expansion.翻译:虽然官方采购经理人指数 (PMI) 预计 11 月将从上个月意外下降的 49.5 改善至 49.7，但路透调查中 31 名经济学家的预测中值显示，该指数仍低于 50 点的水平，标志着经济萎缩。扩张。</p>   <p>Economists appear in agreement that the economy is still largely struggling for traction despite some signs of green shoots in mixed October data, with all respondents returning readings between 49.0 and 50.2 and the vast majority predicting a small contraction of between 49.6 and 49.8.翻译:经济学家们似乎一致认为，尽管 10 月份混合数据出现了一些复苏迹象，但经济在很大程度上仍难以获得牵引力，所有受访者的读数都在 49.0 至 50.2 之间，绝大多数人预测将出现小幅收缩，在 49.6 至 49.8 之间。</p>   <p>The world's second-largest economy has been unable to mount a strong post-COVID recovery this year as a deep crisis in the property market, local government debt risks, slow global growth and geopolitical tensions dented momentum.翻译:由于房地产市场的深度危机、地方政府债务风险、全球经济增长缓慢和地缘政治紧张局势削弱了经济增长势头，全球第二大经济体今年未能在疫情后实现强劲复苏。</p>   <p>A flurry of policy support measures has had only a modest effect, raising pressure on authorities to roll out more stimulus.翻译:一系列政策支持措施收效甚微，加大了当局推出更多刺激措施的压力。</p>   <p>Profit growth at China's industrial firms <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-industrial-profits-fall-78-jan-oct-2023-11-27/">shrank</a> back to the low single digits last month, following an 11.9% increase in September and a 17.2% gain in August, which analysts attributed to volatile input costs. Both new export and import orders shrank in October.翻译:继9月份增长11.9%和8月份增长17.2%之后，中国工业企业利润增速上个月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-industrial-profits-fall-78-jan-oct-2023-11-27/">回落</a>至低个位数，分析师将其归因于投入成本波动。 10月份新出口和进口订单均出现萎缩。</p>   <p>The sputtering recovery has prompted many analysts to warn that China may begin <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">flirting</a> with Japan-style stagnation later this decade unless policymakers take steps to reorientate the economy towards household consumption and market-allocation of resources.翻译:缓慢的复苏促使许多分析师警告称，除非政策制定者采取措施将经济重新定位为家庭消费和资源市场配置，否则中国可能会在本十年晚些时候开始<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">陷入</a>日本式的停滞。</p>   <p>China's central bank governor <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">said</a> on Tuesday he was "confident that China will enjoy healthy and sustainable growth in 2024 and beyond," but urged structural reforms to reduce reliance on infrastructure and property for growth.翻译:中国央行行长周二<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">表示，</a>他“相信中国将在2024年及以后实现健康、可持续的增长”，但敦促进行结构性改革，减少增长对基础设施和房地产的依赖。</p>   <p>Policy advisers say the government will need to implement further stimulus should it wish to sustain an annual economic growth target of 'around 5%' next year, which would match this year's goal.翻译:政策顾问表示，如果政府希望明年维持“5%左右”的年度经济增长目标（这将与今年的目标相匹配），那么政府将需要实施进一步的刺激措施。</p>   <p>The official PMI will be released on Thursday. The private Caixin factory survey will be issued on Friday, and analysts expect its reading to edge up to 49.8 from 49.5 in October.翻译:官方采购经理人指数将于周四发布。私营财新工厂调查将于周五发布，分析师预计其读数将从 10 月份的 49.5 升至 49.8。</p>    <span>Reporting by Joe Cash; Polling by Susobhan Sarkar and Devayani Sathyan in Bangalore; Editing by Kim Coghill翻译:乔·卡什报道； Susobhan Sarkar 和 Devayani Sathyan 在班加罗尔进行的民意调查；编辑：金·科吉尔</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 04:41:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">J67PW3Q2FBMNNKVGN7I3Z2JMQQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-nov-factory-activity-likely-contracted-second-month-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Joe Cash]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/PMI (UPDATE 1, POLL)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[债权国可能就斯里兰卡债务重组达成一致——报告]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/CfJIy_812YhWKRNj7FARUcgy8Ag=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SRKHWMFHPBORZBDS5FF456UIZU.jpg" alt="Sri Lanka unilaterally suspends external debt payments翻译:斯里兰卡单方面暂停偿还外债" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A vendor prepares a bag for a customer at a wholesale market, amid the country's economic crisis in Colombo, Sri Lanka, April 13, 2022. REUTERS/Dinuka Liyanawatte/File Photo翻译:2022 年 4 月 13 日，斯里兰卡科伦坡，在国家经济危机期间，一名供应商在批发市场为顾客准备袋子。路透社/Dinuka Liyanawatte/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A group of Sri Lanka's creditor nations are likely to reach an agreement on debt relief and an extension of repayment deadlines for the South Asian nation, Japan's Jiji News reported on Wednesday, without naming a source or giving any details.翻译:日本时事新闻周三报道称，斯里兰卡的一些债权国可能会就债务减免和延长这个南亚国家的还款期限达成协议，但没有透露消息来源或提供任何细节。</p>   <p>Japan co-chairs this group, together with France and India. China is Sri Lanka's largest bilateral creditor and has steered clear of joining this group as a formal member.翻译:日本与法国和印度共同担任该小组的主席。中国是斯里兰卡最大的双边债权人，并没有以正式成员的身份加入该组织。</p>   <p>Mired in its worst financial crisis in decades, Sri Lanka has been trying to reach restructuring deals with creditors since last year.翻译:斯里兰卡深陷数十年来最严重的金融危机，自去年以来一直试图与债权人达成重组协议。</p>   <p>The agreement with the group of creditor nations came about a month after the debt-ridden island nation reached a deal with the Export-Import Bank of China covering about $4.2 billion of outstanding debt.翻译:与债权国集团达成协议大约一个月前，这个负债累累的岛国与中国进出口银行达成协议，涵盖约 42 亿美元的未偿债务。</p>   <p>The EXIM deal will help Sri Lanka clear the first review of the bailout by Dec. 6 under the International Monetary Fund (IMF) executive board program, while securing a second IMF tranche of about $334 million, its finance ministry says.翻译:斯里兰卡财政部表示，EXIM 协议将帮助斯里兰卡在 12 月 6 日之前通过国际货币基金组织 (IMF) 执行董事会计划的首次救助审查，同时获得 IMF 的第二笔约 3.34 亿美元的援助。</p>   <p>In so doing, Colombo is also seeking to receive more clarity on its debt restructuring talks with key bilateral creditors. The approval would unlock $330 million in funding and signal progress for the four-year programme.翻译:科伦坡此举还寻求与主要双边债权人的债务重组谈判更加明确。此次批准将释放 3.3 亿美元的资金，标志着该四年计划取得进展。</p>    <span>Reporting by Tetsushi Kajimoto; Editing by Chang-Ran Kim and Miral Fahmy翻译:梶本哲司报道；编辑：Chang-Ran Kim 和 Miral Fahmy</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 04:34:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">DUTBD5TYDNLGDMSS7SD3QTDOKQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/creditor-nations-likely-agree-sri-lanka-debt-restructuring-report-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SRI LANKA</category>
                
                <category>DEBT/ (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国对武汉代孕、假亲子鉴定展开调查]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Chinese authorities have suspended a hospital and a judicial institute in the city of Wuhan from conducting some services after they were accused of surrogacy and issuing fake paternity results.翻译:武汉市一家医院和一家司法机构被指控代孕并出具虚假亲子鉴定结果，中国当局已暂停其提供部分服务。</p>   <p>The suspension comes amid several investigations related to the issuance of fake birth certificates as China, where surrogacy is illegal, tries to boost its birth rate.翻译:此次暂停是在代孕非法的中国试图提高出生率之际，针对签发虚假出生证明进行了几项调查。</p>   <p>Wuhan Puren Hospital has been suspended from releasing birth certificates and Wuhan Ruiboxiang Judicial Appraisal Institute has been suspended from providing judicial appraisal services, the Wuhan Municipal Health Commission said on Tuesday.翻译:武汉市卫生健康委员会周二表示，武汉普仁医院已暂停发放出生证明，武汉瑞博祥司法鉴定所已暂停提供司法鉴定服务。</p>   <p>A task force has been set up to investigate the hospital and institute.翻译:已成立一个工作组对医院和研究所进行调查。</p>   <p>"We will seriously pursue accountability in accordance with laws and regulations based on the investigation," the commission said.翻译:证监会表示：“我们将根据调查结果，依法依规严肃追究责任。”</p>   <p>The hospital and institute were accused of "illegal activities" by an online influencer called Shangguanzhengyi, the official China Daily newspaper reported.翻译:据官方的《中国日报》报道，该医院和研究所被一位名叫上官正义的网络影响者指控为“非法活动”。</p>   <p>He alleged the institute could provide fake paternity test results and parents could provide fake results to reissue the birth certificate, allowing non-biological children to be given a bogus identification.翻译:他声称该机构可以提供虚假的亲子鉴定结果，父母也可以提供虚假的结果来重新签发出生证明，从而允许非亲生子女获得虚假的身份证明。</p>   <p>The service cost around 180,000 yuan ($25,187) in cash, the newspaper said.翻译:该报称，这项服务的现金费用约为 18 万元人民币（25,187 美元）。</p>   <p>The case comes a few weeks after the director of a hospital in China's central Hubei province was investigated for brazenly <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hospital-director-chinas-hubei-under-investigation-selling-birth-certificates-2023-11-08/">selling birth certificates</a>, with the hospital's obstetrics and gynaecology department forced to suspend operations.翻译:几周前，中国中部湖北省一家医院的院长因公然<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hospital-director-chinas-hubei-under-investigation-selling-birth-certificates-2023-11-08/">出售出生证明</a>而受到调查，该医院的妇产科被迫暂停营业。</p>   <p>Birth certificates are required in China for obtaining household registration and are necessary for vaccinations, medical insurance enrolment and application for a social security card.翻译:在中国，办理户口登记、接种疫苗、参加医疗保险和申请社会保障卡都需要出生证明。</p>   <p>Birth rates have fallen in China to their lowest since records began in 1949, at just 9.56 million in 2022.翻译:中国的出生率已降至 1949 年有记录以来的最低水平，2022 年仅为 956 万人。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1463 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.1463 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Farah Master and the Beijing newsroom; Editing by Stephen Coates翻译:法拉·马斯特和北京新闻编辑室的报道；斯蒂芬·科茨编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 04:24:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6DSECOURZVLWVPJYZQPAUUQGAE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-launches-probe-into-surrogacy-fake-paternity-tests-wuhan-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>HOSPITALS/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[朝鲜经济特区有望复兴俄罗斯新贸易]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/1jUgpeIUmg2nIso2A0bNkO61Q68=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NNT654L7FJNEDLSDGCWDEHWTFY.jpg" alt="A satellite image shows a port in Rason翻译:卫星图像显示罗先市的一个港口" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A satellite image shows a port in Rason翻译:卫星图像显示罗先市的一个港口, North Korea, October 27, 2023. Planet Labs Pbc/Handout via REUTERS翻译:卫星图像显示 2023 年 10 月 27 日朝鲜罗先市的一个港口。Planet Labs Pbc/路透社的讲义</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/kutZJXWHp9AnbsFiETCKFcJkD14=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GOFFYSDNPFJOLNTIZPCXFUPG3U.jpg" alt="A satellite image shows a port in Primorsky Krai翻译:卫星图像显示滨海边疆区的一个港口" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A satellite image shows a port in Primorsky Krai翻译:卫星图像显示滨海边疆区的一个港口, Russia, October 27, 2023. Planet Labs Pbc/Handout via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/QrJl5OWBVaSV8NvdtuKXA_qcPHI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/S7JB3QV7LVIBRM4HRRHUMFA3BE.jpg" alt="A North Korean woman drinks beer at a local market in Rajin at the Special Economic Zone of Rason City, northeast of Pyongyang翻译:一名朝鲜妇女在平壤东北部罗先市经济特区罗津的当地市场喝啤酒" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A North Korean woman drinks beer at a local market in Rajin at the Special Economic Zone of Rason City, northeast of Pyongyang翻译:一名朝鲜妇女在平壤东北部罗先市经济特区罗津的当地市场喝啤酒 August 29, 2011. REUTERS/Carlos Barria/File Photo翻译:2011 年 8 月 29 日，平壤东北部罗先市经济特区，一名朝鲜妇女在罗津当地市场喝啤酒。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/9w7fK1epCKBO8mZVuPOPT9f7Vn4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CPC7SOI3U5JIXHPKMYQWAD246E.jpg" alt="Local residents wave as a cruise ship with visitors leaves the port in the North Korean special economic zone of Rason翻译:朝鲜罗先经济特区一艘载有游客的游轮离开港口时，当地居民挥手致意" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Local residents wave as a cruise ship with visitors leaves the port in the North Korean special economic zone of Rason翻译:朝鲜罗先经济特区一艘载有游客的游轮离开港口时，当地居民挥手致意, located northeast of Pyongyang August 30, 2011. REUTERS/Carlos Barria /File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/GaWL1hIv0ccRIY_b4IPj7dG4v8U=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7KNHTBUTOFO6ZKPZRWZQX4R4EM.jpg" alt="A satellite image shows a port in Primorsky Krai翻译:卫星图像显示滨海边疆区的一个港口" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A satellite image shows a port in Primorsky Krai翻译:卫星图像显示滨海边疆区的一个港口, Russia, October 28, 2023. Planet Labs Pbc/Handout via REUTERS翻译:卫星图像显示 2023 年 10 月 28 日俄罗斯滨海边疆区的一个港口。Planet Labs Pbc/来自 REUTERS 的讲义</figcaption></figure>                     <p>Once a North Korean experiment in limited capitalism, the Rason Special Economic Zone appears to be the epicentre of the isolated country's growing cooperation with Russia, experts say, including possible shipments of arms for the war in Ukraine.翻译:专家表示，罗先经济特区曾经是朝鲜有限资本主义的实验，现在似乎成为这个孤立国家与俄罗斯日益加强合作的中心，其中包括可能为乌克兰战争运送武器。</p>   <p>With apartment blocks and booming markets flooded with imported goods, the Rason SEZ, established in the 1990s on the border with China and Russia, was a dream destination for many North Koreans before tighter sanctions hit and pandemic-era border closings choked off nearly all trade and tourism, two experts who study Rason said.翻译:20世纪90年代在中国和俄罗斯边境建立的罗先经济特区，公寓楼和蓬勃发展的市场充斥着进口商品，在更严格的制裁打击和大流行时期的边境关闭导致几乎所有贸易中断之前，它是许多朝鲜人的梦想目的地两位研究罗先的专家说：</p>   <p>In recent months, there have been clear signs that the area is poised for a comeback, with ships docking there for the first time since 2018, and satellite imagery suggesting a spike in trade from both the port and a rail line to Russia.翻译:近几个月来，有明显迹象表明该地区即将卷土重来，船只自 2018 年以来首次在此停靠，卫星图像显示从该港口和一条通往俄罗斯的铁路线的贸易量激增。</p>   <p>Although China - with its vastly larger economy and deeper historic ties with North Korea - might seem the obvious driver of a recovery in Rason, experts say the country's deepening cooperation with Russia may make a more immediate impact.翻译:尽管中国——拥有庞大的经济规模和与朝鲜更深厚的历史关系——似乎是罗先市复苏的明显推动力，但专家表示，中国与俄罗斯深化合作可能会产生更直接的影响。</p>   <p>"Now that North Korea and Russia are becoming very close against the backdrop of the Ukraine war, Russia might send more tourists to North Korea, which can reinvigorate tourism (in Rason)," said Jeong Eunlee, a North Korea economy expert at South Korea’s government-run Korea Institute for National Unification.翻译:韩国经济研究中心朝鲜经济专家郑恩利表示，“现在，在乌克兰战争的背景下，朝鲜和俄罗斯关系变得非常密切，俄罗斯可能会向朝鲜派遣更多游客，这可以重振罗先市的旅游业”。政府运营的韩国国家统一研究院。</p>   <p>Russia can also sell coal, oil, and flour through Rason, Jeong said, and if more North Korean workers are allowed to cross the border, they can send Russian medicine and other goods home for relatives to sell.翻译:郑说，俄罗斯还可以通过罗先出售煤炭、石油和面粉，如果允许更多朝鲜工人越过边境，他们可以将俄罗斯药品和其他货物运回家供亲戚出售。</p>   <p>The Russian Federal Customs Service said it had "temporarily suspended the publication of foreign trade statistics".翻译:俄罗斯联邦海关总署表示，已“暂时停止公布对外贸易统计数据”。</p>   <p>China accounted for 97% of North Korea's overall trade in 2022, according to South Korea's Korea Trade Investment Promotion Agency (KOTRA).翻译:据韩国贸易投资振兴院(KOTRA)称，2022年中国占朝鲜贸易总额的97%。</p>   <p>But Russia resumed <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/russia-resumes-oil-exports-north-korea-after-long-pause-data-2023-06-14/">oil exports</a> to North Korea in December 2022 and had exported 67,300 barrels of refined petroleum to North Korea by April, United Nations data shows, the first such shipments reported since 2020.翻译:但联合国数据显示，俄罗斯于 2022 年 12 月恢复了对朝鲜的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/russia-resumes-oil-exports-north-korea-after-long-pause-data-2023-06-14/">石油出口</a>，截至 4 月已向朝鲜出口了 67,300 桶精炼石油，这是自 2020 年以来首次报告此类出口。</p>   <p>Lee Chan-woo, a North Korea economy expert at Teikyo University in Tokyo, said Russian wood cut by North Korean loggers could be resold to China through Rason, a town of about 200,000 people.翻译:东京帝京大学朝鲜经济专家李赞宇表示，朝鲜伐木工人砍伐的俄罗斯木材可以通过罗先市转售到中国，罗先市是一个约有 20 万人口的城镇。</p>   <p>Cho Sung-chan of Hananuri, a South Korean nonprofit that has financed a food-processing factory in Rason, predicted Russian influence there would grow.翻译:韩国非营利组织 Hananuri 的 Cho Sung-chan 预测，俄罗斯在那里的影响力将会增强。Hananuri 为罗先市的一家食品加工厂提供了资金。</p>   <p>"Assuming North Korea and Russia's honeymoon period becomes a long one, North Korea could get Russian support on food, energy and infrastructure through Rason," Cho said.翻译:“假设朝鲜和俄罗斯的蜜月期变得很长，朝鲜可以通过罗先获得俄罗斯在食品、能源和基础设施方面的支持，”赵说。</p>   <p>The two countries discussed expanding trade and testing delivery of meat products next year, Russia's natural resources minister <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/russian-delegation-led-by-natural-resources-minister-arrives-pyongyang-kcna-2023-11-14/">Alexander Kozlov</a> said on his Telegram channel after meeting with North Korean officials in Pyongyang in November.</p>    <h 1="">MILITARY LOGISTICS</h>  <p>Since August, Rason's port has seen visits from Russian ships linked to that country’s military logistics system, according to U.S. and South Korean officials and reports by Western researchers citing satellite imagery.翻译:据美国和韩国官员以及西方研究人员援引卫星图像的报道，自八月以来，与该国军事后勤系统相关的俄罗斯船只多次访问罗先港。</p>   <p>Those ships are suspected of military supplies from North Korea to Russia, the reports said. The Kremlin has denied such shipments.翻译:报道称，这些船只涉嫌从朝鲜向俄罗斯运送军事物资。克里姆林宫否认有此类货物。</p>   <p>From Rason's port, North Korea has sent Russia an estimated 2,000 containers suspected of carrying artillery shells, and possibly short-range missiles, South Korean military officials have told reporters.翻译:韩国军方官员告诉记者，朝鲜已从罗先港向俄罗斯发送了约 2,000 个集装箱，疑似装有炮弹，可能还有短程导弹。</p>   <p>Since late 2022, activity has been spotted around Rason's Tumangang station, which has rail links to Russia, said Chung Songhak, a senior researcher at the Korea Institute for Security Strategy who analyses satellite imagery around Rason.翻译:韩国安全战略研究所分析罗先周边卫星图像的高级研究员 Chung Songhak 表示，自 2022 年底以来，罗先市土满江站周围就发现了活动，该站有通往俄罗斯的铁路。</p>   <p>More train carriages were spotted after the Russian defence minister visited Pyongyang in July, Chung said, citing satellite imagery, adding that possible new cargo depots popped up in May.翻译:郑先生援引卫星图像说，俄罗斯国防部长7月份访问平壤后发现了更多火车车厢，并补充说5月份可能会出现新的货运站。</p>   <p>When leader Kim Jong Un visited Russia in September, he discussed restarting a stalled joint logistics project in Rason, building a new road bridge connecting it with Russia and additional grain supplies, Kozlov said.</p>    <h 1="">'GLOBAL HUB'</h>  <p>Since Kim’s grandfather Kim Il Sung designated Rason a special zone in 1991 after the Soviet Union’s collapse and as China opened further, North Korean officials have tried to attract investment there.翻译:1991年苏联解体后，金正恩的祖父金日成将罗先指定为特区，随着中国进一步开放，朝鲜官员一直试图在那里吸引投资。</p>   <p>Rason, the oldest and largest of North Korea's 29 economic development zones, has been central to the country's push to attract foreign investment.翻译:罗先是朝鲜 29 个经济开发区中历史最悠久、规模最大的一个，一直是该国吸引外国投资的核心。</p>   <p>It has one of North Korea's first and biggest markets, was the site of the country's first mobile network, and is the only place where North Korea legalised buying and selling homes in 2018, according to experts and North Korea’s government publications.翻译:据专家和朝鲜政府出版物称，这里是朝鲜最早也是最大的市场之一，是该国第一个移动网络的所在地，也是朝鲜 2018 年唯一一个合法买卖房屋的地方。</p>   <p>The other zones have had poor results because of shaky infrastructure and international sanctions, according to South Korea's National Institute for Unification Education.翻译:韩国国家统一教育研究所表示，由于基础设施不稳定和国际制裁，其他地区的成绩不佳。</p>   <p>Abraham Choi, a Korean American pastor who works on religion exchanges with North Korea, said that when he last visited Rason in 2015, he saw both Chinese and Russian tourists.翻译:从事与朝鲜宗教交流工作的韩裔美国牧师亚伯拉罕·崔(Abraham Choi)表示，他上次访问罗先是在2015年，当时他看到了中国和俄罗斯游客。</p>   <p>South Korean media reports said that the Rason border with China had reopened in January 2023 and that trucks were trickling in. Choi said there were no signs yet of large groups of foreign tourists visiting Rason.翻译:韩国媒体报道称，罗先与中国的边境已于 2023 年 1 月重新开放，卡车正在缓缓驶入。崔表示，目前还没有大批外国游客访问罗先的迹象。</p>   <p>Lee of Teikyo University said that whichever outside country helped reinvigorate the special economic zone, it offered a potential bright spot for North Koreans after years of pandemic restrictions.翻译:帝京大学的李表示，无论哪个外部国家帮助重振经济特区，它都为朝鲜人在多年的流行病限制之后提供了一个潜在的亮点。</p>   <p>"Rason took a harder hit than other places in North Korea because it used to be on the front lines of the opening," Lee said. "Now many businesses have collapsed there, but as soon as the border fully reopens, North Koreans might think that the paradise can come back."翻译:“罗先市比朝鲜其他地方受到的打击更严重，因为它曾经位于开放的前线，”李说。 “现在那里的许多企业都倒闭了，但一旦边境完全重新开放，朝鲜人可能会认为天堂可以回来。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Ju-min Park; Additional reporting by Josh Smith and Gleb Stolyarov; Editing by Gerry Doyle翻译:格里·多伊尔编辑翻译:朴柱民报道；约什·史密斯 (Josh Smith) 和格列布·斯托利亚罗夫 (Gleb Stolyarov) 的补充报道；格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 02:41:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BOKP7DL2VJKE7L3BSWI6QEF4EY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/north-korean-special-economic-zone-poised-revival-new-russia-trade-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ju-Min Park]]></author>
            
                
                <category>NORTHKOREA</category>
                
                <category>RUSSIA/ECONOMY (PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[澳大利亚为外国干涉审判开绿灯]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Australia's attorney general has approved foreign interference charges against an Australian marketing executive who worked in China, seven months after the man was arrested by police on his return from Shanghai.翻译:澳大利亚总检察长批准对一名在中国工作的澳大利亚营销主管提出外国干涉指控，七个月前该男子从上海回国后被警方逮捕。</p>   <p>Alexander Csergo, 55, who appeared on video link in a Sydney court on Wednesday, has been in custody <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australian-man-back-china-charged-with-foreign-interference-seeks-bail-2023-04-17/">since his arrest</a> by Australian Federal Police in April at his mother's beachside Bondi home.翻译:55 岁的亚历山大·塞尔戈 (Alexander Csergo) 周三出现在悉尼一家法院的视频连线中，自 4 月份在其母亲位于邦迪海滨的家中被澳大利亚联邦警察<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australian-man-back-china-charged-with-foreign-interference-seeks-bail-2023-04-17/">逮捕以来，他</a>一直被拘留。</p>   <p>He was the first person charged with "reckless foreign interference", and the second person charged under a law that criminalises activity that helps a foreign power interfere with Australia's sovereignty or national interests. It carries a maximum 15-year prison sentence.翻译:他是第一个被指控“鲁莽外国干涉”的人，也是根据一项将帮助外国势力干涉澳大利亚主权或国家利益的活动定为刑事犯罪的法律受到指控的第二个人。最高可判处 15 年监禁。</p>   <p>Csergo has denied the allegations and has not yet entered a plea.翻译:塞尔戈否认了这些指控，并且尚未提出抗辩。</p>   <p>He is accused of accepting cash from suspected Chinese intelligence agents in exchange for writing reports on Australia, including its AUKUS nuclear submarine partnership with the United States and Britain, and lithium mining, while living in Shanghai.翻译:他被指控在上海居住期间收受可疑中国情报人员的现金，以换取撰写有关澳大利亚的报告，包括澳大利亚与美国和英国的 AUKUS 核潜艇合作伙伴关系以及锂矿开采。</p>   <p>Csergo's lawyers have argued the reports were based on publicly available information and the case against him was shallow. They raised concerns about the broad scope of the foreign interference law, introduced in 2018.翻译:塞尔戈的律师辩称，这些报告是基于公开信息，而且针对他的案件很肤浅。他们对 2018 年推出的外国干涉法的广泛范围表示担忧。</p>   <p>Prosecutor Conor McCraith told the Sydney court a police brief and charges had been served on Tuesday.翻译:检察官康纳·麦克雷思向悉尼法院提交了一份警方简报，并已于周二提出指控。</p>   <p>"We needed the consent of the attorney general, which has been obtained," McCraith told the court. A committal hearing date was set for Jan. 24.翻译:麦克雷思在法庭上表示：“我们需要得到总检察长的同意，我们已经获得了总检察长的同意。”预审听证会日期定于 1 月 24 日。</p>   <p>Csergo had worked in China since 2002 in data marketing, and wrote the reports during the COVID-19 lockdown in Shanghai as a source of income when he was unable to leave China because of border restrictions, an earlier court hearing was told.翻译:早些时候的法庭听证会获悉，Csergo 自 2002 年以来一直在中国从事数据营销工作，并在上海 COVID-19 封锁期间撰写了这些报告，作为收入来源，当时他由于边境限制而无法离开中国。</p>   <p>The court heard that Csergo told police in Australia he became anxious about two suspected Chinese intelligence agents, known as "Ken" and "Evelyn", who made contact via the LinkedIn social media platform, and whom he later met in Shanghai cafes.翻译:法庭获悉，Csergo 告诉澳大利亚警方，他对两名涉嫌中国情报人员（“Ken”和“Evelyn”）感到焦虑，他们通过 LinkedIn 社交媒体平台联系，后来他在上海的咖啡馆遇见了他们。</p>   <p>The court was told he arrived back in Australia with a "shopping list" of intelligence priorities.翻译:法庭被告知，他带着一份情报优先事项的“购物清单”回到澳大利亚。</p>    <span>Reporting by Kirsty Needham. Editing by Gerry Doyle翻译:科斯蒂·李约瑟报道。格里·多伊尔编辑翻译:格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 02:05:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">45IP7MEK5VP6VIQSYOAIVKSYJQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australia-gives-green-light-foreign-interference-trial-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Kirsty Needham]]></author>
            
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[负债累累的中国地方政府争相发行210亿美元专项债券救助小银行]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/WDwjuJTfojue9CkpS7a75cuxrlQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KFAJWWAST5N7RK5QWKER2ZVTLU.jpg" alt="Chinese national flag flutters at the headquarters of a commercial bank on a financial street near the headquarters of the People's Bank of China, China's central bank, in central Beijing翻译:位于北京市中心中国人民银行总部附近的金融街上，中国国旗在一家商业银行总部飘扬" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Chinese national flag flutters at the headquarters of a commercial bank on a financial street near the headquarters of the People's Bank of China, China's central bank, in central Beijing翻译:位于北京市中心中国人民银行总部附近的金融街上，中国国旗在一家商业银行总部飘扬 November 24, 2014. REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/File Photo翻译:2014年11月24日，位于北京市中心中国人民银行总部附近的金融街上，一面中国国旗在一家商业银行总部飘扬。路透社/Kim Kyung-Hoon/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Local governments in China have sold record amounts of so-called special bonds this year to inject capital into struggling smaller banks, as authorities seek to contain spillover risks from a deepening property crisis and a sputtering economy.翻译:中国地方政府今年发行了创纪录数量的所谓特别债券，为陷入困境的小型银行注入资金，当局试图遏制房地产危机加深和经济不景气带来的溢出风险。</p>   <p>Special-purpose bonds are a form of off-budget debt financing used by local governments in China, with the proceeds raised typically earmarked for specific policy goals, such as spending on infrastructure projects.翻译:特殊用途债券是中国地方政府使用的一种预算外债务融资形式，筹集的资金通常专门用于特定的政策目标，例如基础设施项目支出。</p>   <p>Local governments plan to use the proceeds of the latest bond sales to purchase equity or convertible bonds from smaller banks, most of them state-owned, effectively recapitalising them, according to the deal prospectuses.翻译:交易招股说明书显示，地方政府计划利用最新发债所得的资金，从规模较小的银行（其中大多数是国有银行）购买股权或可转换债券，从而有效地对这些银行进行资本重组。</p>   <p>The governments have raised 152.3 billion yuan ($21.05 billion) via such bonds so far in 2023 to replenish the capital of small and medium-sized banks, according to data from the official China Electronic Local Government Bond Market Access.翻译:根据中国电子地方政府债券市场准入的官方数据，2023年迄今为止，政府已通过此类债券筹集了1523亿元人民币（210.5亿美元），以补充中小型银行的资本。</p>   <p>But total funds raised so far are modest compared to the banks' needs, analysts say.翻译:但分析师表示，与银行的需求相比，迄今为止筹集的资金总额并不多。</p>   <p>China's small, regional banks would need to address a capital shortfall of an estimated 2.2 trillion yuan based on a scenario where up to 20% of regional lenders face capital inadequacy, according to an October report by S&amp;P Global Ratings.翻译:标准普尔全球评级公司 10 月份的一份报告显示，如果高达 20% 的地区性银行面临资本不足的情况，中国小型地区性银行将需要解决估计 2.2 万亿元人民币的资本短缺问题。</p>   <p>Highlighting Beijing's push to avoid a financial crisis like the one in 2008, the value of special-purpose bonds issued this year is already more than double the 63 billion yuan issued in 2022, and is the highest on record since such instruments were introduced in 2020 to help smaller lenders impacted by the COVID-19 pandemic.翻译:今年发行的特殊用途债券的价值已经是2022年发行的630亿元人民币的两倍多，并且是自2020年推出此类工具以来的最高记录，突显了北京为避免2008年那样的金融危机所做的努力帮助受 COVID-19 大流行影响的小型贷方。</p>   <p>The trend highlights how more and more of the country's smaller banks are being propped up with government support, amid a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/">deepening crisis</a> in the property market, which accounts for about a quarter of the economy.翻译:这一趋势突显出，在占经济约四分之一的房地产市场<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/">危机日益加深</a>之际，越来越多的中国小型银行得到了政府的支持。</p>   <p>Authorities have been ramping up measures to support real estate, including relaxing home purchase restrictions and lowering borrowing costs, although these have failed to shore up a meaningful recovery.翻译:当局一直在加大支持房地产的措施，包括放宽购房限制和降低借贷成本，尽管这些措施未能支撑有意义的复苏。</p>   <p>The People's Bank of China (PBOC) and the National Financial Regulatory Administration (NFRA) did not respond to Reuters request for comment.</p>    <h 1="">DEEPER IN DEBT</h>  <p>The intensified efforts to support smaller banks also come amid growing worries about the impact of ballooning local government debt on the economy.翻译:在加大力度支持小型银行之际，人们越来越担心地方政府债务不断膨胀对经济的影响。</p>   <p>Local government debt reached 92 trillion yuan ($12.6 trillion), or 76% of China's economic output in 2022, up from 62.2% in 2019, according to the latest data from the International Monetary Fund.翻译:根据国际货币基金组织的最新数据，到2022年，地方政府债务将达到92万亿元人民币（12.6万亿美元），占中国经济产出的76%，高于2019年的62.2%。</p>   <p>While policymakers are highly concerned over rising debt levels, Beijing has little option but to support smaller banks to contain spillover risks, analysts said.翻译:分析师表示，尽管政策制定者高度关注债务水平上升，但北京别无选择，只能支持规模较小的银行遏制溢出风险。</p>   <p>"It is important to avoid any failures of even the smallest institutions, as a single failure could generate knock-on effects and spread financial contagion to other financial institutions," said Gavekal Dragonomics researcher Zhang Xiaoxi.翻译:龙洲经讯研究员张晓曦表示：“即使是最小的机构，也要避免出现任何倒闭，因为单一的倒闭可能会产生连锁反应，并将金融危机蔓延到其他金融机构。”</p>   <p>It was not immediately clear if the central authorities had given any guidance to the local governments on recapitalising smaller banks, and who were the buyers of these special-purpose bonds.翻译:目前尚不清楚中央是否已就小型银行资本重组向地方政府提供任何指导，以及这些特殊用途债券的买家是谁。</p>   <p>Some provinces are accelerating plans to reform and defuse risks at local, high-risk small and medium-sized banks and to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">replenish capital</a> via multiple channels, central bank governor Pan Gongsheng said in Beijing earlier this month.</p>    <h 1="">CONTAGION RISK</h>  <p>Local governments and banks are fundamental to China's economy, with Beijing tasking provincial and city officials with meeting ambitious growth targets.翻译:地方政府和银行对中国经济至关重要，北京向省市官员下达了实现雄心勃勃的增长目标的任务。</p>   <p>But after years of over-investment in infrastructure, plummeting returns from land sales, and soaring COVID costs, economists say debt-laden municipalities now represent a major risk to the world's second-largest economy.翻译:但经济学家表示，经过多年对基础设施的过度投资、土地销售回报大幅下降以及新冠疫情成本飙升，负债累累的城市现在对世界第二大经济体构成了重大风险。</p>   <p>The issuance of fresh debt by the local governments to recapitalise banks, coming at a time when their own liabilities are growing rapidly, could make the financial balancing act for municipalities even more precarious.翻译:地方政府在自身负债迅速增长之际发行新债以对银行进行资本重组，可能会使市政当局的财务平衡行为变得更加不稳定。</p>   <p>On top of $21 billion raised so far this year, the Henan provincial government last week announced a plan to issue 28.2 billion yuan worth of special purpose bonds to recapitalise 26 local banks, according to the government website.</p>    <h 1="">WEAK LINKS</h>  <p>Smaller regional banks are the weak links in China's $61 trillion financial sector, due to their industrial, sectoral and geographical concentration, opaque governance, and lack of stringent regulatory oversight.翻译:由于行业、部门和地域集中、治理不透明以及缺乏严格的监管，小型区域性银行是中国 61 万亿美元金融部门的薄弱环节。</p>   <p>As of end-September, China's rural commercial banks reported a 3.18% non-performing loan ratio with city commercial banks at 1.91%, data from the NFRA showed, higher than the average of 1.61% in the banking sector.翻译:NFRA数据显示，截至9月底，中国农村商业银行不良贷款率为3.18%，城市商业银行不良贷款率为1.91%，高于银行业1.61%的平均水平。</p>   <p>Many analysts believe the real amount of soured loans is far higher.翻译:许多分析师认为，不良贷款的实际数量要高得多。</p>   <p>Smaller Chinese banks face greater challenges in raising funds to replenish their balance sheets compared with their large peers, because of their lower creditworthiness, limited operating scope and risk profiles.翻译:与大型银行相比，规模较小的中国银行在筹集资金补充资产负债表方面面临更大的挑战，因为它们的信用度较低，经营范围和风险状况有限。</p>   <p>Among the top issuers of the special bonds this year are debt-laden provincial governments in Liaoning, Yunnan and the government in Inner Mongolia region, which aim to use the proceeds to recapitalise local banks.翻译:今年特别债券的最大发行者是负债累累的辽宁省、云南省政府和内蒙古地区政府，它们的目的是利用所得资金对当地银行进行资本重组。</p>   <p>Regional banks operating primarily in weaker regions heavily exposed to indebted local government financing vehicles bear higher credit risks than their peers in wealthy regions, S&amp;P analysts said in last month's research note.翻译:标准普尔分析师在上个月的研究报告中表示，主要在实力较弱地区运营、地方政府融资工具负债累累的地区性银行比富裕地区的同行承担更高的信贷风险。</p>   <p>"Local governments are a likely the first line of defense whenever regional banks become stressed," they said. "Nevertheless, we expect local-government support to strained lenders will be selective."翻译:他们表示：“每当地区性银行面临压力时，地方政府可能是第一道防线。” “尽管如此，我们预计地方政府对紧张的贷方的支持将是有选择性的。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Ziyi Tang and Ryan Woo; Editing by Sumeet Chatterjee and Kim Coghill翻译:唐子仪和吴瑞安报道；编辑：Sumeet Chatterjee 和 Kim Coghill</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 01:58:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">LE35VK4SHVM3XL6PFWDU2NUNDU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/debt-laden-chinas-local-governments-scramble-rescue-small-banks-with-21-bln-2023-11-28/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ziyi Tang, Ryan Woo]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>LOCALGOVERNMENT/BANKS (ANALYSIS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shein 的 IPO 引发了有关其供应链中涉嫌强迫劳动的新问题]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0ZEBwrUF5l53uGohNippDToQ-Vg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4MRVJDJEGROX7OJQQJ36O7FTXU.jpg" alt="A Shein logo is pictured at the company's office in the central business district of Singapore翻译:Shein 标志位于该公司位于新加坡中央商务区的办公室" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Shein logo is pictured at the company's office in the central business district of Singapore翻译:Shein 标志位于该公司位于新加坡中央商务区的办公室, October 18, 2022. REUTERS/Chen Lin/File Photo翻译:2022 年 10 月 18 日，Shein 标志在该公司位于新加坡中央商务区的办公室拍摄。路透社/Chen Lin/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>As China-founded e-commerce behemoth Shein moves to list in New York, U.S. lawmakers are again calling on it to prove that forced labor is not used to make its $5 T-shirts and $10 sweaters.翻译:随着中国创立的电子商务巨头 Shein 在纽约上市，美国立法者再次呼吁该公司证明其 5 美元的 T 恤和 10 美元的毛衣的生产过程中没有使用强迫劳动。</p>   <p>Shein <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinese-fast-fashion-shein-files-us-ipo-wsj-2023-11-27/">confidentially filed</a> for an initial public offering on Monday and could launch sales of its shares some time in 2024. The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/how-chinas-shein-became-fast-fashion-giant-2023-11-28/">Singapore-based company</a> has not determined the size of the deal or the valuation at IPO. Bloomberg reported earlier this month that it targeted up to $90 billion in the float.翻译:Shein 周一<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinese-fast-fashion-shein-files-us-ipo-wsj-2023-11-27/">秘密申请</a>首次公开募股，并可能在 2024 年某个时候出售其股票。这家<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/how-chinas-shein-became-fast-fashion-giant-2023-11-28/">总部位于新加坡的公司</a>尚未确定交易规模或 IPO 估值。彭博社本月早些时候报道称，其发行目标为 900 亿美元。</p>   <p>Founded in 2012, Shein has been <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/shein-talks-with-banks-exchanges-about-us-ipo-sources-2023-07-04/">eyeing a U.S. IPO</a> for at least three years but has been deterred by headwinds that included tensions between Beijing and Washington.翻译:Shein 成立于 2012 年，至少三年来一直<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/shein-talks-with-banks-exchanges-about-us-ipo-sources-2023-07-04/">考虑在美国首次公开募股</a>，但因北京和华盛顿之间的紧张局势等不利因素而止步。</p>   <p>The online fast-fashion retailer, which manufactures most of its merchandise in China, faces criticism that Uyghur forced labor is used to make its low-priced apparel and home goods.翻译:这家在线快时尚零售商的大部分商品在中国生产，该公司面临着使用维吾尔族强迫劳动来生产其低价服装和家居用品的批评。</p>   <p>Critics are concerned that Shein may use contract manufacturers in China's Xinjiang region, where advocates and governments have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/us-committee-demands-reasons-lack-xinjiang-sanctions-2023-09-19/">accused China</a> of interning Uyghurs and other largely Muslim minority groups. Beijing denies any abuses.翻译:批评者担心，谢因可能会使用中国新疆地区的合同制造商，那里的倡导者和政府<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/us-committee-demands-reasons-lack-xinjiang-sanctions-2023-09-19/">指责中国</a>拘禁维吾尔人和其他以穆斯林为主的少数民族群体。北京否认有任何侵权行为。</p>   <p>Convincing regulators that its supply chain is clean will likely be a major regulatory hurdle as Shein works to convince the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission that its shares should be traded publicly.翻译:让监管机构相信其供应链是干净的可能会成为主要的监管障碍，因为 Shein 正在努力说服美国证券交易委员会其股票应该公开交易。</p>   <p>“If the fast-fashion giant Shein wants to go public in the U.S., they should have to prove to American consumers that their products are not sourced from forced labor,” Democratic Representative Jennifer Wexton said in a statement on Tuesday.翻译:“如果快时尚巨头 Shein 想要在美国上市，他们应该向美国消费者证明他们的产品并非来自强迫劳动，”民主党众议员詹妮弗·韦克斯顿 (Jennifer Wexton) 在周二的一份声明中表示。</p>   <p>Earlier this year, the congresswoman led a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/us-lawmakers-push-sec-order-audit-shein-ipo-over-uyghur-forced-labor-fears-2023-05-01/">bipartisan call</a> for the SEC to halt Shein’s IPO until it verifies that the company does not use forced labor within its supply chain.翻译:今年早些时候，这位女议员领导<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/us-lawmakers-push-sec-order-audit-shein-ipo-over-uyghur-forced-labor-fears-2023-05-01/">两党</a>呼吁美国证券交易委员会停止 Shein 的首次公开募股，直到核实该公司在其供应链中不使用强迫劳工。</p>   <p>A separate group of Republican attorneys general from 16 U.S. states has also asked the SEC to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/society-equity/us-states-ask-sec-check-if-shein-complies-with-forced-labor-rules-2023-08-28/">audit the company</a>, and Shein has been investigated by two separate Congressional committees over its sourcing and use of a trade loophole that allows most of its products to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/key-trade-loophole-keeps-cheap-chinese-products-flowing-us-2023-08-04/">enter the U.S. duty-free</a>.翻译:来自美国 16 个州的共和党总检察长组成的独立小组也要求美国证券交易委员会<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/society-equity/us-states-ask-sec-check-if-shein-complies-with-forced-labor-rules-2023-08-28/">对该公司进行审计</a>，Shein 已受到两个独立的国会委员会的调查，原因是该公司的采购和利用了允许其大部分产品<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/key-trade-loophole-keeps-cheap-chinese-products-flowing-us-2023-08-04/">进入美国的</a>贸易漏洞。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/key-trade-loophole-keeps-cheap-chinese-products-flowing-us-2023-08-04/">免税</a>。</p>   <p>Shein did not immediately respond to a request for comment, but the company has previously told Reuters it has “zero tolerance for forced labor” and has no contract manufacturers in Xinjiang.翻译:Shein 没有立即回应置评请求，但该公司此前曾告诉路透社，该公司“对强迫劳动持零容忍态度”，并且在新疆没有合同制造商。</p>   <p>A spokesperson for the SEC said the agency does not comment on any individual entity’s filings.翻译:美国证券交易委员会发言人表示，该机构不会对任何个别实体的备案文件发表评论。</p>   <p>Megan Penick, a public securities lawyer at Michelman &amp; Robinson, said it is unlikely to see a "direct block" from the SEC, but the agency could make the process difficult for Shein by making "the disclosure requirements so detailed, and, perhaps extreme, that it makes it seem ... trying to go public cannot be achieved."翻译:米歇尔曼·罗宾逊律师事务所 (Michelman &amp; Robinson) 的公共证券律师梅根·佩尼克 (Megan Penick) 表示，不太可能看到 SEC 的“直接阻止”，但该机构可能会通过“披露要求如此详细，甚至可能是极端”，从而使 Shein 的流程变得困难。 ，这看起来……试图上市是不可能实现的。”</p>   <p>"There may be issues with the forced labor allegations and the IP (intellectual property) issues that may make it hard for (Shein) to be able to answer the questions to the satisfaction of the SEC," Penick said.</p>       <h 1="">LOBBYING CAPITOL HILL</h>  <p>Public disclosures show that Shein has spent $1.28 million on Capitol Hill lobbying this year as it prepares to go public.翻译:公开披露的信息显示，Shein 今年在准备上市时已花费 128 万美元用于国会山游说。</p>   <p>The company has also met privately with lawmakers, including some of its biggest critics, in an effort to shift its reputation in Washington, according to several Congressional aides.翻译:据几位国会助手称，该公司还与立法者私下会面，其中包括一些最大的批评者，以努力改变其在华盛顿的声誉。</p>   <p>One source familiar with the matter said that representatives for Shein emphasized the retailer’s efforts to diversify its supply chain from China to other countries, including India.翻译:一位知情人士表示，Shein 的代表强调了该零售商努力将其供应链从中国转向包括印度在内的其他国家。</p>   <p>Shein also touted its efforts to bring more China-made goods to the U.S. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/shein-shifts-shipping-strategy-bring-china-made-goods-closer-us-shoppers-2023-09-22/">in bulk on traditional container ships</a>, which requires paying tariffs on those items.翻译:Shein还宣传其努力<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/shein-shifts-shipping-strategy-bring-china-made-goods-closer-us-shoppers-2023-09-22/">通过传统集装箱船将更多中国制造的商品批量</a>运往美国，这需要对这些商品缴纳关税。</p>   <p>“Shein is fundamentally a Chinese company and investors should approach Chinese offerings with extreme caution. Its attempt to go public should prompt a closer look at its business practices, especially its links to slave labor and its evasion of U.S. customs laws," Republican Sen. Marco Rubio told Reuters.翻译:“Shein 从根本上来说是一家中国公司，投资者应极其谨慎地对待中国产品。它的上市尝试应该促使人们更仔细地审视其商业行为，特别是其与奴役劳工的联系以及其逃避美国海关法的行为，”共和党参议员马可·卢比奥告诉路透社。</p>   <p>"I will closely monitor Shein's disclosures in the lead-up to its IPO,” added Rubio, who in June criticized the retailer’s lobbying efforts in a letter distributed to other senators.翻译:卢比奥补充道：“我将在 Shein 首次公开募股前夕密切关注 Shein 的披露情况。”6 月份，卢比奥在发给其他参议员的一封信中批评了该零售商的游说努力。</p>   <p>Republican Representative Chris Smith, chairman of the Congressional-Executive Commission on China, has also criticized Shein's lobbying efforts.翻译:国会及行政部门中国委员会主席、共和党众议员克里斯·史密斯也批评了谢因的游说努力。</p>   <p>“Any investor in this company should be wary of the material risks involved in Shein’s business model ... particularly as Congress is demanding an end to forced labor and closure of import subsidies for Chinese companies,” Congressman Smith said.</p>    <h 1="">INCREASED SCRUTINY</h>  <p>In its most recent social impact report, Shein highlighted its partnership with Oritain, a company also used by the U.S. government to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/us-customs-finds-garments-made-with-banned-chinese-cotton-documents-2023-09-01/">test cotton </a>for links to China’s Xinjiang region. Shein previously told Reuters that it tests samples from every third-party cotton mill the company works with, and that it conducted 2,111 tests between June 1, 2022 and July 11, 2023.翻译:Shein 在其最新的社会影响报告中强调了其与 Oritain 的合作关系，该公司也被美国政府用来<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/us-customs-finds-garments-made-with-banned-chinese-cotton-documents-2023-09-01/">测试棉花</a>与中国新疆地区的联系。 Shein此前告诉路透社，它测试了与该公司合作的每一家第三方棉纺厂的样本，并在2022年6月1日至2023年7月11日期间进行了2,111次测试。</p>   <p>Critics, however, say that the testing does not adequately screen the millions of garments exported globally by Shein every year.翻译:然而批评者表示，测试并没有充分筛查 Shein 每年向全球出口的数百万件服装。</p>   <p>Public securities lawyer Penick said that the SEC's handling of Shein's IPO will be crucial for other e-commerce players including ByteDance's TikTok and PDD Group's Temu, which may consider going public in the U.S. in the future.翻译:公共证券律师佩尼克表示，SEC 对 Shein IPO 的处理对于包括字节跳动旗下 TikTok 和拼多多集团旗下 Temu 在内的其他电子商务公司至关重要，这些公司未来可能会考虑在美国上市。</p>   <p>Shein's IPO is "going to be raising issues (for the SEC) that may later be applied across the board to all China-based or China-related companies that are going public," Penick said.翻译:佩尼克表示，Shein 的首次公开募股“将（向美国证券交易委员会）提出问题，这些问题随后可能会全面适用于所有即将上市的中国或与中国相关的公司”。</p>    <span>Reporting by Katherine Masters and Arriana Mclymore; additional reporting by Michael Martina
Editing by Marguerita Choy翻译:凯瑟琳·马斯特斯和阿里安娜·麦克利莫尔的报道；迈克尔·马丁娜 (Michael Martina) 的补充报道 玛格丽塔·蔡 (Marguerita Choy) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 21:59:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CBHAFJU6ZBKW7KOMWE6QWZQDKI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/sheins-ipo-raises-fresh-questions-alleged-forced-labor-its-supply-chain-2023-11-28/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Katherine Masters, Arriana McLymore]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SHEIN</category>
                
                <category>IPO/ (UPDATE 1, ANALYSIS, PIX, GRAPHIC)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早盘竞价：金融状况再次放松]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/6GXhLZCGA6l6Aho9QggJ_t8wCVc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DL3AW47ERVIFVJVHHV3KWNNLFA.jpg" alt="Passersby walk past an electric monitor displaying the Japanese yen exchange rate against the U.S. dollar outside a brokerage in Tokyo翻译:东京一家经纪公司外，路人走过显示日元兑美元汇率的电子显示屏" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Passersby walk past an electric monitor displaying the Japanese yen exchange rate against the U.S. dollar outside a brokerage in Tokyo翻译:东京一家经纪公司外，路人走过显示日元兑美元汇率的电子显示屏, Japan October 4, 2023. REUTERS/Issei Kato/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>A look at the day ahead in Asian markets.翻译:展望未来一天的亚洲市场。</p>   <p>Interest rate decisions and guidance from <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/poll-rbnz-to-hold-rates-in-november-and-through-mid-2024-cut-in-q3#:~:text=Stocks-,POLL-RBNZ%20to%20hold%20rates%20in%20November%20and,mid-2024%2C%20cut%20in%20Q3&amp;text=BENGALURU%2C%20Nov%2024%20(Reuters),according%20to%20a%20Reuters%20poll" target="_blank">New Zealand</a> and <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/poll-bank-of-thailand-likely-to-hold-rates-at-2.50-until-at-least-mid-2025#:~:text=BENGALURU%2C%20Nov%2027%20(Reuters),long%20tightening%20cycle%20was%20over" target="_blank">Thailand</a>, and inflation figures from Australia will be the main events for Asian markets on Wednesday, as a curiously directionless week for risk assets reaches the midway point.翻译:<a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/poll-rbnz-to-hold-rates-in-november-and-through-mid-2024-cut-in-q3#:~:text=Stocks-,POLL-RBNZ%20to%20hold%20rates%20in%20November%20and,mid-2024%2C%20cut%20in%20Q3&amp;text=BENGALURU%2C%20Nov%2024%20(Reuters),according%20to%20a%20Reuters%20poll" target="_blank">新西兰</a>和<a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/poll-bank-of-thailand-likely-to-hold-rates-at-2.50-until-at-least-mid-2025#:~:text=BENGALURU%2C%20Nov%2027%20(Reuters),long%20tightening%20cycle%20was%20over" target="_blank">泰国</a>的利率决定和指导，以及澳大利亚的通胀数据将成为周三亚洲市场的主要事件，因为风险资产奇怪地没有方向的一周已经到了中点。</p>   <p>While emerging market and Asian equities clocked up decent gains on Tuesday, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-subdued-ahead-comments-fed-officials-zscaler-falls-2023-11-28/">Wall Street</a> struggled to make much headway despite a seemingly constructive market and economic backdrop.翻译:尽管新兴市场和亚洲股市周二录得可观涨幅，但尽管市场和经济背景看似建设性，但<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-subdued-ahead-comments-fed-officials-zscaler-falls-2023-11-28/">华尔街</a>仍难以取得太大进展。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/dollar-hangs-three-month-low-traders-eye-pce-data-2023-11-28/">The dollar</a>, <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/treasuries-us-yields-fall-after-waller-comments-data" target="_blank">Treasury yields</a>, and stock market volatility all fell, and U.S. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-consumer-confidence-rises-november-2023-11-28/">consumer confidence</a> was higher than expected. Fed Governor <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/feds-waller-increasingly-confident-policy-is-right-spot-2023-11-28/">Christopher Waller</a> - thought to be close to Fed Chair Jerome Powell's thinking on policy - also signaled that U.S. interest rates could be cut in the months ahead.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/dollar-hangs-three-month-low-traders-eye-pce-data-2023-11-28/">美元</a>、 <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/treasuries-us-yields-fall-after-waller-comments-data" target="_blank">国债收益率</a>和股市波动均下跌，美国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-consumer-confidence-rises-november-2023-11-28/">消费者信心</a>高于预期。美联储理事<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/feds-waller-increasingly-confident-policy-is-right-spot-2023-11-28/">克里斯托弗·沃勒</a>——被认为与美联储主席杰罗姆·鲍威尔的政策想法接近——也暗示美国可能在未来几个月降息。</p>   <p>The dollar and two-year Treasury yield slid to fresh three-month lows, the 10-year yield hit a two-month low and the VIX volatility index fell back to recent lows last seen before the pandemic. Yet the S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq ended flat.翻译:美元和两年期国债收益率跌至三个月新低，10年期国债收益率触及两个月低点，VIX波动率指数回落至疫情爆发前的近期低点。然而标准普尔 500 指数和纳斯达克指数收盘持平。</p>   <p>Perhaps that broad loosening of financial conditions will give Asian markets a bigger boost on Wednesday, although the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/beijing-stock-exchange-tells-major-shareholders-refrain-selling-sources-2023-11-27/">underperformance</a> of Chinese stocks shows little sign of abating even as the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">central bank chief</a> pledged to keep monetary policy "accommodative" to provide support to the economy."翻译:或许，金融环境的全面宽松将在周三给亚洲市场带来更大的提振，尽管中国股市<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/beijing-stock-exchange-tells-major-shareholders-refrain-selling-sources-2023-11-27/">表现不佳</a>，尽管<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">央行行长</a>承诺保持“宽松”的货币政策以支持经济，但中国股市的表现并没有显示出任何缓解的迹象。</p>   <p>The first of the main policy events in the region on Wednesday will be the Reserve Bank of New Zealand's policy decision. It is widely expected to hold the cash rate at 5.50%, so investors' interest will lie more in the bank's guidance.翻译:周三该地区的第一个主要政策事件将是新西兰储备银行的政策决定。人们普遍预计现金利率将维持在5.50%，因此投资者的兴趣将更多地取决于银行的指导。</p>   <p>Traders expect up to 50 basis points of easing next year, with the first cut coming in July. That's about half of what the Fed is expected to do, so it's no wonder the New Zealand dollar is outperforming - it is up 6.5% in the past month.翻译:交易员预计明年将实施最多 50 个基点的宽松政策，首次降息将在 7 月份进行。这大约是美联储预期行动的一半，因此新西兰元表现优异也就不足为奇了——过去一个月上涨了 6.5%。</p>   <p>Thailand's central bank is also expected to keep rates on hold, at 2.50%, through the middle of 2025. Disappointing third quarter growth and the exchange rate's 7% appreciation over the last month will have eased any lingering pressure on policymakers to raise rates again.翻译:泰国央行预计将在 2025 年中期之前将利率维持在 2.50%。令人失望的第三季度增长以及上个月汇率升值 7% 将缓解政策制定者再次加息的挥之不去的压力。</p>   <p>Finally, figures from Australia are expected to show that price pressures cooled in October, with the annual rate of weighted consumer inflation slowing to 5.20% from 5.60%.翻译:最后，澳大利亚的数据预计将显示 10 月份物价压力有所降温，加权消费者通胀年率将从 5.60% 放缓至 5.20%。</p>   <p>Reserve Bank of Australia Governor Michele Bullock on Tuesday reaffirmed that monetary policy was restrictive and working to dampen demand, though inflation in the service sector was proving sticker than hoped.翻译:澳大利亚储备银行行长米歇尔·布洛克周二重申，货币政策是限制性的，旨在抑制需求，尽管事实证明服务业的通胀高于预期。</p>   <p>The RBA is expected to keep its cash rate on hold at 4.35% next week, although there is around a 10% chance of a quarter point hike, according to futures market pricing.翻译:预计澳洲联储下周将维持现金利率在 4.35% 不变，但根据期货市场定价，加息 25 个基点的可能性约为 10%。</p>   <p>Here are key developments that could provide more direction to markets on Wednesday:翻译:以下是周三可能为市场提供更多方向的关键进展：</p>   <p>- New Zealand interest rate decision翻译:- 新西兰利率决定</p>   <p>- Thailand interest rate decision翻译:- 泰国利率决定</p>   <p>- Australia inflation翻译:- 澳大利亚通货膨胀</p>    <span>By Jamie McGeever
Editing by翻译:作者：杰米·麦克吉弗 编辑：</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 21:51:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FVCTNHEOVJO7RHLYXOXNB6ORAI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/global-markets-view-asia-pix-2023-11-28/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jamie McGeever]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>ASIA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国美团第四季度外卖收入增长放缓]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/rvz9-yYlt3yr6B1mpMfIfiShWbw=/800x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/EM42Q3LTA5LVNMCTDDEFS6KOFM.jpg" alt="A Meituan delivery worker rides a scooter carrying vegetables on a snowy day in Beijing翻译:北京雪天，美团外卖员骑着滑板车运送蔬菜" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Meituan delivery worker rides a scooter carrying vegetables on a snowy day in Beijing翻译:北京雪天，美团外卖员骑着滑板车运送蔬菜, China January 19, 2021. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's Meituan <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3690.HK" target="_blank">(3690.HK)</a> on Tuesday said it expects fourth-quarter revenue growth for its core food delivery business to slow versus the preceding quarter, as persistent consumer caution and warmer weather for the winter season hits orders.翻译:中国美团点评<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3690.HK" target="_blank">（3690.HK）</a>周二表示，由于消费者持续谨慎以及冬季天气转暖影响订单，预计其核心食品配送业务第四季度收入增长将较上一季度放缓。</p>   <p>Deliveries will also likely decline versus the same period last year, Meituan Chief Financial Officer Chen Shaohui said, as demand in the fourth quarter last year was helped by customers still grappling with curbs on movement caused by China's COVID policy, placing larger orders over longer distances.翻译:美团点评首席财务官陈少辉表示，与去年同期相比，交付量也可能会下降，因为去年第四季度的需求得益于仍在努力应对中国新冠疫情政策造成的出行限制的客户，他们在更远的距离下了大量订单。</p>   <p>He said he expects a similar trend for its non-food delivery service Meituan Instashopping.翻译:他表示，他预计其非食品配送服务美团Instashopping也会出现类似的趋势。</p>   <p>"We are stepping up our marketing efforts to stimulate demand in the current consumption environment," he said, adding that this would include higher subsidies.翻译:他说：“我们正在加大营销力度，以刺激当前消费环境下的需求。”他补充说，这将包括提高补贴。</p>   <p>The comments come as demand in the world's second-largest economy remains lacklustre, with China's post-pandemic economic recovery losing steam in recent months. Meituan CEO Wang Xing previously flagged a tougher third quarter for the food delivery business due to macroeconomic headwinds.翻译:此番言论发表之际，全球第二大经济体的需求依然低迷，中国疫情后的经济复苏近几个月失去动力。美团点评首席执行官王兴此前曾表示，由于宏观经济不利因素，外卖业务第三季度将更加艰难。</p>   <p>Asked about whether the company will consider a share buyback, Wang said the company's board had authorised one of up to $1 billion. However, a buyback would depend on Meituan's cash position due to plans to invest in new initiatives and explore overseas investments, he said.翻译:当被问及公司是否会考虑进行股票回购时，王表示，公司董事会已授权其中一项高达 10 亿美元的回购。不过，他表示，由于美团计划投资新项目和探索海外投资，因此回购将取决于美团的现金状况。</p>   <p>Shares in Meituan, China's largest food delivery provider ahead of Aliaba's Ele.me, have fallen to their lowest level since 2020, having declined 5.2% on Tuesday before its earnings.翻译:美团是中国最大的食品配送提供商，领先于阿里旗下的饿了么，其股价已跌至 2020 年以来的最低水平，周二发布财报前下跌 5.2%。</p>   <p>The platform, whose app provides services such as bike sharing, ticket booking and maps, earlier in the day posted a bigger-than-expected 22.1% rise in third-quarter revenue to 76.47 billion yuan ($10.69 billion) versus 62.62 billion yuan in the same period a year earlier.翻译:该平台的应用程序提供自行车共享、票务预订和地图等服务，当天早些时候公布第三季度收入增长 22.1%，达到 764.7 亿元人民币（合 106.9 亿美元），而去年同期为 626.2 亿元人民币。一年前的同一时期。</p>   <p>The result compared with the 75.59 billion average of 15 analyst estimates compiled by LSEG.翻译:该结果与 LSEG 编制的 15 名分析师平均预期 755.9 亿美元进行了比较。</p>   <p>Meituan posted a profit of 3.59 billion yuan versus profit of 1.22 billion yuan a year earlier.翻译:美团点评净利润为35.9亿元人民币，而去年同期为12.2亿元人民币。</p>   <p>Quarterly revenue from core local commerce, which includes food delivery as well as Meituan Instashopping, rose 24.5% to 57.69 billion yuan.翻译:包括外卖和美团Instashopping在内的核心本地商业的季度收入增长24.5%，达到576.9亿元人民币。</p>   <p>Revenue from in-store, hotel booking, and travel sector businesses benefited from a domestic travel rebound over the summer with transaction volume rising 90% year on year.翻译:到店、酒店预订、旅游板块业务收入受益于夏季国内旅游反弹，交易量同比增长90%。</p>   <p>Meituan in May expanded beyond mainland China to Hong Kong with new food delivery business KeeTa, and is reportedly eyeing further international expansion, possibly to Southeast Asia.翻译:美团5月通过新的食品配送业务KeeTa将业务从中国大陆扩展到香港，据报道，美团正在考虑进一步国际扩张，可能会扩展到东南亚。</p>    <span>Reporting by Casey Hall; Additional reporting by Brenda Goh; Editing by Christopher Cushing, Edmund Klamann and Mark Porter翻译:凯西·霍尔报道； Brenda Goh 的补充报道；编辑：克里斯托弗·库欣、埃德蒙·克拉曼和马克·波特</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 13:54:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3LAFRRDWWRPYJCMN5D5YZP4YS4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/china-food-delivery-firm-meituans-q3-revenue-beats-estimates-2023-11-28/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Casey Hall]]></author>
            
                
                <category>MEITUAN</category>
                
                <category>RESULTS/ (UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：中国支付宝将以近4亿美元出售其在印度Zomato的股份]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/4pJdKTBxTRuMiGNy9xgeKRMX2DA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/I2OK77FIFNMLZENCBCDS26RMIA.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of Indian food delivery company Zomato翻译:印度外卖公司Zomato插画图" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of Indian food delivery company Zomato is seen on its app on a mobile phone displayed in front of its company website in this illustration picture taken July 14, 2021. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张 2021 年 7 月 14 日拍摄的插图图片中，可以在手机应用程序上看到印度食品配送公司 Zomato 的徽标，该应用程序显示在其公司网站前。REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Chinese payments group Alipay plans to sell its 3.4% stake in Indian food delivery giant Zomato <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ZOMT.NS" target="_blank">(ZOMT.NS)</a> for nearly $400 million through block deals on Indian stock exchanges, according to three sources and a Reuters review of the deal's term sheet.翻译:据三位消息人士和路透社对交易条款清单的审查，中国支付集团支付宝计划通过印度证券交易所的大宗交易，以近 4 亿美元的价格出售其持有的印度食品配送巨头 Zomato <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ZOMT.NS" target="_blank">(ZOMT.NS)</a> 3.4% 的股份。</p>   <p>Alipay, owned by Ant Group, will offload its entire 3.44% stake in the deal, the term sheet seen by Reuters showed.翻译:路透社看到的条款清单显示，蚂蚁集团旗下的支付宝将出售其在此次交易中全部 3.44% 的股份。</p>   <p>Bank of America and Morgan Stanley are advisers on the deal, which is likely to be executed later this week on Indian exchanges, said the three sources, who declined to be named as the plan is private.翻译:这三位消息人士表示，美国银行和摩根士丹利是该交易的顾问，该交易可能于本周晚些时候在印度交易所执行。由于该计划是私人的，因此他们拒绝透露姓名。</p>   <p>Zomato, Bank of America and Morgan Stanley did not immediately respond to a request for comment. Alipay also did not respond outside regular business hours.翻译:Zomato、美国银行和摩根士丹利没有立即回应置评请求。支付宝在正常营业时间之外也没有做出回应。</p>   <p>Zomato shares have surged more than 90% this year, after falling by more than half in 2022 when tech stocks struggled around the world.翻译:Zomato 股价在 2022 年全球科技股陷入困境时下跌了一半以上，但今年已飙升超过 90%。</p>   <p>Alipay "wants to cash out ... the (market) timing is good," said the first source, referring to the rapid rise in Zomato's shares in recent months.翻译:第一位消息人士表示，支付宝“想要套现……（市场）时机很好”，他指的是近几个月来 Zomato 股价的快速上涨。</p>   <p>The block deals are set to be executed at 111.28 rupees per share, a 2.2% discount to Zomato's close on Tuesday, the term sheet said.翻译:条款清单称，大宗交易将以每股 111.28 卢比的价格执行，较 Zomato 周二收盘价折让 2.2%。</p>   <p>In October, Japan's SoftBank <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9984.T" target="_blank">(9984.T)</a> sold a 1.1% stake in Zomato, which is India's biggest food delivery service. Demand for online ordering has rapidly grown in recent years, prompting companies like Zomato to aggressively expand.翻译:10月，日本软银<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9984.T" target="_blank">（9984.T）</a>出售了印度最大的食品配送服务公司Zomato 1.1%的股份。近年来，在线订购的需求迅速增长，促使 Zomato 等公司积极扩张。</p>   <p>Alipay's exit from Zomato comes as other Chinese investors have been paring their stakes in Indian companies. In August, China's Antfin <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/paytm-ceo-sharma-buy-103-stake-co-antfin-holding-2023-08-07/">sold</a> a 10.3% stake in Indian financial giant Paytm <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PAYT.NS" target="_blank">(PAYT.NS)</a>.翻译:支付宝退出 Zomato 之际，其他中国投资者纷纷减持印度公司的股份。 8月，中国Antfin <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/paytm-ceo-sharma-buy-103-stake-co-antfin-holding-2023-08-07/">出售了</a>印度金融巨头Paytm <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PAYT.NS" target="_blank">（PAYT.NS）</a> 10.3%的股份。</p>   <p>Tech stocks such as Zomato have staged a rebound after a drubbing last year amid a market meltdown, when investors also <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/zombie-unicorns-indian-startups-go-feast-famine-2022-05-18/">raised questions</a> about sky-high valuations of some Indian startups that had made their stock market debut in recent years.翻译:Zomato 等科技股在经历了去年市场崩盘的惨败后现已实现反弹，当时投资者还对一些近年来首次在股市首次亮相的印度初创公司的天价估值<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/zombie-unicorns-indian-startups-go-feast-famine-2022-05-18/">提出了质疑</a>。</p>    <span>Reporting by M. Sriram; Editing by Aditya Kalra and Susan Fenton翻译:M. Sriram 报道； Aditya Kalra 和 Susan Fenton 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 13:45:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">SAC33XTK7JKWLHKLCM2PISG7U4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-alipay-plans-near-400-mln-stake-sale-indias-zomato-sources-2023-11-28/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[M. Sriram]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ZOMATO</category>
                
                <category>INDIA/ANT (UPDATE 1, EXCLUSIVE, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国恒大集团对母公司提起法律诉讼]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/x1Un4BLp4DPSUue4O3jzAcJENxA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/N6SYACE4HVNN7JLTSD4D725HUE.jpg" alt="The company logo is seen on the headquarters of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen翻译:中国恒大集团深圳总部的公司标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The company logo is seen on the headquarters of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen翻译:中国恒大集团深圳总部的公司标志, Guangdong province, China September 26, 2021. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2021年9月26日，该公司标志出现在中国广东省深圳的中国恒大集团总部。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Evergrande Property Services Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">(6666.HK)</a> said on Tuesday one of its units had commenced legal proceedings against Hengda Real Estate Group Company and embattled developer China Evergrande <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a>, among others.翻译:恒大物业服务集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">（6666.HK）</a>周二表示，其旗下之一已对恒大地产集团公司和陷入困境的开发商中国恒大<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）</a>等公司提起法律诉讼。</p>   <p>The unit, Jinbi Property Management Company, has commenced the proceedings for the recovery of about 2 billion yuan ($279.60 million) deposit certificate pledge guarantees.翻译:该单位金碧物业管理公司已启动追回约20亿元人民币（2.796亿美元）存单质押担保的程序。</p>   <p>The proceedings are related to the enforcement of Evergrande Property Services' deposit pledge of about 13.4 billion yuan.翻译:该诉讼涉及恒大物业约134亿元存款质押的执行。</p>   <p>Jinbi Property has also commenced legal proceedings against Shenzhen Qihang Metals Materials Company, Guizhou Guangjuyuan Real Estate Development and Hengda Real Estate Group Guiyang Property.翻译:金碧置业还对深圳市启航金属材料公司、贵州广聚源房地产开发有限公司和恒大地产集团贵阳置业提起法律诉讼。</p>   <p>In February, parent Evergrande had <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/china-evergrande-says-directors-fell-below-standards-property-unit-probe-2023-02-15/">said</a> it was in talks with Evergrande Property Services to repay the funds.翻译:今年2月，母公司恒大集团曾<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/china-evergrande-says-directors-fell-below-standards-property-unit-probe-2023-02-15/">表示</a>，正在与恒大物业洽谈偿还资金事宜。</p>   <p>In <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-ceo-cfo-step-down-after-probe-into-property-services-unit-2022-07-22/">July 2022</a>, Evergrande's chief executive and its finance head resigned after a preliminary probe found their involvement in diverting loans secured by Evergrande Property Services.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-ceo-cfo-step-down-after-probe-into-property-services-unit-2022-07-22/">2022年7月</a>，恒大首席执行官和财务负责人因涉嫌挪用恒大物业担保贷款而辞职。</p>   <p>Evergrande was investigating how deposits worth 13.4 billion yuan belonging to Evergrande Property Services were used as collateral for pledge guarantees and seized by banks.翻译:恒大正在调查恒大物业的134亿元存款如何被用作质押担保的抵押品，并被银行扣押。</p>   <p>Evergrande Property Services has received a notice from the Guangzhou Intermediate People's Court of Guangdong Province formally accepting the filing of the case, it said on Tuesday.翻译:恒大物业周二表示，已收到广东省广州市中级人民法院正式立案的通知。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1532 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.1532 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Echha Jain in Bengaluru; Editing by Devika Syamnath翻译:Echha Jain 班加罗尔报道；编辑：德维卡·萨姆纳特</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 13:07:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">JIINBKCETFJFXLK3K5BKG42UHY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-evergrande-unit-commences-legal-proceedings-against-parent-2023-11-28/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/DEBT</category>
                
                <category>CHINA EVERGRANDE (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[汽车业务负责人表示，华为部分汽车业务正走向独立]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/AQzvxq611KtXlarqmEf-wbJVdGU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/H6FXB5CTDRINRAXIAVDL4X4NJY.jpg" alt="The World Artificial Intelligence Cannes Festival翻译:世界人工智能戛纳节" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Visitors walk past the Huawei logo at the World Artificial Intelligence Cannes Festival (WAICF) in Cannes, France, February 10, 2023. REUTERS/Eric Gaillard/File Photo翻译:2023 年 2 月 10 日，在法国戛纳举行的世界人工智能戛纳节 (WAICF) 上，参观者走过华为标志。路透社/Eric Gaillard/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Huawei Technologies (HWT.UL) said some of its automotive partnerships, having gained skills in user experience, product design and marketing, were now ready to move towards independent operations and investment.翻译:华为技术有限公司 (HWT.UL) 表示，其一些汽车合作伙伴在用户体验、产品设计和营销方面获得了技能，现在已准备好转向独立运营和投资。</p>   <p>Huawei's managing director and chairman of its smart car solutions unit Richard Yu made the comments while speaking at a launch event in Shanghai for the Luxeed S7 sedan that Huawei has jointly developed with Chinese automaker Chery(CHERY.UL).翻译:华为董事总经理兼智能汽车解决方案部门董事长余承东在上海举行的华为与中国汽车制造商奇瑞(CHERY.UL)联合开发的Luxeed S7轿车发布会上发表讲话时发表了上述言论。</p>   <p>On Sunday, Huawei announced <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-huawei-changan-auto-form-joint-auto-systems-venture-2023-11-26/">it would launch</a> a new joint company owned up to 40% with automaker Changan Auto (SASAGG.UL).翻译:周日，华为宣布<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-huawei-changan-auto-form-joint-auto-systems-venture-2023-11-26/">将与汽车制造商长安汽车 (SASAGG.UL) 成立</a>一家新的合资公司，持股比例为 40%。</p>   <p>The Huawei-backed electric vehicle (EV) brand Aito has received more than 100,000 orders for its revamped M7 model since going on sale two-and-a-half months ago, Yu said, calling it another milestone for the company.翻译:余表示，自两个半月前上市以来，华为支持的电动汽车（EV）品牌Aito的改款M7车型已收到超过10万份订单，称这是该公司的另一个里程碑。</p>   <p>Huawei has repeatedly said it does not make cars on its own but only helps other automakers make better vehicles.翻译:华为多次表示，它不自己生产汽车，只是帮助其他汽车制造商生产更好的汽车。</p>   <p>On Tuesday, Yu said Huawei has three models for working with autos manufacturers: providing parts, providing smart solutions or designing and building vehicles.翻译:周二，余承东表示，华为与汽车制造商合作有三种模式：提供零部件、提供智能解决方案或设计和制造汽车。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Kirton; Editing by Jacqueline Wong翻译:大卫·科顿报道；编辑：黄杰奎琳</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 08:23:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">WPFJFNBBWNMUTI7GBLKJXF5FGU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/some-huawei-car-businesses-moving-towards-independence-autos-chief-says-2023-11-28/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>HUAWEI/AUTOS</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
