<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub-production-cbbc.up.railway.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 02:15:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[白宫计划于 11 月在旧金山举行拜登与习近平会晤]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TQRP9MsUnS58ZG-h3oXnCadUKCM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/S555ZKOBKJMMVCM7YW5VSPBET4.jpg" alt="G20 summit in Bali" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of the G20 leaders' summit in Bali, Indonesia, November 14, 2022.  REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:美国总统乔·拜登于 2022 年 11 月 14 日在印度尼西亚巴厘岛举行的 G20 领导人峰会期间会见中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>       <p>Teams for U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping have an agreement in principle for them to meet in San Francisco in November but important details need to be hammered out, a senior Biden administration official said on Tuesday.翻译:拜登政府一位高级官员周二表示，美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平的团队已原则上达成协议，将于 11 月在旧金山会面，但重要细节需要敲定。</p>   <p>The official amplified on remarks by White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre at her daily press briefing, where she said the two leaders are aiming to have a "constructive conversation" on the sidelines of the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation forum in San Francisco.翻译:这位官员详细阐述了白宫新闻秘书卡琳·让-皮埃尔在每日新闻发布会上的讲话，她表示两国领导人计划在旧金山亚太经济合作论坛期间进行“建设性对话”。</p>   <p>"There is an agreement in principle to meet in San Francisco in November. We are still working through important details needed to finalize those plans," the official said.翻译:这位官员表示：“原则上已达成协议，将于 11 月在旧金山举行会议。我们仍在研究敲定这些计划所需的重要细节。”</p>   <p>Biden, his national security adviser Jake Sullivan and Secretary of State Antony Blinken <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/blinken-wang-meet-us-china-gear-up-towards-expected-leaders-summit-2023-10-27/">discussed the prospect</a> for a Biden-Xi summit in talks with Chinese foreign minister Wang Yi at the White House and at the State Department on Friday.翻译:拜登、他的国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文和国务卿安东尼·布林肯周五在白宫和国务院与中国外交部长王毅会谈时<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/blinken-wang-meet-us-china-gear-up-towards-expected-leaders-summit-2023-10-27/">讨论了拜登与习近平峰会的前景</a>。</p>   <p>The APEC summit is to take place in mid-November.翻译:APEC峰会将于11月中旬举行。</p>    <span>Reporting by Steve Holland, Jeff Mason and Costas Pitas; Editing by Eric Beech and Chizu Nomiyama翻译:史蒂夫·霍兰德、杰夫·梅森和科斯塔斯·皮塔斯报道；编辑：Eric Beech 和 Chizu Nomiyama</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 02:11:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">UIVZPTLHINLDZLP2JRF26XMNM4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/white-house-aims-biden-xi-meeting-san-francisco-november-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/BIDEN</category>
                
                <category>XI (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国在出生率下降的情况下启动全国人口普查]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/SB8_jHOE5JGUnXvgmkvbM-ml1P8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/43MRVZIIF5KVJBNC3KZNJFHPJE.jpg" alt="A parents pushes a stroller with a baby in a park in Shanghai" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A parents pushes a stroller with a baby in a park in Shanghai, China, April 2, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2023 年 4 月 2 日，中国上海的一个公园里，一对父母推着婴儿车。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/NQXwsQC5FxStJ1DXnWcqqCijjjM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NDVX7PNRTNM7NN6ZAPI7PVLMZI.jpg" alt="A little girl sits with her dad in a park in Shanghai" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A little girl sits with her dad in a park in Shanghai, China, April 2, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2023 年 4 月 2 日，一个小女孩和她的父亲坐在中国上海的一个公园里。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>China will begin polling 1.4 million people on Wednesday in a survey on population changes, as authorities struggle to incentivise people to have more children amid a declining birth rate and the first population drop in more than six decades.翻译:中国将于周三开始对 140 万人进行人口变化调查，在出生率下降和六十多年来首次人口下降的情况下，当局努力激励人们生育更多孩子。</p>   <p>The poll, which was announced on Oct. 10 in an unexpected move, will focus on urban and rural areas throughout the country. The survey will be based on a sample of 500,000 households and last for around two weeks until Nov. 15, China's National Bureau of Statistics said.翻译:这项民意调查于10月10日出人意料地宣布，将重点关注全国城市和农村地区。中国国家统计局表示，此次调查将抽样50万户家庭，持续两周左右，直至11月15日。</p>   <p>It will help provide a basis to monitor China's population developmental changes and for the government and Communist Party to formulate national economic, social development and population related policies, it said.翻译:它将有助于监测中国人口发展变化，为政府和共产党制定国民经济、社会发展和人口相关政策提供依据。</p>   <p>China last conducted its once-in-a-decade census in November 2020 which showed it grew at the slowest pace since the first modern population survey in the 1950s.翻译:中国上一次进行十年一次的人口普查是在 2020 年 11 月，结果显示，中国的增长速度是 20 世纪 50 年代第一次现代人口调查以来最慢的。</p>   <p>Population development has often been linked to the strength and "rejuvenation" of the country in state media amid the declining birth rate and widespread concerns by citizens on the difficulties of raising children.翻译:在出生率下降和公民普遍担心养育困难的情况下，官方媒体常常将人口发展与国家的强大和“复兴”联系起来。</p>   <p>High childcare costs and having to stop their careers have put many women off having more children or any at all. Gender discrimination and traditional stereotypes of women caring for the children are still widespread throughout the country.翻译:高昂的育儿费用和不得不停止自己的职业生涯，让许多女性不愿生更多的孩子，甚至根本不想生孩子。性别歧视和妇女照顾孩子的传统陈规定型观念在全国仍然普遍存在。</p>   <p>Authorities have in recent months increased rhetoric on sharing the duty of child rearing but paternity leave is still limited in most provinces.翻译:近几个月来，当局加大了关于分担抚养子女责任的言论，但大多数省份的陪产假仍然受到限制。</p>   <p>The country reported a drop of roughly 850,000 people for a population of 1.41175 billion in 2022, marking the first decline since 1961, the last year of China's Great Famine.翻译:该国报告称，2022年，中国总人口为14.1175亿，减少约85万人，这是自1961年（中国大饥荒的最后一年）以来的首次下降。</p>    <span>Reporting by Farah Master; Editing by Michael Perry翻译:法拉大师报道；迈克尔·佩里编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 01:31:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">K3U6PWN7GJKRLHLSSAPE5CCXSU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-kicks-off-nationwide-population-survey-amid-declining-birth-rate-2023-11-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ASIA</category>
                
                <category>POPULATION/CHINA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[微型股在中国低迷的股市中大放异彩]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/2pShcVGG0h-3lnHys_k_w0BImdo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/F6OZRCANIJOFTKAQL2QAGH5KYU.jpg" alt="Investors look at an electronic board showing stock information at a brokerage house in Shanghai" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Investors look at an electronic board showing stock information at a brokerage house in Shanghai, China September 7, 2018. REUTERS/Aly Song翻译:2018 年 9 月 7 日，中国上海一家券商，投资者查看显示股票信息的电子板。REUTERS/Aly Song</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's annus horribilis has seen its stock markets fall, funds run up losses and foreign investors run for the exit. But areas of the market dominated by small stocks and frequented by the country's retail investors have done surprisingly well.翻译:中国的灾难之年见证了股市下跌、基金亏损增加、外国投资者纷纷撤离。但以小型股票为主且该国散户投资者经常光顾的市场领域却表现出奇的好。</p>   <p>Scores of retail investors are dabbling in micro-cap stocks - stocks whose market capitalisation is tiny - operating under the radar of big funds and investors and their massive market-moving flows.翻译:许多散户投资者正在涉足微型股（市值很小的股票），这些股票在大型基金和投资者及其巨大的市场波动资金的关注下运作。</p>   <p>Take self-employed retail trader Joseph Cui, for instance. By buying micro-cap stocks of artificial intelligence(AI) companies, Cui has picked a corner of the market big fund managers can barely squeeze into, and made a fat 20% return on his 2-million-yuan ($273,347.27) investment.翻译:以个体零售商人 Joseph Cui 为例。通过购买人工智能（AI）公司的小盘股，崔天凯选择了大型基金经理难以挤入的市场一角，并在他的 200 万元（273,347.27 美元）投资中获得了 20% 的丰厚回报。</p>   <p>"It's a tough environment for big capital. But for short-term money, it's easy play," Cui said.翻译:“对于大资本来说，这是一个艰难的环境。但对于短期资金来说，这很容易，”崔说。</p>   <p>Strategies such as Cui's stand out this year in a stock market depressed by China's wobbly economy, heightened geopolitical risks and surging overseas interest rates.翻译:今年，在中国经济不稳定、地缘政治风险加剧和海外利率飙升导致股市低迷的情况下，崔天凯等策略脱颖而出。</p>   <p>The Wind Micro Market Cap Index, which tracks the 400 China-listed A-shares with market value typically less than 3 billion yuan each, is up 37% so far this year. In contrast, the blue-chip CSI300 Index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI300" target="_blank">(.CSI300)</a> has lost 8%.翻译:Wind微市值指数追踪400只中国上市A股，每只市值通常低于30亿元人民币，今年迄今已上涨37%。相比之下，蓝筹股沪深300指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI300" target="_blank">(.CSI300)</a>下跌了8%。</p>   <p>While institution-dominated companies with large market values in sectors such as banking and manufacturing have faced selling pressure from investment funds in a struggling economy, micro stocks have become neat counter-cyclical targets.翻译:尽管银行和制造业等行业中市值较大的机构主导型公司在经济陷入困境时面临投资基金的抛售压力，但微型股票已成为绝佳的反周期目标。</p>   <p>Such stocks lend themselves to speculation, particularly when tied in some way to Chinese chip behemoth <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-chip-curbs-give-huawei-chance-fill-nvidia-void-china-2023-10-20/">Huawei Technologies</a> or hot concepts such as AI, making the retail rush somewhat similar to last year's meme-stock frenzy in the United States, albeit without short-sellers on the other side of the trades.翻译:此类股票容易引发投机，特别是当以某种方式与中国芯片巨头<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-chip-curbs-give-huawei-chance-fill-nvidia-void-china-2023-10-20/">华为技术公司</a>或人工智能等热门概念联系在一起时，使得散户热潮与去年美国的迷因股票狂潮有些相似，尽管没有卖空者交易的另一面。</p>   <p>Chinese regulators meanwhile seem cool with the micro-cap craze, even though it is worryingly reminiscent of the casino-like Chinese market culture of more than a decade ago.翻译:与此同时，中国监管机构似乎对微型股热潮表现得很冷静，尽管这令人担忧地让人想起十多年前赌场般的中国市场文化。</p>   <p>"Regulators appear to be greenlighting speculative activities so as to prop up the stock market," said Yuan Yuwei, fund manager at Water Wisdom Asset Management.翻译:“监管机构似乎为投机活动开绿灯，以支撑股市，”水智慧资产管理公司基金经理袁宇伟表示。</p>   <p>"The connivance is hurting the system of value investment, encouraging misbehaviours, and is negative to long-term health of the market."翻译:“这种纵容正在损害价值投资体系，鼓励不当行为，对市场的长期健康不利。”</p>   <p>The China Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC) did not immediately respond to a request for comment.翻译:中国证监会（CSRC）没有立即回应置评请求。</p>    <h 1="">CONCEPT STOCKS</h>  <p>Retail investor Helen Wu is not bashful talking about "stir-frying" - the practice of pumping up stocks with hot concepts.翻译:散户吴海伦毫不羞涩地谈论“炒作”——用热门概念炒作股票的做法。</p>   <p>"We mainly pick stocks with a big story to tell, such as AI or Huawei, so that stir-frying becomes easy," Wu said, referring to the mania in China around ChatGPT, as well as much-hyped technological breakthroughs at U.S.-blacklisted firm Huawei.翻译:“我们主要挑选有大故事的股票，比如人工智能或华为，这样炒起来就容易了，”吴说，他指的是中国对ChatGPT的狂热，以及美国大肆炒作的技术突破——华为被列入黑名单。</p>   <p>"We don't touch stocks with big institutional holdings, due to big selling pressure in a downbeat economy."翻译:“由于经济低迷，抛售压力巨大，我们不会接触机构大量持有的股票。”</p>   <p>Retail investors are a big force in China. CSRC Chairman Yi Huiman notes that their transactions accounted for about 60% of the total A-shares turnover in late 2022.翻译:散户投资者是中国的一股重要力量。证监会主席易会满指出，他们的交易额约占2022年底A股总成交额的60%。</p>   <p>An index tracking China's actively-managed equity funds <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI930890" target="_blank">(.CSI930890)</a> has slumped 14% this year after sell-offs in once favoured sectors such as battery companies and spirit makers. In contrast, an index tracking ChatGPT concept stocks such as 360 Security Technology <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601360.SS" target="_blank">(601360.SS)</a> and TRS Information Technology <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300229.SZ" target="_blank">(300229.SZ)</a> has soared more than 40%.翻译:在电池公司和烈酒制造商等曾经受青睐的行业遭到抛售后，追踪中国主动管理股票基金的指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI930890" target="_blank">(.CSI930890)</a>今年已下跌14%。相比之下，追踪360安全科技<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601360.SS" target="_blank">（601360.SS）</a> 、TRS信息科技<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300229.SZ" target="_blank">（300229.SZ）</a>等ChatGPT概念股的指数则飙升超过40%。</p>   <p>In a recent case, loss-making Ningbo Shenglong Automotive Powertrain System Co <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/603178.SS" target="_blank">(603178.SS)</a> jumped nearly 250% in three weeks on speculation that is a supplier for Huawei's planned electric vehicle, forcing the company to flag investment risks last week.翻译:在最近的一个案例中，亏损的宁波盛龙汽车动力系统股份有限公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/603178.SS" target="_blank">（603178.SS）</a>因猜测其是华为计划中的电动汽车的供应商而在三周内上涨了近250%，迫使该公司上周提示了投资风险。</p>   <p>Lu Deyong, a retail trader, said he made a 100% profit of 100,000 yuan betting on a Huawei concept stock, Seres Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601127.SS" target="_blank">(601127.SS)</a>, whose shares doubled in the past two months even while it booked a loss for the first three quarters of 2023.翻译:散户陆德勇表示，他押注华为概念股塞雷斯集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601127.SS" target="_blank">（601127.SS）</a> 10万元，盈利100%，该股前三个月亏损，但近两个月翻了一倍。 2023 年季度。</p>   <p>"Market buys Seres for the imagination of its future, not its current fundamentals," Lu said.翻译:“市场购买 Seres 是为了对其未来的想象，而不是其当前的基本面，”卢说。</p>   <p>Some brokerages are starting to recommend micro stocks to clients.翻译:一些券商开始向客户推荐微型股票。</p>   <p>GF Securities said in an October strategy report that buying micro stocks is part of a new investment paradigm in a stock market suffering from anaemic growth, and global decoupling risks.翻译:广发证券在10月策略报告中表示，在面临增长乏力和全球脱钩风险的股市中，购买微型股是新投资范式的一部分。</p>   <p>"Speculation in concept stocks has been active throughout the year, and regulators have their eyes half-closed," said Huang Yan, general manager of Shanghai QiuYang Capital Co.翻译:上海秋阳资本有限公司总经理黄岩表示：“全年概念股炒作活跃，监管层却是半睁着眼睛。”</p>   <p>"A crackdown would dampen an already lifeless market."翻译:“打击行动将削弱本已毫无生气的市场。”</p>   <p>($1 = 7.3167 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.3167 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Jason Xue, Samuel Shen in Shanghai, Summer Zhen in Hong Kong
Editing by Vidya Ranganathan and Simon Cameron-Moore翻译:Jason Xu、Samuel Shen 在上海报道，Summer Jen 在香港报道 Vidya Ranganathan 和 Simon Cameron-Moore 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 01:04:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">H7C7CK24AFID3AHETQBHHNEYW4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/micro-stocks-shine-chinas-flagging-share-market-2023-11-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jason Xue, Summer Zhen]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>STOCKS/RETAIL</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[焦点转向美联储，日元疲软]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UuEr4UsZqSatLos22yaVW24-7sA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YOOGVMR5UNLVBMEPAHAWP3UVEM.jpg" alt="FILE PHOTO: Illustration picture of Japanese yen and U.S. dollar banknotes" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Banknotes of Japanese yen and U.S. dollar are seen in this illustration picture taken September 23, 2022. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo翻译:这张摄于 2022 年 9 月 23 日的插图照片中可以看到日元和美元纸币。REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>The yen wobbled near 15-year lows on the euro and a one-year trough on the dollar on Wednesday, having slid on bets that a tweak of Japan's yield control policy isn't enough to close wide interest rate gaps that have pressured the currency for years.翻译:周三，日元兑欧元汇率跌至近15年低点，兑美元汇率跌至一年低点，原因是市场押注日本收益率控制政策的调整不足以缩小令日元承压的巨大利差多年。</p>   <p>Moves in early Asia trade were modest ahead of a U.S. Federal Reserve meeting later in the day - where rates are seen on hold - and the release of U.S. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/us-treasury-seen-boosting-auction-sizes-budget-deficit-worsens-2023-10-29/">Treasury refunding details</a>.翻译:在当天晚些时候召开的美联储会议（利率维持不变）以及美国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/us-treasury-seen-boosting-auction-sizes-budget-deficit-worsens-2023-10-29/">国债退款细节</a>公布之前，亚洲早盘交易走势温和。</p>   <p>The New Zealand dollar slipped 0.4% to $0.5805 as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-labor-costs-growth-beat-expectations-third-quarter-2023-10-31/">softer-than-forecast employment data</a> cemented expectations of an end to interest rate hikes.翻译:纽元兑美元下跌 0.4% 至 0.5805 美元，因<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-labor-costs-growth-beat-expectations-third-quarter-2023-10-31/">就业数据弱于预期，</a>巩固了加息结束的预期。</p>   <p>Against the dollar, the yen fell about 1.7% overnight, touching a low of 151.74 - a whisker from the 151.94 level that prompted intervention a year ago. The yen breached 160 per euro for the first time since 2008.翻译:日元兑美元汇率隔夜下跌约 1.7%，触及 151.74 的低点，距离一年前促使干预的 151.94 水平仅一步之遥。日元兑欧元汇率自 2008 年以来首次突破 160。</p>   <p>It was last at 151.27 per dollar - down 13% for the year so far and 38% from its pandemic peak - and at 160.05 per euro.翻译:最新汇率为 151.27 美元兑 151.27 美元，今年迄今已下跌 13%，较疫情高峰下降 38%，最后为 160.05 欧元兑 160.05 美元。</p>   <p>Intervention remained high on investors' watch list, with Japan's top currency diplomat noting on Wednesday that recent moves seemed to be speculative, and that authorities were on "standby" to step in. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/japans-top-fx-diplomat-says-recent-yen-moves-one-sided-speculative-2023-10-31/"> read more </a>翻译:干预仍然是投资者关注的重点，日本最高货币外交官周三指出，最近的举动似乎是投机性的，当局正“待命”介入。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/japans-top-fx-diplomat-says-recent-yen-moves-one-sided-speculative-2023-10-31/">阅读更多</a></p>   <p>The Bank of Japan <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/boj-likely-lift-inflation-forecasts-debate-yield-controls-future-2023-10-30/">raised inflation forecasts</a> on Tuesday, but not policy rates. It redefined its 1% limit on 10-year government bond yields as a reference rate, rather than a hard cap, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/japan-unshackles-its-sliding-bond-market-2023-10-31/">effectively ending</a> its strict yield-curve control policy.翻译:日本央行周二<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/boj-likely-lift-inflation-forecasts-debate-yield-controls-future-2023-10-30/">上调通胀预测</a>，但未上调政策利率。它重新定义了10年期国债收益率1%的上限作为参考利率，而不是硬上限，<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/japan-unshackles-its-sliding-bond-market-2023-10-31/">有效结束了</a>严格的收益率曲线控制政策。</p>   <p>Data from the finance ministry also showed Japan <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/japan-did-not-intervene-forex-market-past-month-mof-data-shows-2023-10-31/">did not intervene</a> in currency markets through October.翻译:日本财务省的数据还显示，日本截至 10 月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/japan-did-not-intervene-forex-market-past-month-mof-data-shows-2023-10-31/">都没有干预</a>货币市场。</p>   <p>Taken together, it adds up to "no obvious new official approach to 'muscle' a stronger yen," so traders feel the coast is clear to take up short positions, said Alan Ruskin, macro strategist at Deutsche Bank.翻译:德意志银行(Deutsche Bank)宏观策略师艾伦·拉斯金(Alan Ruskin)表示，总的来说，“没有明显的新官方方法来‘推动’日元走强”，因此交易员认为海岸线显然会建立空头头寸。</p>   <p>"It is now more evident than ever, that a proper turn in dollar/yen is much less dependent on events in Japan than they are on the macro dynamic in the U.S," he said in a note.翻译:他在一份报告中表示：“现在比以往任何时候都更加明显的是，美元/日元汇率的适当转向对日本事件的依赖要小得多，而对美国宏观动态的依赖要小得多。”</p>   <p>On that score the dollar has been helped by the flattering comparison between the U.S. and other large economies. Data on Tuesday showed European growth a little <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/wrapup1-euzo-zone-inflation-growth-slow-ecb-hikes-weigh-2023-10-31/">softer than expected</a> and a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-factory-activity-unexpectedly-contracted-october-2023-10-31/">surprise slump</a> in Chinese factory activity.翻译:从这一点来看，美国与其他大型经济体之间的良好比较对美元有所帮助。周二的数据显示欧洲经济增长略<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/wrapup1-euzo-zone-inflation-growth-slow-ecb-hikes-weigh-2023-10-31/">弱于预期</a>，中国工厂活动<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-factory-activity-unexpectedly-contracted-october-2023-10-31/">意外下滑</a>。</p>   <p>In the U.S. data showed <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-labor-costs-growth-beat-expectations-third-quarter-2023-10-31/">wages and salaries rose solidly</a> last quarter and while consumer confidence ebbed, it fell far less than markets had expected. The euro declined 0.4% on the dollar overnight and nursed losses at $1.0579.翻译:美国的数据显示，上季度<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-labor-costs-growth-beat-expectations-third-quarter-2023-10-31/">工​​资和薪水稳步增长</a>，尽管消费者信心下降，但降幅远低于市场预期。欧元兑美元隔夜下跌 0.4%，跌至 1.0579 美元。</p>   <p>The U.S. dollar index measure against a basket of major currencies rose 0.5% on Tuesday to 106.66. Sterling was steady at $1.2150. China's offshore yuan held at 7.34 per dollar amid a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/some-chinese-institutions-borrow-50-rate-liquidity-squeezed-2023-10-31/">liquidity crunch</a> in the onshore market that drove overnight repo rates as high as 50% as banks scrambled for month-end cash.翻译:周二衡量一篮子主要货币的美元指数上涨0.5%至106.66。英镑稳定在 1.2150 美元。由于在岸市场<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/some-chinese-institutions-borrow-50-rate-liquidity-squeezed-2023-10-31/">流动性紧缩，</a>银行争相获取月末现金，导致隔夜回购利率高达 50%，中国离岸人民币兑美元汇率维持在 7.34 美元。</p>   <p>China's Caixin PMI data will be in focus later on Wednesday, ahead of U.S. manufacturing and private payrolls figures - before the Fed meeting.翻译:周三晚些时候，在美联储会议之前，美国制造业和私人就业数据之前，中国的财新采购经理人指数数据将成为焦点。</p>   <p>U.S. yields rose in early Asia trade, while Japanese yields fell slightly on thin volumes, leaving the spread between benchmark 10-year rates at 398 bps. That is narrower than 414 bps it had hit in October.翻译:美国国债收益率在亚洲早盘上涨，而日本国债收益率因成交量清淡而小幅下跌，使得基准 10 年期国债收益率之间的利差达到 398 个基点。这比 10 月份触及的 414 个基点要窄。</p>   <p>"Nominal 10Y rate spreads now warrant dollar/yen a fair bit lower, i.e., 147-8," said James Malcolm, UBS currency strategist based in London.翻译:瑞银(UBS)驻伦敦货币策略师詹姆斯·马尔科姆(James Malcolm)表示，“10年期名义利差现在使得美元/日元汇率略微走低，即147比8”。</p>   <p>"Though this relationship is becoming choppier, 10bp has been roughly equivalent to one big figure in spot over the last couple of years."翻译:“尽管这种关系变得更加不稳定，但过去几年 10 个基点大致相当于一个大数字。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Tom Westbrook;
Editing by Shri Navaratnam翻译:汤姆·威斯布鲁克报道；编辑：Shri Navaratnam</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:50:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3TC7B2DZFBLIBGJVPI2OEPL6DA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/yen-languishes-focus-turns-fed-2023-11-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Tom Westbrook]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>FOREX/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[分析：恒大将难以重振债务重组计划]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/o1czUFEA-z0Z6r3aFTgEsneOpko=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PSJLL2NNTRI27OFGN2LOY7SH4Q.jpg" alt="The company logo is seen on the headquarters of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The company logo is seen on the headquarters of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen, Guangdong province, China September 26, 2021. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2021年9月26日，该公司标志出现在中国广东省深圳的中国恒大集团总部。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China Evergrande <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a> is trying to stave off liquidation by revising its debt restructuring plan, but its biggest challenge will be convincing its creditors, and shareholders in two of its units, that the proposal is worth their while.翻译:中国恒大<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）</a>正试图通过修改债务重组计划来避免清算，但其最大的挑战将是说服其债权人以及旗下两个子公司的股东相信该提议是值得的。</p>   <p>A Hong Kong court on Monday gave Evergrande, the world's most indebted property developer, a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-faces-winding-up-challenge-hong-kong-court-2023-10-29/">five week reprieve</a> to come up with a deal. The company, which has more than $300 billion of liabilities, defaulted on its offshore debt in late 2021 and became the poster child of a debt crisis that has since engulfed China's property sector.翻译:香港一家法院周一给予全球负债最重的房地产开发商恒大<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-faces-winding-up-challenge-hong-kong-court-2023-10-29/">五周的缓期</a>以达成交易。该公司负债超过 3000 亿美元，于 2021 年底出现境外债务违约，成为席卷中国房地产行业的债务危机的典型代表。</p>   <p>Evergrande's lawyer said the company was working on a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-faces-winding-up-challenge-hong-kong-court-2023-10-29/">revised plan</a> to "monetise the value" of its two Hong Kong-listed units - Evergrande Property Services Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">(6666.HK)</a> and Evergrande New Energy Vehicle Group (NEV) <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0708.HK" target="_blank">(0708.HK)</a>.翻译:恒大的律师表示，该公司正在制定一项<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-faces-winding-up-challenge-hong-kong-court-2023-10-29/">修订计划</a>，以“将其两个香港上市子公司的价值货币化”——恒大物业服务集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">（6666.HK）</a>和恒大新能源汽车集团（NEV） <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0708.HK" target="_blank">（0708.HK）</a> 。</p>   <p>Sources familiar with the matter told Reuters that plan included allowing Evergrande creditors to swap their debt into equity and bonds tied to these units.翻译:知情人士告诉路透社，该计划包括允许恒大债权人将其债务转换为与这些单位相关的股票和债券。</p>   <p>Evergrande, Evergrande Property Services and Evergrande NEV declined to comment.翻译:恒大、恒大物业和恒大新能源均拒绝置评。</p>   <p>For the plan to proceed, shareholders in both units will need to approve issuing new bonds and a large volume of new shares, a feat restructuring experts said would be time-consuming and difficult to achieve.翻译:为了使该计划得以实施，两个部门的股东将需要批准发行新债券和大量新股，重组专家表示，这一壮举将非常耗时且难以实现。</p>   <p>"Any process to issue new debt would need to take account of the interests of the other shareholders in those subsidiaries," said Mat Ng, a managing director specialising in restructuring at Grant Thornton Hong Kong.翻译:“任何发行新债的程序都需要考虑这些子公司其他股东的利益，”致同香港专门负责重组的董事总经理Mat Ng表示。</p>   <p>"Why would those shareholders want to see new debt issued to replace the existing debt issued by Evergrande, what is the benefit for them?"翻译:“为什么这些股东希望看到恒大发行新债来取代现有债务，对他们来说有什么好处？”</p>   <p>The convertible bonds and equity-linked notes to be issued by these listed units could also be subject to Chinese regulatory approval, industry experts said, even though Evergrande's lawyer told the court these notes faced no regulatory hurdles.翻译:行业专家表示，这些上市单位将发行的可转换债券和股票挂钩票据也可能需要经过中国监管部门的批准，尽管恒大的律师告诉法庭，这些票据没有面临监管障碍。</p>   <p>Evergrande's initial $23 billion offshore debt restructuring plan was thrown off course last month when its billionaire founder Hui Ka Yan was confirmed to be under investigation for suspected criminal activities.翻译:恒大集团最初的230亿美元离岸债务重组计划上个月被搁置，原因是其亿万富翁创始人许家印被证实因涉嫌犯罪活动而接受调查。</p>   <p>Due to an investigation into its flagship property unit, Evergrande was barred by mainland regulators from issuing new dollar bonds, a crucial part of the restructuring. That <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-set-unveil-offshore-debt-restructuring-proposal-2023-03-22/">original</a> plan had also offered options including equity-linked instruments backed by Evergrande and the two listed units.翻译:由于对其旗舰房地产部门进行调查，恒大被内地监管机构禁止发行新的美元债券，这是重组的关键部分。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-set-unveil-offshore-debt-restructuring-proposal-2023-03-22/">最初的</a>计划还提供了选择，包括由恒大和两家上市单位支持的股票挂钩工具。</p>   <p>But even before the plan was derailed by the investigations, some creditors were having a hard time accepting it.翻译:但即使在该计划因调查而脱轨之前，一些债权人也很难接受。</p>   <p>Evergrande did not get the 75% of votes required in one of its debt classes to pass the restructuring terms, five sources with knowledge of the matter told Reuters. These Class C creditors include private lenders holding equity in projects as collateral. Some Chinese banks and pre-IPO investors in this class also vetoed the proposal.翻译:五位知情人士告诉路透社，恒大未能获得其中一项债务类别所需的 75% 的票数以通过重组条款。这些 C 类债权人包括持有项目股权作为抵押品的私人贷款人。一些中资银行和此类IPO前投资者也否决了该提议。</p>   <p>Some Class C creditors told Reuters they vetoed the terms because they were not treated fairly by being offered fewer shares in the property services unit than public bondholders who are in the other creditor class.翻译:一些C级债权人告诉路透社，他们否决了这些条款，因为他们在物业服务部门获得的股份少于其他债权人类别的公共债券持有人，因此没有受到公平对待。</p>   <p>"We hold collaterals, which will help us realize value even if Evergrande is liquidated," said a Class C creditor, who expected a better recovery rate for his debt than the bondholders.翻译:一位C级债权人表示：“我们持有抵押品，即使恒大被清算，这也将帮助我们实现价值。”他预计自己的债务回收率会比债券持有人更高。</p>   <p>Evergrande has been focusing on negotiating with a major group of bondholders, and had gained their support for the initial restructuring deal. But now they are also unhappy with the revised terms, three people familiar with the matter said.翻译:恒大一直专注于与主要债券持有人群体进行谈判，并获得了他们对初步重组协议的支持。但三名知情人士表示，现在他们对修改后的条款也不满意。</p>   <p>"As the judge said in court, a winding-up may be better for us because a restructuring carried out by a liquidator would treat all creditors fairly," said another Class C creditor. Both creditors declined to be named as they were not authorised to speak to media.翻译:另一位 C 级债权人表示：“正如法官在法庭上所说，清盘可能对我们更好，因为清算人进行的重组会公平对待所有债权人。”两位债权人均拒绝透露姓名，因为他们无权接受媒体采访。</p>    <span>Reporting by Clare Jim and Xie Yu in HONG KONG, Scott Murdoch in SYDNEY; Editing by Miral Fahmy翻译:克莱尔·吉姆和谢宇在香港报道，斯科特·默多克在悉尼报道；米拉尔·法赫米编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZQPXW6AXUBNAJEF7L4ON744U6U</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/evergrande-will-struggle-revive-its-debt-restructuring-plan-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Clare Jim, Yu Xie, Scott Murdoch]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/DEBT</category>
                
                <category>EVERGRANDE (REPEAT, ANALYSIS)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早盘竞价：日本剧烈的外汇、债券市场分歧]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/rKsMzOdMo8VpeTL-bdreABf9Jhg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CMFCPYVCTFOOLA3UM4F6452GSQ.jpg" alt="Japanese yen media event in Tokyo" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A worker holds samples of new Japanese yen banknotes at a factory of the National Printing Bureau producing Bank of Japan notes at a media event about the new notes scheduled to be introduced in 2024, in Tokyo, Japan, November 21, 2022. REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/File Photo翻译:2022 年 11 月 21 日，在日本东京举行的关于计划于 2024 年推出的新纸币的媒体活动上，一名工人在国家印刷局一家生产日本银行纸币的工厂里拿着新日元纸币的样品。 REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A look at the day ahead in Asian markets from Jamie McGeever, financial markets columnist.翻译:金融市场专栏作家杰米·麦克吉弗 (Jamie McGeever) 对亚洲市场未来一天的展望。</p>   <p>It promises to be another dramatic day in Asia on Wednesday, as investors digest the huge moves in Japan's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/japan-unshackles-its-sliding-bond-market-2023-10-31/">government bond</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/yen-rises-speculation-boj-policy-tweak-dollar-ebbs-2023-10-31/">currency</a> markets and brace for a raft of potentially market-moving economic indicators from across the continent.翻译:周三亚洲有望成为又一个戏剧性的一天，投资者将消化日本<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/japan-unshackles-its-sliding-bond-market-2023-10-31/">政府债券</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/yen-rises-speculation-boj-policy-tweak-dollar-ebbs-2023-10-31/">货币</a>市场的巨大波动，并为来自整个非洲大陆的一系列可能影响市场的经济指标做好准备。</p>   <p>The U.S. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/fed-buzz-words-watch-fed-sets-rates-2023-10-31/">Federal Reserve</a> policy decision and details from the U.S. Treasury outlining its $776 billion fourth quarter <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-treasury-borrow-776-billion-q4-2023-10-30/">borrowing needs</a> are the two major global events on Wednesday. But Asian markets' first chance to react to that will be Thursday.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/fed-buzz-words-watch-fed-sets-rates-2023-10-31/">美联储的</a>政策决定和美国财政部概述其第四季度 7,760 亿美元<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-treasury-borrow-776-billion-q4-2023-10-30/">借款需求的</a>详细信息是周三的两大全球事件。但亚洲市场对此做出反应的第一个机会将是周四。</p>   <p>Before then, purchasing managers index reports for several countries, including India, South Korea and Indonesia are on tap, as well as Indonesian inflation, South Korean trade, Hong Kong retail sales and Australian housing data.翻译:在此之前，印度、韩国和印度尼西亚等多个国家的采购经理人指数报告以及印度尼西亚通胀、韩国贸易、香港零售销售和澳大利亚住房数据均已发布。</p>   <p>Particular attention will be paid to China's 'unofficial' Caixin PMI report, a day after <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-factory-activity-unexpectedly-contracted-october-2023-10-31/">'official' PMI</a> data showed that factory activity unexpectedly contracted in October. Not only that, it shrank faster than the most pessimistic prediction in a Reuters poll had forecast.翻译:在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-factory-activity-unexpectedly-contracted-october-2023-10-31/">“官方”PMI 数据显示 10 月份工厂活动意外收缩的第二天，中国“</a>非官方”财新 PMI 报告将受到特别关注。不仅如此，它的收缩速度比路透社民意调查中最悲观的预测还要快。</p>   <p>This calls into question the strength of China's recovery. Economic surprises had recently risen to the highest since May, and stocks had rallied five days in a row. That run was brought to a halt on Tuesday.翻译:这让人对中国复苏的力度产生质疑。最近经济意外上升至5月份以来的最高水平，股市连续五天上涨。那次跑步活动于周二停止。</p>   <p>A gloomy 'official' PMI report would likely intensify that downward pressure on stocks, and the currency. The yuan is languishing near September's 16-year low, and selling pressure bearing down on the offshore yuan, in particular, is strong.翻译:黯淡的“官方”采购经理人指数报告可能会加剧股市和货币的下行压力。人民币目前正徘徊在 9 月份的 16 年低点附近，离岸人民币面临的抛售压力尤其强劲。</p>   <p>But if the yuan is under pressure, it is nothing compared to the onslaught Japan's yen is facing. After the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/boj-likely-lift-inflation-forecasts-debate-yield-controls-future-2023-10-30/">Bank of Japan</a> on Tuesday scrapped the 1% ceiling for the 10-year government bond yield, the yen sank to a new one-year low against the dollar and a fresh 15-year low against the euro.翻译:但如果人民币承受压力，与日元面临的猛攻相比，这根本算不了什么。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/boj-likely-lift-inflation-forecasts-debate-yield-controls-future-2023-10-30/">日本央行</a>周二取消10年期政府债券收益率1%的上限后，日元兑美元跌至一年新低，兑欧元跌至15年新低。</p>   <p>The currency and bond market reactions to the BOJ's policy tweak could not have been more different - the yen fell the most since April, while Japanese bond yields surged to a fresh decade-high.翻译:货币和债券市场对日本央行政策调整的反应截然不同——日元跌幅创 4 月份以来最大，而日本债券收益率则飙升至十年新高。</p>   <p>This suggests investors are not sure what the longer term implications are, or they are not fully convinced by the BOJ's actions. Or both.翻译:这表明投资者不确定长期影响是什么，或者他们并不完全相信日本央行的行动。或两者。</p>   <p>World and U.S. stocks ended the month with a flourish on Tuesday, Wall Street volatility fell back below long-term averages, the Treasuries market was pretty steady, and oil prices fell more than 1%. All this bodes well for the Asian market open on Wednesday.翻译:世界股市和美国股市周二收盘上涨，华尔街波动性回落至长期平均水平以下，国债市场相当稳定，油价下跌超过 1%。所有这些对于周三开盘的亚洲市场来说都是好兆头。</p>   <p>But it was a bruising start to the fourth quarter. World, U.S. and Asian stocks all fell for a third month in a row, bond yields surged and financial conditions tightened significantly. Investors will be hoping for some respite in November.翻译:但这是第四季度的一个惨痛开局。全球、美国和亚洲股市均连续第三个月下跌，债券收益率飙升，金融状况显着收紧。投资者希望 11 月份能得到一些喘息的机会。</p>   <p>Here are key developments that could provide more direction to markets on Wednesday:翻译:以下是周三可能为市场提供更多方向的关键进展：</p>   <p>- China PMI (Caixin, October)翻译:- 中国 PMI（财新，10 月）</p>   <p>- Indonesia CPI inflation (October)翻译:- 印度尼西亚CPI通胀（10月）</p>   <p>- South Korea trade (October)翻译:- 韩国贸易（10月）</p>    <span>By Jamie McGeever;翻译:作者：杰米·麦克吉弗；</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 21:52:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">H7D6WF5TEFLODAMENVBSZ2OF44</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/global-markets-view-asia-graphics-pix-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jamie McGeever]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>ASIA (GRAPHICS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[道萨里、科尔荣获亚洲足联年度最佳球员奖]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/jTBvpGhhbEBhC3Nxp9pYbQRdWpQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HC3GTIWRY5MIZP7ICHJLA5ZQOI.jpg" alt="FIFA Women’s World Cup Australia and New Zealand 2023 - Semi Final - Australia v England" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Soccer Football - FIFA Women’s World Cup Australia and New Zealand 2023 - Semi Final - Australia v England - Stadium Australia, Sydney, Australia - August 16, 2023 Australia's Sam Kerr celebrates scoring their first goal REUTERS/Hannah Mckay/File Photo翻译:足球 - FIFA 2023 年澳大利亚和新西兰女足世界杯 - 半决赛 - 澳大利亚对阵英格兰 - 澳大利亚体育场，澳大利亚悉尼 - 2023 年 8 月 16 日，澳大利亚队的萨姆·科尔 (Sam Kerr) 庆祝他们的第一个进球 REUTERS/Hannah Mckay/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/jmV8R2cOj3oELdlV2V6SeBQPttQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MYTXB45QYVNHLPARDVH5OBH5MU.jpg" alt="Saudi Pro League - Al Hilal v Al Riyadh" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Soccer Football - Saudi Pro League - Al Hilal v Al Riyadh - Prince Faisal bin Fahd Stadium, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia - September 15, 2023 Al Hilal's Salem Al Dawsari in action REUTERS/Ahmed Yosri/File Photo翻译:足球 - 沙特职业联赛 - 阿尔希拉尔 v 阿尔利雅得 - 沙特阿拉伯利雅得费萨尔本法赫德王子体育场 - 2023 年 9 月 15 日阿尔希拉尔的塞勒姆阿尔道萨里在比赛 REUTERS/Ahmed Yosri/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>Saudi Arabia's Salem Al-Dawsari has been named the Asian Football Confederation's Player of the Year with Chelsea and Australia forward Sam Kerr taking the women's title at the regional body's awards ceremony in Doha on Tuesday.翻译:沙特阿拉伯的塞勒姆·道萨里被评为亚洲足球联合会年度最佳球员，切尔西和澳大利亚前锋萨姆·科尔周二在多哈举行的亚洲足球联合会颁奖典礼上荣获女子冠军。</p>   <p>Al-Dawsari, who scored Saudi Arabia's winner in their shock 2-1 victory over Argentina at the World Cup last year, took the men's award after also leading Al-Hilal to the final of the Asian Champions League and the Club World Cup.翻译:去年世界杯上，沙特阿拉伯队以2-1战胜阿根廷队的比赛中，道萨里攻入制胜球，他在带领阿尔希拉尔打入亚洲冠军联赛和世俱杯决赛后，获得了男子奖项。</p>   <p>The awards were being held for the first time in four years as a result of the disruption caused to the game across the continent by the COVID-19 pandemic.翻译:由于COVID-19大流行对整个非洲大陆的比赛造成干扰，该奖项是四年来首次举办。</p>   <p>"I am very happy with this achievement and I would like to thank the leadership in Saudi Arabia for their keen interest in athletes and support for sport," said Al-Dawsari, who won ahead of Qatar's Almoez Ali and Mathew Leckie of Australia.翻译:“我对这一成就感到非常高兴，我要感谢沙特阿拉伯领导层对运动员的浓厚兴趣和对体育运动的支持，”领先于卡塔尔选手阿尔莫兹·阿里和澳大利亚选手马修·莱基获胜的道萨里说道。</p>   <p>Kerr, who on Monday had finished as runner-up in the Ballon d'Or vote in Paris, won her award for the second time having previously been named the confederation's best female player in 2017.翻译:克尔周一在巴黎举行的金球奖投票中获得亚军，这是继 2017 年金球奖最佳女球员之后第二次获奖。</p>   <p>She becomes the third woman to claim the award more than once, joining Japanese duo Aya Miyama and Homare Sawa as a multiple title-holder.翻译:她成为第三位多次获得该奖项的女性，加入了日本双人组合 Aya Miyama 和 Homare Sawa 的行列，成为多次获得该奖项的人。</p>   <p>"I just want to say what an amazing honour it is to win this award, especially up against some amazing finalists," said Kerr, who was given the award ahead of China's Zhang Linyang and Saki Kumagai from Japan, the 2019 winner.翻译:“我只想说，赢得这个奖项是多么令人惊叹的荣誉，尤其是面对一些令人惊叹的决赛入围者，”克尔说。他领先于 2019 年获奖者、中国选手张林洋和来自日本的熊谷早纪获得该奖项。</p>   <p>Japan's Hajime Moriyasu won the trophy for best men's coach after leading the Samurai Blue to the last 16 at the World Cup, with victories over Germany and Spain in the group stage of the tournament.翻译:日本队守安肇带领武士蓝队在世界杯上杀入16强，并在小组赛中击败德国队和西班牙队，获得最佳男子教练奖。</p>   <p>Shui Qingxia claimed the honours in the women's coaching category after she led China to the Women's Asian Cup last February in India, the country's first continental title since 2006.翻译:去年2月，水青霞带领中国队在印度夺得女子亚洲杯冠军，这是中国队自2006年以来首次夺得洲际冠军，水青霞获得了女子教练组的荣誉。</p>    <span>Reporting by Michael Church, Editing by Christian Radnedge翻译:迈克尔·丘奇 (Michael Church) 报道，克里斯蒂安·拉德内奇 (Christian Radnedge) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 19:42:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">R4OMXL5XFVMYZJWRIXV2PCK3HY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sports/soccer/al-dawsari-kerr-take-asian-confederations-player-year-awards-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Michael Church]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SOCCER</category>
                
                <category>ASIA/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[英伟达股价下跌，因中国订单被取消]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/8jEmXCTT_pficlVKSP408KzAfi8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FP3BMIMPX5PUZBJ7RT7OWS4AJ4.jpg" alt="Foxconn to use Nvidia chips to build self-driving platforms" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of NVIDIA as seen at its corporate headquarters in Santa Clara, California, in May of 2022. Courtesy NVIDIA/Handout via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:2022 年 5 月，在位于加利福尼亚州圣克拉拉的公司总部看到的 NVIDIA 徽标。由 NVIDIA 提供/来自 REUTERS 的讲义/文件照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Shares of Nvidia Corp <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NVDA.O" target="_blank">(NVDA.O)</a> dropped by about 5% to a near five-month low on Tuesday following a Wall Street Journal report that the artificial intelligence (AI) giant may be forced to cancel up to $5 billion worth of advanced chip orders to China in compliance with new U.S. government restrictions.翻译:华尔街日报报道称，英伟达公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NVDA.O" target="_blank">(NVDA.O)</a>的股价周二下跌约 5%，跌至近五个月低点，称这家人工智能 (AI) 巨头可能被迫取消价值高达 50 亿美元的先进芯片根据美国政府的新限制向中国发出订单。</p>   <p>Nvidia was notified last week that AI chip orders scheduled for delivery next year to major Chinese technology companies, including Alibaba Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">(9988.HK)</a>, TikTok owner-ByteDance and Baidu <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9888.HK" target="_blank">(9888.HK)</a>, are subject to the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/biden-cut-china-off-more-nvidia-chips-expand-curbs-more-countries-2023-10-17/">latest export restrictions</a> announced by the U.S. Commerce Department, the Wall Street Journal reported, citing people familiar with the matter.翻译:英伟达上周获悉，计划于明年交付给阿里巴巴集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">（9988.HK）</a> 、TikTok所有者字节跳动和百度<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9888.HK" target="_blank">（9888.HK）</a>等中国主要科技公司的人工智能芯片订单，将受到英伟达宣布的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/biden-cut-china-off-more-nvidia-chips-expand-curbs-more-countries-2023-10-17/">最新出口限制</a>的约束。 《华尔街日报》援引知情人士的话报道，美国商务部。</p>   <p>Nvidia's stock fell to as low as $392.30, down 4.7%, to the lowest level since mid-June. The stock, which has been one of the major drivers of this year's 22% gain in the Nasdaq index, is now down nearly 20% from its record high close of $493.55 reached on Aug. 31. It was last down 2.09%.翻译:英伟达股价最低跌至392.30美元，跌幅4.7%，创6月中旬以来最低水平。该股是今年纳斯达克指数上涨 22% 的主要推动力之一，目前较 8 月 31 日创下的收盘纪录高点 493.55 美元下跌了近 20%。最后下跌 2.09%。</p>   <p>"The stock is getting oversold," said Tom Plumb, chief executive and lead portfolio manager at Plumb Funds, which has Nvidia as one of its largest holdings.翻译:Plumb Funds 首席执行官兼首席投资组合经理汤姆·普拉姆 (Tom Plumb) 表示：“该股已经超卖。”该基金持有英伟达最大的股份之一。</p>   <p>"Previously, Nvidia has said this is not going to have a short-term impact but it's more in the long term. We still expect a pretty strong quarter and think it's a great long-term holding, although we are not adding any new positions because of the volatility," Plumb added.翻译:“此前，英伟达曾表示，这不会产生短期影响，但从长远来看，影响更大。我们仍然预计一个相当强劲的季度，并认为这是一个很好的长期持有，尽管我们不会增加任何新的头寸因为波动性，”普拉姆补充道。</p>   <p>A Nvidia spokesperson said there is "high demand" for its advanced chips, which often require significant lead time to build, and that it is working to allocate orders to its "wide range of customers" in the United States and elsewhere.翻译:英伟达发言人表示，对其先进芯片的需求“很高”，这些芯片通常需要大量的交货时间来制造，并且该公司正在努力将订单分配给美国和其他地方的“广泛客户”。</p>   <p>"These new export controls will not have a meaningful impact in the near term," the Nvidia spokesperson said in a statement.翻译:英伟达发言人在一份声明中表示：“这些新的出口管制在短期内不会产生有意义的影响。”</p>   <p>Earlier this month, the Biden administration <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/biden-cut-china-off-more-nvidia-chips-expand-curbs-more-countries-2023-10-17/">imposed export restrictions on shipments</a> of more AI chips designed by Nvidia and others to China, a move designed to stop Beijing from receiving cutting-edge U.S. technologies to strengthen its military.翻译:本月早些时候，拜登政府<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/biden-cut-china-off-more-nvidia-chips-expand-curbs-more-countries-2023-10-17/">对更多英伟达等公司设计的人工智能芯片向中国出口实施出口限制</a>，此举旨在阻止北京获得美国尖端技术来增强其军事实力。</p>   <p>The new rules go into effect in November and included export controls to countries including Iran and Russia.翻译:新规定将于 11 月生效，其中包括对伊朗和俄罗斯等国家的出口管制。</p>   <p>"I think Nvidia is priced for perfection and any trip off can have major impact when you have a stock that is trading at 20 times sales and 40 times earnings," said Thomas Hayes, chairman at Great Hill Capital in New York.翻译:纽约 Great Hill Capital 董事长托马斯·海耶斯 (Thomas Hayes) 表示：“我认为 Nvidia 的定价是完美的，当你的股票的市盈率是 20 倍、市盈率是 20 倍时，任何偏离都会产生重大影响。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Chibuike Oguh in New York; additional reporting by Stephen Nellis in San Francisco and Amruta Khandekar in Bengaluru; Editing by Lance Tupper, Michelle Price, Jonathan Oatis and Deepa Babington翻译:Chibuike Oguh 纽约报道； Stephen Nellis 在旧金山和 Amruta Khandekar 在班加罗尔的补充报道；兰斯·塔珀、米歇尔·普莱斯、乔纳森·奥蒂斯和迪帕·巴宾顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 17:19:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">WBYYFJTTSVPJZLQJJPD6IHGKB4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/nvidia-shares-drop-five-month-low-after-report-canceled-china-orders-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Chibuike Oguh]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>STOCKS/NVIDIA (UPDATE 1, PIX, GRAPHIC)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[反犹太主义的激增如何影响世界各国]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/DrZmu3nP9d3KhhvNz1PHTp5hfbI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JWKODH6RYZLQHAM2YJPL5SHDWY.jpg" alt="Smoke rises inside the Gaza Strip as seen from Israel" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Smoke rises following an Israeli strike inside the Gaza Strip, as seen from Israel, October 31. REUTERS/Evelyn Hockstein翻译:10 月 31 日，从以色列的角度看，以色列对加沙地带发动袭击后升起浓烟。REUTERS/Evelyn Hockstein</figcaption></figure>       <p>Authorities and civil society groups in many countries have reported a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/open-hatred-jews-surges-globally-inflamed-by-gaza-war-2023-10-31/">surge in antisemitism</a> since the Oct. 7 attack by Hamas on southern Israel and subsequent bombardment of the Gaza Strip by the Israeli military.翻译:许多国家的当局和民间社会团体报告称，自 10 月 7 日哈马斯袭击以色列南部以及随后以色列军队轰炸加沙地带以来<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/open-hatred-jews-surges-globally-inflamed-by-gaza-war-2023-10-31/">，反犹太主义激增</a>。</p>   <p>The following are details of how the surge is affecting countries, compiled by Reuters reporters around the world:翻译:以下是路透社记者在世界各地整理的关于疫情激增如何影响各国的详细信息：</p>    <h 1="">UNITED STATES</h>  <p>Jewish advocacy group the Anti-Defamation League reported last week that antisemitic incidents had risen by about 400% in the two weeks following the Oct. 7 attack, compared with the same period last year.翻译:犹太倡导组织反诽谤联盟上周报告称，10 月 7 日袭击事件发生后的两周内，反犹太主义事件与去年同期相比增加了约 400%。</p>   <p>Government officials met American-Jewish leaders on Monday to discuss steps to counter what a White House official described as an alarming uptick in reported instances of antisemitism on university campuses.翻译:政府官员周一会见了美国犹太领导人，讨论了应对措施，以应对据白宫官员所说的大学校园反犹太主义事件令人震惊的上升。</p>   <p>After a man screaming "Free Palestine" and "Kill Jews" attempted to break into a Jewish family's home in Los Angeles on Oct. 25, Mayor Karen Bass said police would continue stepping up patrols in communities throughout the city.翻译:10 月 25 日，一名男子高喊“自由巴勒斯坦”和“杀死犹太人”，试图闯入洛杉矶一个犹太家庭的家后，市长凯伦·巴斯表示，警方将继续加强在全市社区的巡逻。</p>    <h 1="">CANADA</h>  <p>Prime Minister Justin Trudeau spoke on Oct. 17 of a "scary rise" in antisemitism in Canada, citing incidents at a Jewish high school in Toronto as well as escalating inflammatory language online.翻译:10 月 17 日，加拿大总理贾斯汀·特鲁多 (Justin Trudeau) 谈到加拿大反犹太主义的“可怕崛起”，并列举了多伦多一所犹太高中发生的事件以及网上不断升级的煽动性语言。</p>    <h 1="">ARGENTINA</h>  <p>Scarred by two attacks in the 1990s on the Israeli embassy and on a Jewish community centre, which killed over 100 people in total, Argentine Jewish leaders have been advising community members to exercise caution and increase vigilance.翻译:20 世纪 90 年代，以色列大使馆和犹太社区中心发生两起袭击事件，总共造成 100 多人死亡，阿根廷犹太领袖对此感到伤痕累累，一直建议社区成员谨慎行事并提高警惕。</p>   <p>A well-known Jewish school in Buenos Aires asked pupils not to wear their usual uniforms, while some teams pulled out of a table tennis competition being held at a Jewish club for fear it could be targeted.翻译:布宜诺斯艾利斯一所著名的犹太学校要求学生不要穿平时的校服，而一些球队则退出了在犹太俱乐部举行的乒乓球比赛，因为担心可能成为攻击目标。</p>   <p>Local media reported last week an Argentine man was arrested after calling on social media platform 4chan for attacks on Jewish children in schools.翻译:当地媒体上周报道称，一名阿根廷男子因在社交媒体平台 4chan 上呼吁袭击学校里的犹太儿童而被捕。</p>    <h 1="">BRAZIL</h>  <p>Jewish leaders have noticed a rise in antisemitic discourse online, and incidents such as graffiti defacing a synagogue in Rio de Janeiro. No instances of physical threats or assaults have been reported.翻译:犹太领导人注意到网上反犹太主义言论的增加，以及里约热内卢犹太教堂涂鸦等事件。目前还没有任何人身威胁或袭击事件的报道。</p>   <p>"We are very concerned. We have increased the security of our institutions," said Ricardo Berkiensztat, executive president of the Jewish Federation of the State of Sao Paulo.翻译:圣保罗州犹太联合会执行主席里卡多·贝尔基恩斯塔特说：“我们非常担心。我们已经加强了机构的安全。”</p>   <p>He said he had seen comments online such as "Hitler didn't finish, he should have finished killing Jews".翻译:他说，他在网上看到过诸如“希特勒没有结束，他应该结束对犹太人的屠杀”之类的评论。</p>    <h 1="">BRITAIN</h>  <p>London's police force said there had been a 14-fold increase in incidents of antisemitism since the Oct. 7 attack.翻译:伦敦警方表示，自 10 月 7 日袭击事件以来，反犹太主义事件增加了 14 倍。</p>   <p>The Community Security Trust, which collates reports of antisemitism in Britain, said the number of incidents in the three weeks following the attack was the highest for any three-week period since it started collecting data in 1984.翻译:整理英国反犹太主义报告的社区安全信托基金表示，袭击发生后三周内的事件数量是自 1984 年开始收集数据以来三周内最高的。</p>    <h 1="">FRANCE</h>  <p>Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin said on Monday that since Oct. 7 there had been 819 antisemitic acts. That compares with a figure of 436 for the whole of 2022.翻译:内政部长杰拉尔德·达尔马宁周一表示，自 10 月 7 日以来，已发生 819 起反犹太主义行为。相比之下，2022 年全年的数字为 436。</p>   <p>Darmanin said there had been 414 arrests in connection with this trend.翻译:达马宁表示，已有 414 人因这一趋势被捕。</p>    <h 1="">GERMANY</h>  <p>A survey by a civil society observatory, the RIAS, found a 240% year-on-year increase in antisemitic incidents in the period of Oct. 7-15.翻译:民间社会观察机构RIAS的一项调查发现，10月7日至15日期间，反犹太主义事件同比增加了240%。</p>    <h 1="">NETHERLANDS</h>  <p>No official figures are available yet, but Eddo Verdoner, national coordinator for combating antisemitism, said a sharp rise had been observed and anxiety was high in the Jewish community.翻译:目前还没有官方数据，但打击反犹太主义国家协调员埃多·韦尔多纳表示，犹太社区的反犹太主义数量急剧上升，焦虑情绪很高。</p>   <p>He said Jewish parents had reported their children had been harassed at school, with comments such as "Hamas were right" and "they should have done it earlier" directed at them.翻译:他说，犹太家长报告说，他们的孩子在学校受到骚扰，并针对他们发表了诸如“哈马斯是对的”和“他们应该早点这样做”等评论。</p>    <h 1="">SOUTH AFRICA</h>  <p>The number of antisemitic incidents in October is nine times higher than the average recorded for that month over the past decade, according to David Saks, associate director of the South African Jewish Board of Deputies.翻译:南非犹太人众议院副主任戴维·萨克斯 (David Saks) 表示，十月份的反犹太主义事件数量是过去十年该月平均记录的九倍。</p>   <p>In one incident, a woman who shared a link to information about a protest calling for the release of Israeli hostages being held in Gaza was abused online, including a post that said "we'll come for her babies next".翻译:在一次事件中，一名妇女分享了有关要求释放被扣押在加沙的以色列人质的抗议活动信息的链接，该妇女在网上遭到辱骂，其中包括一条帖子，内容是“我们接下来会来接她的孩子”。</p>    <h 1="">RUSSIA</h>  <p>After an angry crowd stormed an airport in the Dagestan region searching for Jews to harm after a plane arrived from Tel Aviv, the president of Russia's Federation of Jewish Communities called on the authorities to harshly punish the organisers.翻译:一架飞机从特拉维夫抵达后，愤怒的人群冲进了达吉斯坦地区的一个机场，寻找要伤害的犹太人。俄罗斯犹太社区联合会主席呼吁当局严厉惩罚组织者。</p>   <p>Rabbi Alexander Boroda said the airport riot "undermined the basic foundations of our multi-cultural and multi-national state".翻译:拉比亚历山大博罗达表示，机场骚乱“破坏了我们多元文化和多民族国家的基础”。</p>    <h 1="">CHINA</h>  <p>No figures are available on antisemitic incidents. On Oct. 13, a staff member of the Israeli embassy in Beijing was assaulted and a suspect was arrested.翻译:没有关于反犹太主义事件的数据。 10月13日，以色列驻北京使馆一名工作人员遭到袭击，一名嫌疑人被捕。</p>   <p>Chinese social media is awash with antisemitic content, including posts suggesting the Nazi Holocaust was justified and likening Jews to parasites, vampires or snakes.翻译:中国的社交媒体充斥着反犹太主义内容，包括暗示纳粹大屠杀是合理的，并将犹太人比作寄生虫、吸血鬼或蛇的帖子。</p>   <p>A foreign ministry spokesperson said the law prohibited the use of the internet to propagate hate speech, but there were no discernible efforts by the authorities to curb antisemitic activity online.翻译:外交部发言人表示，法律禁止利用互联网传播仇恨言论，但当局没有采取明显措施遏制网上反犹太主义活动。</p>    <span>Reporting by Andrew MacAskill, Layli Foroudi, Julia Harte, Chen Lin, Eliana Raszewski, Maytaal Angel, Andrew Osborn, Carien du Plessis, Steven Grattan, Wa Lone, Thomas Escritt and Stephanie Van Den Berg, Writing by Estelle Shirbon
Editing by翻译:报道：Andrew MacAskill、Layli Foroudi、Julia Harte、Chen Lin、Eliana Raszewski、Maytaal Angel、Andrew Osborn、Carien du Plessis、Steven Grattan、Wa Lone、Thomas Escritt 和 Stephanie Van Den Berg，撰稿：Estelle Shirbon 编辑：</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 15:25:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">M6F5FQU5DFJ7ZJN7X55KJKRIM4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/how-surge-antisemitism-is-affecting-countries-around-world-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ISRAEL</category>
                
                <category>PALESTINIANS/ANTISEMITISM (UPDATE 1, FACTBOX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国议员敦促耶伦加快制定中国境外投资规则]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lcP2EfQg7nVbjyb_SN2LtyUT5QI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7SPQGAVKSJM3XMYMQDEHPYOWPA.jpg" alt="Global infrastructure and investment forum in New York" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Janet Yellen, United States Secretary of Treasury, participates in global infrastructure and investment forum in New York, Thursday, Sept. 21, 2023. Seth Wenig/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦 (Janet Yellen) 于 2023 年 9 月 21 日星期四参加在纽约举行的全球基础设施和投资论坛。Seth Wenig/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Republican and Democratic leaders of a U.S. congressional committee on China urged Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen to urgently implement outbound investment restrictions on the country, warning that Beijing was using American capital to develop technologies as her department debated new rules.翻译:美国国会中国问题委员会的共和党和民主党领导人敦促财政部长珍妮特·耶伦紧急对中国实施对外投资限制，并警告说，在她的部门就新规则进行辩论之际，北京正在利用美国资本来开发技术。</p>   <p>U.S. President Joe Biden in August issued an executive order authorizing the Treasury secretary to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/white-house-detail-plans-restricting-some-us-investments-china-source-2023-08-09/">prohibit or restrict U.S. investments in Chinese entities</a> in three sectors: semiconductors and microelectronics, quantum information technologies and certain artificial intelligence systems.翻译:美国总统乔·拜登8月发布行政命令，授权财政部长<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/white-house-detail-plans-restricting-some-us-investments-china-source-2023-08-09/">禁止或限制美国对中国实体在半导体和微电子、量子信息技术和某些人工智能系统三个领域的投资</a>。</p>   <p>The order, expected to be implemented in the coming year as Treasury develops new guidelines, aims to prevent American money and expertise from helping China develop technologies that could support its military modernization.翻译:该命令预计将在明年随着财政部制定新的指导方针而实施，旨在阻止美国的资金和专业知识帮助中国开发支持其军事现代化的技术。</p>   <p>China has condemned the move, but some U.S. lawmakers have argued it has too many loopholes.翻译:中国谴责此举，但一些美国议员认为此举存在太多漏洞。</p>   <p>"As Treasury deliberates on the definitions and scope to be issued in these guidelines, the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) is developing advanced technologies with the help of American capital and know-how," Mike Gallagher and Raja Krishnamoorthi – the Republican chair and ranking Democrat on the House of Representative's select committee on China, said in a letter.翻译:“在财政部审议这些指南中发布的定义和范围时，中国共产党（CCP）正在美国资本和专业知识的帮助下开发先进技术，”共和党主席和排名的迈克·加拉格尔（Mike Gallagher）和拉贾·克里希纳莫蒂（Raja Krishnamoorthi）众议院中国问题特别委员会的民主党人在一封信中表示。</p>   <p>Yellen should adopt a broad definition of technology in her guidelines on the investment restrictions, the lawmakers said in the letter, dated Oct. 30, arguing China had blurred the lines between commercial and military technology.翻译:立法者在 10 月 30 日的信中表示，耶伦应该在其投资限制指导方针中采用广泛的技术定义，并认为中国模糊了商业和军事技术之间的界限。</p>   <p>"We should expect that the CCP will seek to evade restrictions that are narrowly defined," Gallagher and Krishnamoorthi wrote, adding that Yellen should not allow for "excepted transactions" they felt would dilute the effectiveness of the rules.翻译:加拉格尔和克里希纳莫蒂写道：“我们应该预期中共会寻求规避狭隘定义的限制。”他们补充说，耶伦不应允许他们认为会削弱规则有效性的“例外交易”。</p>   <p>They said Treasury should work with U.S. authorities to pursue maximum penalties for violations, and also address more passive flows of U.S. capital, such as through public markets and mutual funds.翻译:他们表示，财政部应与美国当局合作，对违规行为实行最高处罚，并解决更多美国资本被动流动的问题，例如通过公开市场和共同基金的流动。</p>   <p>Some U.S. officials have said the outbound investment rules should not be overly broad to avoid harming the U.S. economy. Others, including former Biden administration officials, have called the measure <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/former-us-officials-urge-congress-enhance-bidens-china-investment-order-2023-08-16/">a good first step</a>, but said that Congress should provide resources to expand it.翻译:一些美国官员表示，对外投资规则不应过于宽泛，以免损害美国经济。其他人，包括前拜登政府官员，称该措施<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/former-us-officials-urge-congress-enhance-bidens-china-investment-order-2023-08-16/">是良好的第一步</a>，但表示国会应提供资源来扩大该措施。</p>    <span>Reporting by Michael Martina;
Editing by Sandra Maler翻译:迈克尔·玛蒂娜报道；桑德拉·马勒编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 14:32:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F4LYJXNQ6VO63FNFABQ3BOPBII</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/us-lawmakers-urge-yellen-speed-up-china-outbound-investment-rules-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Michael Martina]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/INVESTMENTS</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[澳大利亚总理访华前杨恒均儿子要求释放他]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/2K8H5IbIeuJrKBVINqxbwsMy3Yc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5OKYIRC3KZPMPP4V2BJYIM3MQI.jpg" alt="FILE PHOTO: A Chinese national flag waves outside Beijing No. 2 Intermediate People's Court where Australian writer Yang Hengjun is expected to face trial on espionage charges, in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Chinese national flag waves outside Beijing No. 2 Intermediate People's Court where Australian writer Yang Hengjun is expected to face trial on espionage charges, in Beijing, China May 27, 2021. REUTERS/Carlos Garcia Rawlins/File Photo翻译:2021 年 5 月 27 日，中国北京，一面中国国旗在北京第二中级人民法院外飘扬，澳大利亚作家杨恒均预计将在中国北京接受间谍指控的审判。路透社/Carlos Garcia Rawlins/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The sons of Australian writer Yang Hengjun, jailed in Beijing for four years on espionage charges, have written to Prime Minister Anthony Albanese asking for a "second miracle" ahead of his China visit, after the release of journalist Cheng Lei.翻译:因间谍罪名在北京被判入狱四年的澳大利亚作家杨恒均的儿子在记者成雷获释后，写信给总理安东尼·艾博内塞，要求在访问中国之前创造“第二个奇迹”。</p>   <p>Albanese travels to China on Saturday, the first visit by an Australian leader since 2016 as the trading partners stabilise ties after a diplomatic dispute. He meets Chinese President Xi Jinping on Monday.翻译:阿尔巴内塞将于周六访问中国，这是澳大利亚领导人自 2016 年以来首次访问中国，两国贸易伙伴在外交争端后稳定了关系。他周一会见了中国国家主席习近平。</p>   <p>Pro-democracy blogger Yang is an Australian citizen born in China who was working in New York before his arrest at Guangzhou airport in 2019. His arrest coincided with a deterioration in relations between Australia and China.翻译:民主博主杨是出生在中国的澳大利亚公民，2019年在广州机场被捕前在纽约工作。他被捕之际，正值澳大利亚与中国关系恶化。</p>   <p>A Beijing court heard Yang's trial in secret in May 2021 and the case against him has never been publicly disclosed. He has denied working as a spy for Australia or the United States.翻译:北京一家法院于 2021 年 5 月秘密审理了杨某的审判，针对他的案件从未公开披露。他否认为澳大利亚或美国担任间谍。</p>   <p>Australian <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australian-journalist-cheng-lei-says-feels-fragile-after-china-detention-2023-10-17/">journalist Cheng Lei</a> returned home to Melbourne a fortnight ago, released after three years in jail in Beijing. Analysts said Cheng's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/release-journalist-unlikely-shift-australias-china-policy-2023-10-12/">release</a> was a "sweetener" ahead of Albanese's visit.翻译:澳大利亚<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australian-journalist-cheng-lei-says-feels-fragile-after-china-detention-2023-10-17/">记者程雷</a>在北京被监禁三年后于两周前返回墨尔本的家中。分析人士表示，程的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/release-journalist-unlikely-shift-australias-china-policy-2023-10-12/">获释</a>是阿尔巴内斯访问之前的“甜头”。</p>   <p>In a letter dated Oct. 28 and seen by Reuters, Yang's sons said they hoped Albanese can "achieve a second miracle by saving our father, who has now spent four years and nine months in detention".翻译:路透社看到的一封日期为 10 月 28 日的信中，杨的儿子们表示，他们希望阿尔巴尼斯能够“通过拯救我们的父亲来实现第二个奇迹，他现在已经被拘留了四年零九个月”。</p>   <p>They urged Albanese to seek Yang's release on medical grounds, after being told by consular officials who visited him last week that his health was declining and that he had collapsed several times. Friends had said Yang was suffering health problems since <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/friends-hold-health-concerns-australian-writer-detained-china-2023-08-28/">August</a>.翻译:上周探访杨的领事官员告诉阿尔巴内斯，他的健康状况每况愈下，并且多次昏倒，他们敦促阿尔巴尼斯以健康为由寻求释放杨。朋友们表示，杨自<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/friends-hold-health-concerns-australian-writer-detained-china-2023-08-28/">八月</a>起就出现健康问题。</p>   <p>"The risk of our father being left to die from medical neglect is clear to anyone who has read Wednesday's consular report," the letter to Albanese said.翻译:写给阿尔巴内斯的信中说：“任何读过周三领事报告的人都清楚，我们的父亲因医疗疏忽而死亡的风险。”</p>   <p>Asked by reporters on Tuesday if the release of Cheng increased the chances of Yang being released, Albanese said: "Each case is different, but each case is important."翻译:周二被记者问及程的释放是否会增加杨被释放的机会时，艾博尼斯说：“每个案件都不同，但每个案件都很重要。”</p>   <p>China's foreign ministry has previously said Yang was "suspected of engaging in criminal activities that endanger the national security of the PRC" and said Chinese judicial bodies were reviewing his case.翻译:中国外交部此前曾表示，杨“涉嫌从事危害中华人民共和国国家安全的犯罪活动”，并表示中国司法机构正在审查他的案件。</p>   <p>In the letter, Yang's sons said their father had told consular officials last week he was "basically bedridden", unable to walk for three weeks, and worried about the unknown cause of his illness, saying: "I'm sick, I'm weak, I'm dying".翻译:杨的儿子们在信中说，他们的父亲上周告诉领事官员，他“基本上卧床不起”，已经三周无法行走，并担心他的病情不明，并说：“我病了，我虚弱，我快死了”。</p>   <p>Responding to the letter, Australia's Foreign Minister Penny Wong said in a statement: "The Australian Government is deeply concerned by the deterioration of Dr Yang's health, and we share the concerns of his friends and family about his welfare and medical condition."翻译:澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤在一份声明中回应这封信说：“澳大利亚政府对杨博士的健康状况恶化深表关切，我们与他的朋友和家人一样对他的福利和医疗状况感到担忧。”</p>   <p>The sons, who live in Australia and declined to be named for privacy reasons, said they received the first letter Yang had been permitted to send them from detention on Oct.27.翻译:这对儿子居住在澳大利亚，出于隐私原因拒绝透露姓名，他们表示，他们于 10 月 27 日收到了杨被允许从拘留所寄给他们的第一封信。</p>   <p>They said Yang had not made a "confession" and said he was still innocent under Chinese law.翻译:他们表示，杨尚未“认罪”，并表示根据中国法律，他仍然是无辜的。</p>    <span>Reporting by Kirsty Needham in Sydney; editing by Miral Fahmy翻译:Kirsty Needham 悉尼报道；米拉尔·法赫米 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 13:38:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">INOKEBNTPFI5RO7GLDNTADBTFA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/sons-australian-yang-hengjun-ask-his-release-ahead-pms-visit-china-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Kirsty Needham]]></author>
            
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[由于流动性紧张，一些中国机构以50%的利率借款]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UFZvgV10evozFRO5YrgUPCvaWqI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OYR7OROA6RJV5KRCRFQLMLLUU4.jpg" alt="Illustration photo of a China yuan note" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A China yuan note is seen in this illustration photo May 31, 2017.     REUTERS/Thomas White/Illustration翻译:这张2017年5月31日的插图照片中可以看到一张人民币纸币。路透社/Thomas White/插图</figcaption></figure>       <p>Overnight borrowing costs for some Chinese financial institutions jumped to as high as 50% on Tuesday, as a month-end scramble for cash squeezed liquidity and stressed money markets.翻译:周二，一些中国金融机构的隔夜借款成本跃升至 50%，原因是月底现金争夺战挤压了流动性并给货币市场带来压力。</p>   <p>In addition to seasonal factors, the cash shortage was caused by an upcoming flood of government bond issuance, and traders also pointed to market fears of default by cash-strapped institutions.翻译:除了季节性因素外，现金短缺的原因还包括即将到来的大量政府债券发行，交易员还指出市场对现金短缺的机构违约的担忧。</p>   <p>The highest overnight rate for pledged repo - a short-term financing business - hit 50% on Tuesday, according to official interbank data, although the average rate remains modest at roughly 3.6%.翻译:根据银行间官方数据，质押式回购（一种短期融资业务）的最高隔夜利率周二达到 50%，但平均利率仍维持在 3.6% 左右的温和水平。</p>   <p>Two-day repo rates jumped to as high as 30%, and the highest rate for seven-day repos was 12%.翻译:两日回购利率高达30%，七日回购利率最高为12%。</p>   <p>"The liquidity tightness caught me off the guard, the price suddenly shot up," said a trader at a brokerage.翻译:“流动性紧张让我措手不及，价格突然飙升。”一位券商交易员表示。</p>   <p>The jump in rates stirred memories of a June 2013 cash crunch when the overnight repo rate leapt to a historic high of 30% in an event that roiled global markets.翻译:利率的飙升唤起了人们对 2013 年 6 月现金紧缩的回忆，当时隔夜回购利率跃升至 30% 的历史高位，这一事件震惊了全球市场。</p>   <p>Rocky Fan, economist at Guolian Securities, said that while the 2013 crisis had resulted from China's crackdown on shadow banking, the current stress was likely due to a high level of leveraged trades in the money market.翻译:国联证券经济学家范洛基表示，虽然2013年的危机是中国打击影子银行造成的，但目前的压力很可能是由于货币市场的高杠杆交易造成的。</p>   <p>Several traders at small lenders were still seeking to borrow money in later afternoon trading when contacted by Reuters. Some also expressed concern over default in the market, without giving details.翻译:当路透社联系到小银行的几位交易员时，他们仍在下午晚些时候寻求借钱。一些人还对市场违约表示担忧，但没有透露细节。</p>   <p>"Liquidity is extremely tight today," Caitong Securities wrote in a note to clients.翻译:“目前流动性极其紧张，”财通证券在给客户的报告中写道。</p>   <p>The brokerage attributed the cash shortage to a "record supply" of government bonds, as well as restricted channels for banks to borrow money.翻译:该券商将现金短缺归因于政府债券“创纪录的供应”，以及银行借款渠道受限。</p>   <p>China last week approved 1 trillion yuan ($136.67 billion) of sovereign bond sales to stimulate economic growth while local governments are rushing to issue refinancing bonds to repay existing debts.翻译:中国上周批准发行1万亿元人民币（1366.7亿美元）的主权债券以刺激经济增长，而地方政府则急于发行再融资债券以偿还现有债务。</p>   <p>"We expect tight liquidity to force authorities to speed up the rollout of monetary easing measures," Caitong analysts wrote.翻译:财通分析师写道：“我们预计流动性紧张将迫使当局加快推出货币宽松措施。”</p>   <p>Ming Ming, chief economist at Citic Securities, expects repo rates to fall back in November as the central bank will likely maintain loose monetary conditions, with a cut in banks' required reserve ratio possible.翻译:中信证券首席经济学家明明预计，11月份回购利率将回落，因为央行可能会维持宽松的货币环境，并可能下调银行存款准备金率。</p>   <p>The average seven-day repo rate - a widely watched indictor of short-term borrowing costs in China - remained modest at 2.0765% on Tuesday, meaning many institutions can still borrow money at relatively low rates.翻译:周二，平均7天回购利率（中国短期借贷成本的一项广受关注的指标）仍维持在2.0765%的温和水平，这意味着许多机构仍可以以相对较低的利率借钱。</p>    <span>Reporting by Shanghai newsroom, editing by Ed Osmond, Kirsten Donovan翻译:上海新闻编辑室报道，埃德·奥斯蒙德、克尔斯滕·多诺万编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 13:19:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">445FIDIYX5MO3CHCTQEBVYP76Y</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/some-chinese-institutions-borrow-50-rate-liquidity-squeezed-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/LIQUIDITY (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[芬兰称中国配合波罗的海连接器调查]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/godsmQ-EZb6uTzeaTQZIIP-hZo4=/1854x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PPHPTJRKPFO3ZPYUIQ6GJOTJZE.jpg" alt="A damaged Balticconnector gas pipeline that connects Finland and Estonia is pictured in this undated handout picture in the Baltic Sea" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A damaged Balticconnector gas pipeline that connects Finland and Estonia is pictured in this undated handout picture in the Baltic Sea. Finnish Border Guard/Handout via REUTERS翻译:这张未注明日期的波罗的海宣传图片显示了连接芬兰和爱沙尼亚的一条受损的波罗的海连接器天然气管道。芬兰边防卫队/路透社的讲义</figcaption></figure>       <p>Finnish Prime Minister Petteri Orpo on Tuesday said China was cooperating in Finland's investigation of the Hong Kong-flagged NewNew Polar Bear vessel's role in the Oct. 8 damage to the Balticconnector pipeline.翻译:芬兰总理佩特里·奥尔波周二表示，中国正在配合芬兰调查悬挂香港国旗的“NewNew Polar Bear”号船只在 10 月 8 日波罗的海连接器管道受损事件中所扮演的角色。</p>   <p>Finnish police leading the criminal investigation have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/finland-contacts-china-russia-regarding-baltic-sea-pipeline-investigation-2023-10-20/">named</a> the NewNew Polar Bear container carrier as the prime suspect in damaging the gas pipeline early on Oct. 8, saying it was too early to tell if this was an accident or a deliberate act.翻译:负责刑事调查的芬兰警方于 10 月 8 日早些时候<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/finland-contacts-china-russia-regarding-baltic-sea-pipeline-investigation-2023-10-20/">将</a>NewNew Polar Bear 集装箱运输船列为破坏天然气管道的主要嫌疑人，并表示现在判断这是意外还是故意行为还为时过早。</p>   <p>A large anchor, believed to belong to the NewNew Polar Bear, was found near the pipeline, and the investigators said the pipe was likely broken as it was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/finland-retrieves-anchor-seabed-near-broken-gas-pipeline-2023-10-24/">dragged</a> across the sea bed.翻译:在管道附近发现了一个大锚，据信属于新新北极熊号，调查人员表示，管道很可能是在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/finland-retrieves-anchor-seabed-near-broken-gas-pipeline-2023-10-24/">拖</a>过海床时破裂的。</p>   <p>"We have opened diplomatic discussions with the Chinese and also we have started cooperation with Chinese authorities. And they have promised, and they have said, that they want to do cooperation," Petteri Orpo told reporters in Oslo.翻译:佩特里·奥尔波在奥斯陆对记者说：“我们已经与中国人展开了外交讨论，也开始了与中国当局的合作。他们已经承诺，并且已经说过，他们希望进行合作。”</p>   <p>"We are starting to work together. And the next few days I think (will) show how it goes. But now we have to be patient. We have to get a clear picture of what has happened before (drawing) any conclusions."翻译:“我们正在开始合作。我认为接下来的几天将展示事情的进展。但现在我们必须要有耐心。在（得出）任何结论之前，我们必须清楚地了解发生了什么。”</p>   <p>China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-willing-provide-necessary-information-baltic-sea-pipeline-probe-2023-10-25/">has said</a> it was willing to provide the necessary information in accordance with international law.翻译:中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-willing-provide-necessary-information-baltic-sea-pipeline-probe-2023-10-25/">表示</a>愿意根据国际法提供必要的信息。</p>   <p>Finland's gas pipeline operator Gasgrid said separately on Tuesday it had completed its inspection of the full pipe, and not found any more damage to it than the one confirmed <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/finnish-government-hold-news-conference-suspected-pipeline-leak-media-2023-10-10/">on Oct. 10</a>.翻译:芬兰天然气管道运营商Gasgrid周二另外表示，已完成对整个管道的检查，未发现比<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/finnish-government-hold-news-conference-suspected-pipeline-leak-media-2023-10-10/">10月10日</a>确认的损坏更多的情况。</p>       <span>Reporting by Gwladys Fouche, additional reporting by Anna Ringstrom in Stockholm, editing by Terje Solsvik翻译:Gwladys Fouche 报道，Anna Ringstrom 在斯德哥尔摩补充报道，Terje Solsvik 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 12:41:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">GT24ZEHSMBKEJLOFCEQWUGAIUA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-cooperating-balticconnector-investigation-finland-says-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>FINLAND</category>
                
                <category>ESTONIA/GAS (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[香港财政司长出席亚太经合组织会议回避争议]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/W894IqZEKjdSrmZBxltkq6aIxgk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ARTGGDU6ZVKUJGNI5UF4YTFM2Q.jpg" alt="Hong Kong's Finance Secretary Paul Chan delivers the annual budget address at the Legislative Council in Hong Kong" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Hong Kong's Finance Secretary Paul Chan delivers the annual budget address at the Legislative Council in Hong Kong, China Feburary 22, 2023. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu/File Photo翻译:香港财政司司长陈茂波于 2023 年 2 月 22 日在中国香港立法会发表年度预算案。 REUTERS/Tyrone Siu/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Hong Kong's financial secretary Paul Chan will attend an APEC meeting on Nov. 15-17 in San Francisco, it said on Tuesday, standing in for Chief Executive John Lee and smoothing over a diplomatically sensitive issue for both Beijing and Washington.翻译:周二，香港财政司司长陈茂波将代表行政长官李家超出席 11 月 15 日至 17 日在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织会议，并为北京和华盛顿解决一个外交敏感问题。</p>   <p>Chan's acceptance of the invitation suggests an agreement by the Chinese-ruled city to be represented at the meeting by an official other than its chief executive. Beijing had previously said Lee, who is subject to U.S. sanctions, should attend.翻译:成龙接受邀请表明，这座中国统治的城市同意由行政长官以外的官员代表出席会议。北京此前曾表示，受到美国制裁的李光耀应该出席。</p>   <p>The arrangement follows a high-profile visit by Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi to Washington over the weekend where both sides agreed to work towards an expected <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/blinken-wang-meet-us-china-gear-up-towards-expected-leaders-summit-2023-10-27/">summit</a> between their presidents at the same APEC meeting, as the two nations seek ways to manage their bilateral tensions.翻译:在此安排之前，中国外交部长王毅周末对华盛顿进行了高调访问，双方同意努力推动两国元首在同一次亚太经合组织会议上举行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/blinken-wang-meet-us-china-gear-up-towards-expected-leaders-summit-2023-10-27/">峰会</a>，两国寻求解决双边紧张局势的方法。</p>   <p>The United States imposed sanctions on Lee in 2020 over his role in the crackdown of pro-democracy demonstrations.翻译:2020 年，美国因李在镇压民主示威活动中发挥的作用而对其实施制裁。</p>   <p>Earlier this year, a State Department spokesperson said Washington would work with Hong Kong to ensure "appropriate" <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/us-will-not-invite-sanctioned-hong-kong-leader-apec-2023-07-28/">participation</a> in the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) meeting.翻译:今年早些时候，美国国务院发言人表示，华盛顿将与香港合作，确保“适当” <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/us-will-not-invite-sanctioned-hong-kong-leader-apec-2023-07-28/">参与</a>亚太经合组织(APEC)会议。</p>   <p>Beijing had reacted <a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/eng/xwfw_665399/s2510_665401/202307/t20230728_11119377.html" target="_blank">angrily</a> to suggestions Lee might not attend, saying imposing "illegal" and "unreasonable" sanctions on him was an act of bullying and that not inviting him violated APEC rules and contravened U.S. commitments as the host.翻译:北京对李明博可能不参加的建议做出了<a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/eng/xwfw_665399/s2510_665401/202307/t20230728_11119377.html" target="_blank">愤怒的</a>反应，称对他实施“非法”和“不合理”的制裁是一种欺凌行为，不邀请他违反了亚太经合组织的规则，也违反了美国作为东道主的承诺。</p>   <p>Hong Kong's statement said Lee was unable to attend due to "scheduling issues" and made no mention of the U.S. sanctions.翻译:香港的声明称，李光耀因“日程安排问题”而无法出席，并没有提及美国的制裁。</p>   <p>Chan is not subject to sanctions.翻译:陈没有受到制裁。</p>    <span>Reporting by Twinnie Siu, Farah Master and Ryan Woo; Editing by Louise Heavens and Mark Potter翻译:Twinnie Siu、Farah Master 和 Ryan Woo 报道；路易丝·天堂和马克·波特编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 12:29:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2EGZ3OQ5VJJGFAVQYQNTZRBT6A</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-finance-chief-attend-apec-meet-side-stepping-dispute-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HONGKONG</category>
                
                <category>APEC/ (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着能见度下降，中国雾霾笼罩的北方进入最高污染警报]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/zX5ATdfGfYbk72FADxApJ68CQFg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WFO5GY53ANJJTLYJ2LP35JMUQQ.jpg" alt="Beijing issues orange alert for heavy air pollution" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk at the Ming Dynasty City Wall Relics Park, as Beijing issues orange alert for heavy air pollution, in Beijing, China October 31, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年10月31日，中国北京，北京发布空气重度污染橙色预警，人们在明城墙遗址公园散步。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/eYqJBd1CJ-WF0r68X2nsiwQ1w-o=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XBSWF53SVFL5DCZ3CUQCZWWG6E.jpg" alt="Beijing issues orange alert for heavy air pollution" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A person wearing a face mask stands at the Ming Dynasty City Wall Relics Park, as Beijing issues orange alert for heavy air pollution, in Beijing, China October 31, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年10月31日，中国北京，一名戴着口罩的人站在明城墙遗址公园，北京发布空气重污染橙色警报。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/eq1RQ8oMVx4ifLkwqRDHL3Q5D9c=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XAUMWFOC3BMETFH45ZIDOU7UU4.jpg" alt="Beijing issues orange alert for heavy air pollution" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A train moves on a railway as Beijing issues orange alert for heavy air pollution, in Beijing, China October 31, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023 年 10 月 31 日，中国北京，北京发布空气重度污染橙色预警，一列火车在铁路上行驶。 REUTERS/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/zlrUCW8mvE9o0bsHoLrJyfr36FQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NFTEIYUTDRMVVO34FDDU5NVRZU.jpg" alt="Beijing issues orange alert for heavy air pollution" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People wearing face masks walk in a park as Beijing issues orange alert for heavy air pollution, in Beijing, China October 31, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年10月31日，中国北京，北京发布空气重度污染橙色预警，人们戴着口罩在公园里散步。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/MgwcZeezWAIjaxDXkdqvwF0pjIU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DJBPRLW62NM4XKAQWV4F4UDKLQ.jpg" alt="Beijing issues orange alert for heavy air pollution" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A person wearing a face mask walks at the Ming Dynasty City Wall Relics Park, as Beijing issues orange alert for heavy air pollution, in Beijing, China October 31, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年10月31日，中国北京，一名戴着口罩的人在明城墙遗址公园散步，北京发布空气重度污染橙色预警。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/RxFi7JQCxyc51AmGz5cwZPWEtF4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KQIYKS4GQNJWREUFWPGX5FPM2E.jpg" alt="Men walk amid heave smog on a polluted day in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Men walk amid heave smog on a polluted day in Beijing, China December 2, 2018. REUTERS/Jason Lee/File Photo翻译:2018 年 12 月 2 日，中国北京，污染严重的一天，男子在浓烟中行走。路透社/Jason Lee/资料照片</figcaption></figure>                       <p>Authorities issued their highest warnings for fog and haze on Tuesday as smog enveloped major cities in northern China, warning the public that visibility could drop to less than 50 metres (164 feet).翻译:周二，随着烟雾笼罩中国北方的主要城市，当局发布了雾霾的最高警报，警告公众能见度可能降至不到 50 米（164 英尺）。</p>   <p>Northern province Hebei launched an anti-pollution emergency response, listing traffic safety controls for when necessary including suspending flight takeoffs and landings, temporarily closing highways and suspending ferries, China's meteorological bureau said in a notice.翻译:中国气象局在一份通知中表示，河北省启动了污染防治应急响应，列出了必要时的交通安全控制措施，包括暂停航班起降、暂时关闭高速公路、暂停轮渡等。</p>   <p>Authorities also warned road users to stop in safe parking areas when conditions required and asked people to stay indoors.翻译:当局还警告道路使用者在有需要时将车停在安全停车区，并要求人们呆在室内。</p>   <p>Beijing said it would implement traffic control measures if the capital activates its highest air pollution warning.翻译:北京表示，如果首都启动空气污染最高预警，将实施交通管制措施。</p>   <p>Heavy smog has engulfed the country's north <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sports/athletics/marathoners-beijing-go-maskless-unfazed-by-smog-2023-10-29/">for a few days</a> while autumn temperatures soared to typical early summer levels close to 30 degrees Celsius (86 degrees Fahrenheit) in some areas.翻译:严重的雾霾已经席卷了该国北部<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sports/athletics/marathoners-beijing-go-maskless-unfazed-by-smog-2023-10-29/">几天</a>，而部分地区秋季气温飙升至典型的初夏水平，接近 30 摄氏度（86 华氏度）。</p>   <p>Experts said weak cold air currents from the north pole were a key factor behind the unusual weather.翻译:专家表示，来自北极的微弱冷气流是造成异常天气的关键因素。</p>   <p>As air pollution levels in the wider Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei area and northern part of Henan province reached moderate to severe, pollution control experts said increased industrial activities, heavy trucking and crop fires had contributed to the haze, state media CCTV reported.翻译:据官方媒体中央电视台报道，随着京津冀地区和河南省北部地区的空气污染水平达到中度至重度，污染控制专家表示，工业活动、重型卡车运输和农作物火灾的增加导致了雾霾。</p>   <p>Regional power consumption in late October was up 5% compared with first half of the month, more significantly in the cement, brick and tile industries, worsening conditions, CCTV said.翻译:据央视报道，10月下旬地区用电量较上半月增长5%，其中水泥、砖瓦行业增长更为明显，形势恶化。</p>   <p>Parts of Tianjin municipality and Hebei and Shandong provinces, as well as eastern areas of Jiangsu province saw heavy fog resulting in visibility of less than 1 km (0.62 mile) on Tuesday morning, the National Meteorological Center (NMC) said.翻译:国家气象中心（NMC）表示，周二上午，天津市部分地区、河北省、山东省以及江苏省东部地区出现大雾，能见度不足1公里（0.62英里）。</p>   <p>Until Thursday, light to moderate haze will continue to cover the central and southern parts of China's northern region, with severe haze forecast in the central parts, NMC said.翻译:国家气象局表示，至周四，我国北方地区中南部地区仍将有轻到中度灰霾天气，其中中部地区预计有重度灰霾天气。</p>   <p>Cold air currents are forecast to stream in the north from Thursday night, creating conditions that could weaken and dissipate the haze, the weather forecaster said.翻译:天气预报员表示，预计从周四晚上开始，冷气流将吹向北部，为削弱和消散雾霾创造条件。</p>    <span>Reporting by Liz Lee and Shanghai newsroom; Editing by Jamie Freed翻译:Liz Lee和上海新闻编辑室的报道；杰米·弗里德编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 11:34:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">NPWC52IMUFI6PABPN6EMDLMJ5A</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-smog-covered-north-highest-pollution-alert-visibility-drops-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Liz Lee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ASIA</category>
                
                <category>WEATHER/CHINA</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着转基因规则的彻底修改，KWS Saat 将出售中国玉米业务]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>German seed producer KWS Saat <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/KWSG.DE" target="_blank">(KWSG.DE)</a> said on Tuesday it will sell its Chinese corn business due to new regulations that could mean its conventionally bred traits would be unable to compete with genetically modified corn over the longer term.翻译:德国种子生产商 KWS Saat <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/KWSG.DE" target="_blank">(KWSG.DE)</a>周二表示，由于新的规定，该公司将出售其中国玉米业务，这可能意味着其传统育种的特性从长远来看将无法与转基因玉米竞争。</p>   <p>The company said it expects to sell its corn unit and the corresponding 49% minority stake in joint venture Kenfeng-KWS Seed to its Chinese partner firm Kenfeng for a mid-range double digit million euro sum.翻译:该公司表示，预计将以中位数百万欧元的价格将其玉米部门以及合资企业 Kenfeng-KWS Seed 中相应的 49% 少数股权出售给其中国合作伙伴公司 Kenfeng。</p>   <p>The decision was driven by changes in China’s regulatory framework, a company spokesperson told Reuters.翻译:该公司发言人告诉路透社，这一决定是由于中国监管框架的变化而做出的。</p>   <p>China has approved genetically modified corn for domestic companies, but bans foreign companies – including partners in joint ventures – from developing GMO corn traits.翻译:中国已批准国内公司使用转基因玉米，但禁止外国公司（包括合资企业的合作伙伴）开发转基因玉米性状。</p>   <p>KWS Saat said without giving further details that it expects the deal to positively affect its after-tax operating income for 2023/2024.翻译:KWS Saat 表示，预计该交易将对其 2023/2024 年税后营业收入产生积极影响，但未提供更多细节。</p>   <p>Kenfeng-KWS Seed was founded as a joint venture in 2014 as KWS Saat bet on the Chinese corn market opening up to foreign companies.翻译:KWS Saat 押注于中国玉米市场向外国公司开放，于 2014 年成立了合资企业垦丰 KWS 种业。</p>   <p>With the sale, KWS Saat will largely exit the Chinese market, where its corn business accounts for about 1% of global revenue, or about 15 million euros ($15.95 million).翻译:通过此次出售，KWS Saat 将基本退出中国市场，其玉米业务约占全球收入的 1%，即约 1500 万欧元（1595 万美元）。</p>   <p>($1 = 0.9406 euros)翻译:（1 美元 = 0.9406 欧元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Patricia Weiss, Writing by Ferenc Gaal, Editing by Friederike Heine, Kirsten Donovan翻译:帕特里夏·韦斯 (Patricia Weiss) 报道，费伦茨·加尔 (Ferenc Gaal) 撰稿，弗里德里克·海涅 (Friederike Heine) 和克尔斯滕·多诺万 (Kirsten Donovan) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 11:06:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4MTPO6FAVJM5NDNPCU6OSJUEM4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/kws-saat-sell-china-corn-business-gmo-rules-overhauled-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>KWS SAT</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[雷诺发言人与中国投资银行进行了“友好”讨论]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/pKo1RAUsTK1uJ0S7Xf8Wy3FxoJk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2EQSGBYPT5KUNLTVGBCZ6EQDSI.jpg" alt="The logo of Renault is seen at the Viva Technology conference" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of Renault is seen at the Viva Technology conference dedicated to innovation and startups at Porte de Versailles exhibition center in Paris, France, June 15, 2023. REUTERS/Gonzalo Fuentes/File Photo翻译:2023 年 6 月 15 日，在法国巴黎凡尔赛门展览中心举行的致力于创新和初创企业的 Viva Technology 会议上，可以看到雷诺的标志。 REUTERS/Gonzalo Fuentes/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>French carmaker Renault <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RENA.PA" target="_blank">(RENA.PA)</a> had "friendly" discussions with Chinese investment bank CICC about potential cooperation, but nothing has been signed or decided so far, a company spokesperson said, confirming media reports.翻译:法国汽车制造商雷诺<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RENA.PA" target="_blank">(RENA.PA)</a>发言人表示，该公司与中国投资银行中金公司就潜在合作进行了“友好”讨论，但迄今为止尚未签署或做出任何决定，这证实了媒体报道。</p>   <p>"A meeting took place between CICC and Renault Group for friendly discussions about China's market," a spokeswoman told Reuters.翻译:“中金公司与雷诺集团举行了一次会议，就中国市场进行了友好讨论，”一位发言人告诉路透社。</p>   <p>Chinese media outlet Cailianshe reported on Friday that Renault and CICC had reached a preliminary intention agreement to jointly invest to establish an investment fund to focus on the NEV industry chain, citing people familiar with the matter.翻译:中国媒体《财联社》周五援引知情人士的话报道称，雷诺与中金公司已达成初步意向协议，共同投资设立投资基金，专注于新能源汽车产业链。</p>   <p>Cailianshe added that Renault CEO Luca de Meo was in China for a week long visit.翻译:蔡联社补充说，雷诺首席执行官卢卡·德梅奥正在中国进行为期一周的访问。</p>   <p>CICC did not immediately respond to requests for comment.翻译:中金公司没有立即回应置评请求。</p>    <span>Reporting by Gilles Guillaume, additional reporting by Brenda Goh in Shanghai and Roxanne Liu in Beijing , writing by Tassilo Hummel, editing by Marine Strauss and Louise Heavens翻译:Gilles Guillaume 报道，Brenda Goh 在上海和 Roxanne Liu 在北京的补充报道，Tassilo Hummel 撰稿，Marine Strauss 和 Louise Heavens 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 10:30:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">AQA2WUXL2BIXTKIV7XKLILM4UQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/renault-had-friendly-discussions-with-chinese-investment-bank-spokesperson-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>RENAULT</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：中国中海油和两家化工公司正在考虑收购壳牌新加坡资产——消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/zsURz83gPL1bDzkEJbNocq4fiBw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PVLSX2JDMVPNDAWB6MFTJVDF5Q.jpg" alt="A view of Shell's Pulau Bukom refinery in Singapore" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view of Shell's Pulau Bukom refinery in Singapore November 17, 2020.  REUTERS/Edgar Su/File Photo翻译:2020 年 11 月 17 日，壳牌位于新加坡的 Pulau Bukom 炼油厂一景。REUTERS/Edgar Su/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>At least three Chinese companies including state giant China National Offshore Oil Company (CNOOC) are evaluating Shell's Singapore assets and considering non-binding bids in coming weeks for the city-state's oldest refinery, according to several sources familiar with the matter.翻译:据几位知情人士透露，包括国有巨头中国海洋石油总公司（中海油）在内的至少三家中国公司正在评估壳牌​​在新加坡的资产，并考虑在未来几周内对新加坡最古老的炼油厂进行非约束性投标。</p>   <p>Reuters reported in August that Shell had hired Goldman Sachs to explore a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/shell-taps-goldman-sachs-explore-singapore-refinery-sale-sources-2023-08-23/">potential sale</a> of its refining and petrochemical plants in Singapore as part of a broader strategic review globally to become a lower-carbon operator.翻译:路透社八月报道称，壳牌已聘请高盛探讨<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/shell-taps-goldman-sachs-explore-singapore-refinery-sale-sources-2023-08-23/">出售其在新加坡炼油和石化工厂的可能性</a>，作为全球范围内更广泛战略审查的一部分，以成为低碳运营商。</p>   <p>A buyer of Shell's assets on Bukom and Jurong islands would gain a foothold in Asia's main oil trading hub but would also face competition from newer refineries elsewhere - the Bukom facility opened in 1961 - as well as a Singapore carbon tax set to rise sharply in 2024.翻译:壳牌在武公岛和裕廊岛资产的买家将在亚洲主要石油贸易中心站稳脚跟，但也将面临来自其他地方较新炼油厂的竞争（武公工厂于 1961 年开业），以及新加坡碳税将于 2024 年大幅上涨。</p>   <p>CNOOC, Eversun Holdings and Wanhua Chemical <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/600309.SS" target="_blank">(600309.SS)</a> are among those that have started early evaluations of Shell assets that include a 237,000 barrels per day (bpd) refinery and a one million metric ton per year (tpy) ethylene cracker, the sources said.翻译:消息人士称，中海油、亿升控股和万华化学<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/600309.SS" target="_blank">（600309.SS）</a>等公司已开始对壳牌资产进行早期评估，其中包括一座日产 237,000 桶（bpd）的炼油厂和一座每年 100 万吨（tpy）的乙烯裂解装置。说。</p>   <p>CNOOC, the parent of offshore oil and gas major CNOOC Ltd , operates a joint refining-petrochemical complex with Shell in southern China.翻译:中海油是海上石油和天然气巨头中海油有限公司的母公司，与壳牌在中国南方联合经营炼油石化联合企业。</p>   <p>CNOOC did not immediately respond to a request for comment.翻译:中海油没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>The companies are among more than a dozen Shell invited to explore interest in the facilities. They also included Chinese state majors Sinopec <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/600028.SS" target="_blank">(600028.SS)</a>, PetroChina <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601857.SS" target="_blank">(601857.SS)</a> as well as big independent refiners Rongsheng Petrochemical <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002493.SZ" target="_blank">(002493.SZ)</a> and Hengli Petrochemical <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/600346.SS" target="_blank">(600346.SS)</a>, two of the sources said.翻译:这些公司是壳牌受邀对这些设施进行考察的十几家公司之一。两位消息人士称，其中还包括中国国有大型企业中石化<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/600028.SS" target="_blank">（600028.SS）</a> 、中石油<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601857.SS" target="_blank">（</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002493.SZ" target="_blank">601857.SS）以及大型独立炼油商熔盛石化（002493.SZ）</a>和恒力石化<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/600346.SS" target="_blank">（600346.SS）</a> 。</p>   <p>However, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/sinopec-says-not-interested-acquiring-shells-singapore-refinery-petchem-plant-2023-08-28/">Sinopec</a> Corp's president said in late August it was not interested in the Shell assets. Senior company officials at Hengli Petrochemical and Rongsheng told Reuters that the companies had no plan to bid for the assets.翻译:然而， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/sinopec-says-not-interested-acquiring-shells-singapore-refinery-petchem-plant-2023-08-28/">中石化</a>总裁八月下旬表示，对壳牌资产不感兴趣。恒力石化和熔盛集团的高级官员告诉路透社，两家公司没有竞购这些资产的计划。</p>   <p>PetroChina and its parent China National Petroleum Corp (CNPC) did not immediately respond to requests for comment.翻译:中国石油及其母公司中国石油天然气集团公司（CNPC）没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>"It appears that Shell has invited a broad group of companies and asked interested parties to send in a non-binding bid and proposal as to how they plan to run and manage the facilities," said a person involved in assessing the assets.翻译:一位参与资产评估的人士表示：“看来壳牌已经邀请了众多公司，并要求感兴趣的各方提交一份不具约束力的投标和建议，说明他们计划如何运营和管理这些设施。”</p>   <p>Two of the sources said Shell had set a preliminary Nov. 5 deadline for proposals, although that could be extended.翻译:其中两名消息人士称，壳牌已初步设定提案截止日期为 11 月 5 日，不过该截止日期可能会延长。</p>   <p>In response to questions from Reuters,
 Shell said the strategic review of its energy and chemicals park assets in Singapore is ongoing and it is exploring several options including divestment. It declined to comment on bidders or a schedule.翻译:壳牌在回应路透社的提问时表示，其在新加坡的能源和化工园区资产的战略审查正在进行中，并正在探索包括撤资在内的多种选择。它拒绝对投标人或时间表发表评论。</p>   <p>Goldman Sachs declined to comment.翻译:高盛拒绝置评。</p>   <p>It could not be determined which other companies may be assessing the assets.翻译:目前无法确定哪些其他公司可能正在评估这些资产。</p>    <h 1="">FEEDSTOCK BASE</h>  <p>CNOOC's joint venture with Shell in Huizhou, Guangdong province, produces plastic raw materials ethylene, propylene and derivatives. The companies agreed in 2020 to expand the complex in the next three years.翻译:中海油与壳牌在广东省惠州的合资企业生产塑料原料乙烯、丙烯及其衍生物。两家公司于 2020 年同意在未来三年内扩建该综合体。</p>   <p>Privately-run Eversun Holdings, based in Fujian province, started as a nylon producer and is building a 900,000-tpy polypropylene plant in Putian, according to its website.翻译:据其网站称，总部位于福建省的私营永升控股最初是一家尼龙生产商，目前正在莆田建设一座年产 90 万吨的聚丙烯工厂。</p>   <p>Eversun did not respond to a request for comment.翻译:EVERSUN 没有回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Shandong province-based Wanhua Chemical is the world's largest feedstock supplier for polyurethane foam used in home furnishings and building insulation, and is a leading player in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/chinese-petchem-firms-betting-big-energy-transition-products-2023-07-24/">chemicals</a> used in solar panels and lithium batteries.翻译:总部位于山东省的万华化学是全球最大的家居和建筑保温用聚氨酯泡沫原料供应商，也是太阳能电池板和锂电池<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/chinese-petchem-firms-betting-big-energy-transition-products-2023-07-24/">化学品</a>领域的领先企业。</p>   <p>A Wanhua spokesperson said he was not aware of the company's potential interest in the Shell assets.翻译:万华发言人表示，他不知道该公司对壳牌资产的潜在权益。</p>   <p>For Chinese would-be bidders, Singapore could be a base to produce and secure feedstocks to produce petrochemicals in China as well as a launchpad to expand global trading and marketing, especially in fast-growing Southeast Asia, experts said.翻译:专家表示，对于中国潜在竞标者来说，新加坡可以成为在中国生产和获取石化产品原料的基地，也可以成为扩大全球贸易和营销的启动平台，特别是在快速增长的东南亚。</p>   <p>"The key draw for Chinese companies is to have some form of upstream feedstock integration in Southeast Asia should they decide to expand on downstream petrochemical derivative production and activity within the Southeast Asia region," said Wood Mackenzie's global head of polyesters, Salmon Lee.翻译:Wood Mackenzie 聚酯全球主管 Salmon Lee 表示：“对中国公司来说，最重要的吸引力在于，如果他们决定扩大东南亚地区下游石化衍生产品的生产和活动，他们就能在东南亚进行某种形式的上游原料整合。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Chen Aizhu and Trixie Yap; Editing by Tony Munroe, Florence Tan and Kim Coghill翻译:陈爱珠、Trixie Yap 报道；编辑：Tony Munroe、Florence Tan 和 Kim Coghill</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 09:57:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">S72AFSI3LBIN7KGRYBQHI7NI7U</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/chinas-cnooc-two-chemical-firms-looking-shell-singapore-assets-sources-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Chen Aizhu, Trixie Yap]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SHELL</category>
                
                <category>SINGAPORE/REFINERY (EXCLUSIVE)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[伯克希尔哈撒韦公司出售价值2580万美元的中国比亚迪股份]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/_aRhSO4UT5Oq_Q4JdJJOlaUAGiE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/A66ZQTSOKBOZ7OAEV6CWVRVBLE.jpg" alt="Berkshire Hathaway Chairman Warren Buffett walks through the exhibit hall as shareholders gather to hear from the billionaire investor at Berkshire Hathaway Inc's annual shareholder meeting in Omaha" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Berkshire Hathaway Chairman Warren Buffett walks through the exhibit hall as shareholders gather to hear from the billionaire investor at Berkshire Hathaway Inc's annual shareholder meeting in Omaha, Nebraska, U.S., May 4, 2019. REUTERS/Scott Morgan/File Photo翻译:2019 年 5 月 4 日，在美国内布拉斯加州奥马哈举行的伯克希尔哈撒韦公司年度股东大会上，伯克希尔哈撒韦公司董事长沃伦·巴菲特走过展厅，股东们齐聚一堂，听取这位亿万富翁投资者的发言。路透社/斯科特·摩根/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Berkshire Hathaway, the investment company owned by Warren Buffett, has sold 820,500 Hong Kong-listed shares of electric vehicle maker BYD Co <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002594.SZ" target="_blank">(002594.SZ)</a> for HK$201.73 million ($25.78 million), a stock exchange filing showed.翻译:一份证券交易所文件显示，沃伦·巴菲特旗下的投资公司伯克希尔·哈撒韦公司已以 2.0173 亿港元（2578 万美元）的价格出售了电动汽车制造商比亚迪公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002594.SZ" target="_blank">（002594.SZ）</a>的 820,500 股香港上市股票。</p>   <p>The sale on Oct. 25 lowered Berkshire's holdings in BYD's issued H-shares to 7.98% from 8.05%, the filing to the Hong Kong stock exchange on Tuesday showed.翻译:周二向香港证券交易所提交的文件显示，10 月 25 日的出售使伯克希尔在比亚迪已发行 H 股中的持股比例从 8.05% 降至 7.98%。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.8238 Hong Kong dollars)翻译:(1 美元 = 7.8238 港元)</p>    <span>Reporting by Twinnie Siu; Editing by Louise Heavens翻译:萧婷妮报道；路易丝·天堂编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 09:18:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">LVHDGIPRGNNWRMMF6PMT7KCIOY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/berkshire-hathaway-sells-258-mln-worth-shares-chinas-byd-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>BYD</category>
                
                <category>BUFFETT/ELECTRIC (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[阿里巴巴指望通过激进的双十一定价来恢复销售魔力]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/nFsG4BZYsSjdLuXn4BS3BeGtXxU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/RNDYFDC6GZIGXGPS2RHTTNH2IU.jpg" alt="People sit near an Alibaba's advertisement promoting Singles Day shopping festival, in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People sit near an Alibaba's advertisement promoting Singles Day shopping festival, at a subway station in Beijing, China October 26, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年10月26日，中国北京的一个地铁站，人们坐在阿里巴巴宣传双十一购物节的广告旁边。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/xLclfPLZPMZFqYeBqkgVa-G9Pz4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NMT4JSXFWNOADLEOHEI4TJ77OQ.jpg" alt="Person walks past a JD.com's advertisement promoting Singles Day shopping festival, in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A person walks past a JD.com's advertisement promoting Singles Day shopping festival, at a subway station in Beijing, China October 26, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年10月26日，中国北京的一个地铁站，一个人走过京东的双十一购物节广告。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0fsKii717jbKp423B82vT9--p4s=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CV4AMWEDKJMF7BNL3RHLS4VADQ.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of e-commerce apps Pinduoduo, JD.com, Douyin and Taobao" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logos of e-commerce apps Pinduoduo, JD.com, Douyin and Alibaba's Taobao are displayed on mobile phones in this illustration picture taken October 25, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration翻译:这张摄于 2023 年 10 月 25 日的插图图片中，电子商务应用程序拼多多、京东、抖音和阿里巴巴淘宝的徽标显示在手机上。REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/PdySVqQNktzZgqDAgoK4YTo44-E=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/44ADDIEXLJLZBLM6DTMI5ZPBRY.jpg" alt="People ride on a scooter past a JD.com's advertisement promoting Singles Day shopping festival, in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People ride on a scooter past a JD.com's advertisement promoting Singles Day shopping festival, in Beijing, China October 26, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年10月26日，中国北京，人们骑着摩托车经过京东的双十一购物节广告。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/HRnlmq1yOrhkzz37ZZcNETRl5R8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HHCRHP7MQNPF7DYUST7GECQGBE.jpg" alt="People walk past an Alibaba's advertisement promoting Singles Day shopping festival, in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk past Alibaba's advertisements promoting Singles Day shopping festival, at a subway station in Beijing, China October 26, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年10月26日，中国北京的一个地铁站，人们走过阿里巴巴宣传双十一购物节的广告。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/eU_X7nFFRCr4pvh36yLUoIYbRto=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OCYHFFEBONIDTNQLWOB67SQ72I.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of e-commerce app Taobao" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of Alibaba's e-commerce app Tmall is displayed amid mobile phones displaying the app, in this illustration picture taken October 27, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration翻译:这张摄于 2023 年 10 月 27 日的插图图片中，阿里巴巴电子商务应用程序天猫的徽标显示在显示该应用程序的手机中。REUTERS/Florence Lo/插图</figcaption></figure>                       <p>China's Alibaba <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">(9988.HK)</a> is pressuring merchants to offer rock-bottom prices on its marketplaces in this year's Singles Day extravaganza, three industry sources said, as the e-commerce company seeks to boost sales and stem a drop in market share.翻译:三位业内消息人士称，中国阿里巴巴<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">（9988.HK）</a>正在向商家施压，要求他们在今年的双十一狂欢节中在其市场上提供最低价格，因为这家电子商务公司寻求提高销售额并遏制市场份额下降。</p>   <p>The sources, who help dozens of brands operate their stores on Alibaba’s platforms, said they were told to offer the best price of the year on Tmall or Taobao for the blockbuster shopping event, or risk losing the traffic and support given to event participants.翻译:这些帮助数十个品牌在阿里巴巴平台上运营商店的消息人士表示，他们被告知要在天猫或淘宝上为这场轰动的购物活动提供当年最优惠的价格，否则可能会失去流量和对活动参与者的支持。</p>   <p>While Alibaba has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/alibaba-promises-major-discounts-ahead-chinas-singles-day-shopping-event-2023-10-23/">announced</a> that it will offer 80 million products at their lowest prices this year during Singles Day, which began in late October and stretches till Nov. 11, the push to get merchants to toe its line is unusual for the company, they said.翻译:他们表示，虽然阿里巴巴<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/alibaba-promises-major-discounts-ahead-chinas-singles-day-shopping-event-2023-10-23/">宣布</a>将在今年双十一期间以最低价格提供 8000 万件产品，双十一从 10 月下旬开始，一直持续到 11 月 11 日，但推动商家遵守规定的做法对于该公司来说是不寻常的。 。</p>   <p>The strategy points to how Alibaba is fighting back against rivals such as Douyin and PDD Holdings' <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PDD.O" target="_blank">(PDD.O)</a> Pinduoduo who have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-e-commerce-discount-race-bottom-puts-incumbents-under-pressure-2023-09-26/">changed the landscape</a> of Chinese e-commerce in recent years by selling lower-cost and discounted items year-round, relying on approaches like live-streaming and taking the shine off mega events like Singles Day.翻译:该战略指出阿里巴巴如何反击抖音和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PDD.O" target="_blank">拼多多</a>等竞争对手，这些竞争对手近年来通过全年销售低成本和折扣商品， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-e-commerce-discount-race-bottom-puts-incumbents-under-pressure-2023-09-26/">改变了中国电子商务的格局。</a>采用直播等方式，以及为光棍节等大型活动增添光彩。</p>   <p>"Alibaba came out this year and is being super aggressive on price. They're like 'lowest prices on the internet, period'," said Josh Gardner, CEO of Kungfu Data, which helps operate online stores in categories including fashion and performance-wear.翻译:Kungfu Data 的首席执行官乔什·加德纳 (Josh Gardner) 表示：“阿里巴巴今年推出，在价格上非常激进。它们就像是‘互联网上的最低价格’。”Kungfu Data 帮助运营时尚和性能等类别的在线商店。穿。</p>   <p>"They leveraged all their merchants like us saying, 'If we catch you doing equal or less pricing on any other platform, we will remove you and all your listings from the event'."翻译:“他们利用所有像我们这样的商家说，‘如果我们发现你在任何其他平台上进行相同或更低的定价，我们将从活动中删除你和你的所有列表’。”</p>   <p>The two other sources did not wish to be named as they had not been authorised to speak to media about the event's arrangements.翻译:另外两名消息人士不愿透露姓名，因为他们没有被授权向媒体谈论该活动的安排。</p>   <p>Alibaba's Taobao and Tmall Group did not respond to a request for comment.翻译:阿里巴巴旗下的淘宝网和天猫集团没有回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Three e-commerce consultants whom Reuters spoke to said the company's demands did not appear to show anti-competitive behaviour, with one saying some of its rivals were also making similar stipulations to merchants.翻译:路透社采访的三名电子商务顾问表示，该公司的要求似乎并不表现出反竞争行为，其中一位表示，其一些竞争对手也向商家提出了类似的规定。</p>   <p>China's market regulator, the State Administration for Market Regulation, did not respond to a request for comment.翻译:中国市场监管机构国家市场监督管理总局没有回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Ashley Dudarenok, founder of digital consultancy Chozan, said that some brands who are selling on competing platforms might meet Alibaba's demands by giving it the best prices but simultaneously launch a special line of products on Douyin, for example.翻译:数字咨询公司 Chozan 的创始人阿什利·杜达雷诺克 (Ashley Dudarenok) 表示，一些在竞争平台上销售的品牌可能会通过向阿里巴巴提供最优惠的价格来满足阿里巴巴的要求，但同时会在抖音上推出一系列特殊产品。</p>   <p>Douyin, owned by ByteDance, declined to comment.翻译:字节跳动旗下的抖音拒绝置评。</p>   <p>Alibaba's stepped up sales effort comes at a time when Chinese consumer confidence remains at a low ebb.翻译:阿里巴巴加大销售力度之际，中国消费者信心仍处于低谷。</p>   <p>This year's Singles Day event is also the first since Alibaba Group split into <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/alibaba-splits-into-six-units-that-may-pursue-individual-ipos-bloomberg-news-2023-03-28/">six business units</a>. The unit encompassing the Taobao and Tmall businesses is the only one that will remain under the control of Alibaba Group after it spins off the others.翻译:今年的双十一活动也是阿里巴巴集团分拆为<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/alibaba-splits-into-six-units-that-may-pursue-individual-ipos-bloomberg-news-2023-03-28/">六大业务部门</a>以来的首次双十一活动。淘宝和天猫业务部门是阿里巴巴集团剥离其他业务后唯一仍由阿里巴巴集团控制的部门。</p>   <p>There are indications that Alibaba's push is paying off.翻译:有迹象表明阿里巴巴的努力正在取得成效。</p>   <p>When pre-sales, where consumers can put down deposits on items, began last Tuesday, turnover for over 1,300 brands jumped more than 200% year-over-year in the first hour, Taobao and Tmall Group said.翻译:淘宝和天猫集团表示，当消费者可以在上周二开始预售时，超过 1,300 个品牌的营业额在第一个小时内就同比增长了 200% 以上。</p>   <p>Consultancy AlixPartners has put out an early estimate tipping 18% growth in total spend across all major Chinese platforms. That compared with the 2.9% growth in 2022, according to data provider Syntun.翻译:咨询公司 AlixPartners 做出了初步估计，中国所有主要平台的总支出将增长 18%。根据数据提供商 Syntun 的数据，相比之下 2022 年增长率为 2.9%。</p>    <h 1="">EVENT'S RELEVANCE QUESTIONED</h>  <p>Alibaba reported $85 billion in sales for Singles Day in 2021, but has not released gross merchandise value since and has also toned down on promoting the event among media due to a government crackdown on Chinese technology companies.翻译:阿里巴巴公布 2021 年双十一销售额为 850 亿美元，但此后一直没有公布商品总价值，并且由于政府对中国科技公司的打压，也减少了在媒体上宣传这一活动的力度。</p>   <p>The renewed efforts this year come as Alibaba looks to preserve its e-commerce lead in China which has shrunk as rivals have gained ground. The company's share of China's total e-commerce market has fallen to around 40% now from near 70% in 2019, according to data published in a Credit Suisse report from January.翻译:今年，阿里巴巴推出新举措之际，正值阿里巴巴希望保持其在中国电子商务的领先地位，而随着竞争对手的崛起，这一领先优势已经缩小。根据瑞士信贷 (Credit Suisse) 1 月份发布的数据，该公司在中国整个电子商务市场的份额已从 2019 年的近 70% 降至目前的 40% 左右。</p>   <p>Industry executives said that Douyin has been reshaping Chinese consumer behaviour with daily live-streams that often offer lower prices than regular online stores.翻译:行业高管表示，抖音一直在通过每日直播重塑中国消费者的行为，这些直播的价格往往比普通网上商店更低。</p>   <p>"While the Singles Day festival remains a major shopping event in China, the daily accessibility of discounts and promotions via live-streaming has diluted the exclusivity of these mega sales events to some extent," said Melody Zhao, an e-commerce executive at Hua Gui Food Group, which sells food and beverage products across several e-commerce platforms.翻译:“虽然双十一仍然是中国的一项主要购物活动，但通过直播每天都能获得折扣和促销活动，在一定程度上削弱了这些大型销售活动的排他性，”华夏电子商务高管 Melody Zhu 表示。桂食品集团，通过多个电子商务平台销售食品和饮料产品。</p>   <p>This view is supported by recent polls on social media where the majority of respondents said Singles Day was no longer necessary.翻译:最近社交媒体上的民意调查支持了这一观点，大多数受访者表示不再需要光棍节。</p>   <p>Meara He, a 21-year-old student from Wenzhou, says she often shops using Douyin live-streams and this year, "doesn't care" about Singles Day as much.翻译:来自温州的 21 岁学生 Meara He 表示，她经常使用抖音直播购物，今年“不太关心”光棍节。</p>   <p>"In the past I would wait for Double 11 (Singles Day) and do some shopping, but this time I just plan to buy products that I need," she said.翻译:“以前我会等双11去购物，但这次我只是打算买我需要的产品，”她说。</p>    <span>Reporting by Casey Hall in Shanghai and Sophie Yu in Beijing; Editing by Brenda Goh and Muralikumar Anantharaman翻译:Casey Hall上海报道和Sophie Yu北京报道；编辑：Brenda Goh 和 Muralikumar Anantharaman</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 07:03:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">WAEC5GEDUZMMFHVYR5KLYZVCTU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/alibaba-banks-aggressive-singles-day-pricing-recoup-sales-mojo-2023-10-31/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Casey Hall, Sophie Yu]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>E COMMERCE/ALIBABA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
