<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub-five-red.vercel.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 13:33:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[分析：人工智能峰会只是一个开始，但全球协议的希望还很遥远]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Wvlq1mYJsBbmXchLK0uHLC4Rt0w=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TS3FBNGAOZJHDJTJ55V7UY5YMA.jpg" alt="British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak attends an in-conversation event with Tesla and SpaceX's CEO Elon Musk in London" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak attends an in-conversation event with Tesla and SpaceX's CEO Elon Musk in London, Britain, Thursday, Nov. 2, 2023. Kirsty Wigglesworth/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 2 日星期四，英国首相里希·苏纳克 (Rishi Sunak) 在英国伦敦出席与特斯拉和 SpaceX 首席执行官埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 的对话活动。 Kirsty Wigglesworth/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak championed a series of landmark agreements after hosting the first artificial intelligence (AI) safety summit but a global plan for overseeing the technology remains a long way off.翻译:英国首相里希·苏纳克 (Rishi Sunak) 在主办首届人工智能 (AI) 安全峰会后签署了一系列具有里程碑意义的协议，但监管该技术的全球计划仍有很长的路要走。</p>   <p>Over two days of talks between world leaders, business executives and researchers, tech CEOs such as Elon Musk and OpenAI's Sam Altman rubbed shoulders with the likes of U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris and European Commission chief Ursula von der Leyen to discuss the future regulation of AI.翻译:世界领导人、企业高管和研究人员进行了为期两天的会谈，埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 和 OpenAI 的萨姆·奥尔特曼 (Sam Altman) 等科技首席执行官与美国副总统卡马拉·哈里斯 (Kamala Harris) 和欧盟委员会主席乌苏拉·冯德莱恩 (Ursula von der Leyen) 等人士并肩讨论了人工智能的未来监管。</p>   <p>Leaders from 28 nations – including China – signed the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/britain-publishes-bletchley-declaration-ai-safety-2023-11-01/">Bletchley Declaration</a>, a joint statement acknowledging the technology's risks; the U.S. and Britain both announced plans to launch their own AI safety institutes; and two more summits were announced to take place in South Korea and France next year.翻译:包括中国在内的 28 个国家的领导人签署了《 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/britain-publishes-bletchley-declaration-ai-safety-2023-11-01/">布莱切利宣言》</a> ，这是一份承认该技术风险的联合声明；美国和英国都宣布计划成立自己的人工智能安全机构；并宣布明年将在韩国和法国举行另外两次峰会。</p>   <p>But while some consensus was reached on the need to regulate AI, disagreements remain over exactly how that should happen – and who will lead such efforts.翻译:不过，尽管人们就监管人工智能的必要性达成了一些共识，但对于具体如何实现以及由谁来领导这些努力仍存在分歧。</p>   <p>Risks around rapidly-developing AI have been an increasingly high priority for policymakers since Microsoft-backed Open AI <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O" target="_blank">(MSFT.O)</a> released ChatGPT to the public last year.翻译:自去年微软支持的开放人工智能<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O" target="_blank">(MSFT.O)</a>向公众发布 ChatGPT 以来，快速发展的人工智能带来的风险已成为政策制定者日益关注的重点。</p>   <p>The chatbot’s unprecedented ability to respond to prompts with human-like fluency has led some experts to call for a pause in the development of such systems, warning they could gain autonomy and threaten humanity.翻译:该聊天机器人具有前所未有的像人类一样流畅地响应提示的能力，这导致一些专家呼吁暂停此类系统的开发，并警告说它们可能会获得自主权并威胁人类。</p>   <p>Sunak talked of being "privileged and excited" to host Tesla-founder <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a> Musk, but European lawmakers warned of too much technology and data being held by a small number of companies in one country, the United States.翻译:苏纳克表示，能够接待特斯拉创始人<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">（TSLA.O）</a>马斯克“感到荣幸和兴奋”，但欧洲立法者警告称，美国这个国家的少数公司掌握了太多技术和数据。</p>   <p>"Having just one single country with all of the technologies, all of the private companies, all the devices, all the skills, will be a failure for all of us," French Minister of the Economy and Finance Bruno Le Maire told reporters.翻译:法国经济和财政部长布鲁诺·勒梅尔对记者表示：“只有一个国家拥有所有技术、所有私营公司、所有设备、所有技能，这对我们所有人来说都是失败的。”</p>   <p>The UK has also diverged from the EU by proposing light-touch approach to AI regulation, in contrast to Europe's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/what-is-european-union-ai-act-2023-03-22/">AI Act</a>, which is close to being finalised and will bind developers of what are deemed "high risk" applications to stricter controls.翻译:英国也与欧盟不同，提出了对人工智能监管采取宽松的方法，这与欧洲的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/what-is-european-union-ai-act-2023-03-22/">《人工智能法案》</a>形成鲜明对比，该法案即将敲定，并将对被视为“高风险”应用程序的开发人员进行更严格的控制。</p>   <p>"I came here to sell our AI Act," Vera Jourova, Vice President of the European Commission.翻译:“我来这里是为了推销我们的人工智能法案，”欧盟委员会副主席维拉·朱罗娃（Vera Jourova）说。</p>   <p>Jourova said, while she did not expect other countries to copy the bloc's laws wholesale, some agreement on global rules was required.翻译:朱罗娃表示，虽然她不希望其他国家大规模效仿欧盟的法律，但需要就全球规则达成一些协议。</p>   <p>"If the democratic world will not be rule-makers, and we become rule-takers, the battle will be lost," she said.翻译:“如果民主世界不成为规则制定者，而我们成为规则接受者，那么这场战斗就会失败，”她说。</p>   <p>While projecting an image of unity, attendees said翻译:与会者在展现团结形象的同时表示</p>   <p>the three main power blocs in attendance – the U.S., the EU,翻译:出席的三个主要权力集团——美国、欧盟、</p>   <p>and China – tried to assert their dominance.翻译:和中国——试图维护自己的主导地位。</p>   <p>Some suggested Harris had upstaged Sunak when the U.S. government announced its own <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-vice-president-harris-call-action-threats-ai-2023-11-01/">AI safety institute</a> – just as Britain had a week earlier – and she delivered a speech in London highlighting the technology’s short-term risks, in contrast to the summit’s focus on existential threats.翻译:一些人认为，当美国政府宣布成立自己的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-vice-president-harris-call-action-threats-ai-2023-11-01/">人工智能安全机构</a>时（就像英国一周前所做的那样），哈里斯抢了苏纳克的风头。她在伦敦发表演讲，强调了该技术的短期风险，这与峰会关注的生存威胁形成鲜明对比。</p>   <p>"It was fascinating that just as we announced our AI safety institute, the Americans announced theirs," said attendee Nigel Toon, CEO of British AI firm Graphcore.翻译:英国人工智能公司 Graphcore 首席执行官奈杰尔·图恩 (Nigel Toon) 表示：“令人着迷的是，就在我们宣布成立人工智能安全研究所时，美国人也宣布了他们的安全研究所。”</p>   <p>China's presence at the summit and its decision to sign off on the "Bletchley Declaration" was trumpeted as a success by British officials.翻译:英国官员称赞中国出席峰会并签署《布莱切利宣言》的决定是一次成功。</p>   <p>China’s vice minister of science and technology said the country was willing to work with all sides on AI governance.翻译:中国科技部副部长表示，中国愿与各方就人工智能治理开展合作。</p>   <p>Signalling tension between China and the West, however, Wu Zhaohui told delegates: "Countries regardless of their size and scale have equal rights to develop and use AI."翻译:然而，吴朝晖告诉代表们，这表明了中国和西方之间的紧张关系：“国家无论大小，都拥有开发和使用人工智能的平等权利。”</p>   <p>The Chinese minister participated in the ministerial roundtable on the Thursday, his ministry said. He did not participate in the public events on the second day, however.翻译:中国外交部表示，中国部长参加了周四的部长级圆桌会议。不过，他没有参加第二天的公开活动。</p>   <p>A recurring theme of the behind-closed-door discussions, highlighted by a number of attendees, was the potential risks of open-source AI, which gives members of the public free access to experiment with the code behind the technology.翻译:许多与会者强调，闭门讨论中反复出现的主题是开源人工智能的潜在风险，开源人工智能让公众可以自由地尝试技术背后的代码。</p>   <p>Some experts have warned that open-source models could be used by terrorists to create chemical weapons, or even create a super-intelligence beyond human control.翻译:一些专家警告说，开源模型可能被恐怖分子用来制造化学武器，甚至创造出人类无法控制的超级智能。</p>   <p>Speaking with Sunak at a live event in London on Thursday, Musk said: "It will get to the point where you’ve got open-source AI that will start to approach human-level intelligence, or perhaps exceed it. I don’t know quite what to do about it."翻译:周四在伦敦举行的现场活动中，马斯克与苏纳克交谈时表示：“开源人工智能将开始接近甚至超过人类水平的智能。我不认为很清楚该怎么办。”</p>   <p>Yoshua Bengio, an AI pioneer appointed to lead a "state of the science" report commissioned as part of the Bletchley Declaration, told Reuters the risks of open-source AI were a high priority.翻译:人工智能先驱 Yoshua Bengio 被任命领导一份“科学状况”报告，该报告是布莱切利宣言的一部分，他告诉路透社，开源人工智能的风险是一个高度优先的事项。</p>   <p>He said: "It could be put in the hands of bad actors, and it could be modified for malicious purposes. You can't have the open-source release of these powerful systems, and still protect the public with the right guardrails."翻译:他说：“它可能会落入坏人手中，也可能会被修改用于恶意目的。你不可能在开源这些强大系统的同时，仍然用正确的护栏来保护公众。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Martin Coulter and Paul Sandle; Additional Editing by Matt Scuffham and Louise Heavens翻译:马丁·库尔特和保罗·桑德尔的报道；马特·斯卡夫汉姆 (Matt Scuffham) 和路易斯·天堂 (Louise Heavens) 的额外编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 13:25:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">JGSIH2SFERO6JFWQJ7O7LSAB2I</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/ai-summit-start-global-agreement-distant-hope-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Martin Coulter, Paul Sandle]]></author>
            
                
                <category>AI</category>
                
                <category>BRITAIN/SUMMIT (ANALYSIS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[北京主教将在更广泛的紧张局势中罕见访问香港]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The Bishop of Beijing will visit Hong Kong later this month, building on a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/hong-kong-bishop-visits-beijing-historic-trip-amid-sino-vatican-tension-2023-04-17/">landmark visit</a> to the Chinese capital by his Hong Kong counterpart in April, the Hong Kong Catholic diocese announced on Friday.翻译:香港天主教教区周五宣布，北京主教将于本月晚些时候访问香港，继香港主教四月份对中国首都<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/hong-kong-bishop-visits-beijing-historic-trip-amid-sino-vatican-tension-2023-04-17/">进行具有里程碑意义的访问</a>之后。</p>   <p>Diplomats say Bishop Joseph Li Shan's visit will be closely watched, given tensions in the broader Chinese-Vatican relationship as well as fears among some Catholics that Beijing wants tighter control over religious affairs in Hong Kong.翻译:外交官表示，鉴于中梵关系更广泛的紧张局势，以及一些天主教徒担心北京希望加强对香港宗教事务的控制，李山主教的访问将受到密切关注。</p>   <p>Li is due to start the five-day visit on Nov. 14, a diocese statement said.翻译:教区声明称，李先生将于 11 月 14 日开始为期五天的访问。</p>   <p>As well as meeting Cardinal Stephen Chow, the Bishop of Hong Kong, Li would meet different diocesan "offices to promote exchanges and interactions between the two dioceses", the statement said.翻译:声明称，除了会见香港主教周星驰枢机外，李肇星还将会见不同教区的“办公室，以促进两个教区之间的交流和互动”。</p>   <p>Confirmation of the visit follows an invitation made by Cardinal Chow during his trip to Beijing - the first since the former British colony was returned to Chinese sovereignty in 1997.翻译:此次访问是在周枢机主教访问北京期间发出邀请后确认的，这是自1997年这个前英国殖民地回归中国以来的首次访问。</p>   <p>Chow <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-liked-popes-recent-overture-beijing-bishop-visit-hong-kong-2023-09-28/">told Reuters in September</a> shortly before he was made a cardinal that he hoped his new rank would help him boost the strained ties between the Vatican and Beijing.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-liked-popes-recent-overture-beijing-bishop-visit-hong-kong-2023-09-28/">九月份，周在被任命为枢机主教前不久告诉路透社</a>，他希望他的新职位能够帮助他改善梵蒂冈与北京之间的紧张关系。</p>   <p>"I think we have built up some type of relationships, some friendships," Chow said, adding he hoped Hong Kong could be a "bridging" church.翻译:“我认为我们已经建立了某种关系，一些友谊，”周说，并补充说他希望香港能够成为一个“桥梁”教会。</p>   <p>Hong Kong has traditionally been seen as a regional Catholic hub on the edge of the Chinese mainland under officially-atheist Communist Party rule.翻译:传统上，在无神论的共产党统治下，香港一直被视为位于中国大陆边缘的地区天主教中心。</p>   <p>For decades mainland Catholics have been split between an official church loyal to Beijing and an underground flock loyal to the Pope, but an interim deal struck in 2018 between the Vatican and Beijing over the appointment of bishops was aimed at easing those tensions.翻译:几十年来，大陆天主教徒一直分裂为忠于北京的官方教会和忠于教皇的地下教会，但梵蒂冈和北京在 2018 年就主教任命问题达成的临时协议旨在缓解这些紧张关系。</p>   <p>The confidential pact, which has been renewed twice, remains tenuous, with the Vatican complaining Beijing has broken it several times.翻译:这项保密协议已两次续签，但仍然脆弱，梵蒂冈抱怨北京多次违反该协议。</p>   <p>Conservatives in the Church have accused the Vatican of selling out to China by maintaining the accord, which has been renewed twice. The Vatican says an imperfect deal is better than no dialogue at all.翻译:教会中的保守派指责梵蒂冈通过维持该协议来出卖中国，该协议已经两次续签。梵蒂冈表示，不完美的协议总比没有对话好。</p>    <span>Reporting By Greg Torode; Editing by Emelia Sithole-Matarise翻译:格雷格·托罗德报道；编辑：埃米莉亚·西托尔-马塔里斯</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 13:09:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZRLXK4TF3NLTTNO72TT52UVPDI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/beijing-bishop-make-rare-visit-hong-kong-amid-broader-tensions-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Greg Torode]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>POLITICS/CATHOLICS (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[布林肯：拜登希望改善美非贸易计划，而不仅仅是更新它]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>AGOA trade initiative expires in 2025翻译:AGOA 贸易倡议将于 2025 年到期</li>  <li>Africans want early renewal, with possible changes after翻译:非洲人希望尽早更新，之后可能会发生变化</li>  <li>U.S. administration says AGOA needs updating翻译:美国政府表示 AGOA 需要更新</li> </ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/EE7ua3WKUmiTdfFne93UgGbTJ7k=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3XQO5RV2PVMONDCXKX3VED6E7M.jpg" alt="U.S. Secretary of State Blinken departs on trip to the Middle East and Asia from Joint Base Andrews in Maryland" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken speaks to reporters about the war between Israel and Hamas and the situation in Gaza as he boards his aircraft to depart Washington on travel to the Middle East and Asia at Joint Base Andrews, Maryland, U.S., November 2, 2023. REUTERS/Jonathan Ernst/Pool翻译:2023 年 11 月 2 日，美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯在美国马里兰州安德鲁斯联合基地登上飞机离开华盛顿前往中东和亚洲，向记者讲述以色列和哈马斯之间的战争以及加沙局势. 路透社/乔纳森·恩斯特/普尔</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/hbpbD9Sao0h9eCP6qNH3_S2J4Vc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7KIITBBCGFI35DTRN4IWU6Z34M.jpg" alt="South Africa hosts US-Africa trade summit" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Ambassador Katherine Tai, United States Trade Representative, speaks during the opening of the U.S.-sub-Saharan Africa trade forum to discuss the future of the African Growth and Opportunity Act (AGOA), at the NASREC conference center in Johannesburg, South Africa, November 3, 2023. REUTERS/Siphiwe Sibeko翻译:11 月，美国贸易代表凯瑟琳·戴大使在南非约翰内斯堡 NASREC 会议中心举行的美国撒哈拉以南非洲贸易论坛开幕式上发表讲话，讨论非洲增长与机会法案 (AGOA) 的未来2023 年 3 月。路透社/Siphiwe Sibeko</figcaption></figure>               <p>President Joe Biden's administration wants to work with Congress to improve the United States' flagship trade programme with Africa, not just renew it without changes, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken said on Friday.翻译:美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯周五表示，乔·拜登总统的政府希望与国会合作，改善美国对非洲的旗舰贸易计划，而不仅仅是不做任何修改地续签该计划。</p>   <p>First launched in 2000, the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-african-growth-opportunity-act-agoa-2023-11-01/">African Growth and Opportunity Act</a> (AGOA) grants exports from qualifying African countries duty-free access to the United States - the world's largest consumer market.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-african-growth-opportunity-act-agoa-2023-11-01/">《非洲增长与机会法案》</a> (AGOA) 于 2000 年首次推出，允许符合条件的非洲国家的出口产品免税进入美国这一全球最大的消费市场。</p>   <p>It is due to expire in September 2025, and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/african-apparel-industrys-future-hangs-us-thread-2023-11-01/">discussions</a> are currently under way over what would be its third reauthorisation.翻译:该授权将于 2025 年 9 月到期，目前正在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/african-apparel-industrys-future-hangs-us-thread-2023-11-01/">讨论</a>第三次重新授权。</p>   <p>African countries are pushing for an early <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa-us-trade-programme-needs-least-10-year-extension-au-says-2023-11-02/">10-year extension</a> without changes to reassure businesses and investors.翻译:非洲国家正在推动在不做任何改变的情况下提前<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa-us-trade-programme-needs-least-10-year-extension-au-says-2023-11-02/">延长 10 年</a>，以安抚企业和投资者。</p>   <p>Despite longstanding bipartisan support from U.S. lawmakers, who view AGOA as critical in countering the influence of China in Africa, there are divisions over the need for updates.翻译:尽管美国立法者长期以来一直支持两党，他们认为《非洲增长机会法案》对于对抗中国在非洲的影响至关重要，但对于更新的必要性存在分歧。</p>   <p>A <a href="https://www.scott.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/senator_scott_leads_call_to_renew_agoa_to_combat_chinese_and_russian_influence_in_africa_provide_certainty_for_usbusinesses.pdf" target="_blank">recent push</a> in the U.S. Senate is aiming to pass a quick AGOA renewal. Biden has also said he fully supports the initiative's reauthorisation.翻译:美国参议院<a href="https://www.scott.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/senator_scott_leads_call_to_renew_agoa_to_combat_chinese_and_russian_influence_in_africa_provide_certainty_for_usbusinesses.pdf" target="_blank">最近的一项努力</a>旨在快速通过《非洲增长机会法案》的续签。拜登还表示，他完全支持该倡议的重新授权。</p>   <p>"But we don't just want to extend AGOA, we want to work with the United States Congress to make it even better," Blinken said in a video message to U.S. officials and African trade ministers meeting in Johannesburg to discuss AGOA's future.翻译:布林肯在给在约翰内斯堡开会讨论 AGOA 未来的美国官员和非洲贸易部长的视频信息中表示：“但我们不仅仅想延长 AGOA，我们还希望与美国国会合作，使其变得更好。”</p>    <h 1="">'FORWARD-LOOKING VISION'</h>  <p>Over $10 billion worth of African exports entered the United States duty free last year under the programme. However, the U.S. International Trade Commission earlier this year highlighted major shortcomings.翻译:去年，根据该计划，价值超过 100 亿美元的非洲出口产品免税进入美国。然而，美国国际贸易委员会今年早些时候强调了重大缺陷。</p>   <p>More than 80% of duty-free non-petroleum AGOA exports, for example, have come from just five countries - South Africa, Kenya, Lesotho, Madagascar and Ethiopia - in recent years.翻译:例如，近年来，超过 80% 的免税非石油类 AGOA 出口仅来自五个国家——南非、肯尼亚、莱索托、马达加斯加和埃塞俄比亚。</p>   <p>"We see that there is opportunity to shape a stronger, new, forward-looking vision for U.S.-Africa trade," U.S. Trade Representative Katherine Tai, who is leading the U.S. delegation, told the African ministers.翻译:美国代表团团长、美国贸易代表凯瑟琳·戴对非洲部长们表示：“我们看到有机会为美非贸易塑造更强大、新的、前瞻性的愿景。”</p>   <p>African governments and U.S. industry associations, however, worry that attempts to radically alter AGOA risk bogging the programme's renewal down in a Congress that is already struggling to pass even the most critical legislation.翻译:然而，非洲各国政府和美国行业协会担心，从根本上改变《非洲增长机会法案》的尝试可能会导致该计划的更新陷入困境，而国会已经在努力通过最关键的立法。</p>   <p>"We would like you to look at an extension of AGOA for a sufficiently lengthy period ... to act as an incentive for investors to build factories on the African continent," South African President Cyril Ramaphosa told the forum.翻译:南非总统西里尔·拉马福萨在论坛上表示：“我们希望大家考虑将《非洲增长机会法案》延长足够长的一段时间……以激励投资者在非洲大陆建设工厂。”</p>   <p>African governments are also pushing for more flexibility concerning eligibility criteria and a loosening of what is now an annual review of those criteria.翻译:非洲各国政府也在推动资格标准更加灵活，并放宽目前对这些标准的年度审查。</p>   <p>The Biden administration said on Oct. 30 it intended to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/us-end-participation-gabon-niger-uganda-central-african-republic-trade-program-2023-10-30/">end the participation</a> of Gabon, Niger, Uganda and the Central African Republic in AGOA over governance and rights failings.翻译:拜登政府10月30日表示，由于治理和权利缺陷，打算<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/us-end-participation-gabon-niger-uganda-central-african-republic-trade-program-2023-10-30/">终止加蓬、尼日尔、乌干达和中非共和国参与</a>AGOA。</p>   <p>Harriet Ntabazi, trade minister of Uganda, whose country was suspended over "gross violations" of internationally recognised human rights, said such issues should be separated from trade.翻译:乌干达贸易部长哈里特·恩塔巴齐(Harriet Ntabazi)表示，此类问题应与贸易分开。乌干达因“严重侵犯”国际公认的人权而被停职。</p>   <p>Ugandan government officials have linked their exclusion to an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/ugandas-anti-gay-law-causing-wave-rights-abuses-activists-say-2023-09-28/">anti-homosexuality</a> law that was passed by its parliament in May.翻译:乌干达政府官员将他们的排斥与议会五月通过的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/ugandas-anti-gay-law-causing-wave-rights-abuses-activists-say-2023-09-28/">反同性恋</a>法联系起来。</p>   <p>"Mistakes are human. If they have been done, reconsider and we go into negotiations. We've never had this chance to sit together and agree. Give us another chance," Ntabazi said.翻译:“人都会犯错误。如果犯了错误，请重新考虑，然后我们进行谈判。我们从来没有机会坐在一起达成一致。再给我们一次机会，”恩塔巴齐说。</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Carien du Plessis;
Writing by Tannur Anders;
Editing by Alexander Winning and Nick Macfie翻译:Carien du Plessis 的补充报道；坦努尔·安德斯 (Tannur Anders) 撰写；亚历山大·温宁和尼克·麦克菲编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 12:27:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">SYO4UQWBIVMHLK4XTMN66KHA5A</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/biden-administration-wants-improve-africa-us-trade-pact-blinken-says-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Joe Bavier, Nellie Peyton, Bhargav Acharya]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>AFRICA/TRADE (UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[习近平：中德合作更加坚实有力]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Cooperation between China and Germany has become more robust, solid and dynamic, Chinese President Xi Jinping told German Chancellor Olaf Scholz through a video link chat on Friday.翻译:中国国家主席习近平周五通过视频连线向德国总理肖尔茨表示，中德合作变得更加强劲、坚实、充满活力。</p>   <p>In a wide-ranging discussion that touched on global trade, climate goals, the Israel-Hamas war and Ukraine crisis, the two leaders agreed that China-German relations are improving on several fronts.翻译:在涉及全球贸易、气候目标、以色列-哈马斯战争和乌克兰危机的广泛讨论中，两位领导人一致认为中德关系在多个方面正在改善。</p>   <p>"China-Germany trade is developing steadily, two-way investment enthusiasm is high, and the cooperation between the two countries is becoming more stable, more solid and more dynamic," Xi was quoted as saying by state broadcaster China Central Television (CCTV).翻译:中央电视台援引习近平的话说：“中德贸易稳定发展，双向投资热情高涨，两国合作更加稳定、更加扎实、更加富有活力。” 。</p>   <p>Scholz, who came to China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/german-chancellor-scholz-lands-beijing-2022-11-04/">last November</a> in the first visit by a G7 leader to the country since the COVID-19 pandemic, said "German-Chinese relations has shown more possibilities and broad prospects."翻译:肖尔茨<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/german-chancellor-scholz-lands-beijing-2022-11-04/">去年11月</a>来到中国，这是自COVID-19大流行以来七国集团领导人首次访华，他表示“德中关系展现出更多可能性和广阔前景”。</p>   <p>In the talks, Xi said he also hoped that Germany would push the European Union to "uphold the principles of marketization and fairness, work with China to uphold fair market competition and free trade, and maintain the stability of global industrial and supply chains."翻译:习近平在会谈中表示，希望德国推动欧盟“坚持市场化和公平原则，同中方共同维护市场公平竞争和自由贸易，维护全球产业链供应链稳定”。</p>   <p>China is facing a probe by the European Union into subsidies for electric vehicles, and also the threat of other investigations linked to Chinese <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/eu-targeting-china-steelmakers-is-against-global-trade-order-commerce-ministry-2023-10-12/">steelmakers</a> and its <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/eu-not-ready-formal-probe-into-chinas-wind-industry-source-2023-10-24/">wind power</a> industry.翻译:中国正面临欧盟对电动汽车补贴的调查，以及与中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/eu-targeting-china-steelmakers-is-against-global-trade-order-commerce-ministry-2023-10-12/">钢铁制造商</a>及其<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/eu-not-ready-formal-probe-into-chinas-wind-industry-source-2023-10-24/">风电</a>行业相关的其他调查的威胁。</p>   <p>Xi said both countries must not only develop good bilateral relations, but also safeguard the international order and multilateralism and work together to address global challenges, according to state media.翻译:据官方媒体报道，习近平表示，两国不仅要发展良好的双边关系，还要维护国际秩序和多边主义，共同应对全球性挑战。</p>   <p>In their meeting last November, both leaders jointly condemned threats of using nuclear weapons as the Ukraine-Russia conflict escalated.翻译:在去年11月的会晤中，两国领导人共同谴责随着乌克兰与俄罗斯冲突升级而威胁使用核武器。</p>   <p>This time Xi pointed out that "whether it is the Palestinian-Israeli conflict or the Ukraine crisis, to solve the root cause, it is necessary to think more deeply about security issues, and promote the construction of a balanced, effective and sustainable security architecture," he was quoted as saying by state media.翻译:此次习近平指出，“无论是巴以冲突，还是乌克兰危机，要解决根源，都要深入思考安全问题，推动构建平衡、有效、可持续的安全架构”。 ，”官方媒体援引他的话说。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ella Cao and Bernard Orr
Editing by Tomasz Janowski, William Maclean翻译:报道：Ella Cao 和 Bernard Orr 编辑：Tomasz Janowski、William Maclean</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 12:22:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">O6BK6QKYCVL2LLL4XYG7HE6C7I</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-germany-cooperation-has-become-more-solid-dynamic-chinas-xi-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>GERMANY/XI</category>
                
                <category>SCHOLZ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[澳大利亚和中国：恢复贸易和访问的道路崎岖]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/7s5iTcrQZOsKdG5VRI29ZHwQtPc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3CXIBCF2WFOPDFLLVAATIF5KUU.jpg" alt="Illustration shows printed Chinese and Australian flags" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>File photo: Printed Chinese and Australian flags are seen in this illustration, July 21, 2022. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File photo翻译:资料照片：这张插图中可以看到印刷的中国和澳大利亚国旗，摄于 2022 年 7 月 21 日。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/t-ZBoJ-4VKqEIM6oSUd0xHH5684=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GAG4HD2QXROPFKPXFLDYOMP6OM.jpg" alt="Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese speaks to media following a Ministry Meeting, in Melbourne" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese speaks to media following a Ministry Meeting, in Melbourne, October 11, 2023. AAP Image/Joel Carrett via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞 (Anthony Albanese) 于 2023 年 10 月 11 日在墨尔本举行的部长级会议后向媒体发表讲话。图片来源：AAP 图片/Joel Carrett via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese will on Saturday become the first Australian leader to visit China in seven years, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-albanese-highlight-trade-china-visit-ties-warm-2023-11-03/">arriving</a> after a period of badly strained relations with the aim of improving dialogue and stabilising ties.翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞将于周六成为七年来第一位访问中国的澳大利亚领导人，他在经历了一段严重紧张的关系之后<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-albanese-highlight-trade-china-visit-ties-warm-2023-11-03/">抵达</a>中国，目的是改善对话和稳定关系。</p>   <p>But difficult issues remain between the major trading partners and Albanese said he would raise concerns over rising tension in the South China Sea in a meeting with President Xi Jinping in Beijing on Monday.翻译:但主要贸易伙伴之间仍存在棘手问题，阿尔巴尼斯表示，他将在周一与国家主席习近平在北京会晤时提出对南海紧张局势升级的担忧。</p>   <p>Following is a timeline of relations between Australia and China over recent years.翻译:以下是近年来澳大利亚与中国关系的时间表。</p>   <p>Nov. 17, 2014 - Australia sealed a landmark free trade agreement with top trade partner China, concluding a decade of negotiations. It comes into effect in late 2015.翻译:2014年11月17日——澳大利亚与最大贸易伙伴中国签署了具有里程碑意义的自由贸易协定，结束了长达十年的谈判。该法案将于 2015 年底生效。</p>   <p>Dec. 5, 2017 - Australia, concerned about Chinese influence, announces ban on foreign political donations to prevent external interference in its politics.翻译:2017年12月5日——担心中国影响力的澳大利亚宣布禁止外国政治捐款，以防止外部干涉其政治。</p>   <p>Aug. 23, 2018 - Australia bans Huawei Technologies Co Ltd from supplying equipment for its planned 5G broadband network, citing national security regulations.翻译:2018 年 8 月 23 日 - 澳大利亚以国家安全法规为由，禁止华为技术有限公司为其计划中的 5G 宽带网络提供设备。</p>   <p>April 2020 - Australia seeks support for an international inquiry into the origins of the COVID-19 pandemic. China's then ambassador to Australia says that in response to the call, the Chinese public would boycott Australian wine, beef and tourism.翻译:2020 年 4 月 - 澳大利亚寻求支持对 COVID-19 大流行的起源进行国际调查。时任中国驻澳大利亚大使表示，响应号召，中国公众将抵制澳大利亚葡萄酒、牛肉和旅游业。</p>   <p>June 9, 2020 - China urges students going overseas to think carefully before choosing Australia, citing racist incidents, threatening a $27.5 billion market for educating foreign students.翻译:2020年6月9日 - 中国以种族主义事件为由，敦促出国留学的学生在选择澳大利亚之前慎重考虑，威胁到275亿美元的外国学生教育市场。</p>   <p>August 2020 - Australian citizen Cheng Lei, a business anchor for Chinese state television in Beijing, is detained.翻译:2020 年 8 月 - 澳大利亚公民成雷，北京中国国家电视台商业主播被拘留。</p>   <p>Nov. 27, 2020 - China will impose temporary anti-dumping tariffs on Australian wine, China announces. Shipments of Australian live lobsters, timber and barley are also blocked or restricted around this time. China's embassy lists 14 grievances with Australia, including the blocking of 10 Chinese investments on national security grounds.翻译:2020年11月27日——中国宣布对澳大利亚葡萄酒征收临时反倾销关税。澳大利亚活龙虾、木材和大麦的运输也在此时被封锁或限制。中国大使馆列出了对澳大利亚的14项不满，其中包括以国家安全为由阻止10项中国投资。</p>   <p>December 2020 - Australia raises concern at WTO meeting about China's measures to restrict or ban shipments of Australian barley, wine, meat, dairy, live seafood, logs, timber, coal and cotton.翻译:2020 年 12 月 - 澳大利亚在世贸组织会议上对中国限制或禁止运输澳大利亚大麦、葡萄酒、肉类、乳制品、活海鲜、原木、木材、煤炭和棉花的措施表示担忧。</p>   <p>May 22, 2022 - Australia's Labor Party, led by Albanese, ends almost a decade of conservative rule with a general election victory.翻译:2022 年 5 月 22 日 - 阿尔巴内塞领导的澳大利亚工党以大选胜利结束了近十年的保守派统治。</p>   <p>Nov. 15, 2022 - Albanese meets President Xi Jinping on sidelines of G20 in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-looks-forward-constructive-dialogue-with-china-pm-albanese-2022-11-15/">Indonesia</a>, first leaders' meeting since 2016.翻译:2022 年 11 月 15 日 - 阿尔巴内塞在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-looks-forward-constructive-dialogue-with-china-pm-albanese-2022-11-15/">印度尼西亚</a>举行的 G20 峰会期间会见了习近平主席，这是自 2016 年以来的首次领导人会议。</p>   <p>Dec. 21, 2022 - Foreign Minister Penny Wong in Beijing for first formal talks in China since 2018.翻译:2022 年 12 月 21 日 - 外交部长黄英贤在北京举行自 2018 年以来首次在华正式会谈。</p>   <p>Jan. 3, 2023 - China allows three government-backed utilities and its top steelmaker to resume coal imports from Australia.翻译:2023 年 1 月 3 日 - 中国允许三个政府支持的公用事业公司及其最大的钢铁制造商恢复从澳大利亚进口煤炭。</p>   <p>May 11 - Australia's Trade Minister Don Farrell arrives in Beijing for talks on removal of trade barriers.翻译:5月11日，澳大利亚贸易部长唐·法雷尔抵达北京就消除贸易壁垒进行会谈。</p>   <p>Aug. 5 - China ends 80.5% tariffs on Australian barley.翻译:8 月 5 日——中国终止对澳大利亚大麦征收 80.5% 的关税。</p>   <p>Sept. 7 - Albanese meets Premier Li Qiang on sidelines of East Asia Summit in Indonesia.翻译:9月7日——阿尔巴内斯在印度尼西亚东亚峰会期间会见了李强总理。</p>   <p>Oct. 11 - China releases Australian journalist Cheng Lei after three years in a Beijing prison on national security charges.翻译:10 月 11 日 - 中国释放了因国家安全罪名被关押在北京监狱三年的澳大利亚记者成雷。</p>   <p>Oct. 21 - Australia gives green light to Chinese company Landbridge's 99-year lease on Port of Darwin after security review.翻译:10月21日——经过安全审查，澳大利亚批准中国公司岚桥集团在达尔文港的99年租约。</p>   <p>Oct. 22 - China agrees to review dumping tariffs of 218% on Australian wine, potentially clearing way for the resumption of imports. Australia pauses WTO complaint.翻译:10 月 22 日——中国同意对澳大利亚葡萄酒征收 218% 的倾销关税进行复审，这可能为恢复进口扫清道路。澳大利亚暂停向世贸组织申诉。</p>    <span>Reporting by Kirsty Needham; editing by Robert Birsel翻译:科斯蒂·李约瑟报道；罗伯特·伯塞尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 11:48:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">QLNYZMNJFZJOJI5TBSQAR4JENA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australia-china-rocky-road-back-trade-visits-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA/ (TIMELINE)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[伊蒂哈德赛取消后，塞帕汉被罚款并禁止进入体育场]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Iran's Sepahan have been handed a $200,000 fine by the Asian Football Confederation and banned from playing at their Nagsh-e-Jahan stadium after last month's Asian Champions League clash with Saudi Arabia's Al-Ittihad was cancelled.翻译:伊朗队Sepahan上个月与沙特阿拉伯队Al-Ittihad队的亚洲冠军联赛比赛被取消后，被亚洲足球联合会处以20万美元罚款，并禁止在他们的Nagsh-e-Jahan体育场比赛。</p>   <p>Sepahan have also been given a 3-0 defeat in the game, which did not kick off after Al-Ittihad players refused to take to the field due to a statue of assassinated Iranian general Qasem Soleimani being placed at the entrance to the pitch.翻译:塞帕汉队也在比赛中0-3落败，由于球场入口处放置了被暗杀的伊朗将军卡西姆·苏莱马尼的雕像，伊蒂哈德队球员拒绝上场，因此比赛没有开始。</p>   <p>The club will not be permitted to play their next two Asian Champions League games--against Uzbekistan's AGMK on Monday and against Iraqis Air Force Club on Nov. 27--at home with the third match of the ban suspended for three years.翻译:该俱乐部将不被允许在主场进行接下来的两场亚洲冠军联赛——周一对阵乌兹别克斯坦AGMK，以及11月27日对阵伊拉克空军俱乐部——第三场比赛将暂停三年。</p>   <p>The confederation's disciplinary committee said Sepahan's behaviour had "created an unsafe and unstable security environment" and "caused reputational damage to the AFC, the AFC Champions League competition and Asian football generally".翻译:亚足联纪律委员会表示，塞帕汉的行为“造成了不安全、不稳定的治安环境”，“对亚足联、亚冠联赛以及亚洲足球整体声誉造成损害”。</p>   <p>The incident occurred in Isfahan on Oct. 2, with the game called off minutes after the scheduled start time and with around 60,000 fans in the stadium.翻译:这起事件于 10 月 2 日发生在伊斯法罕，比赛在预定开始时间几分钟后取消，体育场内约有 6 万名球迷。</p>   <p>Al-Ittihad moved onto nine points from three games in the group standings, five ahead of Air Force Club and Sepahan with AGMK bottom without a point.翻译:伊蒂哈德队在小组积分榜上三场比赛中积 9 分，领先空军俱乐部和塞帕汉队 5 分，AGMK 队垫底，无一分。</p>   <p>Soleimani, a prominent general in the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps, was killed near Baghdad airport in a United States drone strike in January 2020 and is viewed as a martyr by the country's ruling regime.翻译:苏莱马尼是伊斯兰革命卫队的著名将军，于 2020 年 1 月在巴格达机场附近的一次美国无人机袭击中丧生，被该国统治政权视为烈士。</p>   <p>Relations between Iran and Saudi Arabia have long been strained and this year's Asian Champions League is the first since 2016 in which clubs from both nations have been permitted to play each other home and away.翻译:伊朗和沙特阿拉伯之间的关系长期以来一直紧张，今年的亚冠联赛是自2016年以来首次允许两国俱乐部进行主客场比赛。</p>   <p>Other matches between clubs from the nations have taken place in Iran during the current competition, passing off without incident.翻译:本届比赛期间，各国俱乐部之间的其他比赛也在伊朗进行，顺利进行。</p>    <span>Reporting by Michael Church, Editing by Ed Osmond翻译:迈克尔·丘奇报道，埃德·奥斯蒙德编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 11:46:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">XJYLUKTX2RLPBBJXVOS44V5MZ4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sports/soccer/sepahan-handed-fine-stadium-ban-after-al-ittihad-cancellation-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SOCCER</category>
                
                <category>AFCCHAMPIONS/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[出于对虚假信息的担忧，TikTok首席执行官将于下周会见欧盟高级领导人]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/VtJJDkgcxXoXZ2-NnFDLG704Jm4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BDJQZE3AYFLZZK5TNY4SC5WJDA.jpg" alt="TikTok Chief Executive Shou Zi Chew testifies before a House Energy and Commerce Committee, in Washington" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>TikTok Chief Executive Shou Zi Chew testifies before a House Energy and Commerce Committee hearing entitled "TikTok: How Congress can Safeguard American Data Privacy and Protect Children from Online Harms," as lawmakers scrutinize the Chinese-owned video-sharing app, on Capitol Hill in Washington, U.S., March 23, 2023. REUTERS/Evelyn Hockstein/File Photo翻译:TikTok 首席执行官寿子洲 (Shou Zi Chew) 在众议院能源和商业委员会听证会上作证，题为“TikTok：国会如何保护美国数据隐私并保护儿童免受网络伤害”，立法者正在国会山审查这款中国拥有的视频共享应用程序。美国华盛顿，2023 年 3 月 23 日。路透社/Evelyn Hockstein/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>TikTok CEO Shou Zi Chew will meet EU industry chief Thierry Breton, EU digital chief Vera Jourova and EU antitrust chief Didier Reynders in Brussels next week, TikTok said on Friday.翻译:TikTok 周五表示，TikTok 首席执行官 Shou Zi Chew 将于下周在布鲁塞尔会见欧盟工业主管蒂埃里·布雷顿 (Thierry Breton)、欧盟数字主管维拉·朱罗娃 (Vera Jourova) 和欧盟反垄断主管迪迪埃·雷德尔斯 (Didier Reynders)。</p>   <p>The visit by Chew, his second to Brussels, comes amid heightened regulatory scrutiny of TikTok's role in the proliferation of disinformation following Hamas' attack on Israel last month and the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza.翻译:这是周第二次访问布鲁塞尔，正值哈马斯上个月袭击以色列以及以色列与哈马斯在加沙的战争之后，监管机构对 TikTok 在虚假信息扩散中所扮演的角色进行了更严格的审查。</p>   <p>Chew will meet Breton on Nov. 6 and Jourova and Reynders on Nov. 7, a TikTok spokesperson said.翻译:TikTok 发言人表示，Chew 将于 11 月 6 日与 Breton 会面，并于 11 月 7 日与 Jourova 和 Reynders 会面。</p>   <p>He will update the commissioners on TikTok's data security regime called Project Clover which started to store European user data locally this year, a TikTok spokesperson said.翻译:TikTok 发言人表示，他将向委员们通报 TikTok 名为“三叶草计划”的数据安全制度的最新情况，该制度今年开始在本地存储欧洲用户数据。</p>   <p>The company has a data centre in Dublin, Ireland, and is building two more in Ireland and Norway.翻译:该公司在爱尔兰都柏林设有一个数据中心，并正在爱尔兰和挪威再建设两个数据中心。</p>   <p>Chew will also brief them on the company's compliance with new EU online content rules known as the Digital Services Act which requires Big Tech to do more to counter illegal and harmful online content on their platforms, the spokesperson said.翻译:该发言人表示，Chew 还将向他们介绍该公司遵守新的欧盟在线内容规则（即《数字服务法》）的情况，该规则要求大型科技公司采取更多措施打击其平台上的非法和有害在线内容。</p>   <p>Breton last month gave TikTok an Oct. 25 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/eu-asks-meta-tiktok-clarity-steps-against-disinformation-illegal-content-2023-10-19/">deadline</a> to provide information on its crisis response measures. He also ordered the company to provide details by Nov. 8 on how it protects the integrity of elections and minors online on its platform.翻译:布雷顿上个月给 TikTok 规定了 10 月 25 日<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/eu-asks-meta-tiktok-clarity-steps-against-disinformation-illegal-content-2023-10-19/">的最后期限</a>，要求其提供有关其危机应对措施的信息。他还命令该公司在 11 月 8 日之前提供有关如何保护其平台上的在线选举和未成年人的完整性的详细信息。</p>    <span>Reporting by Foo Yun Chee; editing by Sudip Kar-Gupta and Jason Neely翻译:符润芝报道；编辑：Sudip Kar-Gupta 和 Jason Neely</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 11:41:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4LRY2QTRYFOGRAZQNJPG5TCGWA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/tiktok-ceo-meet-eu-industry-digital-antitrust-chiefs-next-week-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Foo Yun Chee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>EU</category>
                
                <category>TIKTOK/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中钢协称欧盟碳税构成新贸易壁垒，呼吁加强谈判]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/WbRAPn1XQl8SItJ30H4eY57hxBo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/QAIGC7BNQBNFHNYFSHX4MSW234.jpg" alt="Workers load steel products for export to a cargo ship at a port in Lianyungang" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Workers load steel products for export to a cargo ship at a port in Lianyungang, Jiangsu province, China May 27, 2020. China Daily via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:2020 年 5 月 27 日，中国江苏省连云港的一个港口，工人正在将用于出口的钢铁产品装载到一艘货船上。《中国日报》来自路透社/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism (CBAM) proposed by the European Union creates a new trade barrier for Chinese exports, China's state-backed steel association said on Friday, calling for more talks with the bloc to address climate issues.翻译:中国国家支持的钢铁协会周五表示，欧盟提出的碳边境调整机制（CBAM）为中国出口设置了新的贸易壁垒，呼吁与欧盟进行更多谈判以解决气候问题。</p>   <p>The EU approved in April the world's first plan to impose a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/eu-countries-approve-reform-blocs-carbon-market-2023-04-25/">levy</a> on high-carbon goods imports from 2026, targeting imports of steel, cement, aluminium, fertilisers, electricity, and hydrogen.翻译:欧盟于4月批准了全球首个计划，从2026年起对高碳商品进口<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/eu-countries-approve-reform-blocs-carbon-market-2023-04-25/">征税</a>，针对钢铁、水泥、铝、化肥、电力和氢气的进口。</p>   <p>The levy would pose a big threat to steel producers in China, the world's top exporter of steel, as long as their production remains more carbon-intensive than in the EU.翻译:只要中国这个全球最大钢铁出口国的生产碳排放量仍然高于欧盟，这项征税将对中国钢铁生产商构成巨大威胁。</p>   <p>The new regime entered a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/eu-launches-first-phase-worlds-first-carbon-border-tariff-2023-09-30/">trial stage in October</a>, requiring importers of goods into the EU only to report carbon emissions embedded in those products.翻译:新制度<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/eu-launches-first-phase-worlds-first-carbon-border-tariff-2023-09-30/">于十月进入试行阶段</a>，要求欧盟货物进口商仅报告这些产品中包含的碳排放量。</p>   <p>A fee will be required from 2026 when it is fully in force.翻译:2026 年全面生效后，将收取费用。</p>   <p>The carbon border levy aims to put EU industries and foreign competitors on a level footing, to prevent EU producers relocating to regions with less stringent environmental rules.翻译:碳边境税旨在让欧盟工业和外国竞争对手处于平等地位，防止欧盟生产商迁移到环境规则不太严格的地区。</p>   <p>However, it will also raise costs of steel products shipped to the EU, weakening China's price competitiveness.翻译:但同时也会提高输往欧盟的钢材成本，削弱中国的价格竞争力。</p>   <p>"The EU's unilateral establishment of CBAM is in essence a new trade barrier created under the auspice of low carbon," the China Iron and Steel Association (CISA) said.翻译:中国钢铁工业协会表示：“欧盟单方面设立CBAM，本质上是在低碳理念下设置的新贸易壁垒。”</p>   <p>CISA's comments came in response to a query from Reuters sent in September, ahead of the start of the initial phase of the CBAM.翻译:CISA 的评论是为了回应路透社 9 月份在 CBAM 初始阶段开始之前发出的询问。</p>   <p>CBAM does not take into account varying stages of development in different countries and goes against the principle of "common but differentiated responsibilities", the association said.翻译:该协会表示，CBAM没有考虑到不同国家的不同发展阶段，违背了“共同但有区别的责任”原则。</p>   <p>"Once other countries take reciprocal and similar trade protection measures to safeguard their interests, it will result in higher trading costs and mounting risks of trade friction," CISA said.翻译:“一旦其他国家采取对等、类似的贸易保护措施来维护自身利益，就会导致贸易成本上升，贸易摩擦风险加大。”中钢协表示。</p>   <p>"We hope the EU could carefully consider cost and operational challenges posed to its downstream steel consumers due to the change in import structure and engage in more communication with all relevant parties to address climate challenges together," it added.翻译:“我们希望欧盟认真考虑进口结构变化给下游钢铁消费者带来的成本和运营挑战，并与各方加强沟通，共同应对气候挑战。”</p>   <p>The scheme will likely increase China's export costs of steel products by between 4% and 6%, Jiang Wei, the association's vice chairman, told reporters at a quarterly briefing in late October.翻译:该协会副会长姜伟在10月底的季度简报中对记者表示，该计划可能会使中国钢铁产品的出口成本增加4%至6%。</p>   <p>Consultancy Wood Mackenzie said in September that CBAM is likely to significantly raise the costs of steel imports from India and China.翻译:咨询公司Wood Mackenzie在9月份表示，CBAM可能会大幅提高从印度和中国进口钢材的成本。</p>   <p>India is weighing <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/india/india-weighs-local-tax-options-avoid-eu-carbon-levy-minister-2023-11-02/">local tax options</a> to avoid the EU carbon levy after unveiling in May its plan to file a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/india/india-plans-challenge-eu-carbon-tax-wto-sources-2023-05-16/">complaint</a> to the World Trade Organization over the EU's carbon tax on imports.翻译:印度在五月份宣布计划就欧盟对进口产品征收的碳税向世界贸易组织提出<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/india/india-plans-challenge-eu-carbon-tax-wto-sources-2023-05-16/">投诉</a>后，正在考虑采取<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/india/india-weighs-local-tax-options-avoid-eu-carbon-levy-minister-2023-11-02/">地方税收方案</a>来避免欧盟征收碳税。</p>    <span>Reporting by Amy Lv and Dominique Patton in Beijing; Editing by Florence Tan and Sonali Paul翻译:吕艾米和多米尼克·巴顿北京报道；编辑：Florence Tan 和 Sonali Paul</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 11:39:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">VOITG6O5L5JBPI7L74BBWLBEOA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-steel-association-says-eu-carbon-tax-new-trade-barrier-calls-more-talks-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Amy Lv, Dominique Patton]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>EUROPE/CARBON TAX</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[亚洲黄金 当地价格上涨削弱了印度的零售需求]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>High prices could dampen Indian demand during festive season- WCG翻译:高价格可能会抑制印度节日期间的需求 - WCG</li>  <li>Indian discounts widens to $9 an ounce翻译:印度折扣扩大至每盎司 9 美元</li>  <li>China demand not substantial enough to drive higher premiums - Analyst翻译:分析师称中国需求不足以推动保费上涨</li> </ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/oh3sDH5PgfleiRRRv8mKutD1YeU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GJGSNGMAPBPSVJ7IVNPDETCRBY.jpg" alt="Dhanteras festival in Mumbai" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People shop for gold ornaments at a jewellery showroom during Dhanteras, a Hindu festival associated with Lakshmi, the goddess of wealth, in Mumbai, India, October 22, 2022. REUTERS/Niharika Kulkarni/File Photo翻译:2022 年 10 月 22 日，印度孟买，人们在 Dhanteras 节日期间在珠宝陈列室购买金饰。 Dhanteras 是与财富女神拉克希米相关的印度教节日。 REUTERS/Niharika Kulkarni/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Physical gold dealers in India offered discounts for a fourth consecutive week as consumers shied away from making purchases due to higher domestic prices, while top consumer China also saw muted demand.翻译:由于国内金价上涨，消费者不愿购买，印度实物黄金交易商连续第四周提供折扣，而最大消费国中国的需求也疲弱。</p>   <p>In India, this week, dealers offered a discount of up to $9 an ounce over official domestic prices — inclusive of the 15% import and 3% sales levies, up from last week's discount of $5.翻译:本周在印度，经销商提供比国内官方价格最高每盎司 9 美元的折扣，其中包括 15% 的进口税和 3% 的销售税，高于上周的 5 美元折扣。</p>   <p>"The market was cruising along pretty nicely in the first half of October, but then the price hike came along and threw a wrench in the works. Now, we're seeing demand lower than usual," said Amit Modak, CEO at jeweller PN Gadgil and Sons, in the city of Pune.翻译:珠宝商 PN 首席执行官阿米特·莫达克 (Amit Modak) 表示：“10 月上半月市场运行良好，但随后价格上涨，给工作带来了麻烦。现在，我们看到需求低于平时。” Gadgil and Sons，位于浦那市。</p>   <p>Local gold prices jumped this week to 61,539 rupees ($739.01) per 10 grams, not far from the all-time high of 61,845 rupees ($742.68) hit in May.翻译:当地金价本周跃升至每 10 克 61,539 卢比（739.01 美元），距离 5 月份触及的历史高点 61,845 卢比（742.68 美元）不远。</p>   <p>Jewellers have become pessimistic about demand during the upcoming Diwali festival due to the price rise and are hesitant to make purchases, said a Mumbai-based dealer with a private bullion importing bank.翻译:一家私人金银进口银行的孟买经销商表示，由于价格上涨，珠宝商对即将到来的排灯节期间的需求变得悲观，并且不愿购买。</p>   <p>High prices could dampen demand in India during peak festival season and lead to the lowest purchase volumes in three years, the World Gold Council (WGC) said on Tuesday.翻译:世界黄金协会（WGC）周二表示，高价格可能会抑制印度节日旺季的需求，并导致购买量降至三年来最低水平。</p>   <p>In China, premiums over global spot prices were quoted at $25-$40 per ounce, little changed from last week.翻译:在中国，全球现货价格溢价为每盎司 25-40 美元，与上周相比变化不大。</p>   <p>"Despite various easing measures, such as controlling the lease of import quotas, gold imports remain sluggish. The issue lies in the fact that demand is not substantial enough to drive a higher premium," Bernard Sin, regional director of Greater China at MKS PAMP, said.翻译:MKS PAMP 大中华区总监 Bernard Sin 表示：“尽管采取了各种宽松措施，例如控制进口配额的租赁，但黄金进口仍然低迷。问题在于需求不足以推动更高的溢价。” ， 说。</p>   <p>In Japan, gold was sold between a discount of $0.25 and a premium of $1 versus last week's premium of $0.5-$1.翻译:在日本，黄金售价在 0.25 美元的折扣和 1 美元的溢价之间，而上周的溢价为 0.5 美元至 1 美元。</p>   <p>In Hong Kong, bullion was sold at premiums of $1.5-$2.5 per ounce and $1.50-$2.50 in Singapore. .翻译:在香港，金条以每盎司 1.5-2.5 美元的溢价出售，在新加坡则以 1.50-2.50 美元的溢价出售。 。</p>   <p>($1 = 83.2420 Indian rupees)翻译:（1 美元 = 83.2420 印度卢比）</p>    <span>Reporting by Rajendra Jadhav in Mumbai and Anjana Anil in Bengaluru; Editing by Shweta Agarwal翻译:Rajendra Jadhav 在孟买和 Anjana Anil 在班加罗尔的报道；舒维塔·阿加瓦尔 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 11:15:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">SZIHPHMUD5ONNHKVHJK2CUCECY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/asia-gold-elevated-local-prices-dent-retail-demand-india-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Rajendra Jadhav, Anjana Anil]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ASIA</category>
                
                <category>GOLD/DEMAND (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[苹果公司因假期季度低迷发出警告后暴跌]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/g5HL0xOQ45IgPmjpUClvCjehyfk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NJVCWLYPHJJFXFVEWWMUTHK3PU.jpg" alt="An Apple iPhone 12 in a mobile phone store in Nantes" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An Apple iPhone 12 is pictured in a mobile phone store in Nantes, France, Sept. 13, 2023. REUTERS/Stephane Mahe/File Photo翻译:2023 年 9 月 13 日，法国南特一家手机商店内拍摄的苹果 iPhone 12。路透社/Stephane Mahe/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Apple fell 3% on Friday after it disappointed Wall Street with a forecast that indicated growth will stay subdued in the quarter where the holiday season usually drives its strongest sales.翻译:苹果周五股价下跌 3%，此前该公司的预测令华尔街感到失望，该预测表明，假日季通常会推动销售最强劲的季度增长将保持低迷。</p>   <p>The world's most valuable firm <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a> was set to lose more than $80 billion in market value, based on its premarket share price of $172. Its shares have rallied nearly 40% this year.翻译:根据 172 美元的盘前股价计算，全球最有价值的公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O) 的</a>市值将损失超过 800 亿美元。今年以来，其股价已上涨近40%。</p>   <p>The iPhone maker on Thursday <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/apple-beats-quarterly-estimates-iphone-sales-edge-up-2023-11-02/">predicted quarterly sales that were below market estimates</a>, blaming weak demand for iPads and wearables, especially in key market China.翻译:这家 iPhone 制造商周四<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/apple-beats-quarterly-estimates-iphone-sales-edge-up-2023-11-02/">预计季度销量将低于市场预期</a>，原因是 iPad 和可穿戴设备需求疲软，尤其是在主要市场中国。</p>   <p>The projection fanned fears about broader holiday demand, with estimates including those from the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-holiday-sales-grow-slower-pace-this-holiday-season-report-2023-11-02/">U.S. National Retail Federation</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/us-holiday-sales-set-slowest-year-since-2018-consumers-turn-frugal-report-2023-09-13/">Deloitte</a> predicting the slowest rise in sales in the crucial shopping period in years due to sticky inflation.翻译:这一预测加剧了人们对更广泛的假期需求的担忧， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-holiday-sales-grow-slower-pace-this-holiday-season-report-2023-11-02/">美国全国零售联合会</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/us-holiday-sales-set-slowest-year-since-2018-consumers-turn-frugal-report-2023-09-13/">德勤的</a>估计预计，由于通货膨胀率高，关键购物期的销售额将出现多年来最慢的增长。</p>   <p>"Apple's revenue growth has stalled over the past few quarters - and appears likely to continue to stagnate over the next year," said brokerage Bernstein, noting the holiday quarter usually sets the tone for Apple's fiscal year that runs until September.翻译:券商 Bernstein 表示：“过去几个季度，苹果的收入增长陷入停滞，而且明年可能会继续停滞不前。”他指出，假期季度通常会为苹果截至 9 月份的财年定下基调。</p>   <p>At least 11 analysts cut their price targets on the stock, pushing down the median price target to $196.5, according to LSEG data. Apple currently trades at nearly 26 times its 12-month forward earnings estimates, among the lowest in the so-called "Magnificent Seven" stocks.翻译:LSEG 数据显示，至少 11 名分析师下调了该股的目标价，将目标价中值下调至 196.5 美元。苹果目前的市盈率为其 12 个月预期盈利预期的近 26 倍，是所谓“七大”股票中最低的股票之一。</p>   <p>"We view management's flat sales guidance as proof the company cannot rely on iPhone sales to drive shares higher, as it has in the past," D.A. Davidson analyst Tom Forte said.翻译:DA Davidson 分析师汤姆·福特 (Tom Forte) 表示：“我们认为管理层持平的销售指引证明该公司不能像过去那样依靠 iPhone 销售来推高股价。”</p>   <p>The iPhone, Apple's main revenue generator, saw its sales rise in the September quarter and is also forecast to post an increase in the last three months of 2023.翻译:iPhone 是苹果的主要收入来源，其销量在 9 月份季度有所增长，预计 2023 年最后三个月也将出现增长。</p>   <p>CEO Tim Cook also insisted the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/china-iphone-sales-strong-apple-tells-investors-huawei-threat-looms-2023-11-03/">iPhone 15 models were doing well in China</a>, as he sought to allay Wall Street fears that Apple was losing market share to a resurgent Huawei and other local smartphone sellers. "In mainland China, we set a quarterly record for the September quarter for iPhone," Cook told Reuters.翻译:首席执行官蒂姆·库克还坚称<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/china-iphone-sales-strong-apple-tells-investors-huawei-threat-looms-2023-11-03/">iPhone 15 机型在中国表现良好</a>，因为他试图缓解华尔街对苹果正在将市场份额输给复兴的华为和其他本土智能手机销售商的担忧。库克对路透表示：“在中国大陆，我们创下了 iPhone 9 月份季度的季度记录。”</p>   <p>Several analysts cheered the remarks. "The Street will breathe a sigh of relief on this front," Wedbush Securities analyst Dan Ives said.翻译:几位分析师对这一言论表示欢迎。韦德布什证券分析师丹·艾夫斯表示：“华尔街将在这方面松一口气。”</p>   <p>He was also positive on the outlook for the services business, whose strong growth in the September quarter had helped the company top quarterly revenue expectations.翻译:他还对服务业务的前景持乐观态度，该业务在九月季度的强劲增长帮助该公司超出了季度收入预期。</p>    <span>Reporting by Aditya Soni; Editing by Shounak Dasgupta翻译:Aditya Soni 报道；肖纳克·达斯古普塔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 10:28:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">GWYHVLKQP5OSFMSYEDNC6CAQQA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/apple-tumbles-after-warning-dull-holiday-quarter-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APPLE</category>
                
                <category>STOCKS/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国欧盟商会批评即将举行的上海贸易博览会是“政治展示”]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/hLv2dUD7uNX8-Kxvz3lO9a0HCGI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/AO22HWIFARMWVJR7V4JKECY64I.jpg" alt="China International Import Expo in Shanghai" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping is seen on a giant screen at a media centre as he delivers a speech via video at the opening ceremony of the China International Import Expo (CIIE) in Shanghai, China November 4, 2021. REUTERS/Andrew Galbraith/File Photo翻译:2021 年 11 月 4 日，在中国上海举行的中国国际进口博览会 (CIIE) 开幕式上，中国国家主席习近平在媒体中心的大屏幕上通过视频发表讲话。路透社/Andrew Galbraith/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The European Union Chamber of Commerce on Friday criticised an upcoming trade fair in China as being more of a "political showcase" than about doing business and pushed for more <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-could-do-a-lot-reduce-eu-perception-risk-eu-trade-chief-2023-09-25/">tangible measures</a> to restore confidence among European companies.翻译:欧盟商会周五批评即将在中国举行的贸易博览会更多的是“政治展示”，而不是做生意，并推动采取更<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-could-do-a-lot-reduce-eu-perception-risk-eu-trade-chief-2023-09-25/">切实的措施</a>来恢复欧洲企业的信心。</p>   <p>Shanghai is due to host the China International Import Expo (CIIE) between Nov. 5-10, an annual event launched by President Xi Jinping in 2018 to promote the country's free trade credentials and tackle criticism of its trade surplus with many partners.翻译:上海将于 11 月 5 日至 10 日举办中国国际进口博览会 (CIIE)，这是习近平主席于 ​​2018 年发起的年度盛会，旨在宣传中国的自由贸易资格，并解决对其与许多合作伙伴的贸易顺差的批评。</p>   <p>Premier Li Qiang is set to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-premier-li-make-key-speech-shanghai-economic-forum-2023-11-03/">address attendees</a> at the event's opening ceremony on Sunday, which is expected to include Australian Prime Minister <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-albanese-highlight-trade-china-visit-ties-warm-2023-11-03/">Anthony Albanese</a>.翻译:李强总理将于周日在活动开幕式上<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-premier-li-make-key-speech-shanghai-economic-forum-2023-11-03/">向与会者发表讲话</a>，预计澳大利亚总理<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-albanese-highlight-trade-china-visit-ties-warm-2023-11-03/">安东尼·阿尔巴内塞</a>将出席。</p>   <p>But the chamber said that contrary to the CIIE's ambitions of boosting China's global imports and showcasing the country's opening up and reform agenda, China's trade surplus with Europe had grown significantly over the past five years.翻译:但该商会表示，与进博会推动中国全球进口、展示中国开放改革议程的雄心相反，过去五年中国对欧洲的贸易顺差大幅增长。</p>   <p>"It's more a government affairs event, more a marketing event and there's been really little said on business. You can say CIIE has become more of a political showcase rather than a business event," Carlo D'Andrea, the chamber's vice president, told reporters at a briefing in Shanghai.翻译:“这更多的是一场政府事务活动，更多的是一场营销活动，关于商业的话题真的很少。可以说，进博会已经更多地成为一场政治展示，而不是商业活动，”中国商会副会长卡洛·德安德里亚(Carlo D&#39;Andrea)告诉记者。记者在上海举行吹风会。</p>   <p>"European businesses are becoming disillusioned as symbolic gestures take the place of tangible results needed to restore business confidence," he said.翻译:他表示：“欧洲企业正在幻灭，因为象征性的姿态取代了恢复商业信心所需的切实成果。”</p>   <p>The fair's organisers did not immediately respond to a request for comment. China has said it is willing to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-could-do-a-lot-reduce-eu-perception-risk-eu-trade-chief-2023-09-25/">take more</a> European exports in response to complaints from the European Union about the lack of a level playing field in China and the politicization of the business environment.翻译:展会组织者没有立即回应置评请求。中国表示愿意<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-could-do-a-lot-reduce-eu-perception-risk-eu-trade-chief-2023-09-25/">接受更多</a>欧洲出口，以回应欧盟对中国缺乏公平竞争环境和商业环境政治化的抱怨。</p>   <p>The EU and China plan a summit by the end of the year. The European Union's top diplomat, Josep Borrell, visited last month, as have several other top EU officials in recent months.翻译:欧盟和中国计划在今年年底前举行峰会。欧盟最高外交官何塞普·博雷尔(Josep Borrell)上个月访问了该国，其他几位欧盟高级官员近几个月也访问了该国。</p>   <p>A survey by the chamber last month that received 116 responses from its members found that participation rates had dropped from 42% to 32% since the first CIIE. Those who had opted not to attend this year after attending previously cited the diminishing value of investment and limited policy changes as among their reasons.翻译:商会上个月进行的一项调查收到了116份会员的回复，发现自首届进博会以来，参与率已从42%下降至32%。那些在参加过之后选择今年不参加的人表示，投资价值下降和政策变化有限是他们的原因。</p>   <p>Although 59% of the survey's respondents said they benefited from government engagement at the show, only a quarter of attendees closed any business deals at last year's CIIE, significantly lower than in 2018 when half of participants closed deals, the chamber added.翻译:该商会补充说，尽管59%的受访者表示他们从政府参与展会中受益，但只有四分之一的与会者在去年的进博会上达成了任何商业交易，显着低于2018年，当时有一半的与会者达成了交易。</p>   <p>European businesses would like to see the CIIE "move away from the politicization" and focus on the business impact, as well as undertake concrete policy measures to open the market alongside the fair, the chamber added.翻译:该商会补充说，欧洲企业希望看到进博会“摆脱政治化”，关注对企业的影响，并在进博会的同时采取具体的政策措施开放市场。</p>   <p>More than 60 countries and three international organisations, as well as 289 of the world's top 500 companies, will be participating in CIIE, according to Chinese state media, including firms such as Micron <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MU.O" target="_blank">(MU.O)</a>, Nestle and Burberry <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BRBY.L" target="_blank">(BRBY.L)</a>翻译:据中国官方媒体报道，超过 60 个国家和三个国际组织以及世界 500 强企业中的 289 家将参加进博会，其中包括美光<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MU.O" target="_blank">(MU.O)</a> 、雀巢和巴宝莉<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BRBY.L" target="_blank">(BRBY.L</a> ) 等公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BRBY.L" target="_blank">）</a></p>   <p>Last year, $73.52 billion worth of 'intentional' deals were signed at the fair, up 3.9%.翻译:去年，展会上签署了价值 735.2 亿美元的“意向”交易，增长 3.9%。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.3142 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.3142 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Brenda Goh; Editing by Sonali Paul翻译:布伦达·吴报道；索纳利·保罗编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 09:09:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZWHENSEBLFJORJBDYPDCFNVLGM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/european-chamber-china-criticises-upcoming-shanghai-trade-fair-smoke-mirrors-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Brenda Goh]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>TRADE/FORUM</category>
                
                <category>EUROPE (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国将迎来极端天气年由暖转冷]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/7cbB-QRWDG7P02SDfuKteG4Y_kM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/55ACLAQPRZMEHID2PSPXSA6NMY.jpg" alt="Beijing shrouded in smog" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Vehicles move on a street in Beijing's Central Business District (CBD) as the city is shrouded in smog, in China November 1, 2023. REUTER/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023 年 11 月 1 日，中国北京中央商务区 (CBD) 的街道上，车辆在雾霾笼罩下行驶。 REUTER/Tingshu Wang  </figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/YrhIb7oRV0OlcEOqTh5ATBYTCPs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/B7LRLQURUBNTNKSNG5VV6W2ZBA.jpg" alt="Beijing shrouded in smog" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Cars move on a street in Beijing's Central Business District (CBD) as the city is shrouded in smog, in China November 1, 2023. REUTER/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023 年 11 月 1 日，中国北京中央商务区 (CBD) 的街道上，汽车在雾霾笼罩下行驶。 REUTER/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/4lFg53QZ8TbijD-ANv9BDzVpp8U=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/QTD7QDNQTZO4FBIFM6RAZZD4DE.jpg" alt="Beijing shrouded in smog" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Cars move on a street in Beijing's Central Business District (CBD) as the city is shrouded in smog, in China November 1, 2023. REUTER/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023 年 11 月 1 日，中国北京中央商务区 (CBD) 的街道上，汽车在雾霾笼罩下行驶。 REUTER/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>                 <p>Temperatures in northern China are set to plunge as much as 20 degrees Celsius after the second-warmest October in decades, but warmer-than-usual conditions could soon be back under the influence of El Nino.翻译:在经历了几十年来第二热的10月之后，中国北方的气温预计将骤降20摄氏度，但在厄尔尼诺现象的影响下，气温可能很快就会恢复到高于正常水平的水平。</p>   <p>A stream of cold air entering China on Saturday from the northwest will join one that arrived on Thursday to push temperatures sharply lower, the China Meteorological Administration (CMA) said.翻译:中国气象局表示，周六从西北进入中国的一股冷空气将与周四抵达的一股冷空气汇合，导致气温大幅下降。</p>   <p>In the sparsely populated deserts and grasslands of the northern Inner Mongolia region, temperatures could plummet on Friday and again from Saturday while blizzards could hit the Xinjiang region in the northwest.翻译:内蒙古北部地区人口稀少的沙漠和草原，周五和周六起气温可能会骤降，而西北地区的新疆地区可能会出现暴风雪。</p>   <p>From next week, most of the northeast is expected to see maximum temperatures dive to the single-digits or below freezing as cold air moves east and south, in an abrupt reversal of a recent "big warming", the CMA said.翻译:CMA表示，从下周开始，随着冷空气向东和向南移动，东北部大部分地区的最高气温预计将降至个位数或冰点以下，这是最近“大变暖”的突然逆转。</p>   <p>While freezing temperatures are not uncommon for the time of year, the sudden change is unusual.翻译:虽然一年中的某个时候，气温结冰并不罕见，但突然的变化却是不寻常的。</p>   <p>A few days ago, uncharacteristically warm weather saw parts of northern China post <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/winter-coming-week-late-beijing-northern-china-basks-warm-weather-2023-11-02/">record high temperatures</a> exceeding 30C.翻译:日前，我国北方部分地区出现反常高温<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/winter-coming-week-late-beijing-northern-china-basks-warm-weather-2023-11-02/">，气温</a>超过30℃。</p>   <p>Weather has become more extreme in China in recent years, destroying urban infrastructure as well as farmland, causing hefty economic losses and raising fears about the pace and impact of global warming.翻译:近年来，中国的天气变得更加极端，破坏了城市基础设施和农田，造成了巨大的经济损失，并引发了人们对全球变暖速度和影响的担忧。</p>   <p>This summer, typhoons dumped historic rainfall in inland regions unaccustomed to tropical storms. Typhoon Doksuri caused the worst flooding since 1963 in the Hai river basin that encompasses Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei province.翻译:今年夏天，台风给不习惯热带风暴的内陆地区带来了历史性的降雨。台风“多克苏里”给京津冀海河流域带来了自1963年以来最严重的洪水。</p>   <p>Authorities are due to issue 1 trillion yuan ($137 billion) of sovereign bonds to help rebuild areas hit by the floods and improve infrastructure to cope with disasters.翻译:当局将发行1万亿元人民币（1,370亿美元）的主权债券，以帮助重建遭受洪水袭击的地区并改善基础设施以应对灾害。</p>   <p>Earlier in the year, northern China basked in unseasonal heat, with temperatures reaching summer-levels, shortly after a very cold January, when the northernmost city of Mohe saw the temperature dip to a record minus 53C.翻译:今年早些时候，中国北方迎来了反季节的高温，在经历了非常寒冷的一月份后不久，最北端城市漠河的气温降至创纪录的零下53摄氏度，气温达到了夏季水平。</p>   <p>Winter this year, however, could be warmer due to a moderate El Nino, Jia Xiaolong, deputy director of China's National Climate Centre, told a press conference on Friday.翻译:然而，中国国家气候中心副主任贾小龙在周五的新闻发布会上表示，由于温和的厄尔尼诺现象，今年的冬季可能会变暖。</p>   <p>El Nino is a natural climate pattern associated with warming of the ocean surface temperatures in the central and eastern Pacific. The phenomenon occurs every two to seven years, lasting nine to 12 months.翻译:厄尔尼诺现象是一种与太平洋中部和东部海洋表面温度变暖有关的自然气候模式。这种现象每两到七年就会发生一次，持续九到十二个月。</p>   <p>"The sea surface temperature in the east-central equatorial Pacific will continue to exceed 0.5C in November, and the El Nino event will persist in the 2023/2024 winter, with a peak intensity of 1.5-2C," Jia said.翻译:“11月赤道中东部太平洋海温将继续超过0.5℃，厄尔尼诺事件将持续到2023/2024年冬季，峰值强度为1.5-2℃。”贾说。</p>   <p>But statistics showed that winter temperatures could fluctuate greatly during El Nino, Jia warned.翻译:但贾警告说，统计数据显示，厄尔尼诺现象期间冬季气温可能会出现大幅波动。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.3127 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.3127 人民币）</p>   <p>(This story has been refiled to drop reference to Fahrenheit scale in paragraph 1)翻译:（这个故事已被重新提交，以删除第 1 段中对华氏温标的引用）</p>    <span>Reporting by Ethan Wang and Ryan Woo; Editing by Simon Cameron-Moore翻译:西蒙·卡梅伦-摩尔 编辑, Robert Birsel</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 06:44:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7SNNTJF3AZOHLDCEMTRWRMJ7SM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-set-abrupt-switch-warm-freezing-weather-year-extremes-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ethan Wang, Ryan Woo]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ASIA</category>
                
                <category>WEATHER/CHINA (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着与华盛顿的紧张关系缓和，中国对美国芯片制造商美光科技态度热情]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/FsVY3fwBYsnDQrR1v_3LxM-mpwk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4OGBAMIUQ5PLZD4RFSD7VEU654.jpg" alt="The company logo is seen on the Micron Technology Inc. offices in Shanghai" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The company logo is seen on the Micron Technology Inc. offices in Shanghai, China May 25, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2023 年 5 月 25 日，该公司徽标出现在中国上海美光科技有限公司办公室。路透社/Aly Song/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's commerce minister told Micron Technology Inc's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MU.O" target="_blank">(MU.O)</a> president Beijing would welcome the U.S. semiconductor company deepening its footprint in the Chinese market, signally a further thaw in relations between the world's top two economies.翻译:中国商务部长告诉美光科技公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MU.O" target="_blank">(MU.O)</a>总裁，北京欢迎这家美国半导体公司加深在中国市场的足迹，这标志着世界两大经济体之间关系的进一步解冻。</p>   <p>In a meeting on Nov. 1, Commerce Minister Wang Wentao told Sanjay Mehrotra, President and CEO of Micron Technology, that China will optimize the environment for foreign investment and provide service guarantees for foreign enterprises, according to a brief statement published on Friday on the commerce ministry's website.翻译:据商务部周五发布的一份简短声明称，商务部部长王文涛在 11 月 1 日的会议上向美光科技总裁兼首席执行官 Sanjay Mehrotra 表示，中国将优化外商投资环境，为外国企业提供服务保障。商务部网站。</p>   <p>"We welcome Micron Technology to continue to take root in the Chinese market and achieve better development under the premise of complying with Chinese laws and regulations," Wang added.翻译:“我们欢迎美光科技继续扎根中国市场，在遵守中国法律法规的前提下取得更好的发展。”王补充道。</p>   <p>The detente comes just months after China's cyberspace regulator said Micron had failed a network <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-regulator-says-finds-serious-security-issues-us-micron-technologys-2023-05-21/">security review</a> and barred Chinese operators of key infrastructure from buying from the largest U.S. memory chipmaker.翻译:就在几个月前，中国网络空间监管机构表示美光科技未能通过网络<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-regulator-says-finds-serious-security-issues-us-micron-technologys-2023-05-21/">安全审查</a>，并禁止中国关键基础设施运营商从这家美国最大的存储芯片制造商购买产品。</p>   <p>China's move against Micron was widely seen as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-micron-ban-highlights-chipmakers-dilemma-sino-us-tensions-grow-2023-05-22/">retaliation</a> for Washington's efforts to restrict Beijing's access to key technology. It came just a day after the Group of Seven (G7) rich nations agreed they would look to "de-risk, not decouple" from China, and as Washington pressured its allies to join it in restricting chip equipment exports to China.翻译:人们普遍认为，中国针对美光科技的举动是对华盛顿限制北京获取关键技术的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-micron-ban-highlights-chipmakers-dilemma-sino-us-tensions-grow-2023-05-22/">报复</a>。就在一天前，七国集团（G7）富裕国家同意寻求与中国“降低风险，而不是脱钩”，而华盛顿则向其盟友施压，要求其加入限制向中国出口芯片设备的行列。</p>   <p>The Wednesday meeting between Wang and Mehrotra is line with a recent thawing in tensions between Washington and Beijing, as officials from both countries work to organise a meeting between U.S. President Joe Biden and his Chinese counterpart Xi Jinping later this month at the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation summit in San Francisco.翻译:王毅和梅赫罗特拉周三的会面正值华盛顿和北京之间最近紧张局势缓和之际，两国官员正在努力组织美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平本月晚些时候在亚太经合组织举行的会晤。旧金山合作峰会。</p>    <span>Reporting by Beijing newsroom; Editing by Sonali Paul and Lincoln Feast翻译:北京新闻编辑室报道；索纳利·保罗和林肯·费斯特编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 06:30:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BNKAAQIF4BMVBCAIT4ELAMFC6Q</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/china-warms-us-chipmaker-micron-tensions-with-washington-ease-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>MICRON TECH/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着关系改善，中国葡萄酒市场准备迎接澳大利亚葡萄酒可能回归]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Australian Prime Minister Albanese begins visit to China on Saturday翻译:澳大利亚总理阿尔巴内塞周六开始访华</li>  <li>First visit by an Australian prime minister since 2016翻译:澳大利亚总理自2016年以来首次访华</li>  <li>China put 218% tax on Australian wine in 2021 as ties worsened翻译:随着关系恶化，中国将于2021年对澳大利亚葡萄酒征收218%的税</li>  <li>Both sides have agreed to review tariffs, including for wine翻译:双方同意审查关税，包括葡萄酒关税</li>  <li>Australian wine could return to the China market early next year if punitive tariffs removed翻译:如果取消惩罚性关税，澳大利亚葡萄酒可能于明年初重返中国市场</li> </ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/dTZTHptBV-3Y097sNaClCtXSMlI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/IL5C7ETBMVPSZC2PVCP6YAM5JY.jpg" alt="Wine bar in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Wine bottles from around the world fill shelves in the cellar of Trio Wine Bar in Beijing, China November 1, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo翻译:2023 年 11 月 1 日，中国北京 Trio 酒吧酒窖的货架上摆满了来自世界各地的葡萄酒。路透社/Florence Lo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/RScblGL6Bdcuagz5k_D17X-FhKI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BINNTXRNPVJYJO2POGTYHV7IWI.jpg" alt="Wine bar in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A staff member sniffs wine in a glass while a customer watches at Trio Wine Bar in Beijing, China November 1, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo翻译:2023 年 11 月 1 日，中国北京 Trio 酒吧，一名工作人员在嗅着玻璃杯中的葡萄酒，而一名顾客正在观看。路透社/Florence Lo</figcaption></figure>               <p>News that punitive tariffs on Australian wine introduced by China in 2021 would be reviewed as part of a push to improve the relationship between the two countries was cheered by many, including Campbell Thompson.翻译:作为推动改善两国关系的一部分，中国将于 2021 年对澳大利亚葡萄酒征收惩罚性关税的消息受到了包括坎贝尔·汤普森 (Campbell Thompson) 在内的许多人的欢呼。</p>   <p>The Beijing-based Australian CEO of wine importer and distributor The Wine Republic has spent more than a decade making his living from bringing wine, much of it from Australia, into the China market.翻译:葡萄酒进口商和经销商 The Wine Republic 驻北京的澳大利亚首席执行官十多年来一直靠将葡萄酒（其中大部分来自澳大利亚）引入中国市场谋生。</p>   <p>"We are looking forward to the tariffs being removed. I think for Australia there is definitely an opportunity," he said.翻译:“我们期待取消关税。我认为对澳大利亚来说绝对有机会，”他说。</p>   <p>Late last month, as ties between Beijing and Canberra improved, the two sides announced they had reached a consensus to settle a World Trade Organisation dispute about wine and that anti-dumping tariffs, which weren't set to expire until 2026, would be reviewed.翻译:上个月末，随着北京和堪培拉之间关系的改善，双方宣布已就解决世界贸易组织有关葡萄酒的争端达成共识，并将对将于 2026 年到期的反倾销关税进行审查。</p>   <p>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese kicks off a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-pm-says-deal-reached-with-china-resolve-wto-wine-dispute-2023-10-21/">visit to China</a> on Saturday, the first visit by a sitting Australian leader since 2016 as the trading partners <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-albanese-highlight-trade-china-visit-ties-warm-2023-11-03/">continue to work</a> on stabilising ties.翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞周六开始<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-pm-says-deal-reached-with-china-resolve-wto-wine-dispute-2023-10-21/">对中国进行访问</a>，这是澳大利亚在任领导人自 2016 年以来的首次访问，贸易伙伴<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-albanese-highlight-trade-china-visit-ties-warm-2023-11-03/">继续致力于</a>稳定关系。</p>   <p>The introduction of a 218% tax on most Australian wine introduced by China early in 2021 prompted that trade, previously valued as high as $1.2 billion annually, to collapse.翻译:中国于 2021 年初对大多数澳大利亚葡萄酒征收 218% 的关税，导致此前每年价值高达 12 亿美元的贸易崩溃。</p>   <p>Penfold's maker, Treasury Wine Estates, said in 2022 it had lost 97% of its China business due to the introduction of the tariffs, it's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/australias-treasury-wine-rebuild-china-business-after-tariff-review-2023-10-22/">shares rose</a> more than 5% on news they could soon be removed.翻译:奔富酒庄的制造商富邑葡萄酒集团 (Treasury Wine Estates) 表示，2022 年，由于关税的实施，该公司失去了 97% 的中国业务，因关税可能很快被取消的消息，该公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/australias-treasury-wine-rebuild-china-business-after-tariff-review-2023-10-22/">股价上涨了</a>5% 以上。</p>   <p>Prior to Australia's call for an investigation into the origins of COVID-19 in 2020, Australian wines imported into China were subject to zero tariffs following the signing of a free trade agreement in 2015, giving them a 14% tariff advantage over many other wine producing nations.翻译:在澳大利亚于2020年呼吁对COVID-19起源进行调查之前，自2015年签署自由贸易协定以来，进口到中国的澳大利亚葡萄酒实行零关税，比许多其他葡萄酒生产国享有14%的关税优势国家。</p>   <p>Thompson is already in touch with the 10-plus Australian wineries he worked with before 2021, along with some newer players, in expectation that tariffs will soon be removed.翻译:汤普森已经与他在 2021 年之前合作过的 10 多家澳大利亚酒庄以及一些新加入的酒庄取得了联系，预计关税将很快取消。</p>   <p>Though he says this is good news, perhaps paving the way for the return of Australian wine to the Chinese market by early next year, he is not necessarily expecting business to bounce back immediately.翻译:尽管他表示这是个好消息，或许为澳大利亚葡萄酒明年初重返中国市场铺平了道路，但他并不一定期望业务会立即反弹。</p>   <p>"I don't think that's realistic any time soon. However, for a lot of good quality Australian wine producers ... customers still know the wines and I think will re-engage with those wines fairly readily," he said.翻译:“我认为这在短期内不太现实。然而，对于许多优质的澳大利亚葡萄酒生产商来说……顾客仍然了解这些葡萄酒，我认为他们会很容易地重新接触这些葡萄酒，”他说。</p>   <p>Layla Wang, co-owner of Trio Wine Bar in Beijing agreed that Chinese market perceptions of Australian wine haven't changed in the years since it was last available, with no clear winner in the battle to take over Australian wine's market share.翻译:北京 Trio Wine Bar 的合伙人 Layla Wang 也认为，自澳大利亚葡萄酒上次上市以来，中国市场对澳大利亚葡萄酒的看法多年来一直没有改变，在争夺澳大利亚葡萄酒市场份额的争夺战中没有明显的赢家。</p>   <p>The bar's small cellar is lined floor to ceiling with bottles of wine from all over the world, and Wang said the market has become more crowded as people seek out new and different wine experiences, leading to the increased popularity of homegrown Chinese wines, biodynamic and natural options.翻译:酒吧的小酒窖从地板到天花板都摆满了来自世界各地的葡萄酒，王说，随着人们寻求新的、不同的葡萄酒体验，市场变得更加拥挤，导致中国本土葡萄酒、生物动力和葡萄酒越来越受欢迎。自然选择。</p>   <p>"I think even if people have been away from Australian wine for a while, every time we talk about this category of wine, we all think it's a very good quality wine," Wang said, sat at her bar.翻译:“我认为，即使人们已经远离澳大利亚葡萄酒有一段时间了，每次我们谈论这类葡萄酒时，我们都认为这是一种品质非常好的葡萄酒，”王坐在她的酒吧里说道。</p>   <p>"For us, we're definitely delighted as it signifies offering more choices to our customers. For consumers who haven't had Australian wines for years, many will be eager to try them again."翻译:“对我们来说，我们绝对很高兴，因为这意味着为我们的客户提供更多选择。对于多年没有喝过澳大利亚葡萄酒的消费者来说，许多人会渴望再次尝试。”</p>    <span>Editing by Simon Cameron-Moore翻译:西蒙·卡梅伦-摩尔 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 06:26:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">PCLYVUEBVRP4VJKKRFK6ZD6OVY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-wine-market-ready-welcome-likely-return-aussie-wine-ties-improve-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Casey Hall, Xiaoyu Yin]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA/WINE (UPDATE 2, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着关系升温，澳大利亚阿尔巴内斯将在中国访问中强调贸易]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/t-ZBoJ-4VKqEIM6oSUd0xHH5684=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GAG4HD2QXROPFKPXFLDYOMP6OM.jpg" alt="Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese speaks to media following a Ministry Meeting, in Melbourne" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese speaks to media following a Ministry Meeting, in Melbourne, October 11, 2023. AAP Image/Joel Carrett via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞 (Anthony Albanese) 于 2023 年 10 月 11 日在墨尔本举行的部长级会议后向媒体发表讲话。图片来源：AAP 图片/Joel Carrett via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese will highlight trade as an anchor for stabilising ties when he makes the first visit by an Australian leader to China in seven years, as badly strained relations move back to an even footing, business leaders said.翻译:商界领袖表示，随着澳大利亚领导人七年来首次访华，澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞将强调贸易是稳定关系的支柱，因为严重紧张的关系已恢复平衡。</p>   <p>Albanese, who arrives on Saturday, will attend the opening of China's top imports fair in Shanghai, and speak to a large business delegation, the following day.翻译:阿尔巴内塞于周六抵达，将出席在上海举行的中国顶级进口博览会的开幕式，并于次日向一个大型商业代表团发表讲话。</p>   <p>He has said he also will raise concerns over rising tension in the South China Sea in a meeting with President Xi Jinping in Beijing on Monday.翻译:他表示，他还将在周一与中国国家主席习近平在北京会面时提出对南海紧张局势升级的担忧。</p>   <p>His government has taken credit for stabilising ties with Australia's largest trading partner since coming to office last year, as China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-pm-says-deal-reached-with-china-resolve-wto-wine-dispute-2023-10-21/">lifted most trade blocks</a> imposed in a 2020 diplomatic dispute that cost A$20 billion in commodity and food exports.翻译:自去年上任以来，他的政府因稳定与澳大利亚最大贸易伙伴的关系而受到赞誉，中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-pm-says-deal-reached-with-china-resolve-wto-wine-dispute-2023-10-21/">取消了2020年外交争端中施加的大部分贸易封锁</a>，该争端导致大宗商品和食品出口损失200亿澳元。</p>   <p>Even as Australia moves closer to security ally the United States, which has agreed to sell Canberra nuclear-powered submarines under a trilateral <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/australian-pm-tells-us-house-speaker-he-hopes-aukus-legislation-passes-this-year-2023-10-26/">defence technology partnership</a>, AUKUS, with Britain, and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-says-it-will-conduct-more-joint-patrols-with-philippines-south-china-2023-08-25/">boosted military exercises</a>, Albanese has emphasised the importance of better dialogue with Beijing.翻译:尽管澳大利亚与安全盟友美国走得更近，美国已同意根据与英国的三边<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/australian-pm-tells-us-house-speaker-he-hopes-aukus-legislation-passes-this-year-2023-10-26/">防御技术伙伴关系</a>AUKUS 向堪培拉出售核动力潜艇，并<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-says-it-will-conduct-more-joint-patrols-with-philippines-south-china-2023-08-25/">加强军事演习</a>，但阿尔巴内斯仍然强调与北京加强对话的重要性。</p>   <p>"China is the source of our greatest security anxiety ... China is also our largest partner and we do value a productive relationship," Defence Minister Richard Marles told reporters in Washington this week.翻译:“中国是我们最大的安全焦虑的根源......中国也是我们最大的合作伙伴，我们确实重视富有成效的关系，”国防部长理查德·马勒斯本周在华盛顿对记者说。</p>   <p>A quarter of Australia's export earnings come from China, more than the next three trade partners, the United States, South Korea and Japan combined, Albanese said on Tuesday.翻译:阿尔巴内斯周二表示，澳大利亚四分之一的出口收入来自中国，超过了紧随其后的三个贸易伙伴美国、韩国和日本的总和。</p>   <p>"Trade as an anchor provides stability and certainty to allow greater engagement while we navigate uncertain currents and obstacles that lie beneath," said Australia China Business Council president David Olsson.翻译:澳中贸易全国委员会主席戴维·奥尔森 (David Olsson) 表示：“贸易作为锚点提供了稳定性和确定性，使我们能够在应对潜在的不确定潮流和障碍的同时进行更多的接触。”</p>   <p>More than 250 Australian companies will exhibit at China's International Import Expo (CIIE) in Shanghai, to be opened by Premier Li Qiang on Sunday, showcasing products that were top sellers in China before trade hurdles were imposed - seafood, beef and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-wine-market-ready-welcome-likely-return-aussie-wine-ties-improve-2023-11-03/">wine</a> - as well as the iron ore exporters that dominate Australia's trade to China, Fortescue Metals <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FMG.AX" target="_blank">(FMG.AX)</a>, Rio Tinto and BHP <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BHP.AX" target="_blank">(BHP.AX)</a> .翻译:超过 250 家澳大利亚公司将参加在上海举行的中国国际进口博览会 (CIIE)，该博览会将于周日由李强总理主持开幕，展示贸易壁垒实施前在中国最畅销的产品——海鲜、牛肉和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-wine-market-ready-welcome-likely-return-aussie-wine-ties-improve-2023-11-03/">葡萄酒</a>。作为主导澳大利亚对华贸易的铁矿石出口商，福蒂斯丘金属公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FMG.AX" target="_blank">(FMG.AX)</a> 、力拓公司和必和必拓<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BHP.AX" target="_blank">(BHP.AX)</a> 。</p>   <p>"The prime minister's attendance at CIIE and the signal it sends to the Chinese system and business community, is likely to result in more positive attitudes toward Australia as a trade partner," Olsson said.翻译:奥尔森表示：“总理出席进博会及其向中国体系和商界发出的信号，可能会导致人们对澳大利亚作为贸易伙伴的态度更加积极。”</p>   <p>Chairman of the Business Council of Australia's global engagement committee, Warwick Smith, said Albanese would highlight the complementary nature of bilateral trade in a speech on Sunday to 500 business people.翻译:澳大利亚商业理事会全球参与委员会主席沃里克·史密斯 (Warwick Smith) 表示，阿尔巴尼斯将在周日向 500 名商界人士发表的演讲中强调双边贸易的互补性。</p>   <p>"It is important that dialogue has resumed," he said.翻译:“恢复对话很重要，”他说。</p>    <h 1="">DIFFICULT TOPICS</h>  <p>China has lauded the visit's timing, on the 50th anniversary of the first to China by an Australian leader, then Prime Minister Gough Whitlam.翻译:中国对此次访问的时机表示赞赏，适逢澳大利亚领导人、时任总理高夫·惠特拉姆首次访华50周年。</p>   <p>But despite the positive tone, Australian Foreign Minister Penny Wong has said ties won't return to where they were even 15 years ago, when Chinese investment surged into the economy.翻译:但尽管语气积极，澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤表示，两国关系不会回到 15 年前中国投资涌入经济时的水平。</p>   <p>Australia has blocked two Chinese investments in rare earth miners this year on national interest grounds, and in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-us-leaders-discuss-pacific-infrastructure-critical-minerals-2023-10-24/">Washington last week</a>, Albanese sought to boost U.S. investment in Australia's minerals sector, to reduce reliance on China.翻译:澳大利亚今年以国家利益为由阻止了中国对稀土矿商的两项投资， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-us-leaders-discuss-pacific-infrastructure-critical-minerals-2023-10-24/">上周在华盛顿</a>，阿尔巴内塞寻求增加美国对澳大利亚矿产行业的投资，以减少对中国的依赖。</p>   <p>China's ambassador, Xiao Qian, in an Australian newspaper column on Friday, said ties were at a "critical juncture of setting off and sailing off again", and urged more cooperation in "such traditional areas as energy, mining, agriculture, education and tourism".翻译:中国大使肖千周五在澳大利亚一家报纸专栏中表示，两国关系正处于“启程和再次扬帆的关键时刻”，并敦促在“能源、矿业、农业、教育和旅游等传统领域开展更多合作” ”。</p>   <p>Asia Society Australia executive director Richard Maude, a former diplomat who wrote Australia's 2017 foreign policy white paper, said the list of difficult topics for the Australian and Chinese leaders was long.翻译:澳大利亚亚洲协会执行董事理查德·莫德（Richard Maude）是澳大利亚2017年外交政策白皮书的前外交官，他表示，澳大利亚和中国领导人面临的难题清单很长。</p>   <p>"The South China Sea and especially China's attempts to force the Philippines off Second Thomas Shoal will have to be high on the agenda, but the prime minister will also need to make it clear that any attempt to force unification with Taiwan will carry severe consequences," said Maude.翻译:“南海问题，特别是中国迫使菲律宾离开仁爱礁的企图必须成为重要议程，但总理还需要明确表示，任何强迫与台湾统一的企图都将带来严重后果， “莫德说。</p>   <p>Although the Albanese government has put dialogue at the centre of its approach to China, most policy remains the same, he said.翻译:他说，尽管阿尔巴尼亚政府已将对话置于其对华政策的核心，但大多数政策保持不变。</p>   <p>"On the defence front, the Albanese government has doubled down on supporting America build the fabric of military deterrence across the Indo-Pacific. That duality of approach is quite evident to China," he said.翻译:“在国防方面，阿尔巴尼亚政府加倍努力支持美国在印度-太平洋地区建立军事威慑结构。这种双重性对中国来说非常明显，”他说。</p>    <span>Reporting by Kirsty Needham; editing by Robert Birsel翻译:科斯蒂·李约瑟报道；罗伯特·伯塞尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 05:42:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TU4BUB52UBL5ZNZJR24SAPEPCI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-albanese-highlight-trade-china-visit-ties-warm-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Kirsty Needham]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA/ALBANESE</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[全球金融首脑将在香港峰会上面临更严厉的中国问题]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/LjTYSv1uPX1xEtba_1a8HT40f10=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/LTGID5ACHBNODOMZUE6FDGCSII.jpg" alt="A screen showing the Hang Seng stock index is seen outside Exchange Square, in Hong Kong" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A screen showing the Hang Seng stock index is seen outside Exchange Square, in Hong Kong, China, August 18, 2023. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu/File Photo翻译:2023年8月18日，中国香港交易广场外显示恒生股票指数的屏幕。路透社/Tyrone Siu/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Global investment bank and asset manager chiefs are reuniting in Hong Kong next week amid geopolitical tensions and China's economic slowdown, seeking to redefine their position in the world's second-largest economy and its offshore financial hub.翻译:在地缘政治紧张局势和中国经济放缓之际，全球投资银行和资产管理公司高管下周将在香港重聚，寻求重新定义他们在全球第二大经济体及其离岸金融中心的地位。</p>   <p>The Global Financial Leaders Investment Summit, a flagship event hosted by the Hong Kong Monetary Authority, begins on Monday with participants including Goldman Sachs <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GS.N" target="_blank">(GS.N)</a> Chief Executive David Solomon, Morgan Stanley <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MS.N" target="_blank">(MS.N)</a> boss James Gorman, Citigroup's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/C.N" target="_blank">(C.N)</a> Jane Fraser, as well as HSBC's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/HSBA.L" target="_blank">(HSBA.L)</a> Noel Quinn and Standard Chartered's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/STAN.L" target="_blank">(STAN.L)</a> Bill Winters.翻译:由香港金融管理局主办的旗舰活动全球金融领袖投资峰会于周一开幕，与会者包括高盛<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GS.N" target="_blank">(GS.N)</a>首席执行官大卫·所罗门 (David Solomon)、摩根士丹利<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MS.N" target="_blank">(MS.N)</a>总裁詹姆斯·戈尔曼 (James Gorman)、花旗集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/C.N" target="_blank">(CN</a> ) 首席执行官詹姆斯·戈尔曼 (James Gorman) 等。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/C.N" target="_blank">）</a>简·弗雷泽（Jane Fraser），以及汇丰银行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/HSBA.L" target="_blank">（HSBA.L）</a>的诺埃尔·奎因（Noel Quinn）和渣打银行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/STAN.L" target="_blank">（STAN.L）的比尔·</a>温特斯（Bill Winters）。</p>   <p>The heads of Blackstone Group, Carlyle Group, Citadel and others will also speak at the event, which focuses on the main theme of "living with complexity".翻译:黑石集团、凯雷集团、Citadel 等公司的负责人也将在活动上发表讲话，活动围绕“复杂生活”的主题。</p>   <p>The executives are coming to Hong Kong as the city has shed hundreds of banking and asset management jobs because of the slowdown in China dealmaking and the tightened regulatory grip on the market since the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/hong-kongs-lee-pitches-china-advantage-rebuild-citys-image-financial-hub-2022-11-02/">inaugural summit</a> last year. That meeting was billed as Hong Kong's comeback as a global financial hub following the disruptions of the COVID-19 pandemic.翻译:这些高管即将来到香港，因为自去年<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/hong-kongs-lee-pitches-china-advantage-rebuild-citys-image-financial-hub-2022-11-02/">首届峰会</a>以来，由于中国交易放缓以及对市场的监管收紧，香港已经裁掉了数百个银行和资产管理职位。这次会议被认为是香港在受到新冠肺炎 (COVID-19) 大流行破坏后重新成为全球金融中心的标志。</p>   <p>"The main question in the mind of everybody when they come to Hong Kong is how is the Chinese economy performing and what would be the swings coming from there," said Diana Parusheva-Lowery, head of public policy and sustainable finance at the Asia Securities Industry &amp; Financial Markets Association in Hong Kong.翻译:亚洲证券公共政策和可持续金融主管戴安娜·帕鲁舍娃-洛厄里(Diana Parusheva-Lowery)表示：“每个人来到香港时，脑子里的主要问题是中国经济表现如何，以及随之而来的波动是什么。”香港工业及金融市场协会。</p>   <p>The Hong Kong Stock Exchange is only the 11th-largest venue for initial public offerings this year, with merely $2.7 billion raised through the third quarter, a shadow of its top position in most of the last decade. The territory's assets under management fell by 14% in 2022, official data showed.翻译:香港证券交易所仅是今年第 11 大首次公开募股交易场所，第三季度仅筹集了 27 亿美元，与其在过去十年大部分时间里排名第一的地位相形见绌。官方数据显示，2022 年该地区管理的资产下降了 14%。</p>   <p>Trading volumes <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-holds-key-hong-kongs-shrinking-stock-market-2023-10-25/">have also slumped</a> as foreign investors reduce exposure to a China they view as increasingly isolated by its opaque policies, struggling property sector and crackdowns on private enterprise.翻译:由于外国投资者认为中国因不透明的政策、陷入困境的房地产业和对私营企业的打击而日益孤立，因此减少了对中国的投资，交易量<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-holds-key-hong-kongs-shrinking-stock-market-2023-10-25/">也大幅下降</a>。</p>   <p>"The structural slowdown in China's economy, the omnipresent risk that U.S.-China relations might take another leg down in the future, the questions about whether private mainland money now prefers Singapore, none of that has really changed," said Chris Beddor, Gavekal Dragonomics' deputy China research director based in Hong Kong.翻译:龙洲经讯的 Chris Beddor 表示：“中国经济的结构性放缓、中美关系未来可能再次下滑的普遍风险、大陆私人资金现在是否更青睐新加坡的问题，这些都没有真正改变。”驻香港的中国研究副总监。</p>   <p>"And senior people in the financial sector are keenly aware of those issues, even if they don't discuss them publicly," Beddor said.翻译:贝多尔说：“金融领域的资深人士敏锐地意识到这些问题，即使他们没有公开讨论这些问题。”</p>    <h 1="">STRING OF LAYOFFS</h>  <p>Hong Kong's financial job market, which saw an exodus of foreign employees during COVID, is unlikely to recover in the near term amid a challenging operating environment, recruiters and industry insiders say.翻译:招聘人员和业内人士表示，在新冠疫情期间，香港的金融就业市场出现了外籍员工大量外流的情况，但由于经营环境充满挑战，短期内不太可能恢复。</p>   <p>Goldman Sachs, Morgan Stanley and J.P. Morgan have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/morgan-stanley-weighs-cutting-7-asia-investment-bank-jobs-bloomberg-news-2023-05-16/">trimmed</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/jpmorgan-cuts-around-20-asia-investment-banking-jobs-source-2023-06-21/">dozens of bankers</a> based in Hong Kong and mainland China this year, with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/goldman-cutting-more-than-30-asia-investment-banking-jobs-sources-2023-06-15/">key China dealmakers</a> among those laid off.翻译:高盛、摩根士丹利和摩根大通今年已<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/morgan-stanley-weighs-cutting-7-asia-investment-bank-jobs-bloomberg-news-2023-05-16/">裁减了</a>驻香港和中国大陆<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/jpmorgan-cuts-around-20-asia-investment-banking-jobs-source-2023-06-21/">的数十名银行家</a>，其中包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/goldman-cutting-more-than-30-asia-investment-banking-jobs-sources-2023-06-15/">主要的中国交易撮合者</a>。</p>   <p>The surprise merger between Swiss banking rivals UBS and Credit Suisse resulted in a brutal <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/credit-suisse-hong-kong-investing-banking-job-cuts-targeting-80-staff-start-this-2023-08-07/">80% reduction in the Credit Suisse investment banking staff</a> in Hong Kong in August.翻译:瑞士银行业竞争对手瑞银集团(UBS)和瑞士信贷银行(Credit Suisse)出人意料地合并，导致<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/credit-suisse-hong-kong-investing-banking-job-cuts-targeting-80-staff-start-this-2023-08-07/">瑞士信贷银行(Credit Suisse)在香港的投资银行员工8月份大幅裁员80%</a> 。</p>   <p>Canada's largest pension fund CPP Investments also <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/canadas-largest-pension-fund-trims-staff-it-puts-china-deals-hold-sources-2023-09-01/">cut a number of Hong Kong-based staff members</a>.翻译:加拿大最大的养老基金CPP Investments也<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/canadas-largest-pension-fund-trims-staff-it-puts-china-deals-hold-sources-2023-09-01/">裁减了多名香港员工</a>。</p>   <p>John Mullally, recruiter Robert Walters' Hong Kong managing director, said hiring in private banking remains active, helped by wealth coming out of China to Hong Kong after the border reopened.翻译:招聘人员罗伯特·沃尔特斯(Robert Walters)香港董事总经理约翰·穆拉利(John Mulally)表示，私人银行业的招聘仍然活跃，这得益于边境重新开放后财富从中国流入香港。</p>   <p>Hong Kong needs to be aware of competition from rival financial hub Singapore but Mullally expects Hong Kong to "regain some of the ground lost" despite the depressed dealmaking and trading.翻译:香港需要意识到来自竞争对手金融中心新加坡的竞争，但穆拉利预计，尽管交易和贸易低迷，香港仍将“收复部分失地”。</p>   <p>(This story has been refiled to correct the spelling of CPP Investments in paragraph 13)翻译:（本文已重新归档，以更正第 13 段中 CPP Investments 的拼写）</p>    <span>Reporting by Kane Wu in Hong Kong and Scott Murdoch in Sydney; additional reporting by Selena Li and Xie Yu; Editing by Christian Schmollinger翻译:吴凯恩 (Kane Wu) 在香港的报道和斯科特·默多克 (Scott Murdoch) 在悉尼的报道； Selena Li 和 Xie Yu 的补充报道；克里斯蒂安·施莫林格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 04:05:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">62D7U5PUMRN5XCULWYTLFTJE4E</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/global-finance-chiefs-face-tougher-china-questions-hong-kong-summit-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Kane Wu, Scott Murdoch]]></author>
            
                
                <category>BANKS</category>
                
                <category>ASIA/HONGKONG</category>
                
                <category>SUMMIT (CORRECTED, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[财新PMI显示10月中国服务业活动小幅回升]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/xhsOxmn_JSakKSjkb36IeAyBjN8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/V6QJGPKQGRJULIJA3V3QYZH7HA.jpg" alt="Employees prepare meat and vegetables at a kitchen of a hotpot restaurant in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Employees prepare meat and vegetables at a kitchen of a hotpot restaurant in Beijing, China April 8, 2022. Picture taken April 8, 2022. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo翻译:2022年4月8日，中国北京，员工在一家火锅店的厨房里准备肉类和蔬菜。照片摄于2022年4月8日。路透社/Tingshu Wang/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's services activity expanded at a slightly faster pace in October, a private-sector survey showed on Friday, with sales growing at the softest rate in 10 months and employment stagnating as business confidence waned.翻译:周五的一项私营部门调查显示，中国 10 月份服务业活动扩张速度略快，销售增速创 10 个月来最低水平，且随着商业信心减弱，就业停滞。</p>   <p>The vast services sector, which provides about 48% of jobs in China, enjoyed a strong rebound earlier this year but analysts say the sluggish household income growth and uncertain job market raise questions over the sustainability of the industry's growth.翻译:庞大的服务业提供了中国约48%的就业机会，今年早些时候出现了强劲反弹，但分析人士表示，家庭收入增长缓慢和就业市场的不确定性引发了人们对该行业增长可持续性的质疑。</p>   <p>The Caixin/S&amp;P Global services purchasing managers' index (PMI) rose to 50.4 in October from September's nine-month low of 50.2. The pace of expansion also remained much slower than seen on average in the first half of the year.翻译:10 月份财新/标普全球服务业采购经理人指数 (PMI) 从 9 月份的 9 个月低点 50.2 升至 50.4。扩张速度也仍远低于上半年的平均水平。</p>   <p>The 50-point mark separates expansion from contraction in activity.翻译:50 分是经济活动扩张与收缩的分界线。</p>   <p>An <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-factory-activity-unexpectedly-contracted-october-2023-10-31/">official survey</a> showed on Tuesday that services PMI dropped to 50.1 from 50.9 in September.翻译:周二的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-factory-activity-unexpectedly-contracted-october-2023-10-31/">官方调查</a>显示，服务业 PMI 从 9 月份的 50.9 降至 50.1。</p>   <p>"The services sector, which is highly related to youth employment, recovered 90% to pre-COVID levels," said Xing Zhaopeng, senior China strategist at ANZ.翻译:澳新银行高级中国策略师邢兆鹏表示：“与青年就业高度相关的服务业已恢复至新冠疫情前水平90%。”</p>   <p>However, "it is unlikely to see a rebound beyond expectation in the sector," he added.翻译:然而，“该行业不太可能出现超出预期的反弹，”他补充道。</p>   <p>New orders in the services sector last month rose at the weakest pace in 10 months, the Caixin survey showed, offsetting the bump higher from a travel boom seen during the eight-day National Day holiday.翻译:财新调查显示，上个月服务业新订单增速为 10 个月以来最弱，抵消了国庆八天假期旅行热潮带来的增长。</p>   <p>However, there was further improvement in foreign demand for Chinese services amid reports of increased amounts of overseas visitors.翻译:然而，随着海外游客数量的增加，国外对中国服务的需求进一步改善。</p>   <p>The slowdown in sales growth led to companies' more cautious approach to recruitment. Employment in the sector was unchanged in October, having expanded in each of the previous eight months.翻译:销售增长放缓导致企业对招聘采取更加谨慎的态度。该行业的就业人数在 10 月份没有变化，在过去八个月中逐年扩大。</p>   <p>Amid subdued demand, overall optimism slipped for the fourth month in a row and was the lowest since March 2020.翻译:由于需求低迷，整体乐观情绪连续第四个月下滑，为 2020 年 3 月以来的最低水平。</p>   <p>Prices charged by services companies grew at a faster pace as they sought to pass on higher input costs to customers, though the rate of input inflation was the slowest since June 2022.翻译:尽管投入通胀率是 2022 年 6 月以来最慢的，但服务公司寻求将更高的投入成本转嫁给客户，因此其收取的价格增长较快。</p>   <p>Caixin/S&amp;P's composite PMI, which includes both <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-factory-activity-contracts-october-caixin-pmi-2023-11-01/">manufacturing</a> and services activity, declined to 50.0 from 50.9 in September, marking the lowest reading since December 2022.翻译:财新/标普综合 PMI（包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-factory-activity-contracts-october-caixin-pmi-2023-11-01/">制造业</a>和服务业活动）从 9 月份的 50.9 降至 50.0，创下 2022 年 12 月以来的最低读数。</p>   <p>"The market conditions for manufacturing were more sluggish compared with the services sector," said Wang Zhe, economist at Caixin Insight Group.翻译:财新智库经济学家王哲表示：“与服务业相比，制造业的市场状况更加低迷。”</p>   <p>China's economy staged better-than-expected growth in the third quarter, but economists say the weak property sector, fading demand for travel, local government debt and geopolitical tensions may weigh on the outlook.翻译:中国经济第三季度的增长好于预期，但经济学家表示，房地产行业疲软、旅游需求下降、地方政府债务和地缘政治紧张局势可能会给经济前景带来压力。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ellen Zhang and Ryan Woo. Editing by Sam Holmes翻译:张艾伦和吴瑞安报道。山姆·霍姆斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 01:53:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6UKOJK7AAFPFDO7BMPJMRDJ3GM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-services-activity-picks-up-slightly-oct-caixin-pmi-2023-11-03/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/PMI</category>
                
                <category>SERVICES</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[菲律宾指责中国侵入其海域]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tsU7yVP9535QCIzldv4Bbub1lvo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HIV2JPEUHJPYHNYM64VVRTCLTM.jpg" alt="National flags are placed outside a room where Philippine Finance Secretary Carlos Dominguez and China's Commerce Minister Gao Hucheng address reporters after their meeting in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>National flags are placed outside a room where Philippine Finance Secretary Carlos Dominguez and China's Commerce Minister Gao Hucheng address reporters after their meeting in Beijing, China, January 23, 2017. REUTERS/Damir Sagolj翻译:2017年1月23日，菲律宾财政部长卡洛斯·多明计斯和中国商务部部长高虎城在中国北京会晤后向记者发表讲话，房间外悬挂着国旗。路透社/Damir Sagolj</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Philippine foreign ministry on Thursday accused China of intruding into its waters after an incident involving the two countries' military vessels at a disputed shoal in the South China Sea earlier this week.翻译:本周早些时候，两国军舰在南海争议浅滩发生事件，菲律宾外交部周四指责中国侵入菲律宾海域。</p>   <p>The Department of Foreign Affairs (DFA) said the Chinese military's claim that a Philippine military ship "illegally entered" waters near the Scarborough Shoal "has no legal basis and only serves to raise tensions" in the disputed waterway.翻译:外交部表示，中国军方关于菲律宾军舰“非法进入”黄岩岛附近海域的说法“没有法律依据，只会加剧争议航道的紧张局势”。</p>   <p>"It is China that is intruding into Philippine waters," the foreign ministry said in a statement.翻译:外交部在一份声明中表示：“是中国入侵了菲律宾海域。”</p>   <p>The Philippines and China both lay claim to the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-accuses-china-intruding-into-its-waters-2023-11-02/The%20Philippines%20and%20China%20lay%20claim%20to%20the%20shoal%20but%20sovereignty%20has%20never%20been%20established%20and%20it%20remains%20effectively%20under%20Beijing's%20control" target="_blank">Scarborough Shoal</a> but sovereignty has never been established and it remains effectively under Beijing's control since it seized it from Manila in 2012.翻译:菲律宾和中国都声称对<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-accuses-china-intruding-into-its-waters-2023-11-02/The%20Philippines%20and%20China%20lay%20claim%20to%20the%20shoal%20but%20sovereignty%20has%20never%20been%20established%20and%20it%20remains%20effectively%20under%20Beijing's%20control" target="_blank">黄岩岛</a>拥有主权，但主权从未确立，自2012年从马尼拉手中夺取黄岩岛以来，黄岩岛实际上仍处于北京的控制之下。</p>   <p>The DFA said the shoal, which it calls "Bajo de Masinloc", is within the Philippines' exclusive economic zone and the country has sovereign rights and jurisdiction over it.翻译:外交部表示，该浅滩被称为“Bajo de Masinloc”，位于菲律宾专属经济区内，菲律宾对其拥有主权权利和管辖权。</p>   <p>"The Philippines has consistently demanded that Chinese vessels in Bajo de Masinloc leave the area immediately," the foreign ministry said.翻译:菲律宾外交部表示：“菲律宾一贯要求在巴霍德马辛洛克的中国船只立即离开该地区。”</p>   <p>The shoal, located 200 km (124 miles) off the Philippines, was part of an arbitration claim filed by Manila at an international tribunal. The court ruled in 2016 that Beijing's claim to 90% of the South China Sea had no basis under international law, but China has refused to recognise the ruling.翻译:该浅滩距离菲律宾 200 公里（124 英里），是马尼拉向国际法庭提出的仲裁索赔的一部分。该法院于2016年裁定，北京对南海90%海域的主权主张没有国际法依据，但中国拒绝承认这一裁决。</p>   <p>The Philippines presidential office said Thursday South China Sea matters will be part of the bilateral talks between Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida and President Ferdinand Marcos on Friday. Kishida is set to arrive in Manila on Friday for a two-day visit.翻译:菲律宾总统办公室周四表示，南海问题将成为日本首相岸田文雄和总统费迪南德·马科斯周五双边会谈的一部分。岸田定于周五抵达马尼拉进行为期两天的访问。</p>   <p>Ahead of the visit, the Japan defence ministry also announced the delivery of the first air surveillance radar system to the Philippine military as part of a 2020 contract between the Philippines' defence department and Mitsubishi Electric Corp.翻译:在访问之前，日本防卫省还宣布向菲律宾军方交付首个空中监视雷达系统，作为菲律宾国防部与三菱电机公司之间 2020 年合同的一部分。</p>    <span>Reporting by Mikhail Flores; Editing by Kanupriya Kapoor and Miral Fahmy翻译:米哈伊尔·弗洛雷斯报道；编辑：Kanupriya Kapoor 和 Miral Fahmy</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 23:15:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7OMJGPQ565OFLHTMYXT5BVWW4U</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-accuses-china-intruding-into-its-waters-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SOUTHCHINASEA</category>
                
                <category>PHILIPPINES/CHINA (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国火葬“人民”总理并在悲痛中降下国旗]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/IxqS-wK6MMs-X_7y1JTpV1fK8f4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HJJO7BWGMVM2TP6YEVLPHWDJ6E.jpg" alt="Chinese flag at half-mast on former premier Li's cremation day, in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The Chinese flag at a gate to the Zhongnanhai leadership compound flies at half-mast in memory of late former Chinese premier Li Keqiang, in Beijing, China November 2, 2023. REUTERS/Mark Chisholm翻译:2023年11月2日，中国北京，中南海领导大院门口的中国国旗降半旗纪念已故中国前总理李克强。路透社/Mark Chisholm</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/qYdXhFjuSps4qJQSX93-TZQuwiY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZWJZSTSJSRKO5PDJYZNNIDJSDU.jpg" alt="A giant screen broadcasts news footage of a funeral service for the late former Chinese Premier Li Keqiang, in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A giant screen broadcasts news footage of a funeral service for the late former Chinese Premier Li Keqiang, in Beijing, China November 2, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023 年 11 月 2 日，中国北京，一块大屏幕播放已故中国前总理李克强葬礼的新闻片段。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0xLrojPp-QAJPlcQPi-93OcwUs0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2KXE7UMG4BPQFB5OERP4EVGGWY.jpg" alt="China's Premier Li Keqiang waves as he arrives for a news conference after the closing ceremony of China's National People's Congress (NPC) at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>China's Premier Li Keqiang waves as he arrives for a news conference after the closing ceremony of China's National People's Congress (NPC) at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, China, March 15, 2017. REUTERS/Damir Sagolj翻译:2017 年 3 月 15 日，中国北京，中国总理李克强在中国北京人民大会堂闭幕式后抵达出席新闻发布会。 REUTERS/Damir Sagolj</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/m44nm7IQ-hoOn6fsWENafZ_MfJ0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/N4363JLUKBMABL43C5VITC6GOA.jpg" alt="Newspapers with the obituary of late former Chinese Premier Li Keqiang on the frontpage are displayed, at a newsstand in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Newspapers with the obituary of late former Chinese Premier Li Keqiang on the front page are displayed, at a newsstand in Beijing, China October 28, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年10月28日，中国北京的一个报摊上，头版刊登已故中国前总理李克强讣告的报纸。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>                   <p>China lowered the national flag Beijing's Tiananmen Square on Thursday amid an outpouring of online grief as the country cremated Li Keqiang, known as "the people's premier" for his down-to-earth, hands-on leadership.翻译:周四，中国在北京天安门广场降下国旗，火化了因其脚踏实地、亲力亲为的领导而被称为“人民总理”的李克强，网上一片悲痛。</p>   <p>Li, a former economist and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-ex-premier-leaves-an-unfinished-reform-legacy-2023-10-27/">pro-reform</a> leader who served as premier for 10 years before retiring in March, died of a heart attack in Shanghai last Friday. He was 68.翻译:李克强是一位前经济学家和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-ex-premier-leaves-an-unfinished-reform-legacy-2023-10-27/">支持改革的</a>领导人，曾担任总理十年，于今年三月退休，上周五在上海因心脏病去世。他 68 岁了。</p>   <p>At Li's funeral at a Beijing cemetery where high-ranking officials and national heroes are laid to rest, President Xi Jinping and his wife, with the six other members of the Communist Party's Politburo Standing Committee, the highest rung of political power in China, as well as Vice President Han Zheng paid their final respects.翻译:李克强的葬礼在北京一座高官和民族英雄的墓地举行，国家主席习近平和他的妻子，以及中共中央政治局常务委员会的其他六名成员，是中国最高政治权力机构。韩正副院长致以最后的哀悼。</p>   <p>The group stood in silence and took three bows, the official Xinhua news agency reported.翻译:据官方新华社报道，这群人默哀并三鞠躬。</p>   <p>Former President Hu Jintao sent a wreath to express his condolences over Li's passing, according to Xinhua.翻译:据新华社报道，国家主席胡锦涛向李克强逝世致以花圈表示哀悼。</p>   <p>Messages for the late premier flooded social media platforms as Chinese citizens mourned his death.翻译:随着中国公民哀悼已故总理的去世，社交媒体平台上充斥着给他的留言。</p>   <p>On popular social media platform Weibo, which replaced its 'like' button with a chrysanthemum flower symbolising mourning on related posts, tens of thousands of people left comments bidding Li farewell on a Thursday post by China's national broadcaster.翻译:在流行的社交媒体平台微博上，相关帖子中的“点赞”按钮被象征哀悼的菊花取代，数以万计的人在中国国家广播公司周四发布的帖子中发表了告别李的评论。</p>   <p>Li was the top trending topic on Weibo. The hashtag for his mourning drew 430 million views.翻译:李成为微博上的热门话题。哀悼他的标签吸引了 4.3 亿次浏览。</p>   <p>A Beijinger surnamed Gao said Li will be remembered for his contributions to the nation. "It can be said that he has made a great contribution to people's lives, to the improvement of living standards. In the recent pandemic, the premier always rushed to the front line," Gao said.翻译:一位高姓北京人表示，李先生对国家的贡献将被人们铭记。 “可以说，他为人民生活、为人民生活水平的提高做出了巨大贡献。在最近的疫情中，总理总是冲在第一线。”高说。</p>   <p>Once viewed as a Communist Party leadership contender, Li was sidelined in recent years, analysts and diplomats said, as Xi tightened his grip on economic policymaking.翻译:分析人士和外交官表示，随着习近平加强对经济政策制定的控制，李克强一度被视为共产党领导层的有力竞争者，但近年来却被边缘化。</p>   <p>Shanghai resident Zhang Shijun described Li as down-to-earth man who "lot for our people; very humble and low-key".翻译:上海居民张世军形容李是一个脚踏实地的人，“为人民谋福利，非常谦虚和低调”。</p>   <p>Some businesses such as international coffee chain Starbucks <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SBUX.O" target="_blank">(SBUX.O)</a> turned their app interface black and white in mourning for Li.翻译:国际咖啡连锁店星巴克<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SBUX.O" target="_blank">（SBUX.O）</a>等一些企业将其应用程序界面变成黑白，以哀悼李。</p>   <p>Photographs of Li were shared on Weibo by Xinhua news agency, including those of him with Xi, Hu and former leader Jiang Zemin. There were also <a href="https://weibo.com/ttarticle/p/show?id=2309404963649780580732" target="_blank">photographs</a> of Li interacting with ordinary Chinese people in the 2000s as well as one of him clambering over rubble in a disaster-stricken zone after a major earthquake in Sichuan in southwest China.翻译:新华社在微博上分享了李克强的照片，其中包括他与习近平、胡锦涛和前领导人江泽民的照片。还有李在2000年代与普通中国人互动的<a href="https://weibo.com/ttarticle/p/show?id=2309404963649780580732" target="_blank">照片</a>，以及他在中国西南部四川发生大地震后在灾区废墟上攀爬的照片。</p>   <p>"It still feels a bit unreal, because I feel like he's a good premier and suddenly he's gone," said a 24-year-old Beijing-based lawyer surnamed Wan. "And then I also feel sad for him because he was not yet old."翻译:“这仍然感觉有点不真实，因为我觉得他是一个很好的总理，但突然他就走了，”一位 24 岁的北京万姓律师说。 “然后我也为他感到难过，因为他还没有老。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Liz Lee, Xiaoyu Yin, Ryan Woo and Beijing newsroom; Editing by Christian Schmollinger and Shri Navaratnam and Miral Fahmy翻译:Liz Lee、Xiaoyu Yin、Ryan Woo 和北京新闻编辑室报道；编辑：Christian Schmollinger、Shri Navaratnam 和 Miral Fahmy</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 23:11:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ENSRBIKGZJPBTNRFROJF3HM6MI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-lowers-flags-half-mast-former-premier-lis-cremation-day-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Liz Lee, Xiaoyu Yin]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>POLITICS/LIKEQIANG (UPDATE 3, TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[耶伦：印太盟友不应在美国和中国之间做出选择]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/RPS_JGysUWPqaF8F3JddeA5VmCs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/75ILC6WQ25O4LJIDD2XSVNUBYA.jpg" alt="Global infrastructure and investment forum in New York" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Janet Yellen, United States Secretary of Treasury, participates in global infrastructure and investment forum in New York, Thursday, Sept. 21, 2023. Seth Wenig/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦 (Janet Yellen) 于 2023 年 9 月 21 日星期四参加在纽约举行的全球基础设施和投资论坛。Seth Wenig/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen on Thursday sought to reassure Asian countries that the U.S. approach to China would not lead to a 'disastrous' division of the global economy that would force them to take sides.翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦周四试图向亚洲国家保证，美国对华政策不会导致全球经济出现“灾难性”分裂，从而迫使它们选边站队。</p>   <p>In a speech ahead of the U.S.-hosted Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation Summit in San Francisco later this month, Yellen said that a full de-coupling of the U.S. and Chinese economies was "simply not practical," especially given the complexity of Asian supply chains and the region's deep economic ties to China.翻译:耶伦本月晚些时候在旧金山举行的亚太经济合作峰会之前发表演讲时表示，美国和中国经济完全脱钩“根本不切实际”，特别是考虑到亚洲供应链的复杂性以及该地区与中国的深厚经济联系。</p>   <p>Her comments sought to assuage growing concerns about geopolitical fragmentation of the global economy into U.S.-led and China-led factions amid growing national security-driven export and technology controls between the world's two largest economies.翻译:她的言论试图缓解人们对全球经济地缘政治分裂为美国主导和中国主导的派系日益增长的担忧，因为全球最大的两个经济体之间以国家安全为导向的出口和技术控制日益加强。</p>   <p>"A full separation of our economies, or an approach in which countries including those in the Indo-Pacific are forced to take sides, would have significant negative global repercussions," Yellen said. "We have no interest in such a divided world and its disastrous effects."翻译:耶伦表示：“我们经济的全面分离，或者包括印太地区国家在内的国家被迫选边站队的做法，将会对全球产生重大的负面影响。” “我们对这样一个分裂的世界及其灾难性影响不感兴趣。”</p>   <p>Yellen said the U.S. instead was pursuing the "de-risking and diversifying" of its economic ties to China, by investing in manufacturing at home and by strengthening linkages with allies and partners around the world, including Indo-Pacific countries.翻译:耶伦表示，美国正在通过投资国内制造业以及加强与包括印太国家在内的世界各地盟友和伙伴的联系，寻求与中国经济关系的“去风险化和多元化”。</p>   <p>Yellen said the U.S. would not compromise on national security actions, but aimed to keep them narrowly targeted, not for the purpose of "choking off growth in China."翻译:耶伦表示，美国不会在国家安全行动上妥协，但旨在将这些行动锁定在狭窄的目标范围内，而不是为了“遏制中国的增长”。</p>   <p>Her remarks to an Asia Society event came as the U.S. is preparing to host leaders and other top officials from APEC countries in San Francisco from Nov. 11-17. The White House wants to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/white-house-aims-biden-xi-meeting-san-francisco-november-2023-10-31/">schedule a meeting</a> between U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping alongside the summit.翻译:她在亚洲协会活动上发表上述言论之际，美国正准备于 11 月 11 日至 17 日在旧金山接待亚太经合组织国家的领导人和其他高级官员。白宫希望在峰会期间安排美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/white-house-aims-biden-xi-meeting-san-francisco-november-2023-10-31/">举行会晤</a>。</p>    <h 1="">TRADE, INVESTMENT LINKS</h>  <p>Yellen said the Biden administration was committed to expanding trade and investment with Indo-Pacific countries, emphasizing the region's strategic importance ahead of the APEC gathering.翻译:耶伦表示，拜登政府致力于扩大与印太国家的贸易和投资，并在亚太经合组织会议之前强调了该地区的战略重要性。</p>   <p>Deeper economic links with Indo-Pacific countries will help make U.S. supply chains more resilient and tap into a dynamic and growing market for U.S. exports, she said.翻译:她表示，与印太国家加深经济联系将有助于增强美国供应链的弹性，并进入充满活力且不断增长的美国出口市场。</p>   <p>"As we look toward APEC later this month, let me state unequivocally: Claims that America is turning away from the Indo-Pacific are wholly unfounded," Yellen said in the excerpts. "We are deepening our economic ties across the region, with tremendous potential benefits for the U.S. economy and for the Indo-Pacific."翻译:耶伦在摘录中表示：“当我们展望本月晚些时候的亚太经合组织时，让我明确指出：有关美国正在远离印太地区的说法完全没有根据。” “我们正在深化整个地区的经济联系，这将为美国经济和印度-太平洋地区带来巨大的潜在利益。”</p>   <p>The Biden administration also has called a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-calls-indo-pacific-negotiating-round-just-ahead-apec-summit-2023-11-01/">seventh negotiating round</a> for its Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity (IPEF) initiative next week in San Francisco, aimed at reaching some agreements in time for the APEC summit.翻译:拜登政府还呼吁下周在旧金山举行印太经济繁荣框架（IPEF）倡议<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-calls-indo-pacific-negotiating-round-just-ahead-apec-summit-2023-11-01/">第七轮谈判</a>，旨在在亚太经合组织峰会前及时达成一些协议。</p>   <p>IPEF, while far short of a traditional free trade agreement, is the Biden administration's signature initiative to engage economically with Asian countries and provide them a trade and investment alternative to China.翻译:IPEF虽然远非传统的自由贸易协定，但却是拜登政府与亚洲国家进行经济接触并为它们提供中国以外的贸易和投资替代方案的标志性倡议。</p>   <p>Yellen said deeper integration with Indo-Pacific countries would benefit the region and the U.S. She noted that U.S. two-way trade with the region reached a value of $2.28 trillion in 2022, up 25% since 2019, with the region taking nearly a quarter of U.S. exports.翻译:耶伦表示，与印太国家深化一体化将使该地区和美国受益。她指出，美国与该地区的双向贸易额到2022年将达到2.28万亿美元，自2019年以来增长25%，其中该地区占据了近四分之一的贸易额。美国出口。</p>   <p>"The economic case for our expanding trade and investment is clear. The Indo-Pacific is a dynamic and rapidly growing region. As it grows, we gain a fast-expanding customer base for U.S. firms and workers," Yellen said.翻译:“我们扩大贸易和投资的经济理由是明确的。印太地区是一个充满活力且快速增长的地区。随着它的发展，我们为美国公司和工人赢得了快速扩大的客户群，”耶伦说。</p>    <h 1="">SUPPLY CHAIN SECURITY</h>  <p>Part of the reason for increased trade with the region has been the migration of U.S. supply chains away from China, a trend that started with tariffs imposed by former President Donald Trump in 2018 and accelerated since the COVID-19 pandemic.翻译:与该地区贸易增加的部分原因是美国供应链从中国迁移，这一趋势始于前总统唐纳德·特朗普在 2018 年征收关税，并自 COVID-19 大流行以来加速。</p>   <p>Yellen said economic engagement with Indo-Pacific countries, including Vietnam, is "crucial to bolstering our supply chain security" to avoid bottlenecks and shortages that occurred as the world emerged from the pandemic. She repeated her desire to diversify supply chains to countries in the region through "friend-shoring" or using trusted allies as sources of supply.翻译:耶伦表示，与包括越南在内的印太国家的经济接触“对于加强我们的供应链安全至关重要”，以避免世界摆脱疫情后出现的瓶颈和短缺。她重申希望通过“友邦”或使用值得信赖的盟友作为供应来源，使该地区国家的供应链多样化。</p>   <p>"And achieving resilience through partnering with Indo-Pacific countries means gains for Indo-Pacific economies as well," Yellen said.翻译:耶伦表示：“通过与印太国家合作实现韧性也意味着印太经济体的收益。”</p>    <span>Reporting by David Lawder;editing by Diane Craft翻译:大卫·劳德 (David Lawder) 报道；黛安·克拉夫特 (Diane Craft) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 19:44:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZQ2UGKUL7JOX7M5VNRAUAU6XVU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/yellen-us-committed-boosting-trade-investment-with-indo-pacific-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Lawder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/YELLEN (UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
