<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 07:27:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国蓝箭航天准备用甲烷燃料火箭发射卫星]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Beijing-based LandSpace Technology, one of China's private space companies, is preparing to launch satellite payloads to orbit in a key commercial test of its methane and liquid oxygen fuelled rocket.翻译:总部位于北京的蓝箭航天科技有限公司是中国私营航天公司之一，该公司正准备将卫星有效载荷送入轨道，对其甲烷和液氧燃料火箭进行一项重要的商业测试。</p>   <p>Investors and rocket developers have said methane could offer a way to help slash costs and support reusable rockets in a cleaner and more efficient manner.翻译:投资者和火箭开发商表示，甲烷可以提供一种帮助削减成本并以更清洁、更高效的方式支持可重复使用火箭的方法。</p>   <p>LandSpace's Zhuque-2 carrier rocket was transferred to the launch area of a space facility in the Gobi Desert on Friday and is readying for launch, designated Y-3, the company said on its Weibo social media account.翻译:蓝箭航天在其微博社交媒体账户上表示，朱雀二号运载火箭已于周五转移至戈壁沙漠的航天设施发射区，并准备发射，代号为Y-3。</p>   <p>The company did not specify a launch window for the rocket, which will blast off from Jiuquan Satellite Launch Center in Inner Mongolia.翻译:该公司没有具体说明火箭的发射窗口，该火箭将从内蒙古酒泉卫星发射中心发射。</p>   <p>LandSpace aims to prove the feasibility of Zhuque-2 with three test launches; the first two were Y-1 and Y-2, a company representative said on Tuesday.翻译:蓝箭航天旨在通过三次发射验证朱雀二号的可行性；公司代表周二表示，前两个是 Y-1 和 Y-2。</p>   <p>If Zhuque-2 is validated, LandSpace plans to provide clients about three launches in 2024 and double that number in 2025, the representative said.翻译:该代表表示，如果“朱雀二号”获得验证，蓝箭航天计划在 2024 年为客户提供约 3 次发射，并在 2025 年将这一数字增加一倍。</p>   <p>LandSpace declined to provide details on the launch date or the number and type of the satellites to be carried by Y-3.翻译:蓝箭航天拒绝透露发射日期或运三号运载卫星的数量和类型的详细信息。</p>   <p>Chinese commercial space firms have rushed into the sector since 2014, when the government allowed private investment in an industry now dominated by Elon Musk's SpaceX.翻译:自 2014 年以来，中国商业航天公司纷纷涌入该领域，当时政府允许私人投资该行业，目前该行业由埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 的 SpaceX 主导。</p>   <p>LandSpace was one of the earliest and best funded of the Chinese space startups aiming to tap into the demand for rocket launches amid growing competition to place satellites in low-Earth orbit as an alternative to Musk's Starlink.翻译:蓝箭航天是中国最早、资金最充足的航天初创公司之一，旨在满足火箭发射的需求，因为将卫星送入近地轨道以替代马斯克的星链的竞争日益激烈。</p>   <p>In July, LandSpace hit a benchmark in that race with the launch of the world's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/china-beats-rivals-successfully-launch-first-methane-liquid-rocket-2023-07-12/">first methane-liquid oxygen rocket</a>, the Zhuque-2 Y-2, putting China ahead of U.S. rivals including SpaceX and Jeff Bezos' Blue Origin.翻译:7月，蓝箭航天在这场竞赛中创下了基准，发射了世界<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/china-beats-rivals-successfully-launch-first-methane-liquid-rocket-2023-07-12/">上第一枚甲烷液氧火箭“</a>朱雀二号Y-2”，使中国领先于包括SpaceX和杰夫·贝索斯的蓝色起源在内的美国竞争对手。</p>   <p>Before Y-2, which didn't carry a usable satellite, LandSpace said that Zhuque-2 Y-1, the first test rocket, failed a launch last year, without specifying whether it carried any satellite payloads.翻译:在运二号没有携带可用卫星之前，蓝箭航天表示，第一枚试验火箭朱雀二号运一号去年发射失败，但没有具体说明它是否携带任何卫星有效载荷。</p>   <p>Founded in 2015, LandSpace has secured funding from investors including venture capital firm HongShan, known at that time as Sequoia Capital China, the investment arm of Chinese property developer Country Garden and the state-backed China SME Development Fund.翻译:蓝箭空间成立于 2015 年，已获得投资者的融资，包括风险投资公司红杉资本（当时称为红杉资本中国）、中国房地产开发商碧桂园的投资部门以及国家支持的中国中小企业发展基金。</p>   <p>LandSpace's latest announced fundraising was in 2020, when it raised 1.2 billion yuan ($168.14 million). The company has had fundraising rounds of undisclosed sizes since, Chinese company record tracking database Tianyancha showed.翻译:蓝箭航天最新宣布的融资是在 2020 年，当时筹集了 12 亿元人民币（1.6814 亿美元）。中国公司记录追踪数据库天眼查显示，自此以来，该公司已进行过几轮未公开融资规模的融资。</p>   <p>In July, LandSpace founder and CEO Zhang Changwu told Chinese publication Yicai the company had started developing reusable rockets and expected to conduct a test launch in the second half of 2025.翻译:今年7月，蓝箭航天创始人兼首席执行官张昌武告诉第一财经，该公司已开始研发可重复使用火箭，预计于2025年下半年进行试射。</p>   <p>LandSpace rival OrienSpace, founded in 2020, said it plans to launch its first solid-fuel rocket, Gravity-1, in December.翻译:LandSpace 的竞争对手 OrienSpace 成立于 2020 年，表示计划于 12 月发射第一枚固体燃料火箭 Gravity-1。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1368 yuan)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.1368 元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Ella Cao, Roxanne Liu and Bernard Orr; Editing by Kevin Krolicki, Miral Fahmy and Gerry Doyle翻译:Ella Cao、Roxanne Liu 和 Bernard Orr 报道；编辑：Kevin Krolicki、Miral Fahmy 和 Gerry Doyle</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 07:26:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">E6MBXTNT7FNO5BKBUSUCGBCXI4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/chinas-landspace-readies-satellite-launch-with-methane-rocket-2023-12-04/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ella Cao, Roxanne Liu, Bernard Orr]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AEROSPACE/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着焦点转向美国就业，亚洲股市下滑]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/s-m3hjInUQ-fO_jH-fXA0W2xfhU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WQX3OKMRDRLNNCEZM3LC5UBDLE.jpg" alt="Passersby walk past an electric board displaying Japan's Nikkei share average outside a brokerage in Tokyo翻译:东京一家经纪公司外，路人走过显示日本日经指数平均股价的电子板" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Passersby walk past an electric board displaying Japan's Nikkei share average outside a brokerage in Tokyo翻译:东京一家经纪公司外，路人走过显示日本日经指数平均股价的电子板, Japan April 18, 2023.  REUTERS/Issei Kato/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Asian stocks slipped to three-week lows and Hong Kong's unloved Hang Seng index slumped to a one-year trough on Tuesday while bonds and the dollar steadied as investors tempered expectations for cuts to U.S. interest rates and waited on U.S. jobs data.翻译:周二，亚洲股市跌至三周低点，不受青睐的香港恒生指数跌至一年低点，而债券和美元则企稳，因为投资者降低了对美国降息的预期，并等待美国就业数据。</p>   <p>The Australian dollar fell 0.6% after the central bank left interest rates on hold, as expected, and emphasised that the future direction rates would depend on data.翻译:央行如预期维持利率不变，并强调未来利率方向将取决于数据，澳元下跌0.6%。</p>   <p>MSCI's broadest index of Asia-Pacific shares outside Japan <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIAPJ0000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIAPJ0000PUS)</a> was down 1% in late afternoon trade, with Hong Kong doing most of the dragging with a 1.6% fall.翻译:MSCI 日本以外最广泛的亚太股市指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIAPJ0000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIAPJ0000PUS)</a>在午后交易中下跌 1%，其中香港股市跌幅最大，跌幅为 1.6%。</p>   <p>The Hang Seng <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a> is down more than 17% for the year so far, while world stocks <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIWD00000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIWD00000PUS)</a> are up almost 15%, as investors have streamed out of Chinese assets while the economy stumbles.翻译:恒生指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a>今年迄今已下跌超过 17%，而世界股市<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIWD00000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIWD00000PUS)</a>则上涨近 15%，原因是投资者在经济陷入困境时纷纷撤离中国资产。</p>   <p>Japan's Nikkei <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a> was 1.4% lower at three-week trough, mostly thanks to falling chipmaking stocks. S&amp;P 500 futures fell 0.2% and European futures were flat.翻译:日本日经指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a>在三周低点下跌 1.4%，主要是由于芯片制造股下跌。标准普尔 500 指数期货下跌 0.2%，欧洲期货持平。</p>   <p>Gold hung on above $2,000 after a wild session on Monday, when it hit a record high in Asia before recoiling sharply lower.翻译:周一经历了疯狂的交易后，金价维持在 2,000 美元上方，当时金价在亚洲创下历史新高，随后大幅回落。</p>   <p>"The market has more or less priced the soft landing scenario (for the U.S. economy) to perfection," said Bank of Singapore strategist Moh Siong Sim. "Overnight there was a bit of a reality check -- maybe it was too ambitious."翻译:新加坡银行策略师 Moh Siong Sim 表示：“市场或多或少已经将（美国经济）软着陆情景定价为完美。” “一夜之间，我们对现实进行了一些检验——也许它太过雄心勃勃了。”</p>   <p>Treasuries had come under a little pressure on Monday as traders calibrated pretty aggressive pricing for U.S. interest rate cuts. Two-year yields rose 9.1 basis points (bps) and were steady at 4.62% in Asia trade.翻译:由于交易员为美国降息调整了相当激进的定价，美国国债周一承受了一些压力。亚洲贸易中，两年期债券收益率上升 9.1 个基点 (bps)，稳定在 4.62%。</p>   <p>Having been encouraged by a benign inflation report three weeks ago, futures imply about 125 bps of cuts in 2024.翻译:受到三周前良性通胀报告的鼓舞，期货暗示 2024 年将降息约 125 个基点。</p>   <p>U.S. job openings data is due at 1530 GMT, and broader hiring figures, which had last month showed signs of a slowdown in the job market, will be published on Friday.翻译:美国职位空缺数据将于格林尼治标准时间 1530 公布，上个月显示就业市场放缓迹象的更广泛的招聘数据将于周五公布。</p>   <p>"While it's understandable the market has embraced the recent improvement in inflation and softer October labour market data, strong momentum in the economy remains," ANZ analysts said in a note to clients.翻译:澳新银行分析师在给客户的一份报告中表示，“尽管市场接受近期通胀改善和十月份劳动力市场数据疲软的情况是可以理解的，但经济的强劲势头仍然存在。”</p>   <p>"We therefore expect that the (Fed), while encouraged by recent inflation improvements, will continue to adopt a hawkish policy stance."</p>    <h 1="">DOVISH RBA</h>  <p>In currency markets, the dollar, which suffered its sharpest monthly decline for a year in November, rose slightly overnight.翻译:货币市场方面，美元在11月份遭遇一年来最大月度跌幅，但隔夜小幅上涨。</p>   <p>The euro sat at $1.0841 on Tuesday, just above support at its 200-day moving average.翻译:欧元周二报1.0841美元，略高于200日移动均线的支撑位。</p>   <p>Core inflation in Tokyo <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/inflation-japans-capital-slows-november-2023-12-04/">slowed</a> in November, though the yen strengthened a little to 146.88 per dollar.翻译:11 月份东京核心通胀 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/inflation-japans-capital-slows-november-2023-12-04/">放缓</a>，但日元兑美元小幅走强至 146.88。</p>   <p>The Australian and New Zealand dollars retreated from multi-month highs on Monday.翻译:澳元和新西兰元周一从数月高点回落。</p>   <p>They were last a little weaker, with the Aussie dropping to $0.6583, where it was testing support at its 200-day moving average.翻译:最后走势稍弱，澳元跌至 0.6583 美元，正在测试 200 日移动均线的支撑位。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/australias-central-bank-holds-cash-rate-435-2023-12-05/">Reserve Bank of Australia</a> left interest rates on hold and said, as it had a month ago, that future rate settings would depend on data.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/australias-central-bank-holds-cash-rate-435-2023-12-05/">澳大利亚储备银行</a>维持利率不变，并表示与一个月前一样，未来的利率设定将取决于数据。</p>   <p>"We suspect that markets were expecting a more hawkish statement given the unusually long time before the next RBA meeting on 6 February," said Lenny Jin, global FX strategist at HSBC.翻译:汇丰银行全球外汇策略师 Lenny Jin 表示：“鉴于距离 2 月 6 日下一次澳洲联储会议召开的时间异常漫长，我们怀疑市场正在期待一份更加鹰派的声明。”</p>   <p>"The RBA did not forcefully push against the ongoing trend of easing financial conditions that has occurred globally since November."翻译:“自11月以来，澳洲联储并没有强力阻止全球金融环境持续宽松的趋势。”</p>   <p>Falling coal and gas prices pushed <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/australia-trade-drags-q3-growth-government-spending-boost-2023-12-05/">Australia's current account</a> into deficit in the September quarter, data on Tuesday showed.翻译:周二的数据显示，煤炭和天然气价格下跌导致<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/australia-trade-drags-q3-growth-government-spending-boost-2023-12-05/">澳大利亚九月季度经常账户</a>出现赤字。</p>   <p>In commodity trading, Brent crude futures traded broadly steady at $78.07 a barrel, having fallen overnight on doubts that producers will make further cuts to output.翻译:在大宗商品交易中，布伦特原油期货交易大致稳定在每桶 78.07 美元，因对生产商将进一步减产的怀疑而隔夜下跌。</p>   <p>Chicago wheat held near its highest level since late August after the U.S. Department of Agriculture confirmed the largest one-off private sale to China in years.翻译:在美国农业部确认了多年来对中国最大的一次私人出售后，芝加哥小麦价格维持在自八月下旬以来的最高水平附近。</p>   <p>Dalian iron ore futures declined amid lingering fears of China's intervention, though analysts cautioned that the downward trend may be short-lived.翻译:由于对中国干预的担忧挥之不去，大连铁矿石期货下跌，不过分析师警告称，下跌趋势可能是短暂的。</p>    <span>Editing by Kim Coghill翻译:编辑：金·科吉尔</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 06:35:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">PYUXKSEZNFJWZJTHUQXKGA6XP4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/global-markets-wrapup-1-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Tom Westbrook]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/ (WRAPUP 3)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[报告称，2023 年全球化石燃料二氧化碳排放量将创历史新高]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/nA4SK4NDfXTSq4Ih9EzpOeiExU4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BTASQXPOGBLD3BAE523WYJDJEY.jpg" alt="Smoke rises from chimneys at a factory in the port of Dunkirk翻译:敦刻尔克港一家工厂的烟囱冒出浓烟" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Smoke rises from chimneys at a factory in the port of Dunkirk翻译:敦刻尔克港一家工厂的烟囱冒出浓烟, France  January 19, 2023. REUTERS/Yves Herman/File photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Global carbon dioxide emissions from burning fossil fuels are set to hit a record high this year, exacerbating climate change and fuelling more destructive extreme weather, scientists said.翻译:科学家表示，燃烧化石燃料造成的全球二氧化碳排放量今年将创下历史新高，加剧气候变化并助长更具破坏性的极端天气。</p>   <p>The Global Carbon Budget report, published on Tuesday during the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/cop/">COP28 climate summit</a>, said that overall CO2 emissions, which reached a record high last year, have plateaued in 2023 due to a slight drop from uses of land like deforestation.翻译:周二在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/cop/">COP28 气候峰会</a>期间发布的《全球碳预算》报告称，由于森林砍伐等土地使用略有下降，去年创下历史新高的二氧化碳排放总量已于 2023 年趋于稳定。</p>   <p>Countries are expected to emit a total 36.8 billion metric tons of CO2 from fossil fuels in 2023, a 1.1% increase from last year, the report by scientists from more than 90 institutions including the University of Exeter concluded.翻译:来自埃克塞特大学等 90 多家机构科学家的报告得出结论，到 2023 年，各国化石燃料二氧化碳排放量预计将达到 368 亿吨，比去年增加 1.1%。</p>   <p>When land use emissions are included, global CO2 emissions are set to total 40.9 billion tons this year.翻译:如果算上土地使用排放，今年全球二氧化碳排放总量预计将达到 409 亿吨。</p>   <p>Emissions from coal, oil and gas all rose, driven by India and China. The Chinese rise was caused by its economy reopening after COVID-19 lockdowns, while India's was a result of power demand growing faster than the country's renewable energy capacity, leaving fossil fuels to make up the shortfall.翻译:在印度和中国的推动下，煤炭、石油和天然气的排放量均有所上升。中国的崛起是由于新冠肺炎 (COVID-19) 封锁后经济重新开放所致，而印度的崛起是由于电力需求增长快于该国可再生能源产能，导致化石燃料弥补了缺口。</p>   <p>The year's emissions trajectory pulls the world further away from preventing global warming exceeding 1.5 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial times.翻译:今年的排放轨迹使世界距离防止全球变暖较工业化前时期超过 1.5 摄氏度又进一步。</p>   <p>"It now looks inevitable we will overshoot the 1.5C target of the Paris Agreement," said Exeter's Professor Pierre Friedlingstein, who led the research.翻译:领导这项研究的埃克塞特大学教授皮埃尔·弗里德林斯坦 (Pierre Friedlingstein) 表示：“现在看来，我们不可避免地会超出《巴黎协定》规定的 1.5 摄氏度目标。”</p>   <p>Countries agreed in the 2015 Paris Agreement to keep warming well below 2C and to aim for 1.5C. Scientists have said more than 1.5C will unleash more severe and irreversible impacts including fatal heat, catastrophic floods, and the death of coral reefs.翻译:各国在 2015 年《巴黎协定》中同意将升温幅度控制在远低于 2 摄氏度，并力争达到 1.5 摄氏度。科学家表示，超过 1.5 摄氏度将带来更严重且不可逆转的影响，包括致命的高温、灾难性的洪水和珊瑚礁的死亡。</p>   <p>"Leaders meeting at COP28 will have to agree rapid cuts in fossil fuel emissions even to keep the 2C target alive," Friedlingstein said.翻译:Friedlingstein 表示：“在 COP28 会议上举行的领导人会议必须就快速削减化石燃料排放达成一致，即使是为了保持 2C 目标的实现。”</p>   <p>The IPCC, the U.N.'s climate science panel, has said world emissions must plummet 43% by 2030, to stick to the 1.5C limit.翻译:联合国气候变化专门委员会（IPCC）表示，到 2030 年，世界排放量必须下降 43%，才能遵守 1.5 摄氏度的限制。</p>   <p>Instead, emissions have charged higher in recent years. The COVID-19 pandemic caused a brief blip in that trend, but emissions are now back up to 1.4% above pre-COVID levels.翻译:相反，近年来排放量更高。 COVID-19 大流行导致这一趋势短暂中断，但排放量目前已较新冠疫情前的水平回升至 1.4%。</p>   <p>Researchers from the Helsinki-based Centre for Research on Energy and Clean Air (CREA) said last month China's greenhouse emissions could start going into "<a href="https://reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-emissions-could-go-into-structural-decline-next-year-research-2023-11-14/" target="_blank">structural decline</a>" as early as next year due to record-high renewable energy installations.翻译:赫尔辛基能源与清洁空气研究中心（CREA）的研究人员上个月表示，由于可再生能源装机量创历史新高，中国的温室气体排放最早可能在明年开始进入“ <a href="https://reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-emissions-could-go-into-structural-decline-next-year-research-2023-11-14/" target="_blank">结构性下降</a>”。</p>   <p>China produces 31% of global fossil fuel CO2 emissions.翻译:中国的化石燃料二氧化碳排放量占全球的 31%。</p>   <p>The new report cited some bright spots, with emissions in the U.S. and European Union both falling, driven in part by coal plants being retired.翻译:新报告列举了一些亮点，美国和欧盟的排放量均下降，部分原因是燃煤电厂退役。</p>   <p>Overall, 26 countries representing 28% of the world's emissions are now in a downward trend. Most are in Europe, the researchers said.翻译:总体而言，占世界排放量 28% 的 26 个国家目前正处于下降趋势。研究人员表示，大多数都在欧洲。</p>    <span>Reporting by Kate Abnett; Editing by Alexander Smith翻译:凯特·阿布内特报道；亚历山大·史密斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 06:20:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">UHK4U4M2ERIE3IBO4A2SJAVEMM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/global-co2-emissions-fossil-fuels-hit-record-high-2023-report-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Kate Abnett]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CLIMATE</category>
                
                <category>UN/EMISSIONS (TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国国有银行将美元兑换成人民币——消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Uucs0vIIJzOjfBlJhxHY6ackXhs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DWLVRDPCK5OSVK6I7HDXTA5MO4.jpg" alt="Illustration shows U.S. dollar and Chinese Yuan banknotes翻译:插图显示美元和人民币纸币" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Dollar and Chinese Yuan banknotes are seen in this illustration taken January 30, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:这张摄于 2023 年 1 月 30 日的插图中可以看到美元和人民币纸币。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's major state-owned banks were seen swapping yuan for U.S. dollars in the onshore swap market and selling those dollars in the spot market to support the yuan on Tuesday, two sources with knowledge of the matter said.翻译:两位知情人士称，中国主要国有银行周二在境内掉期市场将人民币兑换成美元，并在现货市场出售这些美元以支撑人民币。</p>   <p>The state bank actions come at a time the Chinese yuan strengthened 2.55% to the dollar in November for the best month this year. However, it is still down 3% year-to-date.翻译:国家银行采取行动之际，11 月份人民币兑美元汇率升值 2.55%，创下今年以来表现最好的一个月。然而，今年迄今仍下跌 3%。</p>   <p>The sources said they believed the state bank moves were aimed at accelerating the yuan's recovery and encouraging domestic exporters to settle their foreign exchange receipts into the local currency towards the year-end.翻译:消息人士称，他们认为央行此举旨在加速人民币复苏，并鼓励国内出口商在年底前以本币结算外汇收入。</p>   <p>Chinese state banks often act on behalf of the country's central bank in the foreign exchange market, but they would also trade on their own behalf.翻译:中国国有银行经常代表国家中央银行在外汇市场上行事，但它们也会代表自己进行交易。</p>   <p>Big banks were spotted doing a similar trade late last month, helping the yuan's recovery against a broadly weaker U.S. dollar, Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/chinas-state-banks-seen-swapping-selling-dollars-yuan-sources-2023-11-21/">reported</a>.翻译:据路透社<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/chinas-state-banks-seen-swapping-selling-dollars-yuan-sources-2023-11-21/">报道</a>，大型银行上个月末被发现进行了类似的交易，帮助人民币兑美元汇率普遍走软。</p>    <span>Reporting by Shanghai Newsroom and Tom Westbrook; Editing by Jacqueline Wong翻译:上海新闻室和汤姆·威斯布鲁克的报道；编辑：黄杰奎琳</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 03:49:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5TRUHVPGZZJPLJGXKICQFCSZDI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-state-banks-seen-swapping-selling-dollars-yuan-sources-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>YUAN/ (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[尽管煤炭排放量增加，亚洲发电变得更加清洁]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Asia boosts clean power faster than west</li>  <li>Power sector emissions in Asia still rising</li>  <li>West steps up gas-fired power as Asia cuts share</li>  <li>India sees no energy transition without storage</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>亚洲清洁能源发展速度快于西方</li><li>亚洲电力行业排放量仍在上升</li><li>亚洲削减份额，西方加强燃气发电</li><li>印度认为没有储能就无法实现能源转型</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/3ABzdq8dmJe1MFlP50ddPtS_QAI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/UQ5H55ECKNN4FDY4P3WEKZJVZU.jpg" alt="Smoke rises from chimneys near solar panels in Shaanxi翻译:陕西太阳能电池板附近烟囱冒出浓烟" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Smoke rises from chimneys near solar panels, during a Huawei-organised media tour, in Shaanxi province, China April 24, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo翻译:2023 年 4 月 24 日，在华为组织的中国陕西省媒体参观期间，太阳能电池板附近的烟囱冒出浓烟。REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Asia boosted clean electricity output and slashed its share of fossil fuels faster than North America and Europe from 2015, data shows, underscoring resistance by Asian nations to a western push to choke private financing for coal-fired power.翻译:数据显示，从2015年开始，亚洲提高清洁电力产量并削减化石燃料份额的速度快于北美和欧洲，这凸显了亚洲国家对西方遏制燃煤发电私人融资的抵制。</p>   <p>There is wide agreement that increasing clean power, such as wind and solar, is central to curbing carbon emissions to fight climate change. On Saturday at the U.N. climate summit, 118 governments, led by the U.S. and the European Union, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/over-110-countries-set-join-cop28-deal-triple-renewable-energy-2023-12-02/">pledged to triple</a> the world's renewable energy capacity by 2030.翻译:人们普遍认为，增加风能和太阳能等清洁能源对于遏制碳排放、应对气候变化至关重要。周六在联合国气候峰会上，以美国和欧盟为首的 118 个国家政府<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/over-110-countries-set-join-cop28-deal-triple-renewable-energy-2023-12-02/">承诺到 2030 年将全球可再生能源产能增加两倍</a>。</p>   <p>However, China and India did not back the COP28 pledge as it was twinned with curbing use of fossil fuels, which they see as essential to reliably meeting rapidly rising power demand.翻译:然而，中国和印度并未支持 COP28 的承诺，因为该承诺与限制化石燃料的使用有关，他们认为化石燃料对于可靠地满足快速增长的电力需求至关重要。</p>   <p>Bolstering their view, even with coal, higher financing costs and weaker access to funds, Asia outpaced Europe and North America in fighting climate change by key measures since the Paris climate agreement of 2015, a Reuters analysis of data found.翻译:路透社对数据的分析发现，尽管存在煤炭、较高的融资成本和较弱的资金获取渠道，但自 2015 年巴黎气候协议以来，亚洲在应对气候变化方面的关键措施仍超过了欧洲和北美，这支持了他们的观点。</p>      <p>Asia boosted clean power, including hydro and nuclear, as a share of overall power output by about 8 percentage points to 32% between 2015 and 2022, a review of data from energy think tank Ember showed.翻译:能源智库 Ember 的数据审查显示，2015 年至 2022 年间，亚洲推动了包括水电和核电在内的清洁能源发电，占总发电量的比例提高了约 8 个百分点，达到 32%。</p>   <p>By comparison, clean energy's share in the power mix in Europe rose over 4 percentage points to 55%, while in North America it climbed by more than 6 percentage points to 46%.翻译:相比之下，欧洲清洁能源在电力结构中的份额上升了4个百分点以上，达到55%，而在北美则上升了6个多百分点，达到46%。</p>   <p>"There cannot be any pressure on India to cut down emissions," India's power and renewable energy minister R.K. Singh said on Nov. 30.翻译:印度电力和可再生能源部长RK辛格11月30日表示，“不能对印度施加任何减排压力。”</p>   <p>Asia slashed the share of fossil fuels in power generation by 8 percentage points to 68% in 2022 from 2015, abating more gas and coal use than Europe and North America.翻译:亚洲将比 2015 年化石燃料在发电中的份额削减 8 个百分点，至 2022 年达到 68%，减少的天然气和煤炭使用量超过欧洲和北美。</p>   <p>Over the same period, Europe's dependence on fossil fuels fell 4 percentage points while North America's narrowed by 6 percentage points.翻译:同期，欧洲对化石燃料的依赖度下降了4个百分点，而北美则缩小了6个百分点。</p>   <p>"The data shows that the West is not moving fast enough on scaling up renewables and storage," said Hogeveen Rutter, who works with private companies on behalf of the International Solar Alliance (ISA).翻译:代表国际太阳能联盟（ISA）与私营公司合作的霍格文·鲁特（Hogeveen Rutter）表示：“数据显示，西方在扩大可再生能源和存储方面行动不够快。”</p>   <p>Rutter said delays in approvals for renewables, storage projects and grid interconnections in Europe and the U.S. have hampered growth of clean energy use in the West.</p>    <h 1="">ASIAN EMISSIONS RISE</h>  <p>To be sure, fast-growing Asia, home to half the world's population, accounts for three-fifths of global emissions from power generation, including from sectors exporting goods and services to the west.翻译:可以肯定的是，快速增长的亚洲拥有世界一半的人口，其发电排放量占全球排放量的五分之三，其中包括向西方出口商品和服务的行业。</p>      <p>And <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/india/india-scrambles-add-coal-fired-power-capacity-avoid-outages-sources-2023-11-29/">India</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/chinas-coal-country-full-steam-ahead-with-new-power-plants-despite-climate-2023-11-30/">China continue to build</a> new coal-fired plants to meet rapidly growing electricity demand.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/india/india-scrambles-add-coal-fired-power-capacity-avoid-outages-sources-2023-11-29/">印度</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/chinas-coal-country-full-steam-ahead-with-new-power-plants-despite-climate-2023-11-30/">中国继续建设</a>新的燃煤电厂，以满足快速增长的电力需求。</p>   <p>That means power generation emissions by Asia will continue to climb, after having risen nearly 4% annually since the Paris accord as electricity demand has soared, while emissions in Europe and North America declined, the Ember data showed.翻译:Ember数据显示，这意味着亚洲发电排放量将继续攀升，自《巴黎协定》签署以来，由于电力需求飙升，亚洲发电排放量每年增长近4%，而欧洲和北美的排放量则有所下降。</p>   <p>However, Asian governments have argued that the world's wealthiest countries should help poorer countries cut emissions, citing rich nations' higher per capita emissions and their unabated fossil fuel use in the last century.翻译:然而，亚洲各国政府认为，世界上最富裕的国家应该帮助较贫穷的国家减少排放，理由是富裕国家的人均排放量较高，而且上个世纪化石燃料的使用量有增无减。</p>      <p>This year, western nations expressed unwillingness <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/western-countries-not-ready-finance-early-coal-power-retirement-indonesia-2023-09-25/">to fund early retirement</a> of polluting plants in Indonesia - the world's seventh largest coal-fired power generator, despite commitments to help it decarbonise.翻译:今年，西方国家表示不愿意为世界第七大燃煤发电厂印度尼西亚的污染工厂<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/western-countries-not-ready-finance-early-coal-power-retirement-indonesia-2023-09-25/">提前退役提供资金</a>，尽管承诺帮助其脱碳。</p>   <p>"Asian countries with access to finance have been able to move much quicker, while other parts of Asia need more concessionality to catch up. This illustrates the need for the West to assist with concessional funding for storage to move away from coal," ISA's Rutter said.翻译:ISA 的 Rutter 表示：“能够获得融资的亚洲国家能够更快地采取行动，而亚洲其他地区则需要更多优惠才能迎头赶上。这说明西方需要为储能提供优惠资金，以摆脱对煤炭的依赖。”说。</p>   <p>Funding shortages and high-priced tariffs for renewables have hindered Indonesia's move away from coal, while access to funds have enabled <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-solar-capacity-expected-hit-1000-gw-by-2026-rystad-energy-2023-09-12/">rapid expansion of green energy</a> in China, analysts say.翻译:分析人士表示，资金短缺和可再生能源高价关税阻碍了印度尼西亚摆脱煤炭的步伐，而获得资金则促进了中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-solar-capacity-expected-hit-1000-gw-by-2026-rystad-energy-2023-09-12/">绿色能源的快速扩张</a>。</p>   <p>A report released on Monday estimated developing countries will need <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/climate-finance-takes-centre-stage-cop28-climate-talks-2023-12-04/">$2.4 trillion a year</a> in investment to cap emissions.</p>    <h 1="">WEST TURNS TO GAS</h>  <p>Some western nations are looking to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/sustainable-finance-reporting/france-us-propose-ban-private-finance-coal-fired-plants-cop28-sources-2023-11-21/">curb finance for coal</a>, calling it the "number one threat" to climate goals. Despite challenges, Asia, along with Europe and North America, have cut the share of coal in power use, although at a slower pace.翻译:一些西方国家正在寻求<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/sustainable-finance-reporting/france-us-propose-ban-private-finance-coal-fired-plants-cop28-sources-2023-11-21/">遏制煤炭融资</a>，称其为气候目标的“头号威胁”。尽管面临挑战，亚洲与欧洲和北美一起削减了煤炭在电力使用中的份额，尽管步伐较慢。</p>   <p>However, both Europe and North America are increasing use of natural gas - often described as a transition fuel - to make up for part of the decline in coal-fired power generation, while gas makes up a shrinking share of power generation in Asia.翻译:然而，欧洲和北美都在增加天然气（通常被称为过渡燃料）的使用，以弥补燃煤发电量下降的部分影响，而天然气在亚洲发电量中所占的份额不断缩小。</p>   <p>The share of gas rose 3 percentage points to 26% of European power generation in 2022 from 2015, with North America boosting the share of gas-fired power by 6 percentage points to 36%, despite tepid power demand growth.翻译:到2022年，天然气在欧洲发电量中的份额将比2015年上升3个百分点，达到26%，尽管电力需求增长不温不火，北美燃气发电的份额将增加6个百分点，达到36%。</p>   <p>Cuts in nuclear power have slowed Europe and North America's fight to reduce emissions, although nuclear's share of their power mix remains well above Asia's.翻译:尽管核电在其电力结构中的份额仍然远高于亚洲，但核电的削减减缓了欧洲和北美减排的努力。</p>      <p>"The progress the West has made is to cut use of dirty coal and use relatively less-polluting gas," said Ghee Peh, an analyst at the Institute for Energy Economics and Financial Analysis.翻译:能源经济与金融分析研究所分析师 Ghee Peh 表示：“西方取得的进展是减少污染煤炭的使用，并使用污染相对较少的天然气。”</p>   <p>India, the world's second largest coal user, has argued for the phase-down of all fossil fuels instead of <a href="https://reuters.com/business/cop/india-seeks-cop27-deal-phase-down-all-fossil-fuels-sources-2022-11-12/" target="_blank">singling out coal</a>, and plans to oppose the plan to ban private finance for coal. It wants rich nations to invest more in energy storage to back up renewables.翻译:印度是世界第二大煤炭消费国，主张逐步减少所有化石燃料，而不是<a href="https://reuters.com/business/cop/india-seeks-cop27-deal-phase-down-all-fossil-fuels-sources-2022-11-12/" target="_blank">单独单独使用煤炭</a>，并计划反对禁止私人融资煤炭的计划。它希望富裕国家加大对能源存储的投资，以支持可再生能源。</p>   <p>"We cannot phase out fossil fuels unless we have nuclear or until storage becomes viable," Singh said.翻译:辛格说：“除非我们拥有核能或储存变得可行，否则我们无法逐步淘汰化石燃料。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Sudarshan Varadhan; Editing by Tony Munroe and Sonali Paul翻译:苏达山·瓦拉丹 (Sudarshan Varadhan) 报道；托尼·芒罗和索纳利·保罗编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 02:20:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">E65DQKBANNIMHPHTALAD5VWH4M</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/asian-power-generation-gets-cleaner-even-coal-emissions-rise-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Sudarshan Varadhan]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CLIMATE</category>
                
                <category>UN/EMISSIONS (ANALYSIS)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[财新PMI显示，中国11月服务业活动在新订单的推动下加速]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Gls-ogSSQx58ec7FZTFH5V_NXYI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NHYYUVXV7BK7ZIYZ3CYHL4TX3Q.jpg" alt="People dine at a restaurant in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家餐馆用餐" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People dine at a restaurant in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家餐馆用餐, China September 5, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's services activity expanded at a quicker pace in November, a private-sector survey showed on Tuesday, as the upturn in new businesses were the best seen for three months amid reports of firmer market conditions.翻译:周二的一项私营部门调查显示，中国 11 月份服务业活动扩张速度加快，因有报道称市场状况走强，新业务增长创三个月来最好水平。</p>   <p>The findings present a mixed picture of the vast services sector as an official survey last week showed the sector unexpectedly <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-factory-activity-contracts-second-month-november-2023-11-30/">contracted</a> for the first time since December last year, prompting calls for more stimulus measures.翻译:调查结果显示，庞大的服务业情况好坏参半，上周的一项官方调查显示，该行业自去年 12 月以来首次<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-factory-activity-contracts-second-month-november-2023-11-30/">出现</a>意外收缩，促使人们呼吁采取更多刺激措施。</p>   <p>The Caixin/S&amp;P Global services purchasing managers' index (PMI) rose to a three-month high of 51.5 in November from October's 50.4, but it remained softer than the long-run series average.翻译:财新/标普全球服务业采购经理人指数（PMI）从 10 月的 50.4 升至 11 月的三个月高点 51.5，但仍低于长期系列平均水平。</p>   <p>"Both services supply and demand expanded, as the market continued to heal," said Wang Zhe, economist at Caixin Insight Group.翻译:财新智库经济学家王哲表示：“随着市场持续复苏，服务供给和需求均扩大。”</p>   <p>Taken together with the better-than-expected <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-activity-surprisingly-expands-november-caixin-pmi-2023-12-01/">Caixin manufacturing PMI</a>, Wang said the world's second-biggest economy showed signs of an encouraging recovery, with steady growth in consumer spending, solid improvement in industrial production and an uptick in market confidence.翻译:结合好于预期的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-activity-surprisingly-expands-november-caixin-pmi-2023-12-01/">财新制造业PMI</a> ，王表示，世界第二大经济体显示出令人鼓舞的复苏迹象，消费支出稳定增长，工业生产稳步改善，市场信心回升。</p>   <p>Analysts say the different survey sizes and composition of surveyed companies might explain the discrepancy between the Caixin and official PMI readings.翻译:分析人士表示，不同的调查规模和受访企业的构成可能解释了财新和官方PMI数据之间的差异。</p>   <p>Caixin/S&amp;P's composite PMI, which includes both manufacturing and services activity, grew to 51.6 from 50.0 in October, marking the strongest reading since August.翻译:财新/标准普尔综合 PMI（包括制造业和服务业活动）从 10 月份的 50.0 升至 51.6，创下 8 月份以来的最强读数。</p>   <p>Service providers were upbeat about business activity over the year ahead in November and the degree of positive sentiment picked up for the first time in five months.翻译:服务提供商对 11 月份未来一年的商业活动持乐观态度，积极情绪程度五个月来首次回升。</p>   <p>However, Oxford Economics lead economist Louise Loo said while China heads into 2024 with relatively loose policy settings, the country's private sector confidence was constrained by property pessimism.翻译:然而，牛津经济研究院首席经济学家Louise Loo表示，尽管中国进入2024年的政策相对宽松，但该国私营部门的信心却受到房地产悲观情绪的制约。</p>   <p>Property sales, investment, and home prices extended declines in October and piled more pressure on authorities to step up efforts to prevent contagion across the broader financial sector.翻译:十月份房地产销售、投资和房价继续下跌，给当局带来了更大的压力，要求当局加大力度防止疫情蔓延到更广泛的金融领域。</p>   <p>The country's central bank governor last week said monetary policy will remain accommodative to support growth but <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">urged</a> structural reforms over time to reduce the economy's reliance on infrastructure and property.翻译:该国央行行长上周表示，货币政策将保持宽松以支持增长，但<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">敦促</a>随着时间的推移进行结构性改革，以减少经济对基础设施和房地产的依赖。</p>   <p>According to the Caixin services survey, employment fell for the first time since the start of 2023 as some firms maintained a cautious approach to hiring.翻译:财新服务业调查显示，由于一些企业对招聘保持谨慎态度，就业人数出现 2023 年初以来的首次下降。</p>   <p>November also witnessed a further slowdown in the rate of input cost inflation across China's service sector.翻译:11月份，中国服务业投入成本通胀率进一步放缓。</p>   <p>"China is no longer the spender of last resort for the global economy, so don't expect robust reflation," Oxford Economics' Loo said.翻译:牛津经济研究院的卢表示：“中国不再是全球经济的最后消费国，因此不要指望出现强劲的通货再膨胀。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Ellen Zhang and Ryan Woo
Editing by Shri Navaratnam翻译:Ellen 张和 Ryan Woo 报道 Shri Navaratnam 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 01:48:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZNNA3EGMVZIEJKGGAEAMFOOOBY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-nov-services-activity-accelerates-boost-new-orders-caixin-pmi-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/PMI</category>
                
                <category>SERVICES (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[日本边境岛民谴责缺乏援助台湾人逃离袭击的计划]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/1qDbD2lQAQQ8r0pGzj67K3TyJ-s=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/535LEKWGERL6XNHESBKGCQ4ZSY.jpg" alt="General view shows Kubura fishing port on Yonaguni island, Okinawa翻译:一般视图显示冲绳与那国岛的 Kubura 渔港" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A general view shows Kubura fishing port on Yonaguni island, Japan's westernmost inhabited island in Okinawa prefecture, Japan November 10, 2023. REUTERS/Issei Kato/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 10 日，日本冲绳县最西端有人居住的岛屿与那国岛的 Kubura 渔港全景。REUTERS/Issei Kato/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/7txzMtqRTyyytPSEPNHDv2db27E=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WUPTWCIYXNM7JLKB3W7H5UBGCU.jpg" alt="Local fishermen land a billfish at Kubura fishing port on Yonaguni island on Yonaguni island on Yonaguni island, Okinawa翻译:当地渔民在冲绳县与那国岛的久不乐渔港捕获了一条旗鱼" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Local fishermen land a billfish at Kubura fishing port on Yonaguni island, Japan's westernmost inhabited island in Okinawa prefecture, Japan November 10, 2023. REUTERS/Issei Kato/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 10 日，日本冲绳县最西端有人居住的岛屿与那国岛，当地渔民在久不拉渔港捕获了一条旗鱼。 REUTERS/Issei Kato/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/iGaChmUWi3nmKBHVm5OV_nPTI4g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VZ5X7MWVF5IXVBIZFZCSFPZW44.jpg" alt="A view of a radar facility set up for coastal surveillance by Japan Ground Self-Defense Force's Yonaguni base, on high ground on Yonaguni island翻译:日本陆上自卫队与那国基地在与那国岛高地上设置的用于海岸监视的雷达设施" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view of a radar facility set up for coastal surveillance by Japan Ground Self-Defense Force's Yonaguni base, on high ground on Yonaguni island翻译:日本陆上自卫队与那国基地在与那国岛高地上设置的用于海岸监视的雷达设施, Japan's westernmost inhabited island in Okinawa prefecture, Japan November 13, 2023. REUTERS/Issei Kato/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 13 日，日本冲绳县与那国岛高地上，日本陆上自卫队与那国基地为海岸监视而设立的雷达设施。路透社/Issei Kato/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/E9GnD1Q_2rC6XZUiXrFUPqXV7Y0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/T7BOB4XKARKTJB3TUMOGATHE6M.jpg" alt="Koji Sugama, the Yonaguni town hall official in charge of preparing the island for disasters, checks stocks of supplies for emergencies on Yonaguni island, Okinawa翻译:冲绳与那国岛负责防灾准备的市政厅官员菅间浩二正在检查冲绳与那国岛的紧急物资库存" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Koji Sugama, the Yonaguni town hall official in charge of preparing the island for disasters, checks stocks inside a heavy steel container filled with bottled water and ready meals for emergencies on Yonaguni island, Japan's westernmost inhabited island in Okinawa prefecture, Japan November 9, 2023. REUTERS/Issei Kato/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 9 日，日本冲绳县与那国岛，日本最西端有人居住的岛屿，负责该岛防灾准备工作的与那国岛市政厅官员菅间浩司正在检查一个装满瓶装水和紧急即食食品的重型钢制集装箱内的库存。 . 路透社/Issei Kato/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Cy_nW0gJ-Zl51nXmeGQuA4ooVe8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HJD6EZ6KHBJ2JIKTQHFDG3QQH4.jpg" alt="Yonaguni town mayor Kenichi Itokazu speaks during an interview with Reuters on Yonaguni island, Okinawa翻译:冲绳与那国岛町长糸一健一接受路透社采访时发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Yonaguni town mayor Kenichi Itokazu speaks during an interview with Reuters at Yonaguni town hall, on Yonaguni island, Japan's westernmost inhabited island in Okinawa prefecture, Japan November 9, 2023. REUTERS/Issei Kato/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 9 日，日本冲绳县与那国岛，日本最西端有人居住的岛屿与那国岛，与那国町市长 Kenichi Itokazu 在接受路透社采访时发表讲话。 REUTERS/Issei Kato/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/6F6IxpfAATACvShoSDYGgDYpXBo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GEBDJ5LPVBK77IISJWWMFI6J5I.jpg" alt="Japan Self-Defense Forces soldiers take part in an evacuation drill on Yonaguni island, Okinawa翻译:日本自卫队士兵在冲绳与那国岛参加疏散演习" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Japan Self-Defense Forces soldiers take part in an evacuation drill on Yonaguni island, Japan's westernmost inhabited island in Okinawa prefecture, Japan November 12, 2023. REUTERS/Issei Kato翻译:2023 年 11 月 12 日，日本自卫队士兵参加在日本冲绳县最西端有人居住的与那国岛举行的疏散演习。 REUTERS/Issei Kato</figcaption></figure>                       <p>Sonkichi Sakihara recalls chancing upon some of the last refugees to arrive on Yonaguni: four men who had sailed more than 2,000 kilometres from Vietnam to reach Japan's westernmost inhabited island. It was 1977.翻译:崎原尊吉 (Sonkichi Sakihara) 回忆起偶然遇见最后一批抵达与那国岛的难民：四名男子从越南航行 2000 多公里到达日本最西端有人居住的岛屿。那是 1977 年。</p>   <p>"I was out checking for stowaways from Taiwan when I found them," Sakihara, 80, said at his family store near the port where he encountered the group, among 113 Vietnamese to make the journey after the war ended.翻译:80 岁的咲原在港口附近的自家商店里说：“我出去检查来自台湾的偷渡者，当时我发现了他们。”他在港口附近的家庭商店里遇到了这群人，他们是战争结束后踏上旅程的 113 名越南人中的一员。</p>   <p>Today, some residents of Yonaguni foresee another refugee crisis that they say their isolated outpost and its dwindling population of less than 1,700 would be ill-equipped to handle. Just 110 kilometres to the west, and occasionally visible from Yonaguni, is Taiwan, the self-ruled island of 24 million that China asserts is its territory and which Beijing is menacing with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-says-it-is-monitoring-chinas-drills-around-taiwan-closely-2023-04-08/">simulated missile strikes</a> and other displays of military firepower.翻译:如今，与那国岛的一些居民预见到另一场难民危机，他们说，他们孤立的前哨基地和日益减少的不到 1,700 人的人口将没有能力应对这场危机。台湾以西仅 110 公里处，从与那国岛偶尔可见。这个拥有 2,400 万人口的自治岛屿被中国声称是其领土，北京正在通过<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-says-it-is-monitoring-chinas-drills-around-taiwan-closely-2023-04-08/">模拟导弹袭击</a>和其他军事火力展示来威胁台湾。</p>   <p>Concerned about the potential for conflict, Japan has embarked on its <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/japan-unveils-record-budget-boost-military-capacity-2022-12-23/">biggest defence build-up since World War Two</a>. But the $290 billion outlay comes without a parallel plan to prepare Yonaguni for a possible humanitarian crisis that residents like Sakihara say could quickly overwhelm their shores.翻译:出于对潜在冲突的担忧，日本开始了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/japan-unveils-record-budget-boost-military-capacity-2022-12-23/">自第二次世界大战以来最大规模的防务建设</a>。但 2900 亿美元的支出并没有相应的计划来为与那国岛应对可能的人道主义危机做好准备，像崎原这样的居民表示，这场危机可能很快就会淹没他们的海岸。</p>      <p>In interviews with Reuters, more than two dozen current and former Japanese officials and residents said hundreds, if not thousands of refugees could try to reach Yonaguni in boats if China attacked Taiwan. Tokyo, they said, has no plan to deal with them, and locals' pleas for help have gone unanswered.翻译:在接受路透社采访时，二十多名现任和前任日本官员和居民表示，如果中国攻击台湾，数百甚至数千名难民可能会试图乘船抵达与那国岛。他们说，东京没有处理这些问题的计划，当地人的求助请求也没有得到回应。</p>   <p>"It's like their mouths are taped shut," said Yonaguni mayor Kenichi Itokazu, referring to the central government. Pinned to a noticeboard at his town hall was a list of typhoons and other crises to have visited the island, including the arrival of the Vietnamese.翻译:与那国市市长糸一健一（Kenichi Itokazu）说：“他们的嘴就像被胶带封住了。”他指的是中央政府。他的市政厅的布告栏上贴着一份台风和其他访问该岛的危机的清单，其中包括越南人的到来。</p>   <p>Itokazu said he had appealed for help directly to Japan's Chief Cabinet Secretary Hirokazu Matsuno when he came to Yonaguni in July, but again got no response.翻译:伊藤一说，他7月来到与那国时曾直接向日本内阁官房长官松野博和求助，但再次没有得到回应。</p>   <p>Some U.S. officials say China may be ready to invade Taiwan by 2027. Chinese leader Xi Jinping told U.S. President Joe Biden last month that no such plan exists, but he is raising pressure on Taiwan ahead of a Jan. 13 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-ruling-party-powers-ahead-with-opposition-mired-bitter-dispute-2023-11-22/">presidential election</a> that Vice President Lai Ching-te, who Beijing views as a separatist, is tipped to win.翻译:一些美国官员表示，中国可能已准备好在 2027 年入侵台湾。中国领导人习近平上个月告诉美国总统乔·拜登，不存在这样的计划，但他在 1 月 13 日<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-ruling-party-powers-ahead-with-opposition-mired-bitter-dispute-2023-11-22/">总统大选</a>之前向台湾施加压力，赖副总统表示北京将其视为分裂分子的正德有望获胜。</p>   <p>Taiwan's foreign ministry declined to address questions about whether it had discussed humanitarian contingencies with Japan, but said Taipei would not act rashly or succumb to Chinese coercion.翻译:台湾外交部拒绝回答有关是否与日本讨论人道主义紧急情况的问题，但表示台北不会轻举妄动或屈服于中国的胁迫。</p>   <p>A spokesperson for Japan's Cabinet Secretariat said that "if large numbers of refugees came to Japan, relevant government departments would work together to respond".翻译:日本内阁官房发言人表示，“如果大量难民涌入日本，政府相关部门将共同应对”。</p>   <p>He declined to comment on whether there was a specific plan for Yonaguni and said he did not know whether the island's mayor had directly asked Matsuno for help.</p>    <h 1="">CRISIS SCENARIO</h>  <p>The people who spoke to Reuters included nine current and six former officials with knowledge of Japan's emergency planning, some of whom spoke on the condition of anonymity because they were not authorised to comment publicly.翻译:接受路透社采访的人士包括了解日本应急计划的九名现任官员和六名前任官员，其中一些人要求匿名，因为他们无权公开发表评论。</p>   <p>They said that while Taiwanese refugees could flee to Japan by sea, the nature of any conflict and the numbers who would come were hard to predict. Japan's government has made no public mention of such a scenario.翻译:他们表示，虽然台湾难民可以通过海路逃往日本，但任何冲突的性质以及前来的人数都很难预测。日本政府没有公开提及这种情况。</p>   <p>"There could be hundreds of boats, too many even for a Chinese blockade to stop," a Japan Coast Guard official said. The Cabinet Secretariat, headed by Prime Minister Fumio Kishida and run by Matsuno, is responsible for devising a plan, he added.翻译:日本海上保安厅的一名官员表示：“可能有数百艘船只，数量太多，即使中国的封锁也无法阻止。”他补充说，由首相岸田文雄领导、松野主持的内阁秘书处负责制定计划。</p>   <p>The current and former officials described a government focused on its military build-up rather than a complex humanitarian response plan encompassing the multiple departments, local authorities and companies that would have to screen, transport, feed and house possibly more refugees than Japan has ever encountered.翻译:现任和前任官员表示，政府专注于军事建设，而不是涵盖多个部门、地方当局和公司的复杂的人道主义应对计划，这些计划必须筛查、运输、喂养和安置可能比日本遇到的更多的难民。</p>   <p>Around 18,000 refugees were in Japan in 2022, mostly from Myanmar, according to the Migration Policy Institute, which cited United Nations figures that apply a broader definition than Japan's government. Amid conflict in Europe and the Middle East, Germany had more than 2 million and Poland almost a million, many from Ukraine.翻译:根据移民政策研究所的数据，2022 年约有 18,000 名难民在日本，其中大部分来自缅甸，该研究所引用的联合国数据比日本政府的定义更广泛。在欧洲和中东的冲突中，德国有超过 200 万人，波兰有近 100 万人，其中许多来自乌克兰。</p>   <p>Tokyo has a political decision to make on whether to accept significant numbers of refugees, said Kevin Maher at NMV Consulting in Washington, who was previously head of Japan affairs at the State Department.翻译:华盛顿 NMV 咨询公司前国务院日本事务负责人凯文·马赫 (Kevin Maher) 表示，东京需要就是否接受大量难民做出政治决定。</p>   <p>"Japan has been reluctant to let in large numbers but, whatever the policy may be, the reality is that just about anything that floats could be headed for Japan," Maher said.</p>    <h 1="">A BIG JOB</h>  <p>General Yoshihide Yoshida, the head of Japan's Self-Defense Forces (SDF), said he witnessed the refugee crisis caused by Russia's attack on Ukraine when he visited Poland last year.翻译:日本自卫队司令吉田芳秀大将表示，去年访问波兰时亲眼目睹了俄罗斯袭击乌克兰引发的难民危机。</p>   <p>"If something similar happened near us we would have to offer the same kind of humanitarian response, but that shouldn't be left to the SDF, it's for the whole of government to consider thoroughly," he said on Tokunoshima, at the eastern end of the island chain that includes Yonaguni, where he was observing <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japanese-troops-drill-island-seen-vulnerable-china-2023-11-19/">beach landing</a> drills by Japanese forces on Nov. 19.翻译:他在东端的德之岛表示：“如果类似的事情发生在我们附近，我们将不得不提供同样的人道主义反应，但这不应该留给自卫队，而应该由整个政府来彻底考虑。” 11 月 19 日，他在包括与那国岛在内的岛链上观察日军的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japanese-troops-drill-island-seen-vulnerable-china-2023-11-19/">海滩登陆</a>演习。</p>   <p>That day, Taiwan <a href="https://jp.reuters.com/article/taiwan-china-defence-idAFKBN32E01X">detected Chinese aircraft over the Taiwan Strait and spotted warships</a> carrying out combat readiness patrols.翻译:当天，台湾<a href="https://jp.reuters.com/article/taiwan-china-defence-idAFKBN32E01X">在台海发现中国飞机，并发现军舰</a>进行战备巡逻。</p>   <p>The roughly 200 SDF troops on Yonaguni could be among the first to respond to any refugee crisis should East Asia, as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/peace-stability-taiwan-strait-is-critical-japanese-pm-2022-05-05/">Kishida warned last year</a>, become the next Ukraine.翻译:正如<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/peace-stability-taiwan-strait-is-critical-japanese-pm-2022-05-05/">岸田去年警告的</a>那样，一旦东亚成为下一个乌克兰，驻扎在与那国岛的大约 200 名自卫队士兵可能会成为第一批应对难民危机的部队之一。</p>   <p>But in more than 100 pages of documents outlining Kishida's military build-up, refugees are mentioned only once, in a general reference to working with the U.N.翻译:但在 100 多页概述岸田军事建设的文件中，难民只被提及一次，泛指与联合国的合作</p>   <p>Tokyo will hesitate to implement specific humanitarian plans on Yonaguni because it could lead China into believing Japan is preparing for a Taiwan conflict, said a U.S. official with knowledge of Japanese thinking, speaking on the condition of anonymity because he was not authorised to comment publicly.翻译:一位了解日本想法的美国官员表示，东京将犹豫是否在与那国岛实施具体的人道主义计划，因为这可能会让中国认为日本正在为台湾冲突做准备。该官员要求匿名，因为他无权公开发表评论。</p>   <p>Even if he had a refugee plan, Kishida would still face an obstacle: his contentious relationship with the Okinawa government that administers Yonaguni.翻译:即使有难民计划，岸田仍然面临一个障碍：他与管理与那国岛的冲绳政府之间存在争议的关系。</p>   <p>The governor, Denny Tamaki, wants fewer U.S. troops based in his prefecture, opposes Kishida's military expansion and says it is the prime minister's job to manage migrants arriving by boat.翻译:知事丹尼·玉木希望减少驻扎在该县的美军，反对岸田的军事扩张，并表示管理乘船抵达的移民是首相的职责。</p>   <p>"Even if it's left to local government, the authority and financial resources for this have not yet been clearly defined," he said in an interview. Resentment with Tokyo lingers in Okinawa over the deaths of one in four islanders in World War Two and the substantial military presence that has been there since.翻译:“即使交给地方政府，这方面的权限和财政资源也尚未明确，”他在接受采访时表示。冲绳岛民因二战期间四分之一的岛民死亡以及此后在冲绳岛驻扎的大量军事力量而对东京心存不满。</p>   <p>In March, Okinawa and Tokyo officials conducted their first tabletop drill to simulate the evacuation of around 120,000 residents and tourists on Japan's southwestern islands, including Yonaguni, calculating the operation would take about a week.翻译:今年3月，冲绳和东京官员进行了首次桌面演习，模拟疏散包括与那国岛在内的日本西南部岛屿上约12万名居民和游客，计算行动大约需要一周时间。</p>   <p>"There is no guarantee people won't come from Taiwan and it would overwhelm the system," said one of the drill's advisers, Hironobu Nakabayashi from Kokushikan University's Research Institute of Disaster Management and Emergency Medical System.</p>    <h 1="">NOT ENOUGH TO SHARE</h>  <p>Back in Yonaguni, resident Satoshi Nagahama, 33, was surprised to learn the government had no humanitarian plan for refugees.翻译:回到与那国岛，33 岁的居民 Satoshi Nagahama 惊讶地发现政府没有针对难民的人道主义计划。</p>   <p>"I don't think we could handle any. The government would have to take them elsewhere," he said at the island's closest port to Taiwan, where he was hauling blue marlin from fishing boats and packing them in ice.翻译:“我认为我们无法处理任何东西。政府必须将它们带到其他地方，”他在岛上距离台湾最近的港口说，在那里他从渔船上拖出蓝马林鱼并将其包装在冰中。</p>   <p>Even the community centre that temporarily housed the Vietnamese refugees Sakihara found has been closed for a decade, its crumbling concrete walls draped in green netting.翻译:就连咲原发现的越南难民临时收容所的社区中心也已关闭十年，其摇摇欲坠的混凝土墙覆盖着绿色的网。</p>   <p>Without government help, some residents say it would fall to the island's two police officers or town hall officials including Koji Sugama, a 65-year-old former soldier, to handle any refugee crisis.翻译:一些居民表示，如果没有政府的帮助，处理难民危机的责任将落在岛上的两名警察或市政厅官员身上，其中包括 65 岁的退伍军人菅间浩二 (Koji Sugama)。</p>   <p>Since he was hired in April to improve disaster management, one of Sugama's tasks has been procuring emergency supplies for residents, including bottled water and ready meals packed into three heavy steel containers dotted around the island.翻译:自从四月受聘改善灾害管理以来，Sugama 的任务之一就是为居民采购应急物资，包括瓶装水和即食食品，装在分布在岛上的三个重型钢制集装箱中。</p>   <p>"This will do for one, maybe two days," he said, standing inside one of them. "There isn't enough to share."翻译:“这可以持续一到两天，”他站在其中一间里面说道。 “没有足够的东西可以分享。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Tim Kelly, Kaori Kaneko and Yukiko Toyoda; additional reporting by Ben Blanchard in Taipei and Kentaro Sugiyama in Tokyo; editing by David Crawshaw翻译:蒂姆·凯利、金子香织和丰田由纪子报道； Ben Blanchard 在台北和 Kentaro Sugiyama 在东京的补充报道；大卫·克劳肖编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 01:14:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CIZJ6B64JNINXGZDF7VUKSVBIQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japans-frontier-islanders-decry-lack-plan-aid-taiwanese-fleeing-attack-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Tim Kelly, Kaori Kaneko, Yukiko Toyoda]]></author>
            
                
                <category>JAPAN</category>
                
                <category>DEFENCE/YONAGUNI (INSIGHT, TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[外交部长表示中国希望在峰会上深化欧盟关系]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/CZZUGATUAySU1xofM9RA-_RWBXo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PUVXUNG5SBNLVJ4R5IW2RLWVKU.jpg" alt="10th trilateral foreign ministers' meeting in Busan翻译:第十次中日韩外长会议在釜山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>File Photo: Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi speaks during the 10th trilateral foreign ministers' meeting in Busan翻译:第十次中日韩外长会议在釜山举行, South Korea, Sunday, Nov. 26, 2023. Ahn Young-joon/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:资料照片：2023 年 11 月 26 日星期日，中国外交部长王毅在韩国釜山举行的第十次中日韩外长会议上发表讲话。Ahn Young-joon/Pool via REUTERS/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China hopes to boost relations with the European Union at an upcoming summit, with a firm focus on pragmatic cooperation in the face of complex situations and severe challenges, its foreign minister Wang Yi said.翻译:中国外交部长王毅表示，中方希望在即将举行的峰会上加强同欧盟的关系，面对复杂形势和严峻挑战，坚定不移开展务实合作。</p>   <p>In a meeting on Monday with EU diplomatic envoys to China in Beijing, Wang said the two sides should view bilateral relations from a strategic perspective and added that China's policy toward Europe remains stable, according to Xinhua news agency.翻译:据新华社报道，王毅周一在北京会见欧盟驻华使节时表示，双方应从战略高度看待双边关系，并补充说中国对欧洲政策保持稳定。</p>   <p>"China and the EU have not completely the same point of view on international and regional issues, and only by adhering to communication and coordination can we play a constructive role in maintaining world peace and stability and addressing global challenges," Wang said, according to the Xinhua report.翻译:王毅表示，中欧在国际和地区问题上看法并不完全一致，只有坚持沟通协调，才能为维护世界和平稳定、应对全球性挑战发挥建设性作用。新华社报道。</p>   <p>The remarks came ahead of a highly-anticipated <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-says-summit-with-eu-leaders-discuss-global-economic-issues-2023-12-04/">summit on Thursday</a> between Chinese President Xi Jinping and President of the European Council Charles Michel and President of the European Commission Ursula von der Leyen.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-says-summit-with-eu-leaders-discuss-global-economic-issues-2023-12-04/">周四，中国国家主席习近平与欧洲理事会主席查尔斯·米歇尔和欧盟委员会主席乌苏拉·冯德莱恩将举行备受期待的峰会</a>。</p>   <p>The two sides are trying to mend frayed relations on several trade issues, such as an EU anti-subsidy <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-rebukes-eus-rushed-request-consultations-over-ev-subsidy-probe-2023-10-04/">investigation</a> on electric vehicles and a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/eu-plans-anti-subsidy-probe-into-chinese-steelmakers-ft-2023-10-10/">looming probe</a> on Chinese steelmakers.翻译:双方正试图修复在多个贸易问题上的紧张关系，例如欧盟对电动汽车的反补贴<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-rebukes-eus-rushed-request-consultations-over-ev-subsidy-probe-2023-10-04/">调查</a>以及<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/eu-plans-anti-subsidy-probe-into-chinese-steelmakers-ft-2023-10-10/">即将对中国钢铁制造商进行的调查</a>。</p>   <p>The head of the EU delegation to China and the envoys of EU member states to China said the EU is committed to developing constructive and stable EU-China relations, and is willing to maintain mutual respect and dialogue with China, according to the report.翻译:欧盟驻华代表团团长和欧盟成员国驻华使节表示，欧盟致力于发展建设性、稳定的欧中关系，愿同中方保持相互尊重和对话。</p>   <p>The envoys said the EU has no intention of decoupling from China and hopes to establish "mutually beneficial and balanced economic and trade relations with China", according to Xinhua.翻译:据新华社报道，特使们表示，欧盟无意与中国脱钩，希望与中国建立“互利、平衡的经贸关系”。</p>   <p>In the meeting on Monday, the two sides also exchanged views on the Ukraine crisis and Palestinian-Israeli conflict, according to the report, without elaborating.翻译:报道称，在周一的会晤中，双方还就乌克兰危机和巴以冲突交换了意见，但没有详细说明。</p>    <span>Reporting by Bernard Orr and Shanghai newsroom; Editing by Sonali Paul翻译:伯纳德·奥尔和上海新闻编辑室的报道；索纳利·保罗编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:59:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F7X4QSWTBVN3FLDQJADKXT6PSA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-looks-deepen-eu-ties-summit-foreign-minister-says-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>EU/SUMMIT</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[房屋供应短缺推动全球房价上涨步伐放缓]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li></li>  <li>Reuters poll graphic on average home price change outlook:</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li></li><li>路透社平均房价变化前景的民意调查图表：</li></ul>     <p>Global property prices in most major markets will rise over the next two years, albeit at a slightly slower pace than predicted three months ago as strong demand and tight supply overshadow higher interest rates, a Reuters poll found.翻译:路透调查发现，大多数主要市场的全球房地产价格将在未来两年内上涨，尽管增速略慢于三个月前的预测，因为强劲的需求和紧张的供应掩盖了利率上升的影响。</p>   <p>Home prices across the developed world have defied analysts' expectations, as they predicted at the start of the year prices would register double-digit falls from COVID-19-era peaks. In most markets they will end the year on a positive note.翻译:发达国家的房价超出了分析师的预期，因为他们在今年年初预测价格将比 COVID-19 时代的峰值出现两位数的下跌。在大多数市场，他们将以积极的态度结束今年。</p>   <p>While price rises are expected to continue into next year and 2025, higher mortgage rates and the lack of supply of affordable homes will restrict prices from rising too much.翻译:虽然价格上涨预计将持续到明年和 2025 年，但较高的抵押贷款利率和经济适用房供应不足将限制价格过度上涨。</p>   <p>The latest Reuters polls of over 100 housing market strategists taken between Nov. 15 and Dec. 4 showed property prices rising in five of the eight major property markets surveyed for next year and in all of them in 2025.翻译:路透社在 11 月 15 日至 12 月 4 日期间对 100 多名房地产市场策略师进行的最新民意调查显示，明年接受调查的八个主要房地产市场中，有五个市场的房价都会上涨，到 2025 年所有市场的房价都会上涨。</p>   <p>"Values are underpinned at the moment by the fact there's low stock availability and that is defending prices. The fact prices haven't fallen very much and actually in many markets are beginning to rise again is down to the fact the stock is very low," said Liam Bailey, head of research at Knight Frank.翻译:“目前的价值是由库存量低这一事实支撑的，这正在捍卫价格。事实上，价格没有下跌太多，而且实际上在许多市场上又开始上涨，这是因为库存非常低，莱坊研究主管利亚姆·贝利 (Liam Bailey) 说道。</p>   <p>"Very few vendors are bringing their properties forward into the market at the moment because they're either trying to protect their current debt costs by not moving properties and not porting their mortgages," he said.翻译:他说：“目前很少有卖家将他们的房产推向市场，因为他们要么试图通过不转移房产或不转移抵押贷款来保护当前的债务成本。”</p>   <p>Of the major housing markets polled - U.S., Britain, Canada, Australia, New Zealand, Germany and Dubai - prices were forecast to go up between 1.3% to 5% in 2025, while estimates for India were set to surpass 7%.翻译:在接受调查的主要房地产市场（美国、英国、加拿大、澳大利亚、新西兰、德国和迪拜）中，预计 2025 年价格将上涨 1.3% 至 5%，而印度的涨幅预计将超过 7%。</p>   <p>That outlook was still good news for property owners who at the beginning of the year were anticipating a significant dip in value of their homes over expectations the global economy will enter a recession this year.翻译:对于业主来说，这一前景仍然是个好消息，他们在今年年初预计自己的房屋价值将大幅下跌，因为他们预期全球经济今年将陷入衰退。</p>   <p>But that would also mean affordability will remain a concern, especially for first-time buyers who for years have been waiting on the sidelines to get on the property ladder.翻译:但这也意味着负担能力仍将是一个令人担忧的问题，特别是对于多年来一直在观望的首次购房者来说。</p>   <p>Still, a strong 71% majority, 65 of 91 housing strategists, who answered an additional question said purchasing affordability for first-time homebuyers will improve over the coming year.翻译:尽管如此，在回答了另一个问题的 91 名住房策略师中，有 65 名（71%）的受访者表示，首次购房者的购买能力将在未来一年得到改善。</p>   <p>While many analysts, 51 of 84, who answered a separate question said the supply of affordable homes will improve over the coming two to three years, only 10 among them expected it to improve to a point where it can sufficiently address the demand.翻译:尽管回答单独问题的 84 名分析师中有 51 名表示，经济适用房的供应将在未来两到三年内有所改善，但其中只有 10 名分析师预计会改善到足以满足需求的程度。</p>   <p>"If you look at construction cost plus land costs, it's difficult to deliver affordable housing viably. I think lack of housing is probably likely to be a feature of most developed markets...for the medium-term (5 years)," added Knight Frank's Bailey.翻译:“如果考虑建筑成本加上土地成本，就很难提供经济适用房。我认为缺乏住房可能是大多数发达市场的一个特点......在中期（5年），”补充道莱坊的贝利。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-existing-home-sales-stay-subdued-next-year-along-with-prices-2023-11-30/">Average</a> U.S. home prices were seen rising 2.7% this year and 1.8% in 2024. That was higher than a September survey where prices were forecast to flat line in both years.翻译:美国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-existing-home-sales-stay-subdued-next-year-along-with-prices-2023-11-30/">平均</a>房价预计今年将上涨 2.7%，2024 年将上涨 1.8%。这一数字高于 9 月份的调查，当时预测这两年房价将持平。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rba-hold-rates-dec-5-aussie-home-prices-rise-5-2024-2023-12-01/">Australian</a> home prices, which have recovered all of their 2022 losses since finding a floor in January, were expected to rise 8.0% this year and another 5.0% next year.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rba-hold-rates-dec-5-aussie-home-prices-rise-5-2024-2023-12-01/">澳大利亚</a>房价自 1 月份触底以来已收复 2022 年的全部跌幅，预计今年将上涨 8.0%，明年将再上涨 5.0%。</p>   <p>New Zealand property prices were forecast to rise 4.0% next year and 5.0% in 2025 compared with expected rises of 5.0% and 6.0% in an August poll.翻译:新西兰房地产价格预计明年将上涨 4.0%，2025 年将上涨 5.0%，而 8 月份调查的预期涨幅为 5.0% 和 6.0%。</p>   <p>While home prices in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/german-home-prices-plunge-further-no-respite-surging-rents-2023-11-24/">Germany</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/british-home-prices-dip-again-2024-no-crash-expected-2023-11-29/">Britain</a> were predicted to fall 2.8% and 2.0% respectively next year, in both markets they were forecast to rise around 2-3% in 2025.翻译:虽然<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/german-home-prices-plunge-further-no-respite-surging-rents-2023-11-24/">德国</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/british-home-prices-dip-again-2024-no-crash-expected-2023-11-29/">英国的</a>房价明年预计将分别下跌 2.8% 和 2.0%，但到 2025 年这两个市场的房价预计将上涨 2-3% 左右。</p>   <p>The once red-hot <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/boc-cut-rates-starting-q2-2024-house-prices-seen-flat-2024-2023-11-30/">Canadian</a> housing market, where prices surged about 50% during the coronavirus pandemic, is expected to stagnate in 2024 and then rise 3.3% in 2025.翻译:曾经炙手可热的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/boc-cut-rates-starting-q2-2024-house-prices-seen-flat-2024-2023-11-30/">加拿大</a>房地产市场在新冠病毒大流行期间价格飙升了约 50%，预计 2024 年将陷入停滞，然后在 2025 年上涨 3.3%。</p>   <p>Buoyed by demand from <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/india/india-home-prices-outstrip-inflation-driven-by-high-end-market-2023-11-30/">high earners</a>, home prices in India will beat consumer inflation to rise 6.8% this year and next.翻译:在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/india/india-home-prices-outstrip-inflation-driven-by-high-end-market-2023-11-30/">高收入者</a>需求的推动下，印度房价今明两年将超过消费者通胀，上涨 6.8%。</p>   <p>(Other stories from the Reuters quarterly housing market polls)翻译:（路透社季度房地产市场民意调查的其他故事）</p>    <span>Reporting by Hari Kishan and Sarupya Ganguly; other reporting and polling by Anitta Sunil, Maneesh Kumar, Prerana Bhat, Jonathan Cable, Anant Chandak, Sarupya Ganguly, Milounee Purohit, Susobhan Sarkar, Devayani Sathyan and Vijayalakshmi Srinivasan; Editing by Aurora Ellis翻译:Hari Kishan 和 Sarupya Ganguly 报道； Anitta Sunil、Maneesh Kumar、Prera​​na Bhat、Jonathan Cable、Anant Chandak、Sarupya Ganguly、Milounee Purohit、Susobhan Sarkar、Devayani Sathyan 和 Vijayalakshmi Srinivasan 的其他报道和民意调查；奥罗拉·埃利斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:09:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">U6L6CNHIQVODRELHOWC4JEBB7Y</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/short-supply-homes-push-global-property-prices-higher-slower-pace-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Hari Kishan]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/POLL (POLL, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早盘竞价：随着市场波动，澳洲联储成为焦点]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/uxTjTHJ0oqIJQijlmrQ0Nupgzuc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JCLUN7HNCBPBJIOOCAAJVWLOMY.jpg" alt="A worker is reflected in a wall of the Reserve Bank of Australia head office in central Sydney, Australia翻译:澳大利亚悉尼市中心澳大利亚储备银行总部的墙上映出一名工人的倒影" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A worker is reflected in a wall of the Reserve Bank of Australia (RBA) head office in central Sydney, Australia, March 1, 2016.   REUTERS/David Gray/File Photo翻译:2016 年 3 月 1 日，澳大利亚悉尼市中心澳大利亚储备银行 (RBA) 总部的墙上映出一名工人的倒影。路透社/David Gray/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A look at the day ahead in Asian markets.翻译:展望未来一天的亚洲市场。</p>   <p>An interest rate <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rba-hold-rates-dec-5-aussie-home-prices-rise-5-2024-2023-12-01/">decision from Australia</a> and key inflation <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/tokyo-core-cpi-growth-seen-slowing-25-november-2023-12-01/">readings from Japan</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/bank-korea-extends-rate-pause-lifts-inflation-forecasts-2023-11-30/">South Korea</a> are the big market events for the Asia Pacific region on Tuesday, with investor sentiment cooled by Monday's selloff across <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-dip-focus-shifts-economic-data-policy-cues-2023-12-04/">U.S. stocks</a> and <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/treasuries-ten-year-yields-rise-from-three-month-lows-jobs-data-in-focus#:~:text=Dec%204%20(Reuters)%20-%20Benchmark,from%20Fed%20officials%20last%20week" target="_blank">bonds</a>.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rba-hold-rates-dec-5-aussie-home-prices-rise-5-2024-2023-12-01/">澳大利亚的利率决定</a>以及<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/tokyo-core-cpi-growth-seen-slowing-25-november-2023-12-01/">日本</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/bank-korea-extends-rate-pause-lifts-inflation-forecasts-2023-11-30/">韩国</a>的关键通胀数据是周二亚太地区的重大市场事件，投资者情绪因周一<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-dip-focus-shifts-economic-data-policy-cues-2023-12-04/">美国股票</a>和<a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/treasuries-ten-year-yields-rise-from-three-month-lows-jobs-data-in-focus#:~:text=Dec%204%20(Reuters)%20-%20Benchmark,from%20Fed%20officials%20last%20week" target="_blank">债券</a>的抛售而降温。</p>   <p>Currencies will probably be most sensitive to the data and the Reserve Bank of Australia's guidance, while stocks could struggle to make much headway given the broad-based weakness across global equities on Monday.翻译:货币可能对数据和澳大利亚储备银行的指引最为敏感，而鉴于周一全球股市普遍疲软，股市可能难以取得太大进展。</p>   <p>The relative weakness of Asian equities since the pandemic, magnified by China's even more <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/global-economy-asia-factory-activity-weakens-uncertainty-china-clouds-outlook-2023-12-01/">notable underperformance</a>, has been quite something. But international investors appear to be in no rush to get back in en masse.翻译:自疫情大流行以来，亚洲股市的相对疲软，加上中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/global-economy-asia-factory-activity-weakens-uncertainty-china-clouds-outlook-2023-12-01/">更显着的表现不佳</a>，更是雪上加霜。但国际投资者似乎并不急于集体回归。</p>   <p>The RBA, meanwhile, is expected to keep its cash rate on hold at a 12-year high of 4.35%, according to 28 of 30 analysts polled by Reuters. The other two are going for a 25 basis point hike.翻译:与此同时，据路透社调查的 30 名分析师中的 28 名表示，预计澳大利亚央行将把现金利率维持在 12 年高点 4.35%。另外两个计划加息 25 个基点。</p>   <p>Assuming the RBA does stand pat, Governor Michele Bowman's guidance will carry even greater weight. She has generally been more hawkish than her predecessor Philip Lowe, whom she replaced in September.翻译:假设澳洲联储确实坚持不变，行长米歇尔·鲍曼的指导将具有更大的影响力。总的来说，她比她于九月接任的前任菲利普·洛(Philip Lowe)更加鹰派。</p>   <p>The Aussie dollar spiked to a fresh four-month high of $0.6690 on Monday before closing the day lower.翻译:澳元兑美元周一飙升至四个月新高 0.6690 美元，随后收盘走低。</p>   <p>The Japanese yen, meanwhile, will be sensitive to the latest <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/japans-price-trend-gauge-hits-record-heightens-case-boj-exit-2023-11-28/">Tokyo inflation figures</a>. Core consumer inflation in Japan's capital likely grew in November but at slower pace than the month before, in a sign that price pressures may be easing.翻译:与此同时，日元将对最新的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/japans-price-trend-gauge-hits-record-heightens-case-boj-exit-2023-11-28/">东京通胀数据</a>敏感。日本首都的核心消费者通胀 11 月份可能有所增长，但增速较上月放缓，这表明物价压力可能正在缓解。</p>   <p>The annual rate of inflation is expected to have eased to 2.4% from 2.7% - breathing room for the Bank of Japan, and maybe more selling pressure on the yen.翻译:年通胀率预计将从 2.7% 降至 2.4%，这为日本央行提供了喘息的空间，也可能给日元带来更大的抛售压力。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/dollar-shaky-ground-fed-rate-cut-bets-strengthen-2023-12-04/">U.S. dollar rose 0.5%</a> on Monday against a basket of major currencies, supported by a rebound in U.S. bond yields as traders took some profits on last week's sharp rally in fixed income, especially at the short end of the curve.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/dollar-shaky-ground-fed-rate-cut-bets-strengthen-2023-12-04/">美元兑一篮子主要货币周一上涨0.5%</a> ，受到美国债券收益率反弹的支撑，交易者从上周固定收益大幅上涨中获利了结，尤其是在曲线的短端。</p>   <p>The slump in bond yields last month weighed heavily on the dollar, which appears to have forced the hand of hedge funds and speculators - their long dollar position worth $10 billion only a couple of weeks ago has been almost fully unwound.翻译:上个月债券收益率的暴跌严重打压了美元，这似乎迫使对冲基金和投机者出手——仅在几周前，他们价值100亿美元的美元多头头寸几乎已全部平仓。</p>   <p>If speculators go short dollars from here, Asian currencies could benefit. The relative U.S. interest rate outlook right now fits the weaker dollar narrative - futures markets have the Fed cutting rates next year more than any major or emerging market central bank.翻译:如果投机者从这里做空美元，亚洲货币可能会受益。目前美国的相对利率前景符合美元疲软的说法——期货市场显示，美联储明年降息的幅度超过任何主要或新兴市场央行。</p>   <p>But will the Fed cut rates by 125 to 150 basis points next year? Maybe, but it does sound quite aggressive. And even if the Fed does go that far, other central banks are sure to lower their policy rates more than markets are currently predicting.翻译:但美联储明年会降息125至150个基点吗？也许吧，但这听起来确实很有侵略性。即使美联储确实做到了这一点，其他央行也肯定会比市场目前预测的幅度降低政策利率。</p>   <p>Here are key developments that could provide more direction to markets on Tuesday:翻译:以下是可能为周二市场提供更多方向的关键进展：</p>   <p>- Australia interest rate decision翻译:- 澳大利亚利率决定</p>   <p>- Japan - Tokyo inflation (November)翻译:- 日本 - 东京通货膨胀（十一月）</p>   <p>- South Korea inflation (November)翻译:- 韩国通胀（11 月）</p>    <span>By Jamie McGeever
Editing by Josie Kao翻译:作者：Jamie McGeever 编辑：Josie Kao</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 23:24:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">NX5OCMNPFRLAZL25MVTE37NIMQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/global-markets-view-asia-pix-2023-12-04/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jamie McGeever]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>ASIA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[洞察：西方初创企业寻求打破中国对稀土精炼的控制]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/nMH5I-0r-pqMG8Pc72GXOES5F1g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/INP6IYETJVOMTHSNHFM6P5TAFY.jpg" alt="Canada's Prime Minister Justin Trudeau visits rare earths producer Vital Metals in Saskatoon翻译:加拿大总理贾斯汀·特鲁多访问位于萨斯卡通的稀土生产商 Vital Metals" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Raw Rare Earth ore waiting to be processed at Vital Metals in Saskatoon, Saskatchewan, Canada January 16, 2023.  REUTERS/Nayan Sthankiya/File Photo翻译:2023 年 1 月 16 日，加拿大萨斯喀彻温省萨斯卡通的 Vital Metals 等待加工的稀土矿石原料。REUTERS/Nayan Sthankiya/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/c7LTuxMjeIaAZvFSogVNtXzFTqE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FJ36277VLFNSRIIB4AM2BFIQGU.jpg" alt="A view of the MP Materials rare earth open-pit mine in Mountain Pass翻译:MP Materials 芒廷帕斯稀土露天矿一景" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view of the MP Materials rare earth open-pit mine in Mountain Pass翻译:MP Materials 芒廷帕斯稀土露天矿一景, California, U.S. January 30, 2020. Picture taken January 30, 2020. REUTERS/Steve Marcus</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tomg8Quaiq_Gd-f63oOMe_F6hI8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XZU4J7D2UVNKNDTVSVMZMUF4QI.jpg" alt="A shipping area is filled with 1,500 kg bags of bastnasite concentrate at the MP Materials rare earth mine in Mountain Pass翻译:帕斯山 MP Materials 稀土矿的装运区装满了 1,500 公斤袋的氟碳铈矿精矿" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A shipping area is filled with 1,500 kg bags of bastnasite concentrate at the MP Materials rare earth mine in Mountain Pass翻译:帕斯山 MP Materials 稀土矿的装运区装满了 1,500 公斤袋的氟碳铈矿精矿, California, U.S. January 30, 2020. Picture taken January 30, 2020. REUTERS/Steve Marcus翻译:2020 年 1 月 30 日，美国加利福尼亚州帕斯山 MP Materials 稀土矿的装运区装满了 1,500 公斤袋的氟碳铈矿精矿。照片拍摄于 2020 年 1 月 30 日。路透社/Steve Marcus</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/oX9h9LeiBT93aVuKo8FI2JRuzjc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BJLKFQDINVKXVGH66NQGUEJNAA.jpg" alt="A wheel loader operator fills a truck with ore at the MP Materials rare earth mine in Mountain Pass翻译:一名轮式装载机操作员在帕斯山 MP Materials 稀土矿向卡车装满矿石" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A wheel loader operator fills a truck with ore at the MP Materials rare earth mine in Mountain Pass翻译:一名轮式装载机操作员在帕斯山 MP Materials 稀土矿向卡车装满矿石, California, U.S. January 30, 2020. Picture taken January 30, 2020. REUTERS/Steve Marcus</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/5L6qi0QRv1n9W3jBhRjinfq1xPo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NBIN5I6VSVNP3P4Q6NI7VZ3A6U.jpg" alt="UCore executives pose with blueprints for new rare earth processing equipment in Alexandria翻译:UCore 高管与亚历山大的新型稀土加工设备蓝图合影" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>UCore Chief Operating Officer Michael Schrider and Vice President of Business Development Geoff Atkins pose with blueprints for new rare earth processing equipment that they plan to install at a former U.S. Air Force base in Alexandria, Louisiana, U.S. October 17, 2023. REUTERS/Ernest Scheyder翻译:UCore 首席运营官 Michael Schrider 和业务开发副总裁 Geoff Atkins 展示了新稀土加工设备的蓝图，他们计划于 2023 年 10 月 17 日在美国路易斯安那州亚历山大的前美国空军基地安装这些设备。 REUTERS/Ernest Scheyder</figcaption></figure>                     <p>Start-up tech firms are racing to transform the way rare earths are refined for the clean energy transition, a push aimed at turbocharging the West's expansion into the niche sector that underpins billions of electronic devices.翻译:初创科技公司正在竞相改变稀土提炼方式，以实现清洁能源转型，此举旨在加速西方向支撑数十亿电子设备的利基行业的扩张。</p>   <p>The existing standard to refine these strategic minerals, known as solvent extraction, is an expensive and dirty process that China has spent the past 30 years mastering. MP Materials <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MP.N" target="_blank">(MP.N)</a>, Lynas Rare Earths <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LYC.AX" target="_blank">(LYC.AX)</a> and other Western rare earths companies have struggled at times to deploy it due to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/world-battles-loosen-chinas-grip-vital-rare-earths-clean-energy-transition-2023-08-02/">technical complexities and pollution concerns</a>.翻译:提炼这些战略矿物的现有标准，即溶剂萃取，是一个昂贵且肮脏的过程，中国在过去 30 年里一直在掌握。由于<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/world-battles-loosen-chinas-grip-vital-rare-earths-clean-energy-transition-2023-08-02/">技术复杂性和污染问题，</a> MP Materials <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MP.N" target="_blank">(MP.N)</a> 、莱纳斯稀土公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LYC.AX" target="_blank">(LYC.AX)</a>和其他西方稀土公司有时很难部署它。</p>   <p>Rare earths are a group of 17 metals used to make magnets that turn power into motion for electric vehicles, cell phones and other electronics. While U.S. scientists helped develop solvent extraction for rare earths in the 1950s, radioactive waste from the process gradually made it unpopular in the United States.翻译:稀土是一组 17 种金属，用于制造磁铁，将电力转化为电动汽车、手机和其他电子产品的运动。虽然美国科学家在 20 世纪 50 年代帮助开发了稀土溶剂萃取法，但该过程中产生的放射性废物逐渐使其在美国不再受欢迎。</p>   <p>China began to rapidly expand in the industry starting during the 1980s and now controls 87% of global rare earths refining capacity, according to the International Energy Agency. That prowess has helped propel the country's economy to the second-largest in the world.翻译:据国际能源署称，中国从 20 世纪 80 年代开始在该行业迅速扩张，目前控制着全球 87% 的稀土精炼能力。这种实力帮助该国经济跃升为世界第二大经济体。</p>   <p>Emerging Western rivals now offer the tantalizing prospect of processing the minerals in faster, cleaner and cheaper ways, if they can successfully launch.翻译:如果新兴的西方竞争对手能够成功推出的话，他们现在将提供以更快、更清洁和更便宜的方式加工矿物的诱人前景。</p>   <p>"The existing rare earths refining process is a nightmare," said Isabel Barton, a mining and geological engineering professor at the University of Arizona. "That's why there are so many companies promising new methods, because we need new ones."翻译:“现有的稀土精炼工艺是一场噩梦，”亚利桑那大学采矿和地质工程教授伊莎贝尔·巴顿说。 “这就是为什么有这么多公司承诺新方法，因为我们需要新方法。”</p>   <p>Interviews with nearly two dozen industry consultants, academics and executives show that if one or more of these novel processing technologies succeed as hoped by 2025, they could slash reliance on Chinese rare earths technology and its toxic by-products while also bolstering plans by Western firms to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/western-miners-seek-premium-pricing-rare-earth-metals-break-china-grip-2023-11-08/">charge premium prices</a> for the strategic minerals.翻译:对近二十位行业顾问、学者和高管的采访表明，如果这些新颖的加工技术中的一种或多种在 2025 年之前取得成功，它们可以减少对中国稀土技术及其有毒副产品的依赖，同时也支持西方公司的计划对战略矿产<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/western-miners-seek-premium-pricing-rare-earth-metals-break-china-grip-2023-11-08/">收取溢价</a>。</p>   <p>While none have launched commercially - and some industry consultants and analysts question whether they will be able to do so soon - a cadre of firms are pushing forward with aggressive development plans.翻译:虽然还没有一家公司推出商业化——而且一些行业顾问和分析师质疑他们是否能够很快这样做——但一批公司正在推进积极的开发计划。</p>   <p>On a former U.S. Air Force base in Louisiana, Ucore Rare Metals <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/UCU.V" target="_blank">(UCU.V)</a> aims to process rare earths by mid-2025 using a technology known as RapidSX that it says is at least three times faster than solvent extraction, produces no hazardous chemical waste and requires only a third of the physical space.翻译:在路易斯安那州的前美国空军基地，Ucore Rare Metals <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/UCU.V" target="_blank">(UCU.V)</a>的目标是到 2025 年中期使用名为 RapidSX 的技术加工稀土，据称该技术比溶剂萃取速度至少快三倍，且不产生危险化学品浪费，只需要三分之一的物理空间。</p>   <p>"Our goal is to re-establish a North American rare earths supply chain," Michael Schrider, Ucore's chief operating officer, said during a visit to the site.翻译:Ucore 首席运营官 Michael Schrider 在参观该工厂时表示：“我们的目标是重建北美稀土供应链。”</p>   <p>Formed in 2006, Ucore initially planned to mine a rare earths deposit in Alaska. But the company changed tack in 2022 to focus on refining, not mining, a pivot born from what two executives said they saw as a flaw in the West's strategy to weaken China's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/world-battles-loosen-chinas-grip-vital-rare-earths-clean-energy-transition-2023-08-02/">minerals dominance</a> by trying to master both steps simultaneously.翻译:Ucore 成立于 2006 年，最初计划开采阿拉斯加的稀土矿床。但该公司在 2022 年改变了策略，将重点放在炼油上，而不是采矿上，这一重心源于两位高管表示，他们认为西方试图同时掌握这两个步骤来削弱中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/world-battles-loosen-chinas-grip-vital-rare-earths-clean-energy-transition-2023-08-02/">矿产主导地位</a>的战略存在缺陷。</p>   <p>Ucore, which has been testing its process with Pentagon funding, is in talks now with 17 mining companies to buy lightly processed supplies of rare earths known as concentrate, ship them to the Port of New Orleans, then truck them to a 80,800-square foot warehouse that will be outfitted with the RapidSX technology beginning in January.翻译:Ucore 一直在五角大楼的资助下测试其工艺，目前正在与 17 家矿业公司进行谈判，购买轻加工的稀土（称为精矿）供应，将其运至新奥尔良港，然后用卡车运至 80,800 平方英尺的工厂。该仓库将从一月份开始配备 RapidSX 技术。</p>   <p>Rare earths miners increasingly say they are content to focus on digging up rock - rather than compounding their operations with the added step of processing.翻译:越来越多的稀土矿商表示，他们满足于专注于开采岩石，而不是将其业务与额外的加工步骤相结合。</p>   <p>"Mining companies should focus on finding new deposits," said Luisa Moreno, president of Defense Metals <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DEFN.V" target="_blank">(DEFN.V)</a>, which aims to open a rare earths mine in British Columbia within four years and is interested in licensing Ucore's technology. "You probably should let refining be handled by others that specialize in that."翻译:国防金属公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DEFN.V" target="_blank">(DEFN.V)</a>总裁路易莎·莫雷诺 (Luisa Moreno) 表示：“矿业公司应专注于寻找新矿床。”该公司的目标是四年内在不列颠哥伦比亚省开设一座稀土矿，并有兴趣获得 Ucore 技术的许可。 “你可能应该让其他专门从事精炼工作的人来处理。”</p>   <p>Rainbow Rare Earths <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RBWR.L" target="_blank">(RBWR.L)</a> plans by 2026 to deploy rare earths refining technology in South Africa developed by its Florida-based partner K-Technologies that uses a process known as continuous ion exchange, used by some lithium producers.翻译:Rainbow Rare Earths <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RBWR.L" target="_blank">(RBWR.L)</a>计划到 2026 年在南非部署由其位于佛罗里达州的合作伙伴 K-Technologies 开发的稀土精炼技术，该技术采用了一些锂生产商使用的称为连续离子交换的工艺。</p>   <p>Startup Aether is developing nanotechnology that programs proteins to selectively bind with and extract rare earths from ore deposits.翻译:初创公司 Aether 正在开发纳米技术，对蛋白质进行编程，使其选择性地与矿床结合并提取稀土。</p>   <p>In Norway, privately-held REETec says its proprietary refining process emits 90% less carbon dioxide than solvent extraction and should be operational by late 2024.翻译:在挪威，私营 REETec 表示，其专有精炼工艺的二氧化碳排放量比溶剂萃取法少 90%，预计将于 2024 年底投入运营。</p>   <p>And privately-held Phoenix Tailings earlier this year began refining small amounts of rare earths in Massachusetts using a process that it says is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/mine-waste-finds-new-life-source-rare-earths-2023-04-04/">free of emissions and waste</a>.翻译:今年早些时候，私人控股的 Phoenix Tailings 开始在马萨诸塞州使用一种据称<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/mine-waste-finds-new-life-source-rare-earths-2023-04-04/">没有排放和废物的</a>工艺精炼少量稀土。</p>   <p>"There are technologies that can be developed that are far better than solvent extraction," said Robert Fox, a scientist at the U.S. Department of Energy's Idaho National Laboratory. The lab last month agreed to research new refining techniques for privately-held U.S. Critical Materials, which is developing a rare earths deposit.</p>    <h 1="">SKEPTICISM</h>  <p>Despite the hunger for new refining techniques, industry consultants warned that manufacturers may be expecting too much and too soon from this so-far unproven group of nascent technologies, especially given the world's aggressive electrification targets.翻译:尽管渴望新的炼油技术，但行业顾问警告说，制造商可能对这组迄今为止未经证实的新兴技术期望过高且过早，特别是考虑到世界雄心勃勃的电气化目标。</p>   <p>Ucore's technology, for example, has never worked at commercial scale and is not expected to gain patent protection until next year, a timeline that industry consultants flagged as a cause for concern given strong rivalries for intellectual property.翻译:例如，Ucore 的技术从未在商业规模上发挥过作用，预计要到明年才能获得专利保护，鉴于知识产权竞争激烈，行业顾问将这一时间表标记为令人担忧的原因。</p>   <p>"The time horizon needed to develop all these new refining technologies will be longer than many expect," said Frank Fannon, a minerals industry consultant and former U.S. assistant secretary of state. Talks of production within a few years "creates a false sense of security for policymakers."翻译:矿产行业顾问、美国前助理国务卿弗兰克·范农 (Frank Fannon) 表示：“开发所有这些新炼油技术所需的时间将比许多人预期的要长。”几年内的生产谈判“给政策制定者制造了一种错误的安全感”。</p>   <p>Yet the need for alternatives is rising, especially in the wake of Beijing's decision earlier this year to curb exports of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-export-curbs-choke-off-shipments-gallium-germanium-second-month-2023-10-20/">germanium</a>, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-ups-critical-minerals-heat-with-graphite-controls-2023-10-24/">graphite</a> and other metals. That has sparked concerns that rare earths could be next.翻译:然而，对替代品的需求正在上升，特别是在北京今年早些时候决定限制<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-export-curbs-choke-off-shipments-gallium-germanium-second-month-2023-10-20/">锗</a>、 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-ups-critical-minerals-heat-with-graphite-controls-2023-10-24/">石墨</a>和其他金属的出口之后。这引发了人们对稀土可能成为下一个的担忧。</p>   <p>Fannon and several <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/western-start-ups-seek-break-chinas-grip-rare-earths-refining-2023-12-04/Thanks%20much%20for%20all%20the%20coordination%20and%20internal%20advocacy/strategy" target="_blank">U.S. politicians</a> have called for Western governments to create central rare earths processing hubs, a plan already being pursued by Canada.翻译:范农和几位<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/western-start-ups-seek-break-chinas-grip-rare-earths-refining-2023-12-04/Thanks%20much%20for%20all%20the%20coordination%20and%20internal%20advocacy/strategy" target="_blank">美国政界人士</a>呼吁西方政府建立中央稀土加工中心，加拿大已经在实施这一计划。</p>   <p>In Saskatchewan, government scientists are working to launch their own rare earths processing technology after attempts to buy Chinese technology sputtered in 2020.翻译:在萨斯喀彻温省，政府科学家在 2020 年试图购买中国技术失败后，正在努力推出自己的稀土加工技术。</p>   <p>"We looked at existing technologies and said, 'There's a better way of doing this,'" said Mike Crabtree, CEO of the Saskatchewan Research Council (SRC), which is funded by the provincial government. "We wanted to put our own spin on it."翻译:萨斯喀彻温省研究委员会 (SRC) 由省政府资助，其首席执行官迈克·克拉布特里 (Mike Crabtree) 表示：“我们研究了现有技术并表示，‘有更好的方法可以做到这一点。’” “我们想加入我们自己的想法。”</p>   <p>Using artificial intelligence, the company designed processing equipment it believes is more efficient than Chinese rivals. Rather than needing up to 100 people to run, as with traditional solvent extraction, the SRC estimates that only four people will be needed to run its plant, which it hopes to open by the end of 2024.翻译:该公司利用人工智能设计了其认为比中国竞争对手更高效的处理设备。 SRC 估计只需要 4 个人来运营其工厂，而不是像传统的溶剂萃取那样需要多达 100 人来运营，该工厂希望在 2024 年底前开业。</p>   <p>While the SRC's goal is to spur mining across Canada, Crabtree said he is open to licensing the technology for use anywhere in the world.翻译:虽然 SRC 的目标是刺激加拿大各地的采矿业，但 Crabtree 表示，他愿意授权该技术在世界任何地方使用。</p>   <p>"This entire sector as a whole needs to grow outside of China in order to support the energy transition," he said.翻译:他说：“整个行业需要在中国境外发展，以支持能源转型。”</p>   <p>Crabtree and the SRC expect their facility to cost more to build than Chinese rivals but less to operate, a function of their desire to make processing equipment that has no waste and recycles acid and other key chemicals.翻译:Crabtree 和 SRC 预计，他们的工厂建设成本比中国竞争对手更高，但运营成本更低，因为他们希望制造无废物并回收酸和其他关键化学品的加工设备。</p>   <p>And while MP Materials and others have struggled to tailor their processing equipment to specific geological deposits, SRC, Ucore and others say they believe their new refining processes will be able to process the critical minerals from multiple locations across the globe.翻译:尽管 MP Materials 和其他公司一直在努力根据特定的地质矿床定制加工设备，但 SRC、Ucore 和其他公司表示，他们相信他们的新精炼工艺将能够加工来自全球多个地点的关键矿物。</p>   <p>"These new sources for rare earths are going to be paramount if we're going to reach global net zero targets," said Steve Schoffstall of the Sprott Energy Transition Materials ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SETM.O" target="_blank">(SETM.O)</a>, which holds shares in several rare earths companies.翻译:Sprott Energy Transition Materials ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SETM.O" target="_blank">(SETM.O) 的 Steve Schoffstall 表示：“如果我们要实现全球净零排放目标，这些新的稀土来源将至关重要。”Sprott Energy Transition Materials ETF (SETM.O)</a>持有多家稀土公司的股份。</p>   <p>Shares of Ucore rose more than 6% on Monday in Canadian trading after the Reuters story, while shares traded over-the-counter in the United States gained nearly 8%.翻译:路透社报道后，周一加拿大交易市场 Ucore 股价上涨逾 6%，而美国场外交易股价上涨近 8%。</p>   <p>- For daily comprehensive coverage of COP28 in your inbox, sign up for the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/newsletters/reuters-sustainable-switch/?utm_source=site&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=cop28">Reuters Sustainable Switch newsletter here</a>.翻译:- 如需在您的收件箱中获取 COP28 的每日全面报道，请<a href="https://www.reuters.com/newsletters/reuters-sustainable-switch/?utm_source=site&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=cop28">在此处注册路透社 Sustainable Switch 时事通讯</a>。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ernest Scheyder; Editing by Veronica Brown and Claudia Parsons翻译:欧内斯特·谢德报道；维罗妮卡·布朗和克劳迪娅·帕森斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 19:52:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B4GSIAEK75MPFAJ4FMI4KX5J5Y</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/western-start-ups-seek-break-chinas-grip-rare-earths-refining-2023-12-04/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ernest Scheyder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>MINING</category>
                
                <category>RAREEARTHS/ (UPDATE 1, INSIGHT, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[南非阿斯彭与山德士中国达成交易进一步进军亚洲]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/YTE82iZT3-VuYrcRb4MmVGO4bIM=/849x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DFDHB46U3RJQJD2BKMQFJQTU54.jpg" alt="An Aspen Pharmacare logo is seen at outside company offices in Woodmead翻译:在伍德米德的公司办公室外可以看到 Aspen Pharmacare 标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An Aspen Pharmacare logo is seen at outside company offices in Woodmead翻译:在伍德米德的公司办公室外可以看到 Aspen Pharmacare 标志, Johannesburg, South Africa, September 13, 2018. REUTERS/Siphiwe Sibeko/File Photo翻译:2018 年 9 月 13 日，在南非约翰内斯堡伍德米德的公司办公室外可以看到阿斯彭 Pharmacare 的标志。路透社/Siphiwe Sibeko/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Aspen Pharmacare <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/APNJ.J" target="_blank">(APNJ.J)</a> is expanding further into China through a deal to buy the Chinese business of Swiss group Sandoz <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SDZ.S" target="_blank">(SDZ.S)</a> for up to 92.6 million euros ($100.6 million), the South African company said on Monday.翻译:南非公司 Aspen Pharmacare <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/APNJ.J" target="_blank">(APNJ.J)</a>周一表示，该公司正在通过以高达 9260 万欧元（1.006 亿美元）收购瑞士山德士集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SDZ.S" target="_blank">(SDZ.S)</a>中国业务的交易，进一步向中国扩张。</p>   <p>As part of the deal, Aspen Global Incorporated, a subsidiary of Aspen, will also buy the selling and intellectual property rights of a portfolio of established products that include Sandostatin, Aclasta and Voriconazole.翻译:作为交易的一部分，阿斯彭的子公司阿斯彭全球公司还将购买包括善宁、密固达和伏立康唑在内的一系列成熟产品的销售权和知识产权。</p>   <p>The rights will also cover a pipeline of products to be launched by Sandoz China in the short to medium term.翻译:这些权利还将涵盖山德士中国在中短期内推出的一系列产品。</p>   <p>The deal "represents an attractive opportunity for Aspen to take a major step in its stated objective of increasing its presence in China," the company said.翻译:该公司表示，此次交易“对阿斯彭来说是一个有吸引力的机会，可以在其扩大在中国业务的既定目标方面迈出重要一步”。</p>   <p>Aspen said it will pay up to 92.6 million euros, with 18.5 million euros contingent upon the sales performance of the products in the pipeline. The pharma giant will fund the net upfront cash from existing debt facilities.翻译:阿斯彭表示将支付高达 9260 万欧元，其中 1850 万欧元取决于正在研发的产品的销售业绩。这家制药巨头将从现有债务融资中为净预付款现金提供资金。</p>   <p>Additionally, Aspen will dispose of the commercialisation rights and related intellectual property for four anaesthetic products currently sold by Aspen in the European Economic Area to Sandoz.翻译:此外，阿斯彭还将向山德士处置阿斯彭目前在欧洲经济区销售的四种麻醉产品的商业化权利和相关知识产权。</p>   <p>For the disposal, it will receive up to 55.5 million euros, with 9.3 million euros contingent on the sales performance of its anaesthetic products, namely Nimbex, Tracrium, Carbocaine and Naropin.翻译:对于此次出售，它将获得最多 5550 万欧元，其中 930 万欧元取决于其麻醉产品 Nimbex、Tracrium、Carbocaine 和 Naropin 的销售业绩。</p>   <p>"The disposal will allow Aspen's European management to adopt a more focussed approach to its remaining anaesthetic products in the region," Aspen said.翻译:阿斯彭表示：“此次处置将使阿斯彭的欧洲管理层能够对其在该地区剩余的麻醉产品采取更加集中的方法。”</p>   <p>It added that those drugs it is selling "will be complementary to Sandoz's existing pharmaceutical offering in Europe, where it has significant scale and is well positioned to leverage their potential".翻译:该公司补充说，其销售的这些药物“将补充山德士在欧洲现有的药品产品，山德士在欧洲拥有巨大的规模，并且处于充分利用其潜力的位置”。</p>   <p>Aspen is targeting to add about 1.8 billion rand ($96.23 million) of annual sales to the group from the Chinese business, while the sales of the anaesthetic products during Aspen's financial year ended June 30 were about 280 million rand.翻译:阿斯彭的目标是通过中国业务为该集团增加约18亿兰特（9623万美元）的年销售额，而阿斯彭截至6月30日的财年期间麻醉产品的销售额约为2.8亿兰特。</p>   <p>The deals are expected to be completed in the second quarter of next year.翻译:这些交易预计将于明年第二季度完成。</p>   <p>($1 = 0.9205 euros)翻译:（1 美元 = 0.9205 欧元）</p>   <p>($1 = 18.7048 rand)翻译:（1 美元 = 18.7048 兰特）</p>    <span>Reporting by Nqobile Dludla
Editing by David Goodman and Miral Fahmy翻译:Nqobile Dludla 报道 David Goodman 和 Miral Fahmy 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 19:43:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RR65VURSIBP4VIWIWFVWZNHWJQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/south-africas-aspen-pharmacare-buy-sandozs-china-business-2023-12-04/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Nqobile Dludla]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SANDOZ GRP</category>
                
                <category>M&#38;A/ASPEN PHARMACARE (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[加纳法院因非法采金而入狱中国公民]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>A Ghanaian court has sentenced a Chinese national to prison for illegal gold mining in the West African nation, her lawyer said on Monday, ending a case that started in 2017 and shed light on Chinese involvement in the activity.翻译:一名中国公民的律师周一表示，加纳一家法院以在西非国家非法采金罪判处一名中国公民入狱，结束了一起始于 2017 年的案件，并揭示了中国参与该活动的情况。</p>   <p>The court in the capital Accra sentenced Aisha Huang to four and a half years imprisonment and a fine of 48,000 Ghanaian cedis ($4,000) for running an illegal mining operation, Huang's lawyer Hope Agboado told Reuters.翻译:黄的律师霍普·阿格博阿多 (Hope Agboado) 告诉路透社，首都阿克拉的法院因非法采矿作业，判处艾莎·黄四年半监禁，并罚款 48,000 加纳塞地（4,000 美元）。</p>   <p>Huang, who could not be reached for comment, initially pleaded not guilty but changed her plea to guilty as the trial progressed.翻译:记者未能联系到黄某发表评论，她最初不认罪，但随着审判的进展，她改变了认罪态度。</p>   <p>Agboado said he had asked the court to impose a fine and deport her instead of imposing jail time. He and Huang are still deciding whether or not to appeal, he said.翻译:阿博阿多说，他已要求法院对她处以罚款并将其驱逐出境，而不是判处监禁。他说，他和黄仍在决定是否上诉。</p>   <p>Ghana, a gold, oil and cocoa producer, is facing a scourge of illegal mining with Chinese nationals accused of leading some of the operations that have destroyed large areas of forest, polluted water bodies and sometimes encroached on the concessions of large-scale miners.翻译:加纳是黄金、石油和可可生产国，正面临非法采矿的祸害，中国公民被指控领导了一些破坏大片森林、污染水体、有时还侵犯大型采矿者特许权的活动。</p>   <p>Ghana's cocoa regulator COCOBOD told Reuters in September that around 150,000 metric tons of cocoa was lost due to smuggling and illegal gold mining, locally known as galamsey, on farmlands in the 2022/23 season.翻译:加纳可可监管机构 COCOBOD 9 月告诉路透社，2022/23 产季，由于走私和农田非法采金（当地称为加拉姆西），约 15 万吨可可损失。</p>   <p>Huang was known as the 'Galamsey queen' in the Ghanaian press.翻译:黄被加纳媒体称为“加拉姆西女王”。</p>   <p>Several Chinese nationals were brought to court for similar cases in Ghana in 2021 and 2022.翻译:2021年和2022年，几名中国公民在加纳因类似案件被带上法庭。</p>   <p>($1 = 11.9500 Ghanaian cedi)翻译:（1 美元 = 11.9500 加纳塞地）</p>    <span>Reporting by Maxwell Akalaare Adombila; Editing by Nellie Peyton and Christina Fincher翻译:麦克斯韦·阿卡拉雷·阿杜比拉 (Maxwell Akalaare Adombila) 报道；内莉·佩顿和克里斯蒂娜·芬奇编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 18:02:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">EY3XJJCINZMFPC2O73UJUEYAWQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/ghana-court-jails-chinese-national-over-illegal-gold-mining-2023-12-04/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Maxwell Adombila]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GHANA</category>
                
                <category>MINING/CHINA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[恒大清算听证会推迟至1月 聚焦新债务重组计划]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/k3UZoc_u5sY_HZGISqpcLtjCFL0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4CX7CZM4VJI4RLGLJSDUT2YQAA.jpg" alt="The company logo is seen on the headquarters of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen翻译:中国恒大集团深圳总部的公司标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The company logo is seen on the headquarters of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen翻译:中国恒大集团深圳总部的公司标志, Guangdong province, China September 26, 2021. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2021年9月26日，该公司标志出现在中国广东省深圳的中国恒大集团总部。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/g6wIQTvLo7Bqye0cSusvQXIVkDg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WZUJNBCYMVO4HL2VPEG7ACYX7I.jpg" alt="A general view of the High Court in Hong Kong翻译:香港高等法院概览" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A general view of the High Court in Hong Kong翻译:香港高等法院概览, China December 4, 2023. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/DWQj1P_rbrjVwkWhjSVccx-t750=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/RICV3JRHABI2JJTWSZOIOUABAQ.jpg" alt="A general view of the High Court in Hong Kong翻译:香港高等法院概览" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A general view of the High Court in Hong Kong翻译:香港高等法院概览, China December 4, 2023. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/GcXuY94NWdXHpiSkbdlU-Wu7YgY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4UADPQOW7NMKJBEUY64WVNTEUQ.jpg" alt="Chinese and Hong Kong flags are seen outside the High Court in Hong Kong翻译:香港高等法院外悬挂着中国和香港国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese and Hong Kong flags are seen outside the High Court in Hong Kong翻译:香港高等法院外悬挂着中国和香港国旗, China December 4, 2023. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu</figcaption></figure>                   <p>China Evergrande Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a> on Monday said it has been granted an adjournment of a court hearing into a liquidation petition to Jan. 29, giving the embattled property developer time to finalise a revamped offshore debt-restructuring plan.翻译:中国恒大集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）</a>周一表示，已获准将清算申请的法庭听证会推迟至 1 月 29 日，这让这家陷入困境的房地产开发商有时间敲定修改后的海外债务重组计划。</p>   <p>The decision came as the world's most indebted developer with more than $300 billion in liabilities sought adjournment unexpectedly unopposed by the petitioner's lawyer.翻译:这一决定是在全球负债超过 3000 亿美元的开发商寻求延期审理之际做出的，出人意料的是，申请人的律师并未提出反对。</p>   <p>On Oct. 29, at the previous adjournment, Hong Kong High Court Justice Linda Chan said Monday's hearing would be the last before a decision was made whether to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-faces-winding-up-challenge-hong-kong-court-2023-10-29/">liquidate Evergrande</a> in the absence of a "concrete" restructuring plan.翻译:10月29日，香港高等法院法官陈嘉欣在上一次休庭中表示，周一的听证会将是在没有“具体”重组计划的情况下决定是否<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-faces-winding-up-challenge-hong-kong-court-2023-10-29/">清算恒大</a>之前的最后一次听证会。</p>   <p>After Monday's adjournment, Evergrande stock reversed losses from earlier in the day to jump more than 13%.翻译:周一休会后，恒大股价扭转当天早些时候的跌幅，涨幅超过 13%。</p>   <p>Evergrande defaulted on offshore debt in late 2021, becoming the poster child of a debt crisis that has engulfed China's property sector. Last week, it scrambled to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-seeks-avoid-liquidation-with-last-ditch-debt-plan-sources-2023-11-30/">revise</a> its restructuring plan to avoid liquidation, Reuters has reported.翻译:恒大集团于2021年底出现境外债务违约，成为席卷中国房地产行业的债务危机的典型代表。据路透社报道，上周，该公司紧急<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-seeks-avoid-liquidation-with-last-ditch-debt-plan-sources-2023-11-30/">修改</a>重组计划以避免清算。</p>   <p>Evergrande "somewhat surprisingly has obtained some further time to rethink its plans," said partner Neil McDonald of Kirkland &amp; Ellis, a legal adviser to an ad hoc group of offshore creditors opposed to the revised terms.翻译:凯易律师事务所合伙人尼尔·麦克唐纳（Neil McDonald）表示，恒大“有点令人惊讶的是，它获得了更多时间来重新考虑其计划”。他是反对修订条款的海外债权人特别小组的法律顾问。</p>   <p>Still, Evergrande is likely to be wound up at the next hearing if it does not come up with a plan accepted by all classes of creditors, he said.</p>    <h 1="">SURPRISE</h>  <p>Hong Kong-based investment firm Top Shine filed the petition in June 2022 saying Evergrande had not honoured an agreement to repurchase shares it bought in the developer's Fangchebao unit.翻译:总部位于香港的投资公司Top Shine于2022年6月提交请愿书，称恒大没有履行回购其在开发商房车宝子公司购买的股份的协议。</p>   <p>The petitioner surprised the court on Monday when its lawyer started proceedings saying he was "instructed not to present any argument in opposition to" adjournment.翻译:周一，请愿人的律师在启动诉讼程序时表示，请愿人“被指示不要提出任何反对休庭的论据”，这令法庭感到惊讶。</p>   <p>Justice Chan ordered the petitioner inform other creditors a week ahead of the next hearing should it decide to withdraw the petition, so those creditors can continue action if they wish.翻译:陈法官命令，如果请愿人决定撤回请愿书，请在下次听证会前一周告知其他债权人，以便这些债权人可以根据需要继续采取行动。</p>   <p>"We'll see what happens with the company before the 29th but if nothing changes, then yes," said McDonald when asked by reporters whether the creditors Kirkland represents will file to liquidate Evergrande if the petitioner withdraws.翻译:当被记者问及柯克兰代表的债权人如果申请者撤回是否会申请清算恒大时，麦克唐纳表示：“我们将在29日之前看看该公司会发生什么，但如果没有任何变化，那就是的。”</p>   <p>"It (today's lack of opposition) is not an indication that we will not proceed with the liquidation petition," a representative of Top Shine told Reuters after the hearing.翻译:Top Shine 的一名代表在听证会后对路透社表示：“（今天没有反对）并不表明我们不会继续进行清算申请。”</p>   <p>Evergrande's lawyer told the court the developer expects to "refine" its restructuring proposal in the next five weeks.翻译:恒大的律师告诉法庭，开发商预计将在未来五周内“完善”其重组方案。</p>   <p>Under revised terms, the lawyer said Evergrande is offering shares to creditors - 17.8% of China Evergrande Group, 21.6% of Evergrande Property Services Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">(6666.HK)</a> and 28.5% of Evergrande New Energy Vehicle Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0708.HK" target="_blank">(0708.HK)</a>.翻译:该律师表示，根据修订后的条款，恒大将向债权人发行股份——中国恒大集团17.8%的股份、恒大物业服务集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">（6666.HK）</a> 21.6%的股份以及恒大新能源汽车集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0708.HK" target="_blank">（0708.HK）</a> 28.5%的股份。</p>   <p>It will also offer certificates, or the right to proceeds from disposable assets. Those terms replace its proposal to issue equity-linked instruments backed by the three listed companies and new bonds in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-set-unveil-offshore-debt-restructuring-proposal-2023-03-22/">March</a>.翻译:它还将提供证书，或从可支配资产中获得收益的权利。这些条款取代了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-set-unveil-offshore-debt-restructuring-proposal-2023-03-22/">三月份</a>发行由三家上市公司支持的股票挂钩工具和新债券的提议。</p>   <p>The ratio of shares is different for so-called Class A and Class C creditors, as is the list of assets that can raise funds, the lawyer said.翻译:该律师表示，所谓的A类和C类债权人的股份比例不同，可筹集资金的资产清单也不同。</p>   <p>Justice Chan said Evergrande must hold direct discussion with relevant Chinese authorities on the new restructuring terms, and that the plan needs support from all creditor classes by the next hearing.翻译:陈法官表示，恒大必须与中国有关当局就新的重组条款进行直接讨论，并且该计划需要在下次听证会上获得所有债权人的支持。</p>   <p>Evergrande failed to get the 75% approval required from Class C creditors for original terms proposed in March, Reuters has reported.翻译:据路透社报道，恒大未能获得 C 级债权人 3 月份提出的原始条款所需的 75% 批准。</p>   <p>Managing Director Bert Grisel of investment bank Moelis &amp; Co - advising the same creditor group - said after the hearing the group "firmly" rejects the revised plan because creditors would be entitled to less than through liquidation.翻译:为同一债权人集团提供咨询服务的投资银行 Moelis &amp; Co 的董事总经理伯特·格里塞尔 (Bert Grisel) 在听证会后表示，该集团“坚决”拒绝修改后的计划，因为债权人将有权通过清算获得更少的资金。</p>   <p>"Liquidation does little good to creditors, but it is extremely difficult to get a debt repayment plan that satisfies everyone - that is why we have a deadlock with Evergrande here," said ANZ Bank China credit analyst Ting Meng.</p>    <h 1="">UNFINISHED HOMES</h>  <p>Liquidation of Evergrande, whose assets totalled $240 billion at June-end, would increase pressure on a reeling property sector, which accounts for a quarter of the world's second-largest economy.翻译:截至6月底资产总额达2400亿美元的恒大集团的清算将给摇摇欲坠的房地产行业带来更大的压力，该行业占世界第二大经济体的四分之一。</p>   <p>Its debt woes have been a major concern for global investors at a time when government stimulus has struggled to propel post-pandemic economic recovery, with property sales slowing and hundreds of thousands of homes left unfinished.翻译:在政府刺激措施难以推动疫情后的经济复苏、房地产销售放缓、数十万套房屋未完工之际，其债务困境一直是全球投资者的主要担忧。</p>   <p>Evergrande has been working on a debt revamp plan for almost two years. Its original plan was scuppered in late September when it said its billionaire founder Hui Ka Yan was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shares-china-evergrande-suspended-chairman-under-police-watch-2023-09-28/">under investigation</a> for suspected crimes.翻译:恒大近两年来一直致力于债务重组计划。 9月底，该公司表示其亿万富翁创始人许家印因涉嫌犯罪<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shares-china-evergrande-suspended-chairman-under-police-watch-2023-09-28/">而接受调查，</a>原定计划因此流产。</p>   <p>At the time, the developer also said regulators denied approval to issue new U.S. dollar bonds - a crucial part of the restructuring plan - as its flagship onshore unit was also under investigation.翻译:当时，该开发商还表示，监管机构拒绝批准发行新的美元债券——这是重组计划的重要组成部分——因为其旗舰陆上子公司也正在接受调查。</p>    <span>Reporting by Clare Jim and Xie Yu in Hong Kong; Writing by Sumeet Chatterjee; Editing by Kim Coghill翻译:编辑：金·科吉尔, Christopher Cushing and Louise Heavens</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 15:55:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">43ACKHYEGBMSZPYDEPEKDNHKGU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-seeks-adjournment-hong-kong-liquidation-court-hearing-2023-12-04/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Clare Jim, Yu Xie]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/DEBT</category>
                
                <category>EVERGRANDE (UPDATE 6, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[麦当劳加大对中国的押注，与西方公司降低风险的趋势背道而驰]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/xMnrdmbCuqw2C40zh90IOtw6hhI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CIKYGEQUBROSHG2L2E5TAIDRLM.jpg" alt="A woman sits on a swing attached to a giant sign of McDonald's, outside its themed exhibition in Beijing翻译:北京麦当劳主题展览外，一名女子坐在麦当劳巨型招牌上的秋千上" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A woman sits on a swing attached to a giant sign of McDonald's, outside its themed exhibition in Beijing翻译:北京麦当劳主题展览外，一名女子坐在麦当劳巨型招牌上的秋千上, China December 4, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023 年 12 月 4 日，中国北京，麦当劳主题展览外，一名女子坐在麦当劳巨型招牌旁的秋千上。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Q2cA_EEZaBSp_pdBUMQPOvhtkz4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/K4QTJQEGWZLEDHAGHUQPG2LZ74.jpg" alt="A woman sitting next to a statue of ''Ronald McDonald&quot;, the McDonald's company mascot, poses for pictures outside the McDonald's themed exhibition in Beijing翻译:一位女士坐在麦当劳公司吉祥物“麦当劳叔叔”雕像旁，在北京麦当劳主题展览外拍照留念" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A woman sitting next to a statue of ''Ronald McDonald", the McDonald's company mascot, poses for pictures outside the McDonald's themed exhibition in Beijing, China December 4, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年12月4日，中国北京，麦当劳主题展览外，一名女士坐在麦当劳公司吉祥物“麦当劳叔叔”雕像旁拍照。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/p9wwL-5_GYZpzMocVrA4TFML1_Y=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/EDHGBNHW6FKPZFWEFLTHIHCCJY.jpg" alt="Person pushes a stroller and walks past a poster for McDonald's themed exhibition in Beijing翻译:推着婴儿车的人走过北京麦当劳主题展览的海报" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A person pushes a stroller and walks past a poster for McDonald's themed exhibition in Beijing, China December 4, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年12月4日，中国北京，一个人推着婴儿车走过麦当劳主题展览的海报。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/iTb6EeeuldrxUejO2ZO3bIfzvu8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6WMNYXUCXJNFFJZECLRW2IAOKY.jpg" alt="Women sitting on swings attached to a giant sign of McDonald's pose for pictures, outside its themed exhibition in Beijing翻译:北京麦当劳主题展览外，妇女们坐在麦当劳巨型招牌秋千上拍照" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Women sitting on swings attached to a giant sign of McDonald's pose for pictures, outside its themed exhibition in Beijing翻译:北京麦当劳主题展览外，妇女们坐在麦当劳巨型招牌秋千上拍照, China December 4, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023 年 12 月 4 日，中国北京，麦当劳主题展览外，坐在麦当劳巨型招牌秋千上的妇女们摆姿势拍照。 REUTERS/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/hY3jTwTVD3b1KrSOpdoL559SUJU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XBBWPTVMONKV3G2GF6P53NRETQ.jpg" alt="Man walks a dog past a McDonald's restaurant in Beijing翻译:男子遛狗经过北京一家麦当劳餐厅" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A man walks a dog past a McDonald's restaurant in Beijing, China December 4, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023 年 12 月 4 日，一名男子遛狗经过中国北京的一家麦当劳餐厅。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>                     <p>The decision by McDonald's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MCD.N" target="_blank">(MCD.N)</a> to take greater control of its China business and expand aggressively in the face of a consumer slowdown and geopolitical tensions seems risky - but the potential pay-off is great, analysts say.翻译:分析师表示，面对消费放缓和地缘政治紧张局势，麦当劳<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MCD.N" target="_blank">(MCD.N)</a>决定加强对中国业务的控制并积极扩张，这似乎有风险，但潜在的回报是巨大的。</p>   <p>Last month, the U.S.-based burger maker <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/mcdonalds-acquire-carlyles-stake-china-unit-2023-11-20/">cut a deal</a> to repurchase the 28% stake in its China business Carlyle Group took in 2017, giving it a 48% share in $6 billion worth of operations that include Hong Kong and Macau.翻译:上个月，这家总部位于美国的汉堡制造商<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/mcdonalds-acquire-carlyles-stake-china-unit-2023-11-20/">达成协议</a>，回购凯雷投资集团 2017 年持有的中国业务 28% 的股份，使其在包括香港和澳门在内的价值 60 亿美元的业务中拥有 48% 的股份。</p>   <p>The move contrasts sharply with the prevailing trend of multinational corporations reeling back investments in China or even exiting altogether because of geopolitical and economic challenges.翻译:此举与跨国公司因地缘政治和经济挑战而减少在华投资甚至完全退出的普遍趋势形成鲜明对比。</p>   <p>One advantage for McDonald’s: its majority partner in the China business, CITIC, provides top-level political cover, said Jason Yu, greater China managing director of market research firm Kantar Worldpanel.翻译:市场研究公司凯度消费者指数(Kantar Worldpanel)大中华区总经理贾森·于(Jason Yu)表示，麦当劳的优势之一是：其在中国业务的主要合作伙伴中信集团提供了高层政治掩护。</p>   <p>"Having a very powerful Chinese state-owned conglomerate as a partner means they are not going to be at the forefront of the geopolitical situation; that is quite important," Yu said.翻译:“拥有一家非常强大的中国国有企业集团作为合作伙伴意味着他们不会处于地缘政治局势的最前沿；这一点非常重要，”于说。</p>   <p>McDonald's China, Carlyle Group and CITIC declined to comment.翻译:麦当劳中国、凯雷集团和中信集团均拒绝置评。</p>   <p>Other consumer-facing U.S. firms, including Starbucks <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SBUX.O" target="_blank">(SBUX.O)</a>, Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a>, Coach owner Tapestry <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TPR.N" target="_blank">(TPR.N)</a> and sportswear giant Nike <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NKE.N" target="_blank">(NKE.N)</a>, have remained similarly dedicated to the China market.翻译:其他面向消费者的美国公司，包括星巴克<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SBUX.O" target="_blank">(SBUX.O)</a> 、苹果<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a> 、Coach 所有者 Tapestry <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TPR.N" target="_blank">(TPR.N)</a>和运动服装巨头耐克<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NKE.N" target="_blank">(NKE.N)</a> ，也同样致力于中国市场。</p>   <p>Starbucks and Nike, which face increased competition from lower-priced domestic competitors, show the need to stay agile in order to protect and grow market share, analysts say.翻译:分析师表示，星巴克和耐克面临来自国内低价竞争对手的日益激烈的竞争，这表明需要保持敏捷性，以保护和扩大市场份额。</p>   <p>The coffee giant is sticking with expansion plans and launched a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/starbucks-launches-smaller-cup-size-china-competition-grows-2023-10-18/">smaller cup size</a>; Nike, by contrast, has offered localised, higher-end sneakers such as its "Year of the Rabbit" Dunk Lows.翻译:这家咖啡巨头坚持扩张计划，并推出了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/starbucks-launches-smaller-cup-size-china-competition-grows-2023-10-18/">更小的杯子尺寸</a>；相比之下，耐克则提供本地化的高端运动鞋，例如“兔年”Dunk Lows。</p>   <p>McDonald’s has used funds from the Carlyle investment to double its restaurant count since 2017 to 5,500, and the country has become its second-largest market. The business aims to have more than 10,000 stores in China by 2028.翻译:自 2017 年以来，麦当劳利用凯雷投资的资金将其餐厅数量增加了一倍，达到 5,500 家，中国已成为其第二大市场。该公司的目标是到2028年在中国拥有超过10,000家门店。</p>   <p>Competitors of McDonald's are also expanding their reach in China.翻译:麦当劳的竞争对手也在扩大其在中国的影响力。</p>   <p>Yum China, which operates KFC and Pizza Hut, among other brands, already has more than 14,000 stores across the country. Among domestic players, chicken burger specialist Wallace said in 2021 that it had reached 20,000 stores, and newer entrant Tastien, which specialises in "Chinese-style" burgers, has more than 3,500 stores.翻译:百胜中国旗下经营肯德基和必胜客等品牌，已在全国拥有超过14,000家门店。在国内企业中，鸡肉汉堡专营商华莱士表示，2021年其门店数量已达到2万家，而新进入者专注于“中式”汉堡的Tastien则拥有超过3500家门店。</p>   <p>To be sure, if relations between China and the West worsen, any optimism could evaporate, said Greg Halter, Director of Research at investment advisory firm Carnegie Investment Counsel.翻译:投资咨询公司卡内基投资顾问公司(Carnegie Investment Counsel)研究总监格雷格·哈尔特(Greg Halter)表示，可以肯定的是，如果中国与西方之间的关系恶化，任何乐观情绪都可能消失。</p>   <p>"If tensions deteriorate, we may see not only McDonald's, but other companies divest their Chinese operations, similar to what has occurred in Russia over the past two years," Halter said.翻译:哈尔特表示：“如果紧张局势恶化，我们可能不仅会看到麦当劳，还会看到其他公司剥离其中国业务，类似于过去两年俄罗斯发生的情况。”</p>   <p>Further digitalisation and localisation are needed, Yu said, with localisation key to winning over taste buds in China's $140.2 billion limited-service restaurant sector.翻译:Yu 表示，需要进一步的数字化和本地化，而本地化是赢得中国价值 1,402 亿美元的有限服务餐饮业味蕾的关键。</p>   <p>Although the McDonald's China menu would be familiar to U.S. consumers, there are nods to local tastes, including taro pie, rather than apple.翻译:尽管麦当劳中国的菜单对美国消费者来说很熟悉，但还是迎合了当地的口味，包括芋头派，而不是苹果派。</p>   <p>According to Euromonitor, the market value of limited-service restaurants in China is on track to grow about 4% annually on average through 2025. Of the limited-service burger-focussed restaurants in the country, McDonald's dominates with a 70% share of the market.翻译:根据 Euromonitor 的数据，到 2025 年，中国有限服务餐厅的市场价值有望平均每年增长 4% 左右。在中国以汉堡为主的有限服务餐厅中，麦当劳占据主导地位，占据 70% 的份额。市场。</p>   <p>China's slowing economic growth and lacklustre consumer spending this year have already hurt the bottom lines of global businesses exposed to its consumer market, but McDonald's is well-placed to outperform, said Ben Cavender, the Shanghai-based managing director and head of strategy at China Market Research Group.翻译:麦当劳中国区董事总经理兼战略主管本·卡文德 (Ben Cavender) 表示，今年中国经济增长放缓和消费者支出低迷，已经损害了与其消费市场相关的全球企业的利润，但麦当劳完全有能力跑赢大市。市场研究小组。</p>   <p>He said value-driven middle class consumers and lower commercial rents countrywide should be a boon to such businesses.翻译:他表示，价值驱动的中产阶级消费者和全国范围内较低的商业租金应该对此类企业有利。</p>   <p>"If ever there was a time to double down on China, this is it," he said.翻译:“如果有一个时机对中国加倍下注，那就是现在了，”他说。</p>    <span>Reporting by Casey Hall in Shanghai and Kane Wu in Hong Kong; additional reporting from Deborah Sophia in Bengaluru. Editing by Gerry Doyle翻译:上海Casey Hall和香港Kane Wu的报道；来自班加罗尔黛博拉·索菲亚的补充报道。格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">X2Q62NEXG5N5BCGRTTKCGPL3VI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/lovin-it-mcdonalds-raises-china-bet-bucking-western-firms-derisking-trend-2023-12-04/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Casey Hall]]></author>
            
                
                <category>MCDONALDS</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (REPEAT, ANALYSIS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着亏损和债务的增加，中国大型养猪企业纷纷进军]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/uRMNVUbsk1MAge_hmgEbYPTCDRo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MEJSLLGKGZNLJHKAD36G7XCZR4.jpg" alt="Piglets drink milk from a sow at a pig farm in Yaji翻译:雅吉养猪场的小猪正在喝母猪的奶" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Piglets drink milk from a sow at a pig farm in Yaji翻译:雅吉养猪场的小猪正在喝母猪的奶, Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, China, March 21, 2018. REUTERS/Thomas Suen/File Photo/File Photo翻译:2018年3月21日，中国广西壮族自治区雅吉的一个养猪场，小猪正在喝母猪的奶。REUTERS/Thomas Suen/档案照片/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/OtyJplppFN9KK3MQPTbuy8KuXnA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/B4C5YB6Q7VPPROATXNJYAGK6JY.jpg" alt="The wife of pig farmer Han Yi prepares feed for pigs on his farm at a village in Changtu翻译:昌图某村养猪户韩毅的妻子正在自家农场准备猪饲料" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The wife of pig farmer Han Yi prepares feed for pigs on his farm at a village in Changtu翻译:昌图某村养猪户韩毅的妻子正在自家农场准备猪饲料 county, Liaoning province, China January 17, 2019. REUTERS/Ryan Woo/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TKOTZEOTOQr1J5AeI9hlmJwleas=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WZS7A4KLFJPL5EGPXOUMX6XEOE.jpg" alt="Pigs are seen on a family farm in Xiaoxinzhuang village, Hebei翻译:河北小辛庄村的一个家庭农场里看到了猪" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Pigs are seen on a family farm in  Xiaoxinzhuang village, Hebei province, China January 25, 2018. Picture taken January 25, 2018.  REUTERS/Dominique Patton翻译:2018年1月25日，中国河北省小辛庄村的一个家庭农场里看到猪。照片拍摄于2018年1月25日。路透社/Dominique Patton</figcaption></figure>                 <p>The biggest pig breeders in China, consumer of fully half the world's pork, seem to have bitten off more than they can chew.翻译:中国最大的养猪企业消耗了全球一半的猪肉，但它们似乎已经吃不消了。</p>   <p>Big agribusinesses have elbowed their way into the sector and are rapidly modernising it, but have expanded pig herds so aggressively that, with demand now in a downturn, their hog prices are falling, losses are mounting, and debt is rising.翻译:大型农业综合企业纷纷涌入该行业，并迅速实现现代化，但其生猪存栏规模却过于激进，在需求低迷的情况下，它们的生猪价格不断下跌，损失不断增加，债务不断增加。</p>   <p>More huge losses are expected next year, putting China's pig enterprises under pressure to slim down their breeding herds and sell off farms, many of which are sitting empty.翻译:预计明年将出现更多巨额亏损，这将使中国养猪企业面临减少种猪存栏和出售养殖场的压力，其中许多养殖场已空置。</p>   <p>For now, however, they are digging in, hoping to wait out the market downturn and reap a bonanza when prices eventually recover. And that is raising the stakes, not just for themselves but for their overseas feed suppliers, genetics firms, and the struggling global pork trade.翻译:然而，目前他们正在深耕，希望等待市场低迷结束，并在价格最终回升时收获丰厚的回报。这不仅增加了他们自己的风险，也增加了他们的海外饲料供应商、基因公司和陷入困境的全球猪肉贸易的风险。</p>   <p>"It all comes down to how deep these companies' pockets are," said Lyle Jones, China sales director at U.S.-based Genesus Inc, which supplies breeding pigs to the leading producers.翻译:“这一切都取决于这些公司的财力有多雄厚，”美国加裕公司中国销售总监莱尔琼斯说，该公司向领先的生产商供应种猪。</p>   <p>Hog farming, like other Chinese sectors from homebuilding to electric vehicles, has in recent years prioritised growth and market share over profits, creating a surplus that has driven pig prices lower and is now crowding out imports.翻译:与从住宅建筑到电动汽车等中国其他行业一样，生猪养殖近年来将增长和市场份额置于利润之上，造成的盈余导致生猪价格下跌，目前正在挤出进口。</p>   <p>China's cash hog prices have averaged well below even the most efficient producers' costs this year, for the first time in nearly a decade, and in the past three months alone have dropped 15% to 14.5 yuan per kilogram.翻译:今年，中国的生猪现金平均价格甚至远低于最高效生产者的成本，这是近十年来的首次，并且仅在过去三个月就下跌了15%，至每公斤14.5元。</p>   <p>The most-active live hog futures on the Dalian Commodity Exchange have tumbled 7.3% since the beginning of last week to 13,910 yuan ($1,949) per metric ton, the lowest since they began trading almost three years ago.翻译:大连商品交易所最活跃的生猪期货自上周初以来已下跌 7.3%，至每吨 13,910 元人民币（1,949 美元），为近三年前开始交易以来的最低水平。</p>      <p>The downdraft has defied both state efforts to prop up prices with token purchases for official reserves, and the start of the peak winter season for pork consumption.翻译:国家通过象征性购买官方储备来提振价格的努力，以及冬季猪肉消费旺季的开始，都无视了这种下行趋势。</p>   <p>And it is squeezing a number of big producers in the $200 billion-a-year industry, with the top 10 producers alone recording a 13% increase in net debt this year as of end-September, according to state-run media.翻译:据官方媒体报道，这一年产值达 2000 亿美元的行业中的一些大型生产商受到挤压，截至 9 月底，仅前 10 名生产商的净债务就增加了 13%。</p>   <p>New Hope Liuhe <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/000876.SZ" target="_blank">(000876.SZ)</a>, China's third-largest producer and the world's fifth largest, sold off farms last year and told investors in July it wanted to sell more, while bringing in strategic investors to its poultry and food units.翻译:中国第三大、全球第五大生产商新希望六和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/000876.SZ" target="_blank">（000876.SZ）</a>去年出售了农场，并于7月告诉投资者希望出售更多，同时为其家禽和食品业务引入战略投资者。</p>   <p>The company has made "some progress" on those fronts, it told investors on Friday, but gave no details. It also said a 7.35 billion yuan private share issue announced on Nov. 30 would help it to repay loans and rein in debt.翻译:该公司周五告诉投资者，在这些方面已经取得了“一些进展”，但没有透露细节。该公司还表示，11月30日宣布的73.5亿元非公开发行股票将有助于其偿还贷款和控制债务。</p>   <p>Major producers Tech-Bank <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002124.SZ" target="_blank">(002124.SZ)</a> and Fujian Aonong <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/603363.SS" target="_blank">(603363.SS)</a> have been selling off stakes in themselves or in subsidiaries to raise cash, while Aonong's debt-to-equity ratio reached a hefty 8.26 in the third quarter according to LSEG data. Neither company responded to requests for comment about their current challenges and working capital requirements.</p>    <h 1="">EXPANDING DEBT</h>  <p>Jiangxi Zhengbang Technology <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002157.SZ" target="_blank">(002157.SZ)</a>, which became China's second-largest producer after a rapid expansion drive, was forced into a restructuring last year despite <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/troubled-chinese-hog-breeder-zhengbang-gets-support-from-railway-firm" target="_blank">support from</a> local government-run firms.翻译:江西正邦科技<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002157.SZ" target="_blank">（002157.SZ）</a>经过快速扩张成为中国第二大生产商，尽管<a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/troubled-chinese-hog-breeder-zhengbang-gets-support-from-railway-firm" target="_blank">有地方政府企业的支持</a>，但去年仍被迫进行重组。</p>   <p>Moreover, with debt levels swelling across the Chinese economy, banks and local governments have become less willing or able to offer support.翻译:此外，随着中国经济的债务水平不断膨胀，银行和地方政府提供支持的意愿或能力越来越低。</p>   <p>"Over the past two years, banks could lend them a lot so these companies expanded very fast," said an analyst at an equity research firm, who was not authorised to speak to the media and declined to be named.翻译:一家股票研究公司的分析师表示：“过去两年，银行可以向他们提供大量贷款，因此这些公司扩张得非常快。”该分析师未获授权接受媒体采访，但拒绝透露姓名。</p>   <p>But now, especially given the companies' high debt levels, the analyst said: "It's hard for them to borrow any money from the banks."翻译:但现在，特别是考虑到这些公司的高债务水平，分析师表示：“他们很难从银行借到任何钱。”</p>   <p>Analysts say the biggest players - industry leader Muyuan Foods Co , a low-cost producer and one of the few generating cashflow, and No. 2 Wens Foodstuff Group Co <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300498.SZ" target="_blank">(300498.SZ)</a>, which has reduced costs significantly - may be well-positioned for a shake-out.翻译:分析师表示，最大的参与者——行业领先者牧原食品有限公司（一家低成本生产商，也是为数不多的产生现金流的公司之一）和排名第二的温氏食品集团有限公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300498.SZ" target="_blank">（300498.SZ）</a> ——成本大幅降低——可能处于有利地位。进行一次洗牌。</p>   <p>But challenges are mounting as China produces record volumes of pork, in part a legacy of past encouragement from Beijing, which fears food price volatility and urged a major expansion of sow herds after an African swine fever outbreak in the late 2010s killed half the country's pigs.翻译:但随着中国猪肉产量创历史新高，挑战也越来越大，这在一定程度上是北京过去鼓励政策的结果。北京担心食品价格波动，并在2010年代末非洲猪瘟爆发导致中国一半生猪死亡后敦促大幅扩大母猪存栏量。</p>   <p>Muyuan alone has more than tripled its sow herd since 2018, chasing after market share along with other big publicly listed firms, and now has three times as many sows as WH Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0288.HK" target="_blank">(0288.HK)</a>, which owns top U.S. producer Smithfield Foods.翻译:自2018年以来，仅牧原公司的母猪存栏量就增加了两倍多，与其他大型上市公司一起争夺市场份额，目前母猪数量是万洲国际<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0288.HK" target="_blank">（0288.HK）</a>的三倍，后者拥有美国顶级生产商史密斯菲尔德食品公司。</p>   <p>Analysts at Hua'an Securities forecast that hog output would jump 10% in the first half of 2024. That follows a 17% surge in the first nine months of this year at China's 15 big market-listed breeders even as they reported 200 billion yuan in combined net losses.翻译:华安证券分析师预测，2024年上半年生猪产量将增长10%。今年前9个月，中国15家大型上市养殖企业的产值达2000亿元，但生猪产量仍增长17%。合并净亏损。</p>   <p>To make matters worse, pork consumption in China has been hit both by <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">slowing economic growth</a> and by diners' changing preferences, as more health-conscious consumers - especially young people and urbanites - switch to poultry and other foods.翻译:更糟糕的是，中国的猪肉消费受到<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">经济增长放缓</a>和食客偏好变化的打击，越来越多注重健康的消费者——尤其是年轻人和城市居民——转向家禽和其他食品。</p>   <p>And the costs of battling disease have risen substantially, with African swine fever now endemic and a constant threat to all farms.翻译:与疾病作斗争的成本大幅上升，非洲猪瘟现已流行，并持续威胁着所有农场。</p>   <p>China's agriculture ministry has warned of heavier losses for the sector in early 2024 than a year ago and urged pig producers to cut output.翻译:中国农业部警告称，2024年初该行业的损失将比一年前更严重，并敦促生猪生产者减产。</p>   <p>While the big producers have slashed spending on new equipment and taken other cost-cutting measures, most remain reluctant to unload idle farms and reduce breeding herds.翻译:尽管大型生产商已经削减了新设备的支出并采取了其他削减成本的措施，但大多数生产商仍然不愿意出售闲置农场并减少种猪群。</p>   <p>"Leading companies aggressively expanded in 2020-21, the capex was huge, and they're not willing to reduce capacity, even under the current weak price," said Flora Zhu, director of China Corporate Research at Fitch Ratings.翻译:惠誉国际评级中国企业研究总监朱芙表示：“2020-21年，龙头企业积极扩张，资本支出巨大，即使在当前疲软的价格下，他们也不愿意减少产能。”</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1364 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.1364 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Dominique Patton; Additional reporting by Beijing Newsroom; Editing by Edmund Klamann翻译:多米尼克·巴顿报道；北京新闻编辑室补充报道；编辑：埃德蒙·克拉曼</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 11:46:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">SIALONVXVNOBTL2LSTR7BKGBJM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-big-pig-breeders-dig-losses-debts-mount-2023-12-04/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Dominique Patton]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>HOGS/ (ANALYSIS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国将蔚来汽车列入批准的汽车制造商名单 - 网站]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/8o96ohNAx9BJyCwBmBYwqmeHZo4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/A3FV7LZN3NOLVGOW3RLNL5RFH4.jpg" alt="Nio's first European plant in Biatorbagy翻译:蔚来第一家欧洲工厂位于Biatorbag​​y" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Nio electric car is seen at Nio's first European plant and power swap station in Biatorbagy, Hungary, September 16, 2022. REUTERS/Bernadett Szabo/File Photo翻译:2022 年 9 月 16 日，中国蔚来电动汽车出现在位于匈牙利比亚托巴吉的蔚来第一家欧洲工厂和换电站。 REUTERS/Bernadett Szabo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Electric vehicle maker Nio <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9866.HK" target="_blank">(9866.HK)</a> has been added to a Chinese industry ministry database permitting companies to produce vehicles in the country, according to the ministry's website.翻译:据工信部网站称，电动汽车制造商蔚来汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9866.HK" target="_blank">（9866.HK）</a>已被添加到中国工信部数据库中，允许企业在中国生产汽车。</p>   <p>The website gave no details on whether or when a manufacturing licence was granted to Nio, which has since 2018 partnered with Anhui Jianghuai Automobile Group (JAC) to produce electric vehicles on a contract basis.翻译:该网站没有详细说明蔚来汽车是否或何时获得制造许可证。蔚来汽车自 2018 年以来一直与安徽江淮汽车集团 (JAC) 合作，以合同方式生产电动汽车。</p>   <p>Nio said in response to a Reuters query that it currently had no information to share.翻译:蔚来在回应路透社询问时表示，目前没有可分享的信息。</p>   <p>Receiving a manufacturing licence would clear some uncertainty over the impact on Nio of JAC's plans to sell some assets belonging to the two factories that make Nio EVs.翻译:获得制造许可证将消除江淮汽车计划出售属于生产蔚来电动汽车的两家工厂的部分资产对蔚来影响的一些不确定性。</p>   <p>The state-backed newspaper China Securities Journal in October reported JAC's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/600418.SS" target="_blank">(600418.SS)</a> sale plans. Nio said at the time that such a sale would not affect its future production activities.翻译:国有报纸《中国证券报》十月份报道了江淮汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/600418.SS" target="_blank">（600418.SS）</a>的出售计划。蔚来当时表示，此类出售不会影响其未来的生产活动。</p>   <p>Granting Nio a production licence also marks a shift for Chinese authorities, which have been cautious about approving new production amid overcapacity and a deepening price war that has pulled in over 40 brands.翻译:授予蔚来汽车生产许可证也标志着中国当局的转变，由于产能过剩和价格战不断加深，中国当局对批准新生产持谨慎态度，这场价格战已吸引了 40 多个品牌参与。</p>   <p>Tesla Inc <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a> had yet to win a regulatory nod to proceed with its Shanghai plant expansion plan, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/teslas-china-expansion-hits-speed-bump-amid-industry-overcapacity-2023-06-16/">Reuters reported</a> in June. U.S. luxury EV maker Lucid Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LCID.O" target="_blank">(LCID.O)</a> has also been advised of the low likelihood for approval, sources have told Reuters.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/teslas-china-expansion-hits-speed-bump-amid-industry-overcapacity-2023-06-16/">据路透社 6 月份报道</a>，特斯拉公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a>尚未获得监管机构批准继续其上海工厂扩建计划。消息人士告诉路透社，美国豪华电动汽车制造商 Lucid Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LCID.O" target="_blank">(LCID.O)</a>也被告知获得批准的可能性很低。</p>   <p>To produce and sell cars in China, automakers have to first obtain a permit from the state planner and then the industry ministry. The last EV maker to receive both permits was Shandong-headquartered EV maker Sinogold in May 2019.翻译:要在中国生产和销售汽车，汽车制造商必须首先获得国家规划部门的许可，然后获得工业部的许可。最后一家获得这两项许可证的电动汽车制造商是总部位于山东的电动汽车制造商中金公司，时间为 2019 年 5 月。</p>   <p>Nio ranked ninth in terms of EV sales in the first 10 months in China with 126,067 units, according to data from China Passenger Car Association.翻译:根据中国乘用车联席会的数据，蔚来汽车前 10 个月在中国的电动汽车销量为 126,067 辆，排名第九。</p>   <p>The company has been trying to improve profitability, as it trims its workforce and defers long-term investments to improve efficiency and reduce costs in the face of growing competition.翻译:面对日益激烈的竞争，该公司一直在努力提高盈利能力，通过裁员和推迟长期投资来提高效率和降低成本。</p>    <span>Reporting by Cui Zhuzhu, Zhang Yan and Brenda Goh; Editing by Emelia Sithole-Matarise翻译:崔珠珠、张岩、Brenda Goh报道；编辑：埃米莉亚·西托尔-马塔里斯</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 10:18:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">LSKVDHA3VRNG7GZLYYKH6SR42E</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-adds-nio-list-approved-vehicle-manufactures-website-2023-12-04/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>NIO/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[特斯拉11月份中国制造电动汽车销量下降17.8%，创2022年12月以来最大跌幅]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/uiM34rfeOZTbEyBczcOZ1dRqXGw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4RG2OIRJCVLDDM3JEZVRT3D7QU.jpg" alt="Tesla's electric vehicle (EV) moves on a street in Beijing翻译:特斯拉电动汽车 (EV) 在北京街道上行驶" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Tesla's electric vehicle (EV) moves on a street in Beijing翻译:特斯拉电动汽车 (EV) 在北京街道上行驶, China October 31, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo翻译:2023 年 10 月 31 日，一辆特斯拉电动汽车 (EV) 在中国北京的街道上行驶。路透社/Tingshu Wang/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Sales of U.S. automaker Tesla's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a> China-made electric vehicles (EVs) skidded 17.8% in November from the same month a year earlier, to 82,432 cars, China Passenger Car Association (CPCA) data showed on Monday.翻译:中国乘用车协会 (CPCA) 周一的数据显示，美国汽车制造商特斯拉<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a>的中国制造电动汽车 (EV) 11 月份销量同比下滑 17.8%，至 82,432 辆。</p>   <p>That marked the biggest fall since December 2022 when Tesla's sales of China-made EVs fell 21% on the year as the U.S. automaker reduced output and cut prices to deal with rising inventories and weakening demand.翻译:这是自 2022 年 12 月以来的最大跌幅，当时特斯拉中国制造的电动汽车销量同比下降 21%，原因是这家美国汽车制造商减少产量并降价以应对库存增加和需求疲软。</p>   <p>Deliveries of China-made Model 3 and Model Y cars were however 14.3% higher than in October.翻译:然而，中国制造的 Model 3 和 Model Y 汽车的交付量比 10 月份增长了 14.3%。</p>   <p>Chinese rival BYD <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002594.SZ" target="_blank">(002594.SZ)</a>, with its Dynasty and Ocean series of EVs and petrol-electric hybrid models, saw passenger vehicle deliveries set another record at 301,378 vehicles in November, up 0.09% from October and 31% from a year earlier.翻译:中国竞争对手比亚迪<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002594.SZ" target="_blank">（002594.SZ）</a>凭借其王朝和海洋系列电动汽车和油电混合动力车型，11月份乘用车交付量再创新高，达到301,378辆，环比增长0.09%，同比增长31%。</p>   <p>Tesla has been under pressure to fend off competition in the world's largest auto market, though CEO Elon Musk's charm offensive in China continues unabated.翻译:尽管首席执行官埃隆·马斯克在中国的魅力攻势有增无减，但特斯拉一直面临着抵御全球最大汽车市场竞争的压力。</p>   <p>Musk was among a small group of top U.S. executives who met with Chinese President Xi Jinping before a dinner event on the sidelines of the APEC summit in San Francisco in mid-November.翻译:11 月中旬，在旧金山 APEC 峰会期间举行的晚宴上，马斯克是一小群美国高管中与中国国家主席习近平会面的人之一。</p>   <p>Xi expressed his support for Tesla's development in China, the automaker said in a Weibo post. Musk, in response, said he appreciated the rapid development of China's new energy vehicle sector.翻译:特斯拉在微博中表示，习近平表达了对特斯拉在中国发展的支持。马斯克回应称，他对中国新能源汽车行业的快速发展表示赞赏。</p>   <p>A Tesla-triggered price war in China since the start of the year has roped in more than 40 brands but its share of the country's EV market dropped to 5.78% in October from 8.7% in September, Reuters' calculations based on CPCA data show, as EV sales reached a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/global-ev-sales-stay-strong-china-hits-record-despite-end-subsidies-2023-11-14/">monthly record</a>.翻译:路透社根据CPCA数据计算显示，年初以来特斯拉在中国引发的价格战已经吸引了40多个品牌，但其在中国电动汽车市场的份额从9月份的8.7%下降到10月份的5.78%，随着电动汽车销量创下<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/global-ev-sales-stay-strong-china-hits-record-despite-end-subsidies-2023-11-14/">月度纪录</a>。</p>   <p>Since late October, Tesla has made five upward price adjustments in China where EV demand growth is slowing as consumers favour more affordable plug-in hybrids even with an ever-increasing range of battery-only vehicles.翻译:自10月下旬以来，特斯拉在中国已进行了五次价格上调。中国的电动汽车需求增长正在放缓，因为消费者青睐更实惠的插电式混合动力汽车，尽管纯电池汽车的种类不断增加。</p>   <p>Li Auto <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2015.HK" target="_blank">(2015.HK)</a> last month said mass production and delivery of its <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-li-auto-says-start-mass-production-its-first-ev-feb-2023-11-17/">first full EV</a> are scheduled for February.翻译:理想汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2015.HK" target="_blank">（2015.HK）</a>上个月表示，其<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-li-auto-says-start-mass-production-its-first-ev-feb-2023-11-17/">首款纯电动汽车</a>计划于 2 月份量产和交付。</p>   <p>Smartphone maker Xiaomi <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/1810.HK" target="_blank">(1810.HK)</a> has also moved closer to EV production, with a unit of automaker BAIC Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/1958.HK" target="_blank">(1958.HK)</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/baic-unit-applies-manufacturing-approval-xiaomi-branded-evs-2023-11-15/">applying</a> for regulatory approval to build two Xiaomi-branded cars.翻译:智能手机制造商小米<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/1810.HK" target="_blank">（1810.HK）</a>也向电动汽车生产迈进，汽车制造商北汽集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/1958.HK" target="_blank">（1958.HK）</a>旗下子公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/baic-unit-applies-manufacturing-approval-xiaomi-branded-evs-2023-11-15/">正在申请</a>监管部门批准生产两款小米品牌汽车。</p>    <span>Reporting by Qiaoyi Li, Zhang Yan and Brenda Goh; Editing by Bernadette Baum, Kirsten Donovan翻译:李巧仪、张岩、Brenda Goh 报道；责任编辑：伯纳黛特·鲍姆、克尔斯滕·多诺万</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 10:10:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">N5TBUHR67JJJ7NYTBQRB66OKNQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/teslas-china-made-ev-sales-fall-178-nov-biggest-drop-since-dec-2022-2023-12-04/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>TESLA/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[白俄罗斯总统卢卡申科回国寻求加强双边关系]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/mHwfHz1W9tA-yVo7ed_VVRBF548=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5Q4XQREUNRP45DNOBGBN7CDL6U.jpg" alt="Chinese&nbsp;President Xi Jinping and&nbsp;Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko at a welcome ceremony in Beijing翻译:中国国家主席习近平与白俄罗斯总统卢卡申科在北京举行欢迎仪式" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese&nbsp;President Xi Jinping and&nbsp;Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko review the honour guard during a welcome ceremony at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, China March 1, 2023. cnsphoto via REUTERS/File photo翻译:2023年3月1日，中国国家主席习近平和白俄罗斯总统亚历山大·卢卡申科在中国北京人民大会堂举行的欢迎仪式上检阅仪仗队。 cnsphoto via REUTERS/资料图片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Belarussian President Alexander Lukashenko met China's leader Xi Jinping in Beijing on Monday for the second time this year, with the diplomatically isolated leader talking up his country's economic ties to the Asian giant amid biting Western sanctions.翻译:白俄罗斯总统亚历山大·卢卡申科周一在北京会见了中国领导人习近平，这是今年第二次，这位在外交上孤立的领导人在西方严厉的制裁下谈论了白俄罗斯与这个亚洲巨人的经济关系。</p>   <p>The close ally of Russian President Vladimir Putin is on a "working visit" to the Chinese capital and was received by Xi at the Diaoyutai State Guesthouse for a "working lunch" and three hours of talks, according to Belarussian state media.翻译:据白俄罗斯官方媒体报道，俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京的亲密盟友正在对中国首都进行“工作访问”，并在钓鱼台国宾馆受到习近平的接见，共进“工作午餐”并进行了三个小时的会谈。</p>   <p>Lukashenko, the president of Belarus since 1994, backed Russia's invasion of Ukraine in February 2022 by allowing Moscow to use its territory to launch the war, but is faced with a crippled economy that is heavily reliant on trade with Russia.翻译:卢卡申科自 1994 年起担任白俄罗斯总统，支持俄罗斯于 2022 年 2 月入侵乌克兰，允许莫斯科使用其领土发动战争，但卢卡申科面临着严重依赖与俄罗斯贸易的严重受损的经济。</p>   <p>"China is willing to continue to strengthen strategic cooperation with Belarus, promote practical cooperation and deepen bilateral relations," Xi told his guest, according to Chinese state news agency Xinhua.翻译:据中国国家通讯社新华社报道，习近平对客人表示：“中方愿同白俄罗斯继续加强战略合作，推进务实合作，深化双边关系。”</p>   <p>"The two sides should implement projects like the China-Belarus Industrial Park and promote more achievements in China-Belarus industrial cooperation," Xinhua reported Xi as saying.翻译:新华社报道习近平表示，“双方要落实好中白工业园等项目，推动中白工业合作取得更多成果。”</p>   <p>The world's second-largest economy was Belarus' seventh largest trading partner in 2021 and before the war in Ukraine, according U.N. Comtrade data. China was Belarus' second-largest import partner, but the Eastern European country bought around three-quarters less from China than it did from Russia.翻译:根据联合国商品贸易统计数据库 (UN Comtrade) 的数据，2021 年和乌克兰战争之前，世界第二大经济体是白俄罗斯的第七大贸易伙伴。中国是白俄罗斯的第二大进口伙伴，但这个东欧国家从中国购买的商品比从俄罗斯购买的商品少约四分之三。</p>   <p>Lukashenko highlighted the scope to grow his country's commercial ties with China, Belarussian state media said, and lauded the "more than 120" two-way visits made by Chinese and Belarussian parties since the leaders last met in March.翻译:白俄罗斯官方媒体称，卢卡申科强调了发展白俄罗斯与中国商业关系的范围，并赞扬自3月份两国领导人上次会晤以来，中国和白俄罗斯双方进行了“120多次”双向访问。</p>   <p>Quickening the pace of cooperation between China and Belarus was "the only issue" Lukashenko wished to discuss with Xi on this visit to the Chines capital, the report added.翻译:报道补充说，加快中白合作步伐是卢卡申科此次访问中国首都“唯一希望与习近平讨论的问题”。</p>   <p>Xi told Lukashenko that both countries should improve cross-border transport facilitation and promote economic and trade initiatives like the China-Belarus Industrial Park, as well as people-to-people exchanges, according to Xinhua.翻译:据新华社报道，习近平对卢卡申科表示，两国要改善跨境交通便利化，推动中白工业园等经贸项目和人文交流。</p>   <p>Belarus faces sanctions from the United States, European Union, Britain, Canada, the Netherlands, and a number of other countries over its support of Russia's invasion of Ukraine and longer standing issues surrounding political repression.翻译:白俄罗斯因支持俄罗斯入侵乌克兰以及围绕政治镇压的长期问题而面临美国、欧盟、英国、加拿大、荷兰和其他一些国家的制裁。</p>   <p>Lukashenko told Xi that the world would thank China for its efforts to bring countries into his flagship Belt and Road Initiative, "unlike Western countries that are trying to cut everything into pieces," Belarussian state media reported.翻译:据白俄罗斯官方媒体报道，卢卡申科告诉习近平，世界将感谢中国为将各国纳入其旗舰“一带一路”倡议所做的努力，“这与西方国家试图将一切分割成碎片的做法不同”。</p>   <p>Xi offered to enhance coordination and cooperation between China and Belarus in multilateral mechanisms such as the United Nations and the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation, the Xinhua report said.翻译:新华社报道称，习近平提出加强中白在联合国、上海合作组织等多边机制中的协调与合作。</p>   <p>"China and Belarus are important forces in the reform and construction of the global governance system," it quoted Xi as saying.翻译:习近平表示，“中白是全球治理体系改革和建设的重要力量”。</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Ella Cao and Lidia Kelly; Editing by Kim Coghill翻译:编辑：金·科吉尔 and Jamie Freed</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 08:46:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">HUVTCCBLWFJ4NKHIGSK5XSSLHI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-willing-continue-strengthening-cooperation-with-belarus-state-media-2023-12-04/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Joe Cash, Liz Lee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>BELARUS/ (UPDATE 2, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
