<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub-five-red.vercel.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 11:33:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grifols 在第三季度转向净利润后上调 2023 年指引]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/MItrYUcy7UsQu21mIqafX9X4t8o=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SHVUXTJLUBI5NLZJVKY7C22NSQ.jpg" alt="The logo of the Spanish pharmaceuticals company Grifols is pictured on their headquarters' building in Sant Cugat del Valles" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of the Spanish pharmaceuticals company Grifols is pictured on their headquarters' building in Sant Cugat del Valles, near Barcelona, Spain, September 17, 2021. REUTERS/Albert Gea/File photo翻译:2021 年 9 月 17 日，西班牙制药公司 Grifols 的标志出现在其位于西班牙巴塞罗那附近圣库加特德尔巴列斯的总部大楼上。路透社/Albert Gea/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Spanish drugmaker Grifols <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GRLS.MC" target="_blank">(GRLS.MC)</a> on Thursday reported a third-quarter net profit of 60 million euros ($63.64 million) after a loss in the first half of the year.翻译:西班牙制药商 Grifols <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GRLS.MC" target="_blank">(GRLS.MC)</a>周四公布，继上半年亏损后，第三季度净利润为 6000 万欧元（合 6364 万美元）。</p>   <p>The company lifted its 2023 guidance for adjusted earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortisation to 1.45 billion euros from a previous range of 1.40-1.45 billion, though it kept total revenue growth expectation at 10-12%, when excluding currency swings.翻译:该公司将 2023 年调整后息税折旧及摊销前利润指引从之前的 1.40-14.5 亿欧元上调至 14.5 亿欧元，但在排除汇率波动的情况下，将总收入增长预期保持在 10-12%。</p>   <p>Grifols' third-quarter revenue reached 1.6 billion euros.翻译:Grifols第三季度营收达到16亿欧元。</p>   <p>($1 = 0.9435 euros)翻译:（1 美元 = 0.9435 欧元）</p>   <p>(This story has been corrected to compare with the first half of 2023, not the year-earlier quarter, in paragraph 1, and to say 1.6 billion euros in revenue in the third quarter, not the first nine months of the year, in paragraph 3)翻译:（这个故事已被更正，以与第 1 段中的 2023 年上半年（而不是去年同期）进行比较，并说第三季度的收入为 16 亿欧元，而不是今年前 9 个月，第 1 段3）</p>    <span>Reporting by Marta Serafinko, editing by Inti Landauro翻译:玛尔塔·塞拉芬科 (Marta Serafinko) 报道，英蒂·兰道罗 (Inti Landauro) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 11:26:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">DAP6O7ECJFIH5HI5YA6PJWDHX4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/grifols-shares-soar-after-2023-profit-outlook-upgrade-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GRIFOLS</category>
                
                <category>RESULTS/ (CORRECTED, URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[气候的“第二十二条军规”：减少污染使地球升温]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/bnas4cCzJsUyJCkQlkZ1Mxvman8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YCHI7RNDAJNMTJFB4U3OCDATPY.jpg" alt="Heatwave in Beijing, China" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People wearing sun protection gear amid a heatwave walk on a street in Beijing, China July 1, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo翻译:2023 年 7 月 1 日，中国北京，穿着防晒装备的人们在热浪中行走在街道上。路透社/Tingshu Wang/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/bGp6KbigmALh-83WgkNLnPyXWmA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MWI6S42EPVIV3ATQOJRI3TYJJY.jpg" alt="People drive and ride amid the smog in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People drive and ride amid the smog in Beijing, China, February 14, 2017. REUTERS/Jason Lee/File Photo翻译:2017 年 2 月 14 日，中国北京，人们在雾霾中驾车骑行。REUTERS/Jason Lee/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Hs9hrUQzB4UkLqHzibXXCIP6jW0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/EKHNJA5JOVKRDLNJNTZVRZLDD4.jpg" alt="Cracks run through the partially dried-up river bed of the Gan River, a tributary to Poyang Lake during a regional drought in Nanchang" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Cracks run through the partially dried-up river bed of the Gan River, a tributary to Poyang Lake during a regional drought in Nanchang, Jiangxi province, China, August 28, 2022.  REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2022年8月28日，中国江西省南昌市发生区域性干旱，赣江是鄱阳湖的支流，部分干涸的河床出现裂缝。路透社/Thomas Peter/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/LW6WZbDrs8lrTOQwiLmbdwbU09s=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BLPK3DU77BI2DN3BMJHWYH4FQY.jpg" alt="Vehicles drive amid heavy smog in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Vehicles drive amid heavy smog in Beijing, China, November 30, 2015. REUTERS/Jason Lee/File Photo翻译:2015 年 11 月 30 日，中国北京，车辆在浓雾中行驶。REUTERS/Jason Lee/资料照片</figcaption></figure>                   <p>Air pollution, a global scourge that kills millions of people a year, is shielding us from the full force of the sun. Getting rid of it will accelerate climate change.翻译:空气污染是一种全球性的祸害，每年导致数百万人死亡，它使我们免受阳光的全部伤害。摆脱它会加速气候变化。</p>   <p>That's the unpalatable conclusion reached by scientists poring over the results of China's decade-long and highly effective "war on pollution", according to six leading climate experts.翻译:六位顶尖气候专家表示，这是科学家在研究中国长达十年且卓有成效的“污染战”成果后得出的令人不快的结论。</p>   <p>The drive to banish pollution, caused mainly by sulphur dioxide (SO2) spewed from coal plants, has cut SO2 emissions by close to 90% and saved hundreds of thousands of lives, Chinese official data and <a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.1907956116" target="_blank">health studies</a> show.翻译:中国官方数据和<a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.1907956116" target="_blank">健康研究</a>显示，消除主要由燃煤电厂排放的二氧化硫 (SO2) 造成的污染的努力已将二氧化硫排放量减少了近 90%，并挽救了数十万人的生命。</p>   <p>Yet stripped of its toxic shield, which scatters and reflects solar radiation, China's average temperatures have gone up by 0.7 degrees Celsius since 2014, triggering fiercer heatwaves, according to a Reuters review of meteorological data and the scientists interviewed.翻译:然而，根据路透社对气象数据和接受采访的科学家的评论，自从2014年以来，中国的平均气温已经上升了0.7摄氏度，引发了更猛烈的热浪。</p>   <p>"It's this Catch-22," said Patricia Quinn, an atmospheric chemist at the U.S.翻译:我们 National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), speaking about cleaning up sulphur pollution globally. "We want to clean up our air for air quality purposes but, by doing that, we're increasing warming."</p>   <p>The removal of the air pollution - a term scientists call "unmasking" - may have had a greater effect on temperatures in some industrial Chinese cities over the last decade than the warming from greenhouse gases themselves, the scientists said.翻译:科学家们表示，过去十年，空气污染的消除——科学家称之为“揭露”——对中国一些工业城市气温的影响可能比温室气体本身造成的变暖更大。</p>   <p>Other highly polluted parts of the world, such as India and the Middle East, would see similar jumps in warming if they follow China's lead in cleaning the skies of sulphur dioxide and the polluting aerosols it forms, the experts warned.翻译:专家警告说，印度和中东等世界其他污染严重的地区如果效仿中国的做法，清除天空中的二氧化硫及其形成的污染性气溶胶，也会出现类似的变暖现象。</p>   <p>They said efforts to improve air quality could actually push the world into catastrophic warming scenarios and irreversible impacts.翻译:他们表示，改善空气质量的努力实际上可能会将世界推向灾难性的变暖情景和不可逆转的影响。</p>   <p>"Aerosols are masking one-third of the heating of the planet," said Paulo Artaxo, an environmental physicist and lead author of the chapter on short-lived climate pollutants in the most recent round of reports by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC), completed this year.翻译:“气溶胶掩盖了地球三分之一的热量，”环境物理学家、政府间气候变化专门委员会 (IPCC) 最近一轮报告中短期气候污染物一章的主要作者保罗·阿塔索 (Paulo Artaxo) 说。 ），今年完成。</p>   <p>"If you implement technologies to reduce air pollution, this will accelerate – very significantly – global warming in the short term."翻译:“如果采用减少空气污染的技术，短期内将会非常显着地加速全球变暖。”</p>   <p>The Chinese and Indian environment ministries didn't immediately respond to requests for comment on the effects of pollution unmasking.翻译:中国和印度环境部没有立即回应就污染暴露的影响发表评论的请求。</p>   <p>The link between reducing sulphur dioxide and warming was flagged by the IPCC in <a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg1/chapter/chapter-7/" target="_blank">a 2021 report</a> which concluded that, without the solar shield of SO2 pollution, the global average temperature would already have risen by 1.6 degrees Celsius above preindustrial levels.翻译:IPCC 在<a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg1/chapter/chapter-7/" target="_blank">2021 年的一份报告</a>中指出了减少二氧化硫与变暖之间的联系，该报告得出的结论是，如果没有二氧化硫污染的遮阳罩，全球平均气温将比工业化前水平上升 1.6 摄氏度。</p>   <p>That misses the world's goal of limiting warming to 1.5C, beyond which scientists predict irreversible and catastrophic changes to the climate, according to the IPCC, which pegs the current level at 1.1C.翻译:这没有达到将升温限制在 1.5 摄氏度的世界目标，根据 IPCC 的说法，科学家预测，如果超过这个目标，气候将发生不可逆转的灾难性变化，目前的升温水平将控制在 1.1 摄氏度。</p>   <p>The Reuters review of the Chinese data provides the most detailed picture yet of how this phenomenon is playing out in the real world, drawing on previously unreported numbers on changes in temperatures and SO2 emissions over the past decade and corroborated by environmental scientists.翻译:路透社对中国数据的审查提供了迄今为止这一现象在现实世界中如何发生的最详细的图景，该数据利用了过去十年中温度和二氧化硫排放量变化的先前未报告的数据，并得到了环境科学家的证实。</p>   <p>Reuters interviewed 12 scientists in total on the phenomenon of unmasking globally, including four who have acted as authors or reviewers of sections on air pollution in IPCC reports.翻译:路透社就全球揭秘现象总共采访了12位科学家，其中4位曾担任IPCC报告中空气污染部分的作者或审稿人。</p>   <p>They said there was no suggestion among climate experts that the world should let-up on fighting air pollution, a clear and present danger that the World Health Organization says causes about 7 million premature deaths a year, mostly in poorer countries.翻译:他们表示，气候专家并没有建议世界应该放松对抗空气污染的力度，世界卫生组织表示，空气污染是一种明显而现实的危险，每年导致约 700 万人过早死亡，其中大多数是在较贫穷的国家。</p>   <p>Instead they stressed the need for more aggressive action to cut emissions of climate-warming greenhouse gases, with reducing methane seen as one of the most promising paths to offset pollution unmasking in the short term.翻译:相反，他们强调需要采取更积极的行动来减少导致气候变暖的温室气体的排放，减少甲烷被视为短期内抵消污染的最有希望的途径之一。</p>    <h 1="">XI BATTLES 'AIRPOCALYPSE'</h>  <p>President Xi Jinping pledged to tackle pollution when he took power in 2012 following decades of coal-burning that had helped turn China into "the factory of the world". The following year, as record smog in Beijing inspired "Airpocalypse" newspaper headlines, the government unveiled what scientists called China's version of the U.S.翻译:我们 Clean Air Act.</p>   <p>On March 5, 2014, a week after Xi went on a walkabout during another extreme bout of smog in the capital, the government officially declared a war on pollution at the National People's Congress.翻译:2014年3月5日，习近平在首都另一场严重雾霾天气中巡视一周后，政府在全国人民代表大会上正式向污染宣战。</p>   <p>Under the new rules, power plants and steel mills were forced to switch to lower-sulphur coal. Hundreds of inefficient factories were shuttered, and vehicle fuel standards toughened up. While coal continues to be China's largest power source, smokestack scrubbers now strip out most SO2 emissions.翻译:根据新规定，发电厂和钢厂被迫改用低硫煤炭。数百家效率低下的工厂被关闭，汽车燃料标准也更加严格。虽然煤炭仍然是中国最大的能源，但烟囱洗涤器现在消除了大部分二氧化硫排放。</p>   <p>China's SO2 emissions had decreased from a 2006 peak of at nearly 26 million metric tons to 20.4 million tons in 2013 thanks to more gradual emissions restrictions. But with the war on pollution, those emissions had plummeted by about 87% to 2.7 million metric tons by 2021.翻译:由于更加渐进的排放限制，中国的二氧化硫排放量已从 2006 年近 2600 万吨的峰值下降到 2013 年的 2040 万吨。但随着对污染的战争，到 2021 年，这些排放量已大幅下降约 87%，至 270 万吨。</p>   <p>The drop in pollution was accompanied by a leap in warming - the nine years since 2014 have seen national average annual temperatures in China of 10.34C, up more than 0.7C compared with the 2001-2010 period, according to Reuters calculations based on yearly weather reports published by the China Meteorological Administration.翻译:污染的下降伴随着气温的急剧上升——据路透社根据每年的天气情况计算，自2014年以来的9年里，中国全国年平均气温为10.34摄氏度，比2001年至2010年期间上升了0.7摄氏度以上。中国气象局发布的报告。</p>   <p>Scientific estimates vary as to how much of that rise comes from unmasking versus greenhouse gas emissions or natural climate variations like El Nino.翻译:对于这一上升有多少是由于温室气体排放或厄尔尼诺等自然气候变化造成的，科学估计各不相同。</p>   <p>The impacts are more acute at a local level near the pollution source. Almost immediately, China saw big warming jumps from its unmasking of pollution near heavy industrial regions, according to climate scientist Yangyang Xu at Texas A&amp;M University, who models the impact of aerosols on the climate.翻译:在靠近污染源的地方，影响更为严重。德克萨斯农工大学的气候科学家杨阳徐对气溶胶对气候的影响进行了模拟，他表示，由于揭露了重工业区附近的污染，中国几乎立即就看到了气温大幅上升。</p>   <p>Xu told Reuters he estimated that unmasking had caused temperatures near the cities of Chongqing and Wuhan, long known as China's "furnaces", to rise by almost 1C since sulphur emissions peaked in the mid-2000s.翻译:徐告诉路透社，他估计，自2000年代中期硫排放量达到峰值以来，揭开口罩导致长期以来被称为中国“火炉”的重庆和武汉附近的气温上升了近1摄氏度。</p>   <p>During heatwaves, the unmasking effect can be even more pronounced. Laura Wilcox, a climate scientist who studies the effects of aerosols at Britain's University of Reading, said a computer simulation showed that the rapid decline in SO2 in China could raise temperatures on extreme-heat days by as much as 2C.翻译:在热浪期间，暴露效应可能更加明显。英国雷丁大学研究气溶胶影响的气候科学家劳拉·威尔科克斯(Laura Wilcox)表示，计算机模拟显示，中国二氧化硫浓度的迅速下降可能会使极端炎热天气的气温升高多达2摄氏度。</p>   <p>"Those are big differences, especially for somewhere like China, where heat is already pretty dangerous," she said.翻译:“这些差异很大，特别是对于中国这样的地方来说，那里的高温已经相当危险了，”她说。</p>   <p>Indeed, heatwaves in China have been particularly ferocious this year. A town in the northwestern region of Xinjiang saw temperatures of 52.2C (126F) in July, shattering the national temperature record of 50.3C set in 2015.翻译:事实上，今年中国的热浪尤其猛烈。新疆西北部地区的一个城镇 7 月份的气温达到 52.2 摄氏度（126 华氏度），打破了 2015 年创下的 50.3 摄氏度的全国气温记录。</p>   <p>Beijing also experienced a record heatwave, with temperatures topping 35C (95F) for more than four weeks.翻译:北京也经历了创纪录的热浪，气温超过 35 摄氏度（95 华氏度）长达四个星期多。</p>    <h 1="">INDIA AND MIDDLE EAST</h>  <p>The effects of sulphur unmasking are most pronounced in developing countries, as the U.S.翻译:我们 and most of Europe cleaned up their skies decades ago. While the heat rise from sulphur cleanup is strongest locally, the effects can be felt in far-distant regions. <a href="https://yangyangxu.weebly.com/uploads/8/8/2/1/88214376/wang2021erl.pdf" target="_blank">One 2021 study</a> co-authored by Xu found that a decrease in European aerosol emissions since the 1980s may have shifted weather patterns in Northern China.</p>   <p>In India, sulphur pollution is still rising, roughly doubling in the last two decades, according to calculations by NOAA researchers based on figures from the U.S.翻译:我们-funded Community Emissions Data System.</p>   <p>In 2020, when that pollution plummeted due to COVID lockdowns, ground temperatures in India were the eighth warmest on record, 0.29 C higher than the 1981-2010 average, despite the cooling effects of the La Nina climate pattern, according to the India Meteorological Department.翻译:据印度气象部门称，2020年，尽管拉尼娜气候模式产生了降温作用，但由于新冠疫情封锁，污染大幅下降，印度的地面温度仍处于有记录以来第八高的水平，比1981年至2010年的平均温度高出0.29摄氏度。</p>   <p>India aims for an air cleanup like China's, and in 2019 launched its National Clean Air Programme to reduce pollution by 40% in more than 100 cities by 2026.翻译:印度的目标是像中国一样净化空气，并于 2019 年启动了国家清洁空气计划，到 2026 年将 100 多个城市的污染减少 40%。</p>   <p>Once polluted regions in India or the Middle East improve their air quality by abandoning fossil fuels and transitioning to green energy sources, they too will lose their shield of sulphates, scientists said.翻译:科学家表示，一旦印度或中东的污染地区通过放弃化石燃料并转向绿色能源来改善空气质量，它们也将失去硫酸盐的保护。</p>   <p>"You stop your anthropogenic activities for a brief moment of time and the atmosphere cleans up very, very quickly and the temperatures jump instantaneously," added Sergey Osipov, a climate modeller at the King Abdullah University of Science and Technology in Saudi Arabia.翻译:沙特阿拉伯阿卜杜拉国王科技大学的气候模型师谢尔盖·奥西波夫补充道：“如果人类活动暂时停止，大气就会非常非常快地净化，气温也会瞬间上升。”</p>    <h 1="">OFFSETTING WITH METHANE?</h>  <p>As the implications of the pollution unmasking become more apparent, experts are casting around for methods to counter the associated warming.翻译:随着污染暴露的影响变得越来越明显，专家们正在寻找应对相关变暖的方法。</p>   <p>One proposal called <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/cop/can-solar-geoengineering-stop-global-warming-2023-11-02/">"solar radiation management"</a> envisions deliberately injecting sulphur aerosols into the atmosphere to cool temperatures. But many scientists worry that the approach could unleash unintended consequences.翻译:一项名为<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/cop/can-solar-geoengineering-stop-global-warming-2023-11-02/">“太阳辐射管理”</a>的提案设想故意将硫气溶胶注入大气中以降低温度。但许多科学家担心这种方法可能会带来意想不到的后果。</p>   <p>A more mainstream plan is to curb methane emissions. This is seen as the quickest way to tame global temperatures because the effects of the gas in the atmosphere last only a decade or so, so cutting emissions now would deliver results within a decade. Carbon dioxide, by comparison, persists for centuries.翻译:更主流的计划是遏制甲烷排放。这被认为是控制全球气温的最快方法，因为大气中气体的影响仅持续十年左右，因此现在减少排放将在十年内取得成果。相比之下，二氧化碳可以持续存在几个世纪。</p>   <p>As of 2019, methane had caused about 0.5C in warming compared with preindustrial levels, according to IPCC figures.翻译:根据IPCC的数据，截至2019年，与工业化前水平相比，甲烷导致气温升高约0.5摄氏度。</p>   <p>While more than 100 countries have pledged to reduce methane emissions by 30% by the end of the decade, few have gone further than drawing up "action plans" and "pathways" to cuts. China - the world's biggest emitter - has yet to publish its plan.翻译:尽管已有 100 多个国家承诺到本世纪末将甲烷排放量减少 30%，但除了制定减排“行动计划”和“途径”之外，很少有国家采取了进一步行动。中国——世界上最大的排放国——尚未公布其计划。</p>   <p>By targeting methane, the world could mitigate the warming effect of the reduction in pollution and potentially avert catastrophic consequences, said Michael Diamond, an atmospheric scientist at Florida State University.翻译:佛罗里达州立大学大气科学家迈克尔·戴蒙德表示，通过瞄准甲烷，世界可以减轻污染减少带来的变暖效应，并有可能避免灾难性后果。</p>   <p>"This doesn't doom us to going above 1.5 degrees Celsius if we clean up the air."翻译:“如果我们净化空气，这并不意味着我们的气温会上升到 1.5 摄氏度以上。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Jake Spring in Sao Paulo and David Stanway in Singapore; Additional reporting by Sakshi Dayal in New Delhi; Editing by Katy Daigle and Pravin Char翻译:Jake Spring 在圣保罗和 David Stanway 在新加坡的报道； Sakshi Dayal 在新德里的补充报道；凯蒂·戴格尔和普拉文·查尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 11:06:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">I5BYFE7XJJLOZIGQJFSOXT6G7E</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/cop/climates-catch-22-cutting-pollution-heats-up-planet-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jake Spring, David Stanway]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CLIMATE</category>
                
                <category>CHANGE/POLLUTION (REPEAT, INSIGHT, TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EQT 重启收购 Global Switch 谈判 - 彭博新闻]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>EQT AB <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/EQTAB.ST" target="_blank">(EQTAB.ST)</a> has resumed its efforts to acquire Global Switch Holdings Ltd. in a deal that could value the data centre company at around $6.5 billion, Bloomberg News reported on Thursday citing people familiar with the matter.翻译:据彭博社周四援引知情人士的话报道，EQT AB <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/EQTAB.ST" target="_blank">(EQTAB.ST)</a>已恢复收购 Global Switch Holdings Ltd. 的努力，这笔交易可能使这家数据中心公司的估值达到约 65 亿美元。</p>    <span>Reporting by Devika Nair in Bengaluru翻译:Devika Nair 班加罗尔报道</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 10:59:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">SYTRUSVV3FLRZNZFPAK2X6Q5BE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/eqt-revives-talks-acquire-global-switch-bloomberg-news-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL SWITCH</category>
                
                <category>M&#38;A/EQT AB (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[出于安全和权利担忧，香港举办同性恋运动会首届亚洲站]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/PIm2J1igCwc5ZvlvScTNTZxUr_8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JX3WNTJQFFL3TJPAYWYQHDD34Q.jpg" alt="Volunteer attends a news conference ahead of the Gay Games in Hong Kong" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A volunteer attends a news conference ahead of the Gay Games in Hong Kong, China November 2, 2023. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu翻译:2023 年 11 月 2 日，一名志愿者参加中国香港同性恋运动会前的新闻发布会。 REUTERS/Tyrone Siu</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/DBu2jK4Si9WhUDjdkNj3qpBE_DA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/IGDT6XIBOVIKLM3Y2K2YTGXVHE.jpg" alt="Participants pose for photos at a news conference ahead of the Gay Games in Hong Kong" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Participants pose for photos at a news conference ahead of the Gay Games in Hong Kong, China November 2, 2023. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu翻译:2023 年 11 月 2 日，参与者在中国香港同性恋运动会前的新闻发布会上摆姿势拍照。REUTERS/Tyrone Siu</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ZZS4A9rY7KBbs2lv9ZxGkYuzq0I=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VALVMVFHVJNB3LUSBTNPJW5WHQ.jpg" alt="Volunteer walks past the Gay Games logo at a news conference in Hong Kong" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A volunteer walks past the Gay Games logo at a news conference in Hong Kong, China November 2, 2023. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu翻译:2023 年 11 月 2 日，在中国香港举行的新闻发布会上，一名志愿者走过同性恋运动会标志。REUTERS/Tyrone Siu</figcaption></figure>                 <p>Hong Kong will be the first Asian city to hold the Gay Games from Friday, co-hosting them with a Mexican city in one of the financial hub's biggest events since COVID-19, despite ban calls from rights activists and lawmakers opposing LGBTQ efforts.翻译:尽管权利活动人士和立法者呼吁禁止 LGBTQ 活动，但香港将从周五起成为第一个举办同性恋运动会的亚洲城市，与墨西哥城市共同主办这一金融中心自 COVID-19 以来最大的活动之一。</p>   <p>The Chinese-ruled city has no law against discrimination based on sexual orientation and does not recognise same-sex marriage, but its LGBTQ community has scored some legal wins this year.翻译:这个中国统治的城市没有针对性取向歧视的法律，也不承认同性婚姻，但 LGBTQ 群体今年取得了一些法律胜利。</p>   <p>The most significant was a September ruling by its top court that set a two-year deadline for the government to establish a legal framework to recognise same-sex unions.翻译:最重要的是最高法院九月份的一项裁决，规定政府在两年内建立承认同性婚姻的法律框架。</p>   <p>More than 2,300 athletes from 45 countries, including Britain, China, South Korea and the United States, are expected to participate, the organisers, the Gay Games Hong Kong (GGHK) said.翻译:主办方香港同性恋运动会（GGHK）表示，预计将有来自英国、中国、韩国和美国等 45 个国家的 2,300 多名运动员参加。</p>   <p>"Not only have we been able to introduce the games to the region, we have the highest number of participants ever from Asia join the Gay Games in its 41-year history," Alan Lang, the body's co-chair, told a press conference on Thursday.翻译:该机构联合主席艾伦·朗 (Alan Lang) 在新闻发布会上表示：“我们不仅能够将同性恋运动会引入该地区，而且我们的同性恋运动会 41 年历史上参加人数是有史以来最多的。”星期四。</p>   <p>The government in the former British colony has approved the Gay Games, which run until Nov. 11, but advised organisers to follow laws and regulations in a "safe and orderly manner".
"Our aim is not to advocate for any specific political or legislative changes but to provide a platform for sports, arts, and culture that promotes inclusivity and diversity," the games' organising committee said this week.翻译:这个前英国殖民地政府已批准举办同性恋运动会，该运动会将持续到 11 月 11 日，但建议组织者“安全有序”地遵守法律法规。奥运会组委会本周表示：“我们的目标不是倡导任何具体的政治或立法变革，而是为体育、艺术和文化提供一个促进包容性和多样性的平台。”</p>   <p>Among the sports and cultural events to feature are some of Chinese origin, such as dragon boat racing and mahjong, while a new trail running event is to be held on mountainous Lantau island.翻译:体育和文化活动中包括一些起源于中国的活动，如龙舟赛和麻将，而一项新的越野跑活动将在山区的大屿山举行。</p>   <p>Worries about the national security law Beijing recently clamped on Hong Kong will keep Taiwan's delegation away, however.翻译:然而，对北京最近对香港实施的国家安全法的担忧将使台湾代表团望而却步。</p>   <p>"The main reason ... this time is that the safety of Taiwanese players cannot be guaranteed," said Yang Chih-chun, of Taiwan's Gay Sports and Movement Association, adding that it had been "a painful decision" not to send the athletes.翻译:台湾同性恋运动运动协会的杨志春说：“这次的主要原因是台湾运动员的安全无法得到保障。”他补充说，不派运动员参加是“一个痛苦的决定” 。</p>   <p>Taiwan's athletes will go instead to Mexico's western city of Guadalajara, which is co-hosting the games at the same time.翻译:台湾运动员将前往同时主办奥运会的墨西哥西部城市瓜达拉哈拉。</p>   <p>Several Hong Kong lawmakers have voiced public opposition to the event, saying it posed threats to national security threats, subverted traditional Chinese family values and followed a "western ideology".翻译:多名香港立法会议员公开反对这一活动，称其对国家安全构成威胁、颠覆中国传统家庭价值观并追随“西方意识形态”。</p>   <p>Five Hong Kong human rights activists also called for the games to be cancelled, saying the organisers "aligned themselves with pro-authoritarian figures responsible for widespread persecution" in Hong Kong.翻译:五名香港人权活动人士也呼吁取消奥运会，称组织者“与对香港广泛迫害负有责任的亲独裁人士结盟”。</p>   <p>"We've always respected the law and followed the law... We hope that all of our participants will follow Hong Kong's laws and culture," GGHK's co-chair Lisa Lam said on Thursday.翻译:“我们一直尊重法律并遵守法律……我们希望所有参与者都遵守香港的法律和文化，”GGHK联合主席林丽莎周四表示。</p>   <p>Many events are to be held at private venues, universities or schools, with the opening and closing functions scheduled in a stadium in the busy commercial district of Wan Chai.翻译:许多活动将在私人场地、大学或学校举行，开幕式和闭幕式均安排在湾仔繁忙商业区的体育场举行。</p>   <p>Beijing's national security law, imposed in 2020 after months of anti-government protests, punishes acts such as subversion, collusion with foreign forces and terrorism with terms of up to life in prison.翻译:经过数月的反政府抗议后，北京于 2020 年实施了国家安全法，对颠覆、勾结外国势力和恐怖主义等行为最高可判处无期徒刑。</p>   <p>Hong Kong and mainland China have said the security law has brought stability after the 2019 protests.翻译:香港和中国内地均表示，国安法在 2019 年抗议活动后带来了稳定。</p>    <span>Reporting by Jessie Pang; Editing by Farah Master and Clarence Fernandez翻译:彭杰西报道；法拉·马斯特和克拉伦斯·费尔南德斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 10:55:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">QJHG56DWYFKJJHQEQXG3RVV5KA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/hong-kong-holds-first-asian-leg-gay-games-amid-security-rights-concerns-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jessie Pang]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HONGKONG</category>
                
                <category>GAYGAMES/ (UPDATE 1, PIX,TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着美联储满足全球利率见顶的希望，股票和债券上涨]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Markets trim bets on Dec, Jan Fed rate hikes翻译:市场削减对美联储12月和1月加息的押注</li>  <li>Markets now see rate cuts beginning June 2024翻译:市场预计 2024 年 6 月开始降息</li>  <li>Bank of England meets; Apple results due later in the day翻译:英格兰银行召开会议；苹果结果将于当天晚些时候公布</li> </ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0QB0fEVHqdBYDtprgBfJlyVUmCQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5ZYQDXROBZJMBENNFMBY4ZDOGM.jpg" alt="German share price index DAX graph is pictured at the stock exchange in Frankfurt" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The German share price index DAX graph is pictured at the stock exchange in Frankfurt, Germany, September 29, 2023.  REUTERS/Staff/File Photo翻译:德国股价指数DAX图拍摄于2023年9月29日德国法兰克福证券交易所。REUTERS/Staff/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/VegWflUIbCu2Z2h7ptMLquGa9Z4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/P62BV2YWVZM3NBX7476XGD46NY.jpg" alt="A man works at the Tokyo Stock Exchange after market opens in Tokyo" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A man works at the Tokyo Stock Exchange after market opens in Tokyo, Japan October 2, 2020. REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/File Photo翻译:2020 年 10 月 2 日，日本东京股市开市后，一名男子在东京证券交易所工作。路透社/Kim Kyung-Hoon/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/OgTRlKDtwQA22udkxKZ21VbP60k=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZL3X53S5UVKH3OATASIZIF57J4.jpg" alt="A trader in a face mask works on the trading floor at the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) in New York City" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A trader in a face mask works on the trading floor at the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) as the Omicron coronavirus variant continues to spread in Manhattan, New York City, U.S.翻译:我们, December 20, 2021. REUTERS/Andrew Kelly/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/7SJ7zPCSTTLw3HHj9tYCTXmFktg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/EOSXLYUMJ5IDTHAHRNQTUDNOBE.jpg" alt="German share price index DAX graph is pictured at the stock exchange in Frankfurt" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The German share price index DAX graph is pictured at the stock exchange in Frankfurt, Germany, October 31, 2023.    REUTERS/Staff翻译:德国股价指数 DAX 图拍摄于 2023 年 10 月 31 日在德国法兰克福证券交易所。路透社/工作人员</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/PmoMGVBFmF6801QYlY199bWN2vo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NCHVEVWNNVPLVHULYVRKT3SYNA.jpg" alt="Passersby are reflected on an electric stock quotation board outside a brokerage in Tokyo" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Passersby are reflected on an electric stock quotation board outside a brokerage in Tokyo, Japan April 18, 2023.  REUTERS/Issei Kato/File Photo翻译:2023 年 4 月 18 日，日本东京一家经纪公司外的电子股票报价板上反映了路人的倒影。REUTERS/Issei Kato/档案照片</figcaption></figure>                     <p>European shares and bonds extended a global rally on Thursday as a non-committal Federal Reserve chief had traders doubling down on bets that U.S.翻译:我们 interest rates - the main driver of world borrowing costs - have finally peaked.</p>   <p>With expectations that the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/bank-england-set-keep-rates-15-year-high-despite-slowdown-signs-2023-11-02/">Bank of England</a> might send a similar signal in a few hours , Europe's STOXX 600 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.STOXX" target="_blank">(.STOXX)</a> and London's FTSE <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.FTSE" target="_blank">(.FTSE)</a> were both up over 1% early on, with the former on course for its first four-day run of gains since July.翻译:由于预期<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/bank-england-set-keep-rates-15-year-high-despite-slowdown-signs-2023-11-02/">英国央行</a>可能在几个小时内发出类似信号，欧洲斯托克 600 指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.STOXX" target="_blank">(.STOXX)</a>和伦敦富时指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.FTSE" target="_blank">(.FTSE)</a>早盘均上涨超过 1%，其中前者有望连续第四年上涨。自七月以来的日内上涨。</p>   <p>Shorter-term bond market yields were at two-month lows and the dollar <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DXY" target="_blank">(.DXY)</a> was back-pedalling in the foreign exchange markets, much to the relief of the Japanese yen and the dozens of emerging market currencies that have been suffering this year. /FRX翻译:短期债券市场收益率处于两个月低点，美元<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DXY" target="_blank">（.DXY）</a>在外汇市场上回落，这很大程度上缓解了日元和数十种新兴市场货币今年遭受的损失。 /FRX</p>   <p>Fed Chair Jerome Powell's comments that its aggressive 20-month run of rate increases was likely to slow the economy after what he had described as the "outsized" jump in Q3 U.S.翻译:我们 GDP, was the main takeaway for many analysts, although he had been careful to keep the door open to another hike if needed.翻译:美联储主席杰罗姆·鲍威尔表示，在美国第三季度GDP“大幅”跃升之后，连续20个月的激进加息可能会导致经济放缓，这是许多分析师的主要收获，尽管他一直很谨慎如果需要的话，为另一次徒步旅行敞开大门。</p>   <p>"A lot of things went right for the rates market yesterday," Jefferies chief European economist Mohit Kumar said, adding that today's focus would be on the Bank of England and U.S.翻译:我们 unemployment claims and factory orders data.</p>   <p>Sterling crept 0.2% higher to $1.2173 but slipped to 87.14 per euro as dealers waited for the BOE's rate decision due at 1200, which will also come with new economic forecasts.翻译:英镑小幅上涨0.2%至1.2173美元，但由于交易商等待英国央行在1200点公布的利率决定，英镑兑欧元汇率下滑至87.14美元，该利率决定也将伴随新的经济预测。</p>   <p>Markets price an almost 90% chance the bank will keep UK rates at their current 15-year high of 5.25%, but have not fully priced a rate cut until September 2024 -- well after cuts are expected to have begun in other parts of Europe.翻译:市场预计该行有近 90% 的可能性将英国利率维持在当前 15 年高点 5.25%，但直到 2024 年 9 月才完全考虑降息——预计欧洲其他地区将开始降息。</p>   <p>"Pricing is reflecting the view that BoE rates will have to remain on 'Table Mountain' for some months given the UK's inflation risks," said RaboBank FX strategist Jane Foley.翻译:荷兰合作银行外汇策略师 Jane Foley 表示，“定价反映了这样一种观点，即鉴于英国的通胀风险，英国央行利率将不得不在几个月内保持在‘桌山’水平。”</p>   <p>Jefferies' Kumar added: "we remain of the view that November could see a positive performance from rates, credit and equities".翻译:杰富瑞 (Jefferies) 的库马尔 (Kumar) 补充道：“我们仍然认为 11 月份利率、信贷和股票可能会出现积极表现”。</p>       <h 1="">APPLE EYED</h>  <p>Overnight, MSCI's broadest index of Asia-Pacific shares outside Japan <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIAPJ0000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIAPJ0000PUS)</a> had surged 1.6%，the biggest daily jump since late July. Tokyo's Nikkei <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a> had also gained 1.1% while S&amp;P 500 futures and Nasdaq futures were pointing to another 0.5% rise on Wall Street later.翻译:一夜之间，摩根士丹利资本国际 (MSCI) 日本以外亚太地区最广泛股票指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIAPJ0000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIAPJ0000PUS)</a>飙升 1.6%，创下 7 月下旬以来的最大单日涨幅。东京日经指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a>也上涨 1.1%，而标准普尔 500 指数期货和纳斯达克期货预计稍后华尔街将再上涨 0.5%。</p>   <p>Investors are now awaiting results from Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a>, a bellwether for consumer demand and the tech sector. The Cupertino California-based company is expected to report a 1% decrease in quarterly revenue.翻译:投资者现在正在等待苹果公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">（AAPL.O）</a>的业绩，该公司是消费者需求和科技行业的领头羊。这家总部位于加利福尼亚州库比蒂诺的公司预计季度收入将下降 1%。</p>   <p>The next big focal point after that will be U.S.翻译:我们 non-farm payrolls data on Friday, which analysts expect to show the economy added 180,000 jobs in October, slowing from a 336,000 increase the previous month.</p>   <p>It will come after mixed data showed <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-private-payrolls-miss-expectations-october-adp-2023-11-01/">strong job openings</a> and slower than expected growth in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-private-payrolls-miss-expectations-october-adp-2023-11-01/">private payrolls</a>.翻译:在此之前，好坏参半的数据显示<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-private-payrolls-miss-expectations-october-adp-2023-11-01/">就业机会强劲</a>且<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-private-payrolls-miss-expectations-october-adp-2023-11-01/">私人就业</a>增长低于预期。</p>   <p>Fed funds futures markets pared back the chance of a December rate hike to about 20% and a January move to 25%. Markets have priced in a 70% chance that the tightening is now over and U.S.翻译:我们 rate cuts could begin as soon as June.</p>   <p>The upbeat mood was also lifting commodity markets. Brent crude futures climbed 1.6% to $85.95 a barrel while U.S.翻译:我们 West Texas Intermediate futures were at $81.87 a barrel, up 1.8%.</p>   <p>The price of gold , which has surged almost 10% since Hamas' attack on Israel last month ignited Middle East tensions, was 0.2% higher at $1,985.99 per ounce.翻译:自上个月哈马斯对以色列的袭击引发中东紧张局势以来，金价已飙升近 10%，目前金价上涨 0.2%，至每盎司 1,985.99 美元。</p>    <span>Additional Reporting by Stella Qiu in Sydney and Samuel Indyk in London; Editing by Emelia Sithole-Matarise翻译:Stella Qiu 在悉尼和 Samuel Indyk 在伦敦的补充报道；编辑：埃米莉亚·西托尔-马塔里斯</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 10:54:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">HTWUJLIM2NI47C3GTMUPVSU2RM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/global-markets-wrapup-1-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Marc Jones]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/ (WRAPUP 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[在中国紧张局势中，荷兰公司着眼于越南生产芯片]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/w26DF8smTzKFOFx4l5O5OfaHVgg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4ZUFIPILBFJBPM4YLMD4J5YOUY.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of semiconductor chips" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Semiconductor chips are seen on a printed circuit board in this illustration picture taken February 17, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo翻译:这张摄于 2023 年 2 月 17 日的插图图片中可以看到印刷电路板上的半导体芯片。REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Dutch semiconductor companies and suppliers are planning manufacturing investments in Vietnam, top officials told Reuters on Thursday during a business mission to Hanoi led by outgoing Prime Minister Mark Rutte.翻译:荷兰半导体公司和供应商正在计划在越南进行制造业投资，周四，荷兰高级官员在即将卸任的总理马克·吕特 (Mark Rutte) 率领的商业代表团访问河内期间告诉路透社。</p>   <p>Initial known investments are not large, but signal a shift to reduce reliance on China as a hub for exports amid increasing trade tensions between Beijing and the West which have curbed the Netherlands' sales of the most advanced chips to China.翻译:最初已知的投资规模并不大，但标志着在北京与西方之间贸易紧张局势加剧的情况下，荷兰将减少对中国作为出口中心的依赖，这限制了荷兰向中国销售最先进的芯片。</p>   <p>Roughly a dozen of the nearly 30 businesses that accompanied Rutte were representatives of chips companies or suppliers of semiconductor firms, according to the delegation's list.翻译:根据代表团的名单，随吕特出访的近 30 家企业中，约有 12 家是芯片公司或半导体公司供应商的代表。</p>   <p>During the visit BE Semiconductor Industries (Besi) <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BESI.AS" target="_blank">(BESI.AS)</a>, a Dutch maker of chips equipment, announced it had received approval to make an initial investment of $5 million to rent a factory in the south of the country.翻译:访问期间，荷兰芯片设备制造商BE半导体工业公司(Besi) <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BESI.AS" target="_blank">(BESI.AS)</a>宣布已获得批准，将在该国南部租用一座工厂，初始投资500万美元。</p>   <p>Besi's investment is expected to grow significantly, with plans to build its own factory in Vietnam within the next four years, the company's vice president for global operations, Henk Jan Poerink, told Reuters.翻译:Besi 负责全球运营的副总裁 Henk Jan Poerink 告诉路透社，Besi 的投资预计将大幅增长，并计划在未来四年内在越南建立自己的工厂。</p>   <p>Rutte said he was sure other Dutch chips companies and suppliers would follow, noting the size of the business delegation accompanying him.翻译:吕特表示，他确信其他荷兰芯片公司和供应商也会效仿，并指出随行的商业代表团的规模。</p>   <p>"It's clearly evident," he told Reuters after he met with Vietnam's Prime Minister Pham Minh Chinh.翻译:“这显然是显而易见的，”他在会见越南总理范明正后告诉路透社。</p>   <p>Poerink said Besi would be followed by other Dutch companies to create a semiconductor "ecosystem" in Vietnam, adding that at least two other firms in the delegation were planning to invest.翻译:Poerink 表示，其他荷兰公司将效仿 Besi 在越南创建半导体“生态系统”，并补充说代表团中至少还有另外两家公司正计划投资。</p>   <p>He declined to name them, but added that another one not participating in the mission, VDL Enabling Technologies Group, had also decided to invest in the country.翻译:他拒绝透露他们的名字，但补充说，另一家未参与此次任务的公司 VDL Enabling Technologies Group 也决定在该国投资。</p>   <p>VDL ETG was not immediately available for a comment.翻译:未能立即联系到 VDL ETG 置评。</p>   <p>The main reason for investing in Vietnam was to get closer to Besi's clients, Poerink said, declining to name them, but noting they were top electronics and semiconductors players.翻译:Poerink 表示，在越南投资的主要原因是为了更接近 Besi 的客户，他拒绝透露客户的姓名，但指出他们是顶级电子和半导体厂商。</p>   <p>Vietnam is home to Intel's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/INTC.O" target="_blank">(INTC.O)</a> largest chip assembling factory and is also a major manufacturing hub for South Korea's giants Samsung <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/005930.KS" target="_blank">(005930.KS)</a> and LG <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/066570.KS" target="_blank">(066570.KS)</a>.翻译:越南是英特尔<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/INTC.O" target="_blank">(INTC.O)</a>最大芯片组装厂的所在地，也是韩国巨头三星<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/005930.KS" target="_blank">(005930.KS)</a>和LG <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/066570.KS" target="_blank">(066570.KS)</a>的主要制造中心。</p>   <p>Poerink said the company's strategy entailed relying less on China, where it nevertheless continued to grow but only to serve the expanding Chinese market.翻译:Poerink表示，该公司的战略是减少对中国的依赖，尽管如此，该公司仍在继续增长，但只是为了服务不断扩大的中国市场。</p>   <p>He said he planned to move some operations from China to Vietnam, in line with what Besi's clients had done. "Anything that is not for China ... I will move out," he said, describing his clients' approach.翻译:他表示，他计划将部分业务从中国转移到越南，与 Besi 客户的做法一致。 “任何不适合中国的事情……我都会搬出去，”他在描述客户的做法时说道。</p>   <p>Other officials <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chip-equipment-maker-asmls-suppliers-eye-asia-plants-outside-china-amid-tensions-2023-03-10/">mentioned</a> similar reasons for Dutch companies' interest in Vietnam, especially as trade restrictions increase and top firms, like chip equipment maker ASML <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ASML.AS" target="_blank">(ASML.AS)</a>, can no longer sell their most advanced machines to Beijing.翻译:其他官员<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chip-equipment-maker-asmls-suppliers-eye-asia-plants-outside-china-amid-tensions-2023-03-10/">提到了</a>荷兰公司对越南感兴趣的类似原因，特别是随着贸易限制的增加以及芯片设备制造商ASML <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ASML.AS" target="_blank">（ASML.AS）</a>等顶级公司无法再向北京出售其最先进的机器。</p>   <p>Some of the companies accompanying Rutte are ASML suppliers, but the company did not send a representative.翻译:吕特随行的一些公司是ASML供应商，但该公司没有派出代表。</p>    <span>Reporting by Francesco Guarascio @fraguarascio; Editing by Martin Petty and Sonali Paul翻译:Francesco Guarascio@fraguarascio 报道；马丁·佩蒂和索纳利·保罗编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 10:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">LPMJVUED75N33GS7R7ML4YTK7Q</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/dutch-firms-eye-chips-making-vietnam-amid-china-tensions-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Francesco Guarascio]]></author>
            
                
                <category>VIETNAM</category>
                
                <category>NETHERLANDS/CHIPS (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[菲律宾指责中国侵入其海域]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tsU7yVP9535QCIzldv4Bbub1lvo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HIV2JPEUHJPYHNYM64VVRTCLTM.jpg" alt="National flags are placed outside a room where Philippine Finance Secretary Carlos Dominguez and China's Commerce Minister Gao Hucheng address reporters after their meeting in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>National flags are placed outside a room where Philippine Finance Secretary Carlos Dominguez and China's Commerce Minister Gao Hucheng address reporters after their meeting in Beijing, China, January 23, 2017. REUTERS/Damir Sagolj翻译:2017年1月23日，菲律宾财政部长卡洛斯·多明计斯和中国商务部部长高虎城在中国北京会晤后向记者发表讲话，房间外悬挂着国旗。路透社/Damir Sagolj</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Philippine foreign ministry on Thursday accused China of intruding into its waters after an incident involving the two countries' military vessels at a disputed shoal in the South China Sea earlier this week.翻译:本周早些时候，两国军舰在南海争议浅滩发生事件，菲律宾外交部周四指责中国侵入菲律宾海域。</p>   <p>The Department of Foreign Affairs (DFA) said the Chinese military's claim that a Philippine military ship "illegally entered" waters near the Scarborough Shoal "has no legal basis and only serves to raise tensions" in the disputed waterway.翻译:外交部表示，中国军方关于菲律宾军舰“非法进入”黄岩岛附近海域的说法“没有法律依据，只会加剧争议航道的紧张局势”。</p>   <p>"It is China that is intruding into Philippine waters," the foreign ministry said in a statement.翻译:外交部在一份声明中表示：“是中国入侵了菲律宾海域。”</p>   <p>The Philippines and China both lay claim to the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-accuses-china-intruding-into-its-waters-2023-11-02/The%20Philippines%20and%20China%20lay%20claim%20to%20the%20shoal%20but%20sovereignty%20has%20never%20been%20established%20and%20it%20remains%20effectively%20under%20Beijing's%20control" target="_blank">Scarborough Shoal</a> but sovereignty has never been established and it remains effectively under Beijing's control since it seized it from Manila in 2012.翻译:菲律宾和中国都声称对<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-accuses-china-intruding-into-its-waters-2023-11-02/The%20Philippines%20and%20China%20lay%20claim%20to%20the%20shoal%20but%20sovereignty%20has%20never%20been%20established%20and%20it%20remains%20effectively%20under%20Beijing's%20control" target="_blank">黄岩岛</a>拥有主权，但主权从未确立，自2012年从马尼拉手中夺取黄岩岛以来，黄岩岛实际上仍处于北京的控制之下。</p>   <p>The DFA said the shoal, which it calls "Bajo de Masinloc", is within the Philippines' exclusive economic zone and the country has sovereign rights and jurisdiction over it.翻译:外交部表示，该浅滩被称为“Bajo de Masinloc”，位于菲律宾专属经济区内，菲律宾对其拥有主权权利和管辖权。</p>   <p>"The Philippines has consistently demanded that Chinese vessels in Bajo de Masinloc leave the area immediately," the foreign ministry said.翻译:菲律宾外交部表示：“菲律宾一贯要求在巴霍德马辛洛克的中国船只立即离开该地区。”</p>   <p>The shoal, located 200 km (124 miles) off the Philippines, was part of an arbitration claim filed by Manila at an international tribunal. The court ruled in 2016 that Beijing's claim to 90% of the South China Sea had no basis under international law, but China has refused to recognise the ruling.翻译:该浅滩距离菲律宾 200 公里（124 英里），是马尼拉向国际法庭提出的仲裁索赔的一部分。该法院于2016年裁定，北京对南海90%海域的主权主张没有国际法依据，但中国拒绝承认这一裁决。</p>   <p>The Philippines presidential office said Thursday South China Sea matters will be part of the bilateral talks between Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida and President Ferdinand Marcos on Friday. Kishida is set to arrive in Manila on Friday for a two-day visit.翻译:菲律宾总统办公室周四表示，南海问题将成为日本首相岸田文雄和总统费迪南德·马科斯周五双边会谈的一部分。岸田定于周五抵达马尼拉进行为期两天的访问。</p>   <p>Ahead of the visit, the Japan defence ministry also announced the delivery of the first air surveillance radar system to the Philippine military as part of a 2020 contract between the Philippines' defence department and Mitsubishi Electric Corp.翻译:在访问之前，日本防卫省还宣布向菲律宾军方交付首个空中监视雷达系统，作为菲律宾国防部与三菱电机公司之间 2020 年合同的一部分。</p>    <span>Reporting by Mikhail Flores; Editing by Kanupriya Kapoor and Miral Fahmy翻译:米哈伊尔·弗洛雷斯报道；编辑：Kanupriya Kapoor 和 Miral Fahmy</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 10:21:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7OMJGPQ565OFLHTMYXT5BVWW4U</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-accuses-china-intruding-into-its-waters-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SOUTHCHINASEA</category>
                
                <category>PHILIPPINES/CHINA (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早盘竞价：市场因美联储和融资而飞扬]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/9NWV2I-IQJPR4ga_hb64R2c4DO4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YWAM6HA2LBL5JN6QCPRRFZHXRM.jpg" alt="Traders work on the floor of the NYSE in New York" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Traders work on the floor at the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) in New York City, U.S.翻译:我们, October 27, 2023.  REUTERS/Brendan McDermid翻译:2023 年 10 月 27 日，交易员在美国纽约市纽约证券交易所 (NYSE) 的交易大厅工作。REUTERS/Brendan McDermid</figcaption></figure>       <p>A look at the day ahead in U.S.翻译:我们 and global markets from Mike Dolan</p>   <p>World markets lapped up a combination of steady U.S.翻译:我们 interest rates, rejigged <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/bruised-treasury-bulls-see-glimmer-hope-after-fed-meeting-smaller-issuance-2023-11-02/">Treasury borrowing</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/us-oil-output-hits-record-producers-boost-drilling-efficiency-kemp-2023-11-01/">lower oil</a> prices - with an eye on Thursday's earnings update from America's most valuable company <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/apples-holiday-quarter-forecast-faces-threat-huawei-weak-china-market-2023-11-01/">Apple</a>.翻译:世界市场对稳定的美国利率、调整后的美国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/bruised-treasury-bulls-see-glimmer-hope-after-fed-meeting-smaller-issuance-2023-11-02/">国债</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/us-oil-output-hits-record-producers-boost-drilling-efficiency-kemp-2023-11-01/">较低的</a>油价等因素表示欢迎，并关注美国市值最高的公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/apples-holiday-quarter-forecast-faces-threat-huawei-weak-china-market-2023-11-01/">苹果</a>公司周四发布的财报。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/fed-poised-hold-rates-steady-despite-economys-bullish-tone-2023-11-01/">Federal Reserve</a> left rates on hold again as expected - with an equivocal stance on further tightening as financial conditions generally remain tight. The Treasury, meantime, followed up on Monday's forecast of a lower borrowing tally for the final quarter with plans to ease back somewhat on share of long-term debt it's selling.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/fed-poised-hold-rates-steady-despite-economys-bullish-tone-2023-11-01/">美联储</a>如预期再次维持利率不变，由于金融状况总体依然紧张，对进一步收紧政策的立场模棱两可。与此同时，财政部周一预测最后一个季度的借贷总额将会下降，并计划在一定程度上减少其出售的长期债务份额。</p>   <p>Along with signs of fresh weakness in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-manufacturing-sector-slumps-october-ism-2023-11-01/">U.S.翻译:我们 manufacturing</a> last month and further retreat in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/us-oil-output-hits-record-producers-boost-drilling-efficiency-kemp-2023-11-01/">crude oil prices</a> to their lowest since August, 10-year Treasury yields dialled back yet again as low as 4.70% on Thursday - the lowest in more than two weeks and now 32 basis points below recent highs.翻译:随着上个月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-manufacturing-sector-slumps-october-ism-2023-11-01/">美国制造业</a>出现新的疲软迹象以及<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/us-oil-output-hits-record-producers-boost-drilling-efficiency-kemp-2023-11-01/">原油价格</a>进一步回落至 8 月以来的最低水平，10 年期国债收益率周四再次回落至 4.70%，为两周多以来的最低水平。较近期高点低32个基点。</p>   <p>With Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a> up on the earnings slate after the bell later, S&amp;P500 futures are rising further ahead of the open - setting Wall Street on course for a fourth straight day of gains for the first time in almost a month.翻译:随着苹果<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a>盘后公布财报，标准普尔 500 指数期货在开盘前进一步上涨，使华尔街有望连续第四天上涨，这是近一个月来的首次。</p>   <p>More than half way through the earnings calendar, third quarter annual profit estimates for the S&amp;P500 are tracking a gain 5% - more than twice pre-season forecasts - and 80% of firms have beaten forecasts and tallying with the 4.9% economic growth reading for the same three-month period.翻译:财报日历已过半，标准普尔 500 指数第三季度年度利润预期增长 5%，是季前预测的两倍多，80% 的公司超出了预期，与 4.9% 的经济增长读数相符。同样的三个月期间。</p>   <p>That then makes October economic soundings all the more important for both investors and the Fed to assess.翻译:这使得 10 月份的经济数据对于投资者和美联储的评估变得更加重要。</p>   <p>Emerging softness in the ISM's October manufacturing survey may be a marker in that regard - although the employment picture will dominate the view of consumption going forward.翻译:ISM 10 月制造业调查中出现的疲软可能是这方面的一个标志——尽管就业形势将主导未来消费的看法。</p>   <p>And there was a mixed picture on the extent of loosening in the labor market on Wednesday. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-private-payrolls-miss-expectations-october-adp-2023-11-01/">Job openings</a> fell by less than expected in September, but ADP's private sector payroll tally for last month came in below forecasts again.翻译:周三劳动力市场的宽松程度好坏参半。 9 月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-private-payrolls-miss-expectations-october-adp-2023-11-01/">职位空缺</a>降幅低于预期，但 ADP 上个月私营部门就业人数再次低于预期。</p>   <p>With weekly jobless data watched like a hawk again later, Friday's national employment report now hoves into view.翻译:随着每周失业数据再次受到鹰派的关注，周五的全国就业报告现在进入人们的视野。</p>   <p>Fed futures now show less than a 30% chance of another Fed hike in the cycle, with a first cut coming by June and some 70bps of easing pencilled in by the end of next year.翻译:美联储期货目前显示，美联储在本周期再次加息的可能性不到 30%，首次降息将于 6 月进行，并预计在明年年底前实施约 70 个基点的宽松政策。</p>   <p>For now at least, S&amp;P500 futures are up another 0.5% after the index clocked another gain of 1% on Wednesday. The ViX volatility gauge <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.VIX" target="_blank">(.VIX)</a> fell to as low as 16.4 today.翻译:至少目前来看，标准普尔 500 指数期货在周三再次上涨 1% 后，又上涨了 0.5%。 ViX 波动率指标<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.VIX" target="_blank">(.VIX)</a>今天跌至 16.4。</p>   <p>With mainland <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/evergrande-proposes-offshore-creditors-get-30-equity-stake-subsidiaries-sources-2023-11-01/">Chinese shares</a> the notable outlier yet again, other global bourses climbed rose n Wall Street's slipstream.翻译:由于<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/evergrande-proposes-offshore-creditors-get-30-equity-stake-subsidiaries-sources-2023-11-01/">中国大陆股市</a>再次成为显着的异常，其他全球股市在华尔街的推动下上涨。</p>   <p>Japan's Nikkei <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a> added another 1% even as the yen regained some more lost ground after the early-week swoon on only a modest rowback from the Bank of Japan on its yield capping policy.翻译:日本日经指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a>又上涨 1%，尽管日元在上周初因日本央行对其收益率上限政策略有回落而收复部分失地。</p>   <p>BOJ <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/boj-plans-exit-easy-policy-next-year-needs-some-good-fortune-2023-11-02/">Governor Kazuo Ueda</a> will continue to dismantle the central bank's ultra-easy monetary policy settings only gradually and look to exit the decade-long accommodative regime sometime next year, Reuters reported on Thursday, based on interviews with six sources familiar with the BOJ's thinking.翻译:路透社周四根据六名熟悉日本央行想法的消息人士的采访报道称，日本<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/boj-plans-exit-easy-policy-next-year-needs-some-good-fortune-2023-11-02/">央行行长上田一夫</a>将继续逐步取消央行的超宽松货币政策设置，并寻求在明年某个时候退出长达十年的宽松政策。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/bank-england-set-keep-rates-15-year-high-despite-slowdown-signs-2023-11-02/">Bank of England</a> is the next major central bank decision due later on Thursday. Like the Fed, it is expected to hold rates unchanged with a likely 6-3 vote on its policymaking council for steady rates. Most market players now think BoE rates have peaked for this cycle.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/bank-england-set-keep-rates-15-year-high-despite-slowdown-signs-2023-11-02/">英国央行</a>将于周四晚些时候做出下一个重大央行决定。与美联储一样，预计美联储将维持利率不变，其决策委员会可能会以 6 比 3 的投票结果决定稳定利率。大多数市场参与者现在认为英国央行利率已在本周期见顶。</p>   <p>In China, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-regulators-probe-liquidity-stress-that-sent-rates-record-50-sources-2023-11-02/">financial regulators</a> are investigating a month-end liquidity crunch that saw short-term money rates surge to as much as 50% earlier this week, asking institutions to explain why they borrowed at extremely high rates, three sources said.翻译:三名消息人士称，在中国， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-regulators-probe-liquidity-stress-that-sent-rates-record-50-sources-2023-11-02/">金融监管机构</a>正在调查月末流动性紧缩，本周早些时候短期货币利率飙升至 50%，要求机构解释为何以极高的利率借款。</p>   <p>In other U.S.翻译:我们 corporate news, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/teslas-oct-china-made-ev-sales-fall-26-sept-2023-11-02/">automaker Tesla</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a> delivered 72,115 China-made electric vehicles last month, down 2.6% from a month earlier, the China Passenger Car Association (CPCA) said.翻译:其他美国企业新闻方面，中国乘用车协会 (CPCA) 表示， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/teslas-oct-china-made-ev-sales-fall-26-sept-2023-11-02/">汽车制造商特斯拉</a><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a>上个月交付了 72,115 辆中国制造的电动汽车，环比下降 2.6%。</p>   <p>Key developments that should provide more direction to U.S.翻译:我们 markets later on Thursday:翻译:周四晚些时候的关键事态发展将为美国市场提供更多方向：</p>   <p>* Bank of England policy decision and monetary policy report翻译:* 英国央行政策决定和货币政策报告</p>   <p>* U.S.翻译:我们 weekly jobless, Sept durable goods orders, Q3 unit labor costs翻译:* 美国每周失业率、9月份耐用品订单、第三季度单位劳动力成本</p>   <p>* St Louis Interim Federal Reserve President Kathleen O'Neill speaks; European Central Bank chief economist Philip Lane, and ECB board members Isabel Schnabel and Edouard Fernandez-Bollo all speak翻译:* 圣路易斯临时联邦储备银行行长凯瑟琳·奥尼尔 (Kathleen O&#39;Neill) 讲话；欧洲央行首席经济学家菲利普·莱恩、欧洲央行董事会成员伊莎贝尔·施纳贝尔和爱德华·费尔南德斯-博洛均发表讲话</p>   <p>* U.S.翻译:我们 corporate earnings: Apple, Expedia, Booking, Starbucks, Cigna, Molson Coors, S&amp;PGlobal, Eli Lilly, ConocoPhillips, Pioneer Natural Resources, Duke Energy, Alliant Energy, Moderna, Monster Beverage, EOG, SBA, ICE, Stryker, Motorola Solutions, Live Nation, Consolidated Edison, Federal Realty, Paramount Global, Rockwell, Microchip, Fortinet, Skyworks, Regency, Insulet, Ventas, AES, NRG, Borgwarner, PPL, Howmet, Huntington Ingersolls, Ball, Cencora, Cummins, Fox, Baxter, Teleflex etc翻译:* 美国企业盈利：Apple、Expedia、Booking、星巴克、Cigna、Molson Coors、S&amp;PGlobal、礼来公司、康菲石油公司、先锋自然资源公司、杜克能源公司、Alliant Energy、Moderna、Monster Beverage、EOG、SBA、ICE、Stryker、摩托罗拉解决方案、Live Nation、联合爱迪生、联邦地产、派拉蒙全球、罗克韦尔、Microchip、Fortinet、Skyworks、Regency、Insulet、Ventas、AES、NRG、博格华纳、PPL、Howmet、Huntington Ingersolls、Ball、Cencora、康明斯、福克斯、巴克斯特、泰利福等</p>   <p>* U.S.翻译:我们 Treasury auctions 4-week bills</p>                   <span>By Mike Dolan, editing by Alexander Smith; &lt;a href="mailto:mike.dolan@thomsonreuters.com" target="_blank"&gt;mike.dolan@thomsonreuters.com&lt;/a&gt;. Twitter: @reutersMikeD翻译:作者：迈克·多兰，亚历山大·史密斯编辑； &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mike.dolan@thomsonreuters.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mike.dolan@thomsonreuters.com&lt;/a&gt;。推特：@reutersMikeD</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 10:01:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">KLIKMLI6YBJFBMPAUEM7PQKEDU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/global-markets-view-usa-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国农场领导人访华谈农业贸易]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/XIUNtRWcEtd3mRq_M8y3PEYGiX8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/QYAU3N6NW5PQDGZMTB5BEK7FTA.jpg" alt="美国农场领导人访华谈农业贸易" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Imported soybeans are transported at a port in Nantong, Jiangsu province, China August 6, 2018. REUTERS/Stringer翻译:2018年8月6日，进口大豆在中国江苏省南通市的一个港口运输。REUTERS/Stringer</figcaption></figure>       <p>Dozens of U.S.翻译:我们 agriculture industry representatives gathered in Beijing on Thursday to meet Chinese counterparts amid growing U.S.翻译:我们 efforts to bolster farm trade even as political ties between their two countries remain strained.</p>   <p>A delegation from 11 groups including the U.S.翻译:我们 Soybean Export Council, U.S.翻译:我们 Grains Council and U.S.翻译:我们 Wheat Associates is visiting a week after Chinese grain buyers signed non-binding agreements in Iowa to buy billions of dollars worth of produce, mostly soybeans, the first such signing since 2017.</p>   <p>This week's visit, the likes of which had become rare due to bilateral tensions and three years of Chinese COVID-19 border controls, comes ahead of an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/chinas-foreign-minister-says-road-san-francisco-summit-will-not-be-smooth-2023-10-29/">expected meeting</a> between President Xi Jinping and President Joe Biden in San Francisco this month.翻译:本周的访问是在习近平主席和乔·拜登总统<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/chinas-foreign-minister-says-road-san-francisco-summit-will-not-be-smooth-2023-10-29/">预计本月在旧金山举行会晤</a>之前进行的，由于双边紧张局势和中国对新冠病毒（COVID-19）实施了三年的边境管制，此类访问已经变得罕见。</p>   <p>"We've got a big complicated relationship, but agriculture is the ballast in the relationship," Nicholas Burns, U.S.翻译:我们 ambassador to China, told the gathering of U.S.翻译:我们 and Chinese industry officials.翻译:“我们之间的关系非常复杂，但农业是这种关系的压舱石，”美国驻华大使尼古拉斯·伯恩斯(Nicholas Burns)在美国和中国工业官员聚会上表示。</p>   <p>U.S.翻译:我们 Grains Council officials visited China's commerce ministry earlier on Thursday and raised China's anti-dumping and anti-subsidy measures against U.S.翻译:我们 imports of distillers dried grains (DDGS), a protein-rich byproduct from ethanol production that is fed to animals.</p>   <p>"They suggested we talk with the domestic industry here to have them give their support in the need of the product and they brought up the fact that they'd recently dropped the anti-dumping case on Australian barley, so whether that shows some hope for U.S.翻译:我们 DDGs, possibly. I'm not sure," said Cary Sifferath, vice president of the U.S.翻译:我们 Grains Council.</p>   <p>Oilseeds and grains are the top U.S.翻译:我们 export to China, accounting for $25.4 billion last year, far ahead of other goods such as semiconductors, but Brazil has been eating into the U.S.翻译:我们 share of the Chinese market after harvesting bumper crops of soybeans and corn.翻译:油籽和谷物是美国对华出口的最大产品，去年出口额达254亿美元，远远领先于半导体等其他商品，但巴西在收获大豆和玉米丰收后，一直在蚕食美国在中国市场的份额。</p>   <p>China has been pushing to diversify its import sources in the years since former U.S.翻译:我们 President Donald Trump launched a bruising trade war and amid rising geopolitical risks, opening its market to Brazilian corn late last year.</p>   <p>Imports of Brazilian soybeans are up 18% in the first nine months of 2023 compared with the same period last year, compared with an 8% increase in U.S.翻译:我们 arrivals. Almost 4 million tons of Brazilian corn has reached China, with more on the way.翻译:2023 年前 9 个月，巴西大豆进口量较去年同期增长 18%，而美国大豆进口量增长 8%。近 400 万吨巴西玉米已运抵中国，还有更多正在运抵中国。</p>   <p>The delegation, the industry's largest to China since 2016, will travel to Shanghai for next week's annual China International Import Expo, where the USDA is hosting a pavilion for the first time since the event started in 2018.翻译:这是该行业自 2016 年以来最大规模的中国代表团，将前往上海参加下周举行的一年一度的中国国际进口博览会，这是美国农业部自 2018 年举办该博览会以来首次在此设立展馆。</p>   <p>(This story has been refiled to fix the spelling of 'semiconductors' in paragraph 7)翻译:（这个故事已被重新归档，以修正第 7 段中“半导体”的拼写）</p>    <span>Reporting by Dominique Patton
Editing by Tony Munroe, Robert Birsel翻译:多米尼克·巴顿报道 托尼·芒罗、罗伯特·伯塞尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 09:47:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4OH7YHTXQFPK5LC4T4F5ZBLTWM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us-farm-leaders-visiting-china-talk-up-agriculture-trade-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Dominique Patton]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>USA/AGRICULTURE (CORRECTED, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[特斯拉 10 月份中国制造电动汽车销量环比下降 2.6%]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/A5g2YAg7TlIvFwcExyVMIq8RUOw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CCFO2AWHRJJQRDJOYVKLUQUOIU.jpg" alt="Tesla China-made Model 3 vehicles are seen during a delivery event at its factory in Shanghai" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Tesla China-made Model 3 vehicles are seen during a delivery event at its factory in Shanghai, China January 7, 2020. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2020 年 1 月 7 日，特斯拉中国制造的 Model 3 车辆在中国上海工厂举行的交付活动中亮相。REUTERS/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ladltdm0bB3MHvdng1h_e-xvq5M=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BGK4RGC3UVKP3LHQZER675RCDA.jpg" alt="Tesla logo shown on Model Y vehicle in California" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Tesla logo is shown on a Model Y vehicle in Encinitas, California, U.S.翻译:我们,October 20, 2023.     REUTERS/Mike Blake/File Photo翻译:2023 年 10 月 20 日，美国加利福尼亚州恩西尼塔斯，一辆 Model Y 车辆上显示特斯拉标志。路透社/Mike Blake/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>U.S.翻译:我们 automaker Tesla <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a> delivered 72,115 China-made electric vehicles in October, down 2.6% from a month earlier, the China Passenger Car Association (CPCA) said on Thursday.</p>   <p>Sales of China-made Model 3 and Model Y cars edged up 0.6% from a year earlier.翻译:中国制造的 Model 3 和 Model Y 汽车销量同比小幅增长 0.6%。</p>   <p>Chinese rival BYD <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002594.SZ" target="_blank">(002594.SZ)</a>, which makes EVs and hybrid models from its Dynasty and Ocean series, delivered 301,095 passenger vehicles in October, up 5% from September and a 38.4% increase from the same month last year.翻译:中国竞争对手比亚迪<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002594.SZ" target="_blank">（002594.SZ）</a>生产王朝系列和海洋系列电动汽车和混合动力车型，10月份交付了301,095辆乘用车，环比增长5%，环比增长38.4%。</p>   <p>Elon Musk's Tesla has prioritised sales over earnings, particularly in China, where the U.S.翻译:我们 EV giant has come under growing pressure from local rivals. Aggressive discounts have battered its margins but failed to boost its market share.</p>   <p>Tesla's market share in China's EV segment <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-car-sales-quicken-sept-exports-rise-50-2023-10-11/">shrank</a> to 9.89% in the third quarter from 12.98% in the second quarter and 9.93% a year earlier.翻译:特斯拉在中国电动汽车领域的市场份额从第二季度的12.98%和去年同期的9.93% <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-car-sales-quicken-sept-exports-rise-50-2023-10-11/">缩减</a>至第三季度的9.89%。</p>   <p>It <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-car-sales-quicken-sept-exports-rise-50-2023-10-11/">missed</a> third-quarter estimates for gross margin, profit and revenue. It also undershot third-quarter forecasts for its <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/tesla-reports-fall-third-quarter-deliveries-misses-estimates-2023-10-02/">global deliveries</a>, as planned factory upgrades for a revamped version of the Model 3 curbed production.翻译:第三季度毛利率、利润和收入<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-car-sales-quicken-sept-exports-rise-50-2023-10-11/">均未达到</a>预期。由于 Model 3 改进版的工厂升级计划限制了产量，该公司第三季度的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/tesla-reports-fall-third-quarter-deliveries-misses-estimates-2023-10-02/">全球交付</a>量也低于预期。</p>   <p>Tesla <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/tesla-releases-refreshed-version-model-3-china-website-2023-09-01/">debuted</a> the refreshed and higher-priced Model 3 in China in September and officially began deliveries on Oct. 26.翻译:特斯拉于 9 月在中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/tesla-releases-refreshed-version-model-3-china-website-2023-09-01/">推出了</a>更新版、价格更高的 Model 3，并于 10 月 26 日正式开始交付。</p>   <p>Domestic automakers have made more headway in the world's largest auto market, where foreign brands including Japan's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/mitsubishi-motors-invest-around-20-bln-yen-into-renaults-new-ev-company-nikkei-2023-10-24/">Mitsubishi Motors</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/7211.T" target="_blank">(7211.T)</a> and South Korea's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/beijing-hyundai-cuts-asking-price-chongqing-auto-plant-by-30-2023-10-09/">Hyundai Motor</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/005380.KS" target="_blank">(005380.KS)</a> have taken steps to wind down or scale back on their operations.翻译:国内汽车制造商在全球最大的汽车市场取得了更大进展，日本<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/mitsubishi-motors-invest-around-20-bln-yen-into-renaults-new-ev-company-nikkei-2023-10-24/">三菱汽车</a><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/7211.T" target="_blank">（7211.T）</a>和韩国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/beijing-hyundai-cuts-asking-price-chongqing-auto-plant-by-30-2023-10-09/">现代汽车</a><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/005380.KS" target="_blank">（005380.KS）</a>等外国品牌已采取措施减少或缩减业务。</p>   <p>BYD, Tesla's biggest Chinese rival, secured its market leadership with a 22.12% gross margin in the third quarter.翻译:特斯拉在中国最大的竞争对手比亚迪第三季度以22.12%的毛利率巩固了市场领先地位。</p>   <p>Huawei-backed EV brand Aito has also made a splash lately, with its revamped <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/huawei-backed-aito-says-gets-50000-orders-m7-car-since-relaunch-2023-10-09/">M7 model</a> garnering more than 50,000 orders within the first 25 days after it went on sale in mid-September.翻译:华为支持的电动汽车品牌Aito最近也引起了轰动，其改款的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/huawei-backed-aito-says-gets-50000-orders-m7-car-since-relaunch-2023-10-09/">M7车型</a>在9月中旬上市后的25天内就获得了超过5万份订单。</p>    <span>Reporting by Qiaoyi Li, Zhang Yan and Brenda Goh; Editing by Jamie Freed, Sonali Paul and William Mallard翻译:李巧仪、张岩、Brenda Goh 报道；编辑：杰米·弗里德、索纳利·保罗和威廉·马拉德</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 09:08:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">QJVJHONZERJTNBPWZ4RHUI35LY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/teslas-oct-china-made-ev-sales-fall-26-sept-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>TESLA/ (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国监管机构调查导致利率创纪录50%的流动性压力——消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UFZvgV10evozFRO5YrgUPCvaWqI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OYR7OROA6RJV5KRCRFQLMLLUU4.jpg" alt="Illustration photo of a China yuan note" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A China yuan note is seen in this illustration photo May 31, 2017.     REUTERS/Thomas White/Illustration/File Photo翻译:这张2017年5月31日的插图照片中可以看到一张人民币纸币。路透社/Thomas White/插图/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's financial regulators are investigating a month-end liquidity crunch that saw short-term money rates surge to as much as 50%, asking some institutions to explain why they borrowed at extremely high rates, three sources said.翻译:三名消息人士称，中国金融监管机构正在调查月底的流动性紧缩，导致短期货币利率飙升至 50%，并要求一些机构解释为何以极高的利率借款。</p>   <p>The overnight rate for pledged repo - a short-term financing business - hit a record high of 50% on Oct 31, as a month-end scramble for cash and a flood of government bond sales caused stress in money markets.翻译:10月31日，质押式回购（一种短期融资业务）隔夜利率创下50%的历史新高，原因是月底现金争夺战和大量国债销售给货币市场带来压力。</p>   <p>The China Foreign Exchange Trade System (CFETS), a central bank affiliate that operates China's interbank market, has asked institutions that settled trades on Tuesday at the 50% rate to submit explanations, according two sources with direct knowledge.翻译:据两位直接知情人士透露，负责运营中国银行间市场的央行附属机构中国外汇交易中心（CFETS）已要求周二以 50% 利率进行交易结算的机构提交解释。</p>   <p>"Anyone who borrowed money at very high rates need to explain to regulators the decision-making and bidding process," said another direct source.翻译:另一位直接消息人士表示：“任何以极高利率借钱的人都需要向监管机构解释决策和招标过程。”</p>   <p>Traders and analysts said an increasing supply of government bonds, and newly approved 1-trillion-yuan ($136.63 billion) sovereign bond issue created unusual liquidity stress at a time when banks need to square their books to meet month-end regulatory requirements.翻译:交易员和分析师表示，政府债券供应不断增加，以及新批准的1万亿元人民币（1,366.3亿美元）主权债券发行造成了异常的流动性压力，而此时银行需要调整账目以满足月末监管要求。</p>   <p>Authorities also could have wanted to keep yuan liquidity tight to stem the currency's slide against the U.S.翻译:我们 dollar in the foreign exchange market, Becky Liu, head of China macro strategy at Standard Chartered said.</p>   <p>A trader said a large number of fund houses, brokerages and trust firms were scrambling to borrow money in afternoon trade on Tuesday to avoid defaults as big banks appeared reluctant to lend.翻译:一位交易员表示，周二下午交易中，大量基金公司、经纪公司和信托公司争先恐后地借钱，以避免违约，因为大银行似乎不愿放贷。</p>   <p>"Demand for cash far exceeded supply, boosting short-term rates," the source said. "For each individual institution, it was a rational decision."翻译:消息人士称，“现金需求远远超过供应，推高了短期利率”。 “对于每个机构来说，这是一个理性的决定。”</p>   <p>But regulators on Wednesday told some institutions in a meeting "not to be emotional," another trader source said.翻译:但另一位交易员消息人士称，监管机构周三在一次会议上告诉一些机构“不要情绪化”。</p>   <p>"Everyone is still slightly nervous now. Everyone is prepared and will keep the liquidity ample."翻译:“现在大家还是有点紧张，大家都有准备，会保持流动性充裕。”</p>   <p>($1 = 7.3188 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.3188 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Shanghai newsroom; Editing by Simon Cameron-Moore翻译:上海新闻编辑室报道；西蒙·卡梅伦-摩尔 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 08:58:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">R2NBCTYKIFL65HQ75EPICM26WA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-regulators-probe-liquidity-stress-that-sent-rates-record-50-sources-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/LIQUIDITY (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国火葬“人民”总理并在悲痛中降下国旗]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/IxqS-wK6MMs-X_7y1JTpV1fK8f4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HJJO7BWGMVM2TP6YEVLPHWDJ6E.jpg" alt="Chinese flag at half-mast on former premier Li's cremation day, in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The Chinese flag at a gate to the Zhongnanhai leadership compound flies at half-mast in memory of late former Chinese premier Li Keqiang, in Beijing, China November 2, 2023. REUTERS/Mark Chisholm翻译:2023年11月2日，中国北京，中南海领导大院门口的中国国旗降半旗纪念已故中国前总理李克强。路透社/Mark Chisholm</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0xLrojPp-QAJPlcQPi-93OcwUs0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2KXE7UMG4BPQFB5OERP4EVGGWY.jpg" alt="China's Premier Li Keqiang waves as he arrives for a news conference after the closing ceremony of China's National People's Congress (NPC) at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>China's Premier Li Keqiang waves as he arrives for a news conference after the closing ceremony of China's National People's Congress (NPC) at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, China, March 15, 2017. REUTERS/Damir Sagolj翻译:2017 年 3 月 15 日，中国北京，中国总理李克强在中国北京人民大会堂闭幕式后抵达出席新闻发布会。 REUTERS/Damir Sagolj</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/m44nm7IQ-hoOn6fsWENafZ_MfJ0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/N4363JLUKBMABL43C5VITC6GOA.jpg" alt="Newspapers with the obituary of late former Chinese Premier Li Keqiang on the frontpage are displayed, at a newsstand in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Newspapers with the obituary of late former Chinese Premier Li Keqiang on the front page are displayed, at a newsstand in Beijing, China October 28, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年10月28日，中国北京的一个报摊上，头版刊登已故中国前总理李克强讣告的报纸。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>                 <p>China lowered the national flag Beijing's Tiananmen Square on Thursday amid an outpouring of online grief as the country cremated Li Keqiang, known as "the people's premier" for his down-to-earth, hands-on leadership.翻译:周四，中国在北京天安门广场降下国旗，火化了因其脚踏实地、亲力亲为的领导而被称为“人民总理”的李克强，网上一片悲痛。</p>   <p>Li, a former economist and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-ex-premier-leaves-an-unfinished-reform-legacy-2023-10-27/">pro-reform</a> leader who served as premier for 10 years before retiring in March, died of a heart attack in Shanghai last Friday. He was 68.翻译:李克强是一位前经济学家和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-ex-premier-leaves-an-unfinished-reform-legacy-2023-10-27/">支持改革的</a>领导人，曾担任总理十年，于今年三月退休，上周五在上海因心脏病去世。他 68 岁了。</p>   <p>At Li's funeral at a Beijing cemetery where high-ranking officials and national heroes are laid to rest, President Xi Jinping and his wife, with the six other members of the Communist Party's Politburo Standing Committee, the highest rung of political power in China, as well as Vice President Han Zheng paid their final respects.翻译:李克强的葬礼在北京一座高官和民族英雄的墓地举行，国家主席习近平和他的妻子，以及中共中央政治局常务委员会的其他六名成员，是中国最高政治权力机构。韩正副院长致以最后的哀悼。</p>   <p>The group stood in silence and took three bows, the official Xinhua news agency reported.翻译:据官方新华社报道，这群人默哀并三鞠躬。</p>   <p>Former President Hu Jintao sent a wreath to express his condolences over Li's passing, according to Xinhua.翻译:据新华社报道，国家主席胡锦涛向李克强逝世致以花圈表示哀悼。</p>   <p>Messages for the late premier flooded social media platforms as Chinese citizens mourned his death.翻译:随着中国公民哀悼已故总理的去世，社交媒体平台上充斥着给他的留言。</p>   <p>On popular social media platform Weibo, which replaced its 'like' button with a chrysanthemum flower symbolising mourning on related posts, tens of thousands of people left comments bidding Li farewell on a Thursday post by China's national broadcaster.翻译:在流行的社交媒体平台微博上，相关帖子中的“点赞”按钮被象征哀悼的菊花取代，数以万计的人在中国国家广播公司周四发布的帖子中发表了告别李的评论。</p>   <p>Li was the top trending topic on Weibo. The hashtag for his mourning drew 430 million views.翻译:李成为微博上的热门话题。哀悼他的标签吸引了 4.3 亿次浏览。</p>   <p>A Beijinger surnamed Gao said Li will be remembered for his contributions to the nation. "It can be said that he has made a great contribution to people's lives, to the improvement of living standards. In the recent pandemic, the premier always rushed to the front line," Gao said.翻译:一位高姓北京人表示，李先生对国家的贡献将被人们铭记。 “可以说，他为人民生活、为人民生活水平的提高做出了巨大贡献。在最近的疫情中，总理总是冲在第一线。”高说。</p>   <p>Once viewed as a Communist Party leadership contender, Li was sidelined in recent years, analysts and diplomats said, as Xi tightened his grip on economic policymaking.翻译:分析人士和外交官表示，随着习近平加强对经济政策制定的控制，李克强一度被视为共产党领导层的有力竞争者，但近年来却被边缘化。</p>   <p>Shanghai resident Zhang Shijun described Li as down-to-earth man who "lot for our people; very humble and low-key".翻译:上海居民张世军形容李是一个脚踏实地的人，“为人民谋福利，非常谦虚和低调”。</p>   <p>Some businesses such as international coffee chain Starbucks <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SBUX.O" target="_blank">(SBUX.O)</a> turned their app interface black and white in mourning for Li.翻译:国际咖啡连锁店星巴克<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SBUX.O" target="_blank">（SBUX.O）</a>等一些企业将其应用程序界面变成黑白，以哀悼李。</p>   <p>Photographs of Li were shared on Weibo by Xinhua news agency, including those of him with Xi, Hu and former leader Jiang Zemin. There were also <a href="https://weibo.com/ttarticle/p/show?id=2309404963649780580732" target="_blank">photographs</a> of Li interacting with ordinary Chinese people in the 2000s as well as one of him clambering over rubble in a disaster-stricken zone after a major earthquake in Sichuan in southwest China.翻译:新华社在微博上分享了李克强的照片，其中包括他与习近平、胡锦涛和前领导人江泽民的照片。还有李在2000年代与普通中国人互动的<a href="https://weibo.com/ttarticle/p/show?id=2309404963649780580732" target="_blank">照片</a>，以及他在中国西南部四川发生大地震后在灾区废墟上攀爬的照片。</p>   <p>"It still feels a bit unreal, because I feel like he's a good premier and suddenly he's gone," said a 24-year-old Beijing-based lawyer surnamed Wan. "And then I also feel sad for him because he was not yet old."翻译:“这还是感觉有点不真实，因为我觉得他是一个很好的总理，突然他就走了，”一位24岁的北京万姓律师说。 “然后我也为他感到难过，因为他还没有老。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Liz Lee, Xiaoyu Yin, Ryan Woo and Beijing newsroom; Editing by Christian Schmollinger and Shri Navaratnam and Miral Fahmy翻译:Liz Lee、Xiaoyu Yin、Ryan Woo 和北京新闻编辑室报道；编辑：Christian Schmollinger、Shri Navaratnam 和 Miral Fahmy</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 08:33:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ENSRBIKGZJPBTNRFROJF3HM6MI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-lowers-flags-half-mast-former-premier-lis-cremation-day-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Liz Lee, Xiaoyu Yin]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>POLITICS/LIKEQIANG (UPDATE 3, TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国立法者向拜登施压，要求其制定中国使用开放芯片技术的计划]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/w26DF8smTzKFOFx4l5O5OfaHVgg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4ZUFIPILBFJBPM4YLMD4J5YOUY.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of semiconductor chips" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Semiconductor chips are seen on a printed circuit board in this illustration picture taken February 17, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo翻译:这张摄于 2023 年 2 月 17 日的插图图片中可以看到印刷电路板上的半导体芯片。REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>A wider bipartisan group of U.S.翻译:我们 lawmakers is asking the Biden administration about its plans to respond to China's rising use of RISC-V chip design technology after Reuters last month reported on <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-china-tech-war-risc-v-chip-technology-emerges-new-battleground-2023-10-06/">growing concerns about it</a> in both houses of Congress.</p>   <p>RISC-V, pronounced "risk five," is a free open-source technology that competes with costly proprietary technology from British semiconductor and software design company Arm Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/O9Ty.F" target="_blank">(O9Ty.F)</a>, and Intel Corp <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/INTC.O" target="_blank">(INTC.O)</a>. It can be used as a key part of anything from a smartphone chip to advanced processors for artificial intelligence.翻译:RISC-V，发音为“风险五”，是一种免费的开源技术，与英国半导体和软件设计公司 Arm Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/O9Ty.F" target="_blank">(O9Ty.F)</a>和英特尔公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/INTC.O" target="_blank">(INTC.O)</a>昂贵的专有技术竞争。它可以用作从智能手机芯片到人工智能高级处理器等任何事物的关键部分。</p>   <p>U.S.翻译:我们 firms such as Qualcomm <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/QCOM.O" target="_blank">(QCOM.O)</a> and Alphabet's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GOOGL.O" target="_blank">(GOOGL.O)</a> Google have embraced RISC-V, but so too have many Chinese companies.</p>   <p>Reuters last month reported that at least four influential U.S.翻译:我们 lawmakers view Chinese use of the technology as a potential national security threat because RISC-V is not captured by the sweeping export controls the U.S.翻译:我们 has imposed on sending chip technology to China.</p>   <p>Now, a broader group of 18 lawmakers that includes five Democrats is asking the Biden administration for how it plans to prevent China "from achieving dominance in ... RISC-V technology and leveraging that dominance at the expense of U.S.翻译:我们 national and economic security," according to a letter the group sent to Raimondo and seen by Reuters.</p>   <p>The lawmakers include the Republican chairman and ranking Democrat from a select committee on China in the House of Representatives as well as Democratic lawmakers from New Jersey, Florida, Michigan and Indiana. They also asked the Biden administration about how it might apply an existing executive order to require U.S.翻译:我们 companies to get an export license before working with Chinese companies on RISC-V technology.翻译:议员们包括众议院中国问题特别委员会的共和党主席和民主党资深议员，以及来自新泽西州、佛罗里达州、密歇根州和印第安纳州的民主党议员。他们还询问拜登政府如何应用现有的行政命令，要求美国公司在与中国公司合作开发 RISC-V 技术之前必须获得出口许可证。</p>   <p>"While the benefits of open-source collaboration on RISC-V promise to be significant for advancement and development of the U.S.翻译:我们 semiconductor industry, it can only be realized when contributors are working with the sole aim of improving the technology, and not aiding the technological goals and geopolitical interests of" China, the group of lawmakers wrote in the letter.</p>   <p>A Commerce Department spokesperson said Raimondo had received the letter and would respond through the appropriate channels.翻译:商务部发言人表示，雷蒙多已收到这封信，并将通过适当渠道做出回应。</p>    <span>Reporting by Stephen Nellis in San Francisco; Editing by Jamie Freed翻译:斯蒂芬·内利斯 (Stephen Nellis) 旧金山报道；杰米·弗里德编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 08:10:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">PBGZSI2AI5OQDJAYZ7C4BIQLSA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-lawmakers-press-biden-plans-chinese-use-open-chip-technology-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Stephen Nellis]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/CHIPS (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国称官员将率团参加中美核谈判]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/CGcwLIMXs9Qd0-JwJtPDv_eHgRE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SWIXWSRCFRIJ7H7HAISLD7KH2E.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of U.S.翻译:我们 and Chinese flags" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Flags of U.S.翻译:我们 and China are seen in this illustration picture taken August 2, 2022. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo翻译:这张摄于 2022 年 8 月 2 日的插图照片中可以看到美国和中国的国旗。REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Chinese foreign ministry said on Thursday a leading official from its department of arms control affairs will lead a delegation in China-U.S.翻译:我们 nuclear talks.</p>   <p>The ministry did not name the official.翻译:该部没有透露该官员的姓名。</p>   <p>"Next week in Washington, China and U.S.翻译:我们 will hold arms control and non-proliferation consultations at director-general level," spokesperson Wang Wenbin said when asked about a report that China agreed to nuclear arms-control talks with the United States.</p>   <p>According to plans agreed by both sides, Wang said China and the U.S.翻译:我们 will conduct dialogue and exchanges on a wide range of issues such as implementation of international arms control treaties.</p>   <p>The talks come days after Foreign Minister Wang Yi met with senior U.S.翻译:我们 officials, with both sides agreeing to hold a series of consultations in the near future.</p>   <p>Wang also met with U.S.翻译:我们 President Biden in talks that the White House described as a "good opportunity" in terms of keeping lines of communication open between the two geopolitical rivals with deep policy differences.翻译:王毅还与美国总统拜登进行了会谈，白宫称此次会谈是保持两个政策分歧深刻的地缘政治对手之间沟通渠道畅通的“好机会”。</p>    <span>Reporting by Laurie Chen; Writing by Bernard Orr; Editing by Sonali Paul and Edwina Gibbs翻译:陈劳瑞报道；伯纳德·奥尔撰写；索纳莉·保罗和埃德温娜·吉布斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 07:59:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">EHYFN6PFDVJ3FJ3KCKOO4667DE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-says-official-lead-delegation-china-us-nuclear-talks-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>USA/DIPLOMACY (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[新日铁撤销对丰田、三井的专利诉讼]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/2dZ4Ug0BmHRnF1sjytV-Yj6gVC4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GPUS66TPNBIO7ATCETO7VJHRII.jpg" alt="The logos of Nippon Steel Corp. are didplayed at the company headquarters in Tokyo" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logos of Nippon Steel Corp. are didplayed at the company headquarters in Tokyo, Japan March 18, 2019. REUTERS/Yuka Obayashi/File Photo翻译:2019 年 3 月 18 日，新日铁公司的标志在日本东京的公司总部播放。路透社/Yuka Obayashi/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Japan's Nippon Steel <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/5401.T" target="_blank">(5401.T)</a> said on Thursday it had dropped lawsuits against Toyota Motor <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/7203.T" target="_blank">(7203.T)</a> and Mitsui &amp; Co <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/8031.T" target="_blank">(8031.T)</a> over electrical steel sheet patents, but continues to seek damages from Chinese steelmaker Baoshan Iron &amp; Steel Co <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/600019.SS" target="_blank">(600019.SS)</a>.翻译:日本新日铁<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/5401.T" target="_blank">（5401.T）</a>周四表示，已撤销对丰田汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/7203.T" target="_blank">（7203.T）</a>和三井物产<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/8031.T" target="_blank">（8031.T）</a>有关电工钢板专利的诉讼，但继续向中国钢铁制造商宝山钢铁寻求赔偿公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/600019.SS" target="_blank">（600019.SS）</a> 。</p>   <p>With the lawsuits filed in 2021, Nippon Steel sought compensatory damages from Toyota, Baoshan, Mitsui &amp; Co and Mitsui &amp; Co. Steel, alleging their infringement of its patents relating to non-oriented electrical steel sheets.翻译:新日铁于2021年提起诉讼，向丰田、宝山、三井物产和三井钢铁公司寻求赔偿，指控它们侵犯了新日铁无取向电工钢板的专利。</p>   <p>The Japanese steelmaker has terminated the lawsuits against Toyota and Mitsui by waiving claims against them, it said in a statement.翻译:这家日本钢铁制造商在一份声明中表示，已终止对丰田和三井的诉讼，放弃对它们的索赔。</p>   <p>Nippon Steel will continue its lawsuits against Baoshan, and will "firmly protect its intellectual property rights as the fruits of its technological development," it added.翻译:新日铁将继续对宝钢提起诉讼，并将“坚决保护作为其技术发展成果的知识产权”。</p>    <span>Reporting by Mariko Katsumura in Tokyo; Editing by Janane Venkatraman翻译:胜村真理子 (Mariko Katsumura) 东京报道；编辑：贾南·文卡特拉曼 </span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 07:26:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6HDOXJKWSJIE5B6PJMCHU4ZD4A</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/nippon-steel-drops-patent-lawsuits-against-toyota-mitsui-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>NIPPONSTEEL</category>
                
                <category>TOYOTA/BAO STEEL (URGENT, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[各国政府竞相监管人工智能工具]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/76Jb3z66IupP_fz1J1eLJ3Ff_zs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZJ7VVLBOAZNETDZF34KQ7NPIJ4.jpg" alt="Illustration shows AI (Artificial Intelligence) letters and computer motherboard" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>AI (Artificial Intelligence) letters are placed on  computer motherboard in this illustration taken June 23, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration//File Photo翻译:在这张摄于 2023 年 6 月 23 日的插图中，AI（人工智能）字母被放置在计算机主板上。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration//档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Rapid advances in artificial intelligence (AI) such as Microsoft-backed OpenAI's ChatGPT are complicating governments' efforts to agree laws governing the use of the technology.翻译:人工智能 (AI) 的快速发展，例如微软支持的 OpenAI 的 ChatGPT，使政府就管理该技术使用的法律达成一致的努力变得更加复杂。</p>   <p>Here are the latest steps national and international governing bodies are taking to regulate AI tools:翻译:以下是国家和国际管理机构为监管人工智能工具而采取的最新措施：</p>    <h 1="">AUSTRALIA</h>  <p>* Planning regulations翻译:* 规划规定</p>   <p>Australia will make search engines <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/australia-require-ai-made-child-abuse-material-be-removed-search-results-2023-09-08/">draft new codes</a> to prevent the sharing of child sexual abuse material created by AI and the production of deepfake versions of the same material.翻译:澳大利亚将要求搜索引擎<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/australia-require-ai-made-child-abuse-material-be-removed-search-results-2023-09-08/">起草新代码，</a>以防止共享人工智能创建的儿童性虐待材料以及制作同一材料的深度伪造版本。</p>    <h 1="">BRITAIN</h>  <p>* Planning regulations翻译:* 规划规定</p>   <p>More than 25 countries present at the first global <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/britain-aims-global-leadership-role-with-ai-safety-summit-2023-10-18/">AI Safety Summit</a> at Bletchley Park, including the U.S.翻译:我们 and China, as well as the EU, on Nov. 1 signed a "Bletchley Declaration" saying countries needed to work together and establish a common approach on oversight.翻译:11 月 1 日，包括美国、中国和欧盟在内的超过 25 个国家出席在布莱奇利公园举行的首届全球<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/britain-aims-global-leadership-role-with-ai-safety-summit-2023-10-18/">人工智能安全峰会</a>，签署了一份《布莱奇利宣言》，表示各国需要共同努力，在人工智能安全问题上建立共同的方法。监督。</p>   <p>Britain said at the summit it would triple to 300 million pounds ($364 million) its <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/britain-invest-300-million-pounds-ai-supercomputing-2023-11-01/">funding</a> for the "AI Research Resource", comprising two supercomputers which will support research into making advanced AI models safe.翻译:英国在峰会上表示，将把“人工智能研究资源”的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/britain-invest-300-million-pounds-ai-supercomputing-2023-11-01/">资金</a>增加两倍，达到 3 亿英镑（3.64 亿美元），该资源由两台超级计算机组成，将支持先进人工智能模型安全的研究。</p>   <p>Prime Minister Rishi Sunak on Oct. 26 said Britain would set up the world's first AI <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/uks-sunak-says-ai-risks-must-be-addressed-ahead-key-safety-summit-2023-10-25/">safety institute</a> to "understand what each new model is capable of, exploring all the risks from social harms like bias and misinformation through to the most extreme risks".翻译:英国首相里希·苏纳克 (Rishi Sunak) 10 月 26 日表示，英国将成立世界上第一个人工智能<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/uks-sunak-says-ai-risks-must-be-addressed-ahead-key-safety-summit-2023-10-25/">安全研究所</a>，以“了解每种新模型的能力，探索从偏见和错误信息等社会危害到最极端风险的所有风险”。</p>   <p>Britain's data watchdog said on Oct. 10 it had issued Snap Inc's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SNAP.N" target="_blank">(SNAP.N)</a> Snapchat with a preliminary <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/uk-regulator-issues-notice-snapchat-over-privacy-risks-posed-by-ai-chatbot-2023-10-06/">enforcement notice</a> over a possible failure to properly assess the privacy risks of its generative AI chatbot to users, particularly children.翻译:英国数据监管机构 10 月 10 日表示，已向 Snap 公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SNAP.N" target="_blank">(SNAP.N)</a>的 Snapchat 发出初步<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/uk-regulator-issues-notice-snapchat-over-privacy-risks-posed-by-ai-chatbot-2023-10-06/">执行通知</a>，原因是该公司的生成式人工智能聊天机器人可能未能正确评估其对用户（尤其是儿童）的隐私风险。</p>    <h 1="">CHINA</h>  <p>* Implemented temporary regulations翻译:* 实施临时规定</p>   <p>Wu Zhaohui, China's vice minister of science and technology, told the opening session of the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/britain-aims-global-leadership-role-with-ai-safety-summit-2023-10-18/">AI Safety Summit</a> in Britain on Nov. 1 that Beijing was ready to increase collaboration on AI safety to help build an international "governance framework".翻译:中国科技部副部长吴朝晖11月1日在英国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/britain-aims-global-leadership-role-with-ai-safety-summit-2023-10-18/">人工智能安全峰会</a>开幕式上表示，北京准备加强人工智能安全领域的合作，帮助建立国际“治理框架”。</p>   <p>China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/china-proposes-blacklist-sources-used-train-generative-ai-models-2023-10-12/">published</a> proposed security requirements for firms offering services powered by generative AI in October, including a blacklist of sources that cannot be used to train AI models.翻译:中国于 10 月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/china-proposes-blacklist-sources-used-train-generative-ai-models-2023-10-12/">发布了</a>针对提供生成式人工智能服务的公司的拟议安全要求，其中包括一份不能用于训练人工智能模型的来源黑名单。</p>   <p>The country <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/china-issues-temporary-rules-generative-ai-services-2023-07-13/">issued</a> a set of temporary measures in August, requiring service providers to submit security assessments and receive clearance before releasing mass-market AI products.翻译:该国于 8 月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/china-issues-temporary-rules-generative-ai-services-2023-07-13/">发布了</a>一系列临时措施，要求服务提供商在发布大众市场人工智能产品之前提交安全评估并获得许可。</p>    <h 1="">EUROPEAN UNION</h>  <p>* Planning regulations翻译:* 规划规定</p>   <p>European lawmakers <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/eu-lawmakers-make-progress-crucial-talks-new-ai-rules-sources-2023-10-25/">agreed</a> on Oct. 24 on a critical part of new AI rules outlining the types of systems that will be designated "high risk", inching closer to a broader agreement on the landmark AI Act which is expected in December, according to five people familiar with the matter.翻译:据五位知情人士<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/eu-lawmakers-make-progress-crucial-talks-new-ai-rules-sources-2023-10-25/">透露，</a>欧洲立法者于 10 月 24 日就新人工智能规则的关键部分达成一致，概述了将被指定为“高风险”的系统类型，距离预计于 12 月就具有里程碑意义的人工智能法案达成更广泛的协议又近了一步。熟悉此事。</p>   <p>European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen on Sept. 13 called for a global panel to assess the risks and benefits of AI.翻译:9 月 13 日，欧盟委员会主席乌苏拉·冯德莱恩 (Ursula von der Leyen) 呼吁成立一个全球小组来评估人工智能的风险和收益。</p>    <h 1="">FRANCE</h>  <p>* Investigating possible breaches翻译:* 调查可能的违规行为</p>   <p>France's privacy watchdog <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/french-privacy-watchdog-investigating-complaints-about-chatgpt-2023-04-11/">said in April</a> it was investigating complaints about ChatGPT.翻译:法国隐私监管机构<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/french-privacy-watchdog-investigating-complaints-about-chatgpt-2023-04-11/">4 月份表示</a>正在调查有关 ChatGPT 的投诉。</p>    <h 1="">G7</h>  <p>* Seeking input on regulations翻译:* 寻求有关法规的意见</p>   <p>The Group of Seven countries agreed on Oct. 30 to an 11-point <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/g7-agree-ai-code-conduct-companies-g7-document-2023-10-29/">code of conduct</a> for firms developing advanced AI systems, which "aims to promote safe, secure, and trustworthy AI worldwide".翻译:七国集团于 10 月 30 日就开发先进人工智能系统的公司达成了 11 点<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/g7-agree-ai-code-conduct-companies-g7-document-2023-10-29/">行为准则</a>，“旨在在全球范围内促进安全、可靠和值得信赖的人工智能”。</p>    <h 1="">ITALY</h>  <p>* Investigating possible breaches翻译:* 调查可能的违规行为</p>   <p>Italy's data protection authority <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/italy-watchdog-review-other-ai-systems-after-chatgpt-brief-ban-2023-05-22/">plans to review</a> AI platforms and hire experts in the field, a top official said in May. ChatGPT was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/italy-data-protection-agency-opens-chatgpt-probe-privacy-concerns-2023-03-31/">temporarily banned</a> in the country in March, but it was made <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chatgpt-is-available-again-users-italy-spokesperson-says-2023-04-28/">available</a> again in April.翻译:一位高级官员今年 5 月表示，意大利数据保护机构<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/italy-watchdog-review-other-ai-systems-after-chatgpt-brief-ban-2023-05-22/">计划审查</a>人工智能平台并聘请该领域的专家。 ChatGPT 于 3 月份在该国被<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/italy-data-protection-agency-opens-chatgpt-probe-privacy-concerns-2023-03-31/">暂时禁止</a>，但于 4 月份再次<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chatgpt-is-available-again-users-italy-spokesperson-says-2023-04-28/">开放</a>。</p>    <h 1="">JAPAN</h>  <p>* Investigating possible breaches翻译:* 调查可能的违规行为</p>   <p>Japan expects to introduce <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/japan-leaning-toward-softer-ai-rules-than-eu-source-2023-07-03/">by the end of 2023</a> regulations that are likely closer to the U.S.翻译:我们 attitude than the stringent ones planned in the EU, an official close to deliberations said in July.</p>   <p>The country's privacy watchdog <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/japan-privacy-watchdog-warns-chatgpt-maker-openai-data-collection-2023-06-02/">has warned</a> OpenAI not to collect sensitive data without people's permission.翻译:该国隐私监管机构<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/japan-privacy-watchdog-warns-chatgpt-maker-openai-data-collection-2023-06-02/">警告</a>OpenAI，未经人民许可不得收集敏感数据。</p>    <h 1="">POLAND</h>  <p>* Investigating possible breaches翻译:* 调查可能的违规行为</p>   <p>Poland's Personal Data Protection Office said in September it was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/poland-investigates-openai-over-privacy-concerns-2023-09-21/">investigating OpenAI</a> over a complaint that ChatGPT breaks EU data protection laws.翻译:波兰个人数据保护办公室 9 月表示，正在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/poland-investigates-openai-over-privacy-concerns-2023-09-21/">调查 OpenAI</a> ，因为有人投诉 ChatGPT 违反了欧盟数据保护法。</p>    <h 1="">SPAIN</h>  <p>* Investigating possible breaches翻译:* 调查可能的违规行为</p>   <p>Spain's data protection agency in April launched a preliminary investigation into potential data breaches by ChatGPT.翻译:西班牙数据保护机构四月份对 ChatGPT 潜在的数据泄露事件启动了初步调查。</p>    <h 1="">UNITED NATIONS</h>  <p>* Planning regulations翻译:* 规划规定</p>   <p>The U.N. Secretary-General António Guterres on Oct. 26 announced the creation of a 39-member <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/united-nations-creates-advisory-body-address-ai-governance-2023-10-26/">advisory body</a>, composed of tech company executives, government officials and academics, to address issues in the international governance of AI.翻译:联合国秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯10月26日宣布成立一个由39名成员组成的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/united-nations-creates-advisory-body-address-ai-governance-2023-10-26/">咨询机构</a>，由科技公司高管、政府官员和学者组成，以解决人工智能国际治理中的问题。</p>   <p>The U.N. Security Council <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/un-security-council-meets-first-time-ai-risks-2023-07-18/">held</a> its first formal discussion on AI in July, addressing military and non-military applications of AI that "could have very serious consequences for global peace and security", Guterres said at the time.翻译:古特雷斯当时表示，联合国安理会于 7 月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/un-security-council-meets-first-time-ai-risks-2023-07-18/">举行了</a>关于人工智能的首次正式讨论，讨论了人工智能的军事和非军事应用“可能对全球和平与安全产生非常严重的后果”。</p>   <p>U.S.翻译:我们</p>   <p>* Seeking input on regulations翻译:* 寻求有关法规的意见</p>   <p>The U.S.翻译:我们 will launch an AI <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-launch-its-own-ai-safety-institute-raimondo-2023-11-01/">safety institute</a> to evaluate known and emerging risks of so-called "frontier" AI models, Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo said on Nov. 1 during the AI Safety Summit in Britain.翻译:美国商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多 (Gina Raimondo) 11 月 1 日在英国举行的人工智能安全峰会上表示，美国将成立一个人工智能<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-launch-its-own-ai-safety-institute-raimondo-2023-11-01/">安全研究所</a>，以评估所谓“前沿”人工智能模型的已知和新出现的风险。</p>   <p>President Joe Biden issued a new <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/white-house-unveils-wide-ranging-action-mitigate-ai-risks-2023-10-30/">executive order</a> on Oct. 30 to require developers of AI systems that pose risks to U.S.翻译:我们 national security, the economy, public health or safety to share the results of safety tests with the government.</p>   <p>The U.S.翻译:我们 Congress in September held <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-senate-panel-hold-ai-hearing-with-microsoft-nvidia-2023-09-08/">hearings on AI</a> and an AI forum featuring Meta <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/META.O" target="_blank">(META.O)</a> CEO Mark Zuckerberg and Tesla CEO Elon Musk. More than 60 senators took part in the talks, during which Musk called for a U.S.翻译:我们 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/musk-zuckerberg-gates-join-us-senators-ai-forum-2023-09-13/">"referee" for AI</a>.</p>   <p>The U.S.翻译:我们 Federal Trade Commission opened in July an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-ftc-opens-investigation-into-openai-washington-post-2023-07-13/">investigation</a> into OpenAI on claims that it has run afoul of consumer protection laws.</p>    <span>Compiled by Alessandro Parodi and Amir Orusov in Gdansk; editing by Kirsten Donovan, Mark Potter, Christina Fincher and Milla Nissi翻译:由 Alessandro Parodi 和 Amir Orusov 在格但斯克编译；克尔斯滕·多诺万、马克·波特、克里斯蒂娜·芬奇和米拉·尼西编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 07:20:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">EEMO3Q2B55PETH65PTLK62MESU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/governments-race-regulate-ai-tools-2023-10-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>TECH</category>
                
                <category>AI/REGULATIONS (UPDATE 1, FACTBOX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[北京入冬晚一周，华北地区天气温暖]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/gI_AU9Csr_fqFwvOlvPJLd7uq5I=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FQGM7ZOWQJK3FJZD7MAIVXBHK4.jpg" alt="Beijing shrouded in smog" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People wearing face masks wait at an intersection in Beijing's Central Business District (CBD), as the city is shrouded in smog, in China November 1, 2023. REUTER/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023 年 11 月 1 日，中国，北京中央商务区 (CBD) 的城市被雾霾笼罩，戴着口罩的人们在十字路口等待。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>       <p>Winter is expected to arrive late, and suddenly in Beijing this year as daytime temperatures hovered above 20 degrees Celsius (68 Fahrenheit), bathing the capital in a warm smog, while other parts of China basked in record highs above 30C.翻译:预计今年北京的冬天会来得较晚，而且会突然到来，白天气温徘徊在 20 摄氏度（68 华氏度）以上，让首都沐浴在温暖的雾霾之中，而中国其他地区的气温则创下了 30 摄氏度以上的历史新高。</p>   <p>The official start of winter in the capital could come on Nov. 6, state-run Beijing Daily reported on Wednesday, almost a week later than in previous years, with average temperatures expected to dive more than 10C.翻译:据国营《北京日报》周三报道，首都冬季可能会在11月6日正式开始，比往年晚了近一周，平均气温预计将下降10摄氏度以上。</p>   <p>The weather in many parts of China had stayed stubbornly warm entering November, with cities in eastern and central provinces such as Shandong, Anhui, Jiangsu and Henan still logging temperatures above 30C.翻译:进入11月，我国多地天气持续高温，山东、安徽、江苏、河南等东部和中部省份城市气温仍然在30℃以上。</p>   <p>As of 2 p.m. (0600 GMT) on Wednesday, more than 600 meteorological stations across China had seen temperatures shatter historical highs for November, according to the official Xinhua news agency.翻译:据官方新华社报道，截至周三下午 2 点（格林威治标准时间 0600），中国各地 600 多个气象站的气温打破了 11 月份的历史新高。</p>   <p>One station in eastern China's Jinan city recorded an average temperature of 25C on Wednesday, 12.6C higher than normal and resembling a level observed at the end of August, Jim Yang, a researcher at the China Meteorological Administration, said on the social media platform X.翻译:中国气象局研究员杨吉姆在社交媒体平台X上表示，中国东部济南市的一个站点周三平均气温为25℃，比正常高12.6℃，与8月底的水平相似。 。</p>   <p>Beijing logged its <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/beijing-logs-second-warmest-october-summer-like-autumn-2023-11-01/">second-warmest October</a> last month in over 60 years. Temperatures also averaged 3.4C higher than normal in the last 10 days of the month, a record for the same period since 1961.翻译:上个月，北京经历了 60 多年来<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/beijing-logs-second-warmest-october-summer-like-autumn-2023-11-01/">第二个最热的 10 月</a>。本月最后 10 天平均气温也比正常水平高出 3.4 摄氏度，创下 1961 年以来同期最高纪录。</p>   <p>In tandem with the warm weather, smog has also shrouded Beijing and its surrounding areas for days.翻译:随着天气转暖，雾霾也连续多日笼罩北京及周边地区。</p>   <p>On Thursday, heavy and dense fog is forecast to envelop regions including Beijing and surrounding cities for the fifth day, with visibility dropping below 200 metres in parts of Hebei province, China's National Meteorological Center said.翻译:中国国家气象中心预计，周四，北京及周边城市将连续第五天出现大雾，河北部分地区能见度降至200米以下。</p>   <p>Experts quoted by state media say the recent "rare" summer-like weather was due to weaker-than-usual cold air currents, which had also led to persistent hazy weather with heavy air pollution shrouding the city.翻译:官方媒体援引专家的话称，近期出现“罕见”的夏季天气是由于冷气流弱于平常，这也导致持续的雾霾天气，严重的空气污染笼罩着这座城市。</p>   <p>In coming days, temperatures across northern China are expected to drop sharply. Northeastern cities such as Shenyang, Changchun and Harbin would see a sharp drop of more than 15C.翻译:未来几天，华北地区气温预计将大幅下降。沉阳、长春、哈尔滨等东北城市气温将大幅下降15℃以上。</p>   <p>Other cities such as Beijing, Zhengzhou, Jinan, Xian and Shijiazhuang will see a sudden decline of 10C to 15C.翻译:北京、郑州、济南、西安、石家庄等城市气温将骤降10℃至15℃。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ethan Wang, Ryan Woo and Shanghai Newsroom; Editing by Simon Cameron-Moore翻译:Ethan Wang、Ryan Woo 和上海新闻编辑室的报道；西蒙·卡梅伦-摩尔 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 06:54:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">GWVVG2LE7FMFZPCA2VQ3IZLSLA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/winter-coming-week-late-beijing-northern-china-basks-warm-weather-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ethan Wang, Ryan Woo]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ASIA</category>
                
                <category>WEATHER/BEIJING (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早盘竞价：鲍威尔找到平衡，市场欢呼]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/DXyJWmdsc6bVCa8FIGQsV0aiwa8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GC2ZO6BZVRIGTAWLABOEJW6KG4.jpg" alt="Federal Reserve Chairman Jerome Powell speaks at a press conference in Washington" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Federal Reserve Board Chair Jerome Powell answers a question at a press conference following a closed two-day meeting of the Federal Open Market Committee on interest rate policy at the Federal Reserve in Washington, U.S.翻译:我们, November 1, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>       <p>A look at the day ahead in European and global markets from Wayne Cole.翻译:韦恩·科尔 (Wayne Cole) 对欧洲和全球市场未来一天的展望。</p>   <p>It's been a day for relief rallies in Asia as investors became increasingly confident the next move in U.S.翻译:我们 interest rates will be down, not up. All the major Asian equity markets are higher, as are U.S and European stock futures.</p>   <p>While Federal Reserve Chair Jerome <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/fed-poised-hold-rates-steady-despite-economys-bullish-tone-2023-11-01/">Powell</a> maintained the option of another hike, he sounded less than committed to the idea. Risks were now "more two sided" and almost "balanced", he said in his presser. They were making progress on inflation and, crucially, expectations of inflation "were in a good place".翻译:尽管美联储主席杰罗姆<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/fed-poised-hold-rates-steady-despite-economys-bullish-tone-2023-11-01/">·鲍威尔</a>仍然保留再次加息的选择，但他听起来并不太坚定这一想法。他在新闻发布会上表示，现在的风险“更多是双面性的”并且几乎​​是“平衡的”。他们在通胀方面取得了进展，最重要的是，通胀预期“处于良好状态”。</p>   <p>That was enough for markets to lower the risk of a December rate hike to 22%, and a January move to 28%. Meanwhile, the probability of a rate cut by June next year advanced to almost 70% and futures now imply around 85 basis points of easing for all of 2024.翻译:这足以让市场将 12 月加息的风险降低至 22%，并将 1 月加息的风险降低至 28%。与此同时，明年 6 月降息的可能性升至近 70%，期货目前暗示 2024 年全年降息幅度约为 85 个基点。</p>   <p>Powell, of course, played down the chance of cuts but he must know that with inflation steadily cooling real rates are rising. If the Fed does nothing at all, policy will effectively tighten into next year even as the economy is expected to slow, thus adding to the risks of recession.翻译:当然，鲍威尔淡化了降息的可能性，但他必须知道，随着通胀稳步降温，实际利率正在上升。如果美联储什么都不做，即使经济预计放缓，政策也将在明年有效收紧，从而增加经济衰退的风险。</p>   <p>The Treasury market has played its part by pushing yields up in recent weeks, and duly celebrated by pulling them down again, at least for now. Ten-year yields are off 22 basis points from Wednesday's high of 4.71%, though that remains far above the 4.0% levels held in early August.翻译:最近几周，美国国债市场通过推高收益率发挥了自己的作用，并通过再次拉低收益率来庆祝，至少目前如此。十年期国债收益率较周三高点 4.71% 下跌 22 个基点，但仍远高于 8 月初的 4.0% 水平。</p>   <p>The 30-year yields dropped back under 5% helped by relief Treasury's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us-treasury-increases-size-most-its-debt-auctions-2023-11-01/">refunding</a> plans included less issuance at the longer end than many had <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/view-us-treasury-increases-size-most-its-debt-auctions-2023-11-01/">feared</a>.翻译:受财政部<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us-treasury-increases-size-most-its-debt-auctions-2023-11-01/">退款</a>计划（包括长期债券发行量低于许多人的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/view-us-treasury-increases-size-most-its-debt-auctions-2023-11-01/">担忧</a>）的帮助，30 年期国债收益率回落至 5% 以下。</p>   <p>The dovish mood proved infectious as investors pared back rate risks across much of the developed world. The Dec 2024 EURIBOR future jumped to a five-month high and now implies almost 100 basis points of easing in 2024.翻译:随着投资者削减大部分发达国家的利率风险，鸽派情绪被证明具有感染力。 2024 年 12 月 EURIBOR 期货跃升至五个月高位，目前意味着 2024 年将宽松近 100 个基点。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/bank-england-set-keep-rates-15-year-high-despite-slowdown-signs-2023-11-02/">Bank of England</a> is seen as odds-on to hold rates when it meets later on Thursday, with a near 70% chance its tightening cycle is done and dusted.翻译:人们认为<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/bank-england-set-keep-rates-15-year-high-despite-slowdown-signs-2023-11-02/">英国央行</a>在周四晚些时候举行的会议上保持利率不变的可能性很大，紧缩周期结束并尘埃落定的可能性接近 70%。</p>   <p>For currencies, the drop in Treasury yields pulled the U.S.翻译:我们 dollar down modestly, while the improvement in risk sentiment gave a lift to the battered Aussie and kiwi dollars.</p>   <p>The next major hurdle for equities will be results from the $2.7 trillion behemoth Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a> after the bell. The focus will be on iPhone 15 sales and whether a strong start was slowed by cooling demand in China. Guidance for the crucial December quarter holiday season could also help.翻译:股市的下一个主要障碍将是市值 2.7 万亿美元的庞然大物苹果<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a>盘后的业绩。焦点将集中于 iPhone 15 的销量，以及强劲的开局是否因中国需求降温而放缓。对关键的 12 月季度假期的指导也可能有所帮助。</p>   <p>Markets will now be hoping the payrolls report on Friday doesn't rain on the party.翻译:市场现在希望周五的非农就业报告不会给聚会带来负面影响。</p>   <p>Key developments that could influence markets on Thursday:翻译:周四可能影响市场的主要事态发展：</p>   <p>- Appearances by ECB Board members Edouard Fernandez-Bollo and Isabel Schnabel, and by chief economist Philip Lane翻译:- 欧洲央行董事会成员爱德华·费尔南德斯-博洛和伊莎贝尔·施纳贝尔以及首席经济学家菲利普·莱恩出席</p>   <p>- Interest rate decisions from the Bank of England and Norges Bank翻译:- 英格兰银行和挪威央行的利率决定</p>   <p>- German reports unemployment data, while U.S.翻译:我们 has weekly jobless claims, durable goods orders and auto sales</p>    <span>By Wayne Cole. Editing by Sam Holmes翻译:作者：韦恩·科尔。山姆·霍姆斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:34:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F4HZJJHZTFN35B7JVBBPLKK5WY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/global-markets-view-europe-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Wayne Cole]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>EUROPE</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[菲律宾警方追捕六名被绑架中国公民]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tsU7yVP9535QCIzldv4Bbub1lvo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HIV2JPEUHJPYHNYM64VVRTCLTM.jpg" alt="National flags are placed outside a room where Philippine Finance Secretary Carlos Dominguez and China's Commerce Minister Gao Hucheng address reporters after their meeting in Beijing" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>National flags are placed outside a room where Philippine Finance Secretary Carlos Dominguez and China's Commerce Minister Gao Hucheng address reporters after their meeting in Beijing, China, January 23, 2017. REUTERS/Damir Sagolj翻译:2017年1月23日，菲律宾财政部长卡洛斯·多明计斯和中国商务部部长高虎城在中国北京会晤后向记者发表讲话，房间外悬挂着国旗。路透社/Damir Sagolj</figcaption></figure>       <p>Philippine authorities were trying to track the whereabouts of six Chinese nationals who were abducted in the capital region this week, police said on Thursday.翻译:警方周四表示，菲律宾当局正在试图追踪本周在首都地区被绑架的六名中国公民的下落。</p>   <p>Police anti-kidnapping chief Cosme Abrenica said authorities were investigating the abduction of nine people on Monday in an upscale neighbourhood in southern Metro Manila. Six of the victims were Chinese, who remain missing, and three were Filipino who were released shortly after they were abducted.翻译:警方反绑架负责人科斯梅·阿布伦尼卡 (Cosme Abrenica) 表示，当局正在调查周一在马尼拉大都会南部一个高档社区发生的九人绑架事件。其中六名受害者是中国人，目前仍然失踪，三名受害者是菲律宾人，他们在被绑架后不久就被释放。</p>   <p>"We have no information if it's kidnap-for-ransom, kidnapping or what the motive is. We haven't established it yet," Abrenica said.翻译:“我们不知道这是否是绑架勒索、绑架或动机是什么。我们还没有确定，”阿布雷尼卡说。</p>   <p>Abrenica did not disclose the identities of the victims or give any details on their status in the Philippines.翻译:Abrenica 没有透露受害者的身份，也没有提供有关他们在菲律宾的状况的任何详细信息。</p>   <p>Philip Aguilar, the police chief of Calauan town where the Filipino victims were recovered, said one of the survivors told them the kidnappers had barged into their home before dawn on Monday.翻译:菲律宾受害者被找到的卡劳安镇警察局长菲利普·阿吉拉尔表示，其中一名幸存者告诉他们，绑匪周一黎明前闯入了他们的家。</p>   <p>The Chinese embassy in Manila said it had noted a request from Reuters for comment.翻译:中国驻马尼拉大使馆表示，已注意到路透社的置评请求。</p>   <p>While police said the motive for this week's kidnapping was not known, China has in the past complained to the Philippines about its citizens being lured to work in online gaming firms and then being cheated, extorted and exposed to “modern slavery”.翻译:虽然警方表示本周绑架的动机尚不清楚，但中国过去曾向菲律宾抱怨其公民被引诱到网络游戏公司工作，然后遭到欺骗、勒索并遭受“现代奴隶制”。</p>    <span>Reporting by Mikhail Flores; editing by Robert Birsel翻译:米哈伊尔·弗洛雷斯报道；罗伯特·伯塞尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:34:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">XLLCXOZCRRL2HOSPLU4E5GUUDE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippine-police-hunt-six-kidnapped-chinese-nationals-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>PHILIPPINES</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/CRIME</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国驱逐舰、加拿大护卫舰过境台湾海峡-美军]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The U.S.翻译:我们 destroyer USS Rafael Peralta and a Royal Canadian Navy frigate HMCS Ottawa transited the Taiwan Strait on Wednesday, the U.S.翻译:我们 7th Fleet said in a statement, making their third joint transit in the region since June.</p>   <p>Taiwan's defence ministry said the two warships sailed through the Taiwan Strait in a northerly direction on Wednesday night, adding it monitored the movement and the situation was "normal."翻译:台湾国防部表示，两艘军舰周三晚间向北航行通过台湾海峡，并补充说，国防部监测了这一行动，情况“正常”。</p>   <p>China followed and monitored the transit and handled the situation in line with the law and regulations, the People's Liberation Army Eastern Theater Command said in a statement on Thurday.翻译:中国人民解放军东部战区周四在一份声明中表示，中方对过境情况进行跟踪监控，并依法依规进行处理。</p>   <p>The U.S.翻译:我们 and Canadian navies made a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-canadian-warships-again-sail-through-taiwan-strait-2023-09-09/">similar transit</a> in September.</p>   <p>In June, the U.S.翻译:我们 navy released a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/after-dangerous-encounters-us-accuses-china-military-aggressiveness-2023-06-05/">video</a> of what it called an "unsafe interaction" in the Taiwan Strait in which a Chinese warship crossed in front of a U.S.翻译:我们 destroyer. Chinese foreign ministry said its military's measures were completely reasonable, legitimate, and professional and safe.</p>   <p>The U.S.翻译:我们 destroyer USS Chung-Hoon and Canadian frigate Montreal were conducting a "routine" transit of the strait in June.</p>    <span>Reporting by Albee Zhang and Ryan Woo in Beijing and Yi-Mou Lee in Taiwan; Editing by Simon Cameron-Moore翻译:北京的 Albee 张和 Ryan Woo 以及台湾的 Yi-Mou Lee 的报道；西蒙·卡梅伦-摩尔 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 04:41:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FC3BHBJ7XJLSJBD5GH7UGKDOZ4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us-destroyer-canadian-frigate-transit-taiwan-strait-us-military-2023-11-02/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>USA/TAIWAN (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
