<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 07:19:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[恒大没有按要求的时间提交法庭文件-来源]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/HYWTWNP7jg9c2FlYzXLnn0r47TI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KHGP2JDRPBNUJL46PQKS6Y2B34.jpg" alt="An Evergrande sign is seen near residential buildings at an Evergrande residential complex in Beijing<br><br>北京恒大住宅小区附近的恒大标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An Evergrande sign is seen near residential buildings at an Evergrande residential complex in Beijing<br><br>北京恒大住宅小区附近的恒大标志, China September 27, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China Evergrande Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a> did not submit defence documents to a Hong Kong court before a deadline that comes ahead of a winding-up hearing against the company scheduled for next Monday, a person with knowledge of the matter said.<br><br>一位知情人士称，中国恒大集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）</a>没有在定于下周一举行的针对该公司的清盘听证会之前的截止日期之前向香港法院提交辩护文件。</p>   <p>The embattled Chinese property developer was directed by the Hong Kong High Court to submit new documents by mid-last week, the person said.<br><br>该人士称，香港高等法院指示这家陷入困境的中国房地产开发商在上周中旬之前提交新文件。</p>   <p>It was unclear whether Evergrande will make the defence submission or another request for adjournment in the coming days, the person said on condition of anonymity because they were not authorised to speak with media.<br><br>这位不愿透露姓名的人士表示，目前尚不清楚恒大是否会在未来几天内提出辩护意见或再次提出休会请求，因为他们无权接受媒体采访。</p>   <p>Evergrande and the Hong Kong High Court did not respond immediately to requests for comment.<br><br>恒大和香港高等法院没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Failure to show the judge that a restructuring plan is progressing could increase the chances of a winding-up order, lawyers said.<br><br>律师表示，未能向法官表明重组计划正在取得进展可能会增加清盘令的机会。</p>   <p>Evergrande, the world's most indebted property developer, defaulted its offshore debt in late 2021 and started work on a $31.7 billion debt restructuring plan, becoming the poster child of a debt crisis that has since engulfed China's property sector.<br><br>全球负债最重的房地产开发商恒大集团于 2021 年底发生境外债务违约，并开始实施 317 亿美元的债务重组计划，成为席卷中国房地产行业的债务危机的典型代表。</p>   <p>The company in July had been granted another adjournment until Oct. 30 on the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/evergrande-investor-says-files-lawsuit-non-repurchase-unit-shares-2022-06-27/">winding-up petition</a> based on the progress made on its offshore debt restructuring plan, which required a creditor vote initially scheduled for late September.<br><br>根据其离岸债务重组计划的进展情况，该公司于 7 月获准将<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/evergrande-investor-says-files-lawsuit-non-repurchase-unit-shares-2022-06-27/">清盘申请</a>再次延期至 10 月 30 日，该计划要求原定于 9 月底进行债权人投票。</p>   <p>That plan was thrown off course when Evergrande last month confirmed that its billionaire founder Hui Ka Yan was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shares-china-evergrande-suspended-chairman-under-police-watch-2023-09-28/">under investigation</a> for suspected criminal activities.<br><br>当恒大上个月证实其亿万富翁创始人许家印因涉嫌犯罪活动而<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shares-china-evergrande-suspended-chairman-under-police-watch-2023-09-28/">接受调查</a>时，该计划被打乱。</p>   <p>The company <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/evergrande-shares-sink-after-saying-it-is-unable-issue-new-debt-2023-09-25/">did not get regulatory approval</a> for issuing new dollar bonds, which is a crucial part of the restructuring plan, and has not held the creditor vote.<br><br>作为重组计划的重要组成部分，该公司发行新美元债券<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/evergrande-shares-sink-after-saying-it-is-unable-issue-new-debt-2023-09-25/">尚未获得监管部门批准</a>，也未举行债权人投票。</p>   <p>Evergrande said on Friday it was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-revises-terms-proposed-restructuring-2023-10-20/">revising the terms</a> of a proposed offshore debt restructuring deal to meet the firm's situation and creditors' demand, without providing details. It also said the scheme sanction hearings for courts to approval the revamp plan had been vacated.<br><br>恒大集团周五表示，正在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-revises-terms-proposed-restructuring-2023-10-20/">修改拟议的离岸债务重组协议的条款</a>，以满足公司的情况和债权人的要求，但未提供细节。它还表示，法院批准改革计划的计划制裁听证会已被取消。</p>   <p>Its offshore bondholders said this month they were <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/evergrande-offshore-bondholders-surprised-by-debt-restructuring-regulatory-2023-10-09/">surprised</a> by announcements that its restructuring plan failed to meet regulatory requirements, and raised concerns about a possible liquidation.<br><br>其境外债券持有人本月表示，他们对其重组计划未能满足监管要求的公告感到<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/evergrande-offshore-bondholders-surprised-by-debt-restructuring-regulatory-2023-10-09/">惊讶</a>，并对可能的清算表示担忧。</p>   <p>Top Shine, an investor in Evergrande unit Fangchebao, had filed the winding-up petition in June 2022 because it said Evergrande had not honoured an agreement to repurchase shares the investor bought in the unit.<br><br>恒大旗下房车宝的投资者Top Shine于2022年6月提交了清盘申请，因为该公司表示恒大没有履行回购该投资者在该子公司购买的股份的协议。</p>    <span>Reporting by Clare Jim; Editing by Jamie Freed<br><br>克莱尔·吉姆报道；杰米·弗里德编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 07:13:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ODEPINCKDFIFPI3MN5RKN6FRBY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/evergrande-did-not-file-court-documents-by-requested-time-source-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Clare Jim]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/DEBT</category>
                
                <category>EVERGRANDE (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[香港特首施政报告聚焦财产与安全]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Economic growth of 4-5% expected in 2023<br><br>预计 2023 年经济增长 4-5%</li>  <li>New national security laws to be tabled in 2024<br><br>新国家安全法将于2024年出台</li>  <li>Property transaction fees halved for some buyers<br><br>部分买家的房产交易费用减半</li>  <li>Stock transaction fees shaved from 0.13% to 0.1%<br><br>股票交易费用从 0.13% 削减至 0.1%</li> </ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/MkhwW5WzIdqW9IE8qv-SKA6FWIg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7STDYV36UNKRVGZBSBHNU35HII.jpg" alt="Hong Kong Chief Executive John Lee delivers his annual policy address at the Legislative Council in Hong Kong<br><br>香港行政长官李家超在香港立法会发表年度施政报告<br><br>香港行政长官李家超在香港立法会发表年度施政报告" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Hong Kong Chief Executive John Lee delivers his annual policy address at the Legislative Council in Hong Kong<br><br>香港行政长官李家超在香港立法会发表年度施政报告<br><br>香港行政长官李家超在香港立法会发表年度施政报告, China October 25, 2023. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tZY6JIFd3J2RnLt8DzZ8w5ZM3b4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5UTA5MHMCZPDFDQZUMKOLBN2LI.jpg" alt="Hong Kong Chief Executive John Lee delivers his annual policy address at the Legislative Council in Hong Kong<br><br>香港行政长官李家超在香港立法会发表年度施政报告<br><br>香港行政长官李家超在香港立法会发表年度施政报告" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Hong Kong Chief Executive John Lee delivers his annual policy address at the Legislative Council in Hong Kong<br><br>香港行政长官李家超在香港立法会发表年度施政报告<br><br>香港行政长官李家超在香港立法会发表年度施政报告, China October 25, 2023. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu</figcaption></figure>               <p>Hong Kong's leader focused on bolstering the property market and stabilising the ailing economy in his annual policy blueprint on Wednesday, while confirming new national security laws would be enacted next year to counter meddling by "external forces".<br><br>香港领导人在周三的年度政策蓝图中重点关注提振房地产市场和稳定陷入困境的经济，同时确认明年将颁布新的国家安全法，以应对“外部势力”的干预。</p>   <p>Chief Executive John Lee said Hong Kong's economy, which contracted 3.5% last year, would "resume growth this year" as inbound tourism and consumption improved, but he noted high interest rates elsewhere in the world posed a challenge.<br><br>行政长官李家超表示，随着入境旅游和消费的改善，去年收缩3.5%的香港经济将“今年恢复增长”，但他指出，世界其他地方的高利率构成了挑战。</p>   <p>Hong Kong's economy grew 2.2% in the first half of the year, and is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-q2-gdp-expands-15-yy-2023-08-11/">expected to grow</a> between 4.0% and 5.0% this year.<br><br>香港经济上半年增长2.2%，<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-q2-gdp-expands-15-yy-2023-08-11/">预计今年增长</a>4.0%至5.0%。</p>   <p>Lee, who was sanctioned by the U.S. government for his role in cracking down on freedoms after mass pro-democracy protests in 2019, also emphasized the need to further bolster national security.<br><br>李因2019年大规模民主抗议活动后压制自由而受到美国政府制裁，他还强调需要进一步加强国家安全。</p>   <p>"External forces continue to meddle in Hong Kong affairs," he said, without giving specifics or naming any country.<br><br>“外部势力继续干预香港事务，”他说，但没有透露具体细节，也没有点名任何国家。</p>   <p>Despite Hong Kong's attempts to restore the city's international reputation and lure more capital, further security legislation including anti-espionage laws, known as Article 23, would be enacted by the end of 2024, Lee said.<br><br>李说，尽管香港试图恢复该城市的国际声誉并吸引更多资本，但包括反间谍法（即第 23 条）在内的进一步安全立法仍将在 2024 年底前颁布。</p>   <p>"We should pay particular attention to those anti-China and destabilising activities camouflaged in the name of human rights, freedom, democracy and livelihood," he said.<br><br>他说：“我们应该特别关注那些打着人权、自由、民主、民生旗号的反华破坏稳定活动。”</p>   <p>Some Western governments have criticised the ongoing national security clamp down, which has led to the imprisonment of many opposition democrats and closure of liberal media outlets.<br><br>一些西方政府批评了正在进行的国家安全压制，这导致许多反对派民主党人被监禁，自由派媒体机构被关闭。</p>    <h 1="">PROPERTY AND STOCKS</h>  <p>Turning to the property market, Lee said stamp duty, would be halved to 7.5% from 15% for second home buyers and non-citizen buyers with immediate effect, to help revive a sector that is one of the economy's pillars.<br><br>谈及房地产市场，李表示，第二套房买家和非公民买家的印花税将从 15% 减半至 7.5%，立即生效，以帮助振兴作为经济支柱之一的行业。</p>   <p>Other adjustments were made to allow some home owners to sell properties after two years without incurring hefty duties.<br><br>还进行了其他调整，允许一些房主在两年后出售房产，而无需缴纳高额关税。</p>   <p>And Lee said the government would continue to increase the overall supply of land for public and private housing.<br><br>李显龙表示，政府将继续增加公共和私人住房的土地供应总量。</p>   <p>The reaction from investors was lukewarm, with shares of Sun Hung Kai Properties <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0016.HK" target="_blank">(0016.HK)</a> and Henderson Land <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0012.HK" target="_blank">(0012.HK)</a>, two major residential property developers, easing 0.2% and 1%, respectively, in early afternoon trading.<br><br>投资者反应冷淡，两大住宅地产开发商新鸿基地产<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0016.HK" target="_blank">(0016.HK)</a>和恒基兆业地产<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0012.HK" target="_blank">(0012.HK)</a>的股价在午后交易中分别下跌0.2%和1%。</p>   <p>Hong Kong had tried to cool the property market during a surge of nearly 300% in home prices in the decade to 2019.<br><br>在截至 2019 年的十年间，香港房价飙升了近 300%，香港曾试图为房地产市场降温。</p>   <p>Since then prices have fallen 13% in the wake of anti-government protests, the COVID pandemic, and a subsequent braindrain of hundreds of thousands of people amid a national security crackdown.<br><br>此后，由于反政府抗议、新冠疫情大流行以及随后在国家安全镇压中导致数十万人流失，价格已下跌 13%。</p>   <p>In August, property prices dropped to a seven-month low amid rising interest rates and a bleak economic outlook, and realtors expect them to end 2023 as much as 5% down.<br><br>8 月份，由于利率上升和经济前景黯淡，房地产价格跌至 7 个月低点，房地产经纪人预计 2023 年底房价将下跌 5%。</p>   <p>"The relaxation of cooling measures is only a band-aid solution that is unlikely to reverse the downward trend of home prices," said Joseph Tsang, chairman of property consultancy JLL in Hong Kong, citing the global economic downturn and interest rate hikes as lingering factors weighing on the market.<br><br>香港房地产咨询公司仲量联行主席曾俊华表示：“放松降温措施只是权宜之计，不太可能扭转房价下跌的趋势。”他表示，全球经济低迷和加息的影响挥之不去。影响市场的因素。</p>   <p>Lee said stamp duties for stock transactions would be reduced to 0.1% from 0.13% to help bolster liquidity in the Hong Kong market, and market data fees would be cut later this year to help brokerages.<br><br>李表示，股票交易印花税将从 0.13% 降至 0.1%，以帮助增强香港市场的流动性，今年晚些时候还将削减市场数据费，以帮助券商。</p>   <p>He added Hong Kong would seek to strengthen its role as an offshore yuan centre and bolster financial ties to China.<br><br>他补充说，香港将寻求加强其作为离岸人民币中心的作用，并加强与中国的金融联系。</p>   <p>The government also plans to expand its campaign to attract top international talent, having drawn 160,000 applicants last year, of which 60,000 had already arrived, mostly from mainland China.<br><br>政府还计划扩大吸引国际顶尖人才的力度，去年已吸引了 16 万名申请者，其中 6 万人已经抵达，其中大部分来自中国大陆。</p>   <p>A new entrant scheme for investors will also be introduced for those who invest at least HK$30 million ($3.8 million) in stocks, funds, bonds, excluding real estate.<br><br>还将针对投资至少 3000 万港元（380 万美元）股票、基金、债券（不包括房地产）的投资者推出新的投资者计划。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.8241 Hong Kong dollars)<br><br>(1 美元 = 7.8241 港元)</p>    <span>Reporting by Clare Jim, Twinnie Siu, Jessie Pang, Donny Kwok; Writing by James Pomfret; Editing by Simon Cameron-Moore<br><br>Clare Jim、Twinnie Siu、Jessie Pang、Donny Kwok 报道；詹姆斯·庞弗雷特 (James Pomfret) 撰写；西蒙·卡梅伦-摩尔 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:42:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">UL7UHQZZFRJYHHRCHBFO7KTANI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-leader-focuses-economy-property-policy-address-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Twinnie Siu, Clare Jim]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HONGKONG</category>
                
                <category>POLICYADDRESS/ (UPDATE 2, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国税务调查引发反响，富士康创始人郭台铭在台湾大选中表现不佳]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/jB2qpNKsHDwYhmSqWovu3k2rIYY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ELEZCIXMT5OOVHB2XJKUWX6SME.jpg" alt="中国税务调查引发反响，富士康创始人郭台铭在台湾大选中表现不佳" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Terry Gou, founder of Taiwan's Foxconn poses for pictures while saluting during a news conference in Taoyuan, Taiwan April 5, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Garcia Rawlins/File Photo<br><br>台湾富士康创始人郭台铭于 2023 年 4 月 5 日在台湾桃园举行的新闻发布会上摆姿势拍照并敬礼。路透社/卡洛斯·加西亚·罗林斯/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/JGLV0qM-y0DV1T2DfIVqJS5iLZQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5GUYYNZOBBKQ5MKBAN2WFOJMNY.jpg" alt="中国税务调查引发反响，富士康创始人郭台铭在台湾大选中表现不佳" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Election merchandise can be seen at Foxconn's founder Terry Gou's presidential election campaign headquarter in Taipei, Taiwan October 24, 2023. REUTERS/Ann Wang/File Photo<br><br>2023 年 10 月 24 日，富士康创始人郭台铭位于台湾台北的总统竞选总部展示选举商品。路透社/Ann Wang/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>After mastering making iPhones, Taiwan's Terry Gou, the billionaire founder of major Apple supplier Foxconn <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2317.TW" target="_blank">(2317.TW)</a>, wanted to turn his entrepreneurial skills elsewhere - to be the island's next president.<br><br>在掌握了 iPhone 制造技术后，苹果主要供应商富士康<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2317.TW" target="_blank">(2317.TW)</a>的亿万富翁创始人、亿万富翁郭台铭希望将自己的创业技能转向其他地方——成为台湾的下一任总统。</p>   <p>But three months out from the election, Gou, whose net worth is estimated by Forbes at $6.7 billion, has gone to ground.<br><br>但距大选仅剩三个月，据《福布斯》估计其净资产为 67 亿美元的郭台铭已经一落千丈。</p>   <p>He last appeared at a campaign event on Sunday night, the day a Chinese newspaper said authorities had begun a tax probe into Foxconn's operations in China, even though he stepped back from running the world's largest contract manufacturer four years ago.<br><br>他最后一次出现在周日晚上的一场竞选活动上，当天一家中国报纸称，当局已开始对富士康在中国的业务进行税务调查，尽管他四年前退出了这家全球最大合同制造商的运营。</p>   <p>He cancelled a Monday event without explanation and had no public arrangements for Tuesday or Wednesday, unusual given the previous frequency of his rallies.<br><br>他在没有任何解释的情况下取消了周一的活动，并且在周二或周三没有进行任何公共安排，考虑到他之前集会的频率，这很不寻常。</p>   <p>The tax investigation was first reported by the state-backed, strongly nationalist Chinese tabloid the Global Times, but in its English version of the story it suggested what China was actually unhappy with was Gou running for president as an independent, a decision he announced in August.<br><br>这项税务调查首先由国家支持的、强烈民族主义的中国小报《环球时报》报道，但在其英文版报道中，它暗示中国实际上对郭台铭以无党派人士身份竞选总统感到不满，他在 2017 年宣布了这一决定。八月。</p>   <p>That was because, the paper said, Gou would split the opposition vote and "in the end favour secessionist" Taiwan Vice President Lai Ching-te, making his victory more certain.<br><br>该报称，这是因为，郭台铭将分裂反对派选票，并“最终支持分裂主义”台湾副总统赖清德，从而使他的胜利更加确定。</p>   <p>China claims Taiwan as its own and believes Lai, who leads opinion polls, is a separatist bent on a formal declaration of independence. Lai says he will maintain the status quo and that only Taiwan's people can decide their future.<br><br>中国宣称台湾是自己的领土，并认为民意调查中领先的黎智英是一个一心想正式宣布独立的分裂主义者。赖清德表示，他将维持现状，只有台湾人民才能决定他们的未来。</p>   <p>Since the Global Times report came out, Gou's team has declined to comment, referring questions to Foxconn itself.<br><br>自《环球时报》的报道发表以来，郭台铭的团队拒绝发表评论，并将问题转交给富士康本身。</p>   <p>Gou, 72, has continued to post on his Facebook account, but not mentioned the probe.<br><br>72 岁的郭台铭继续在他的 Facebook 账户上发帖，但没有提及调查。</p>   <p>Late on Tuesday, Gou posted about late Apple founder Steve Jobs, whom he called his idol, and how he "cherished" their relationship even with often tricky requests when it came to making iPhones.<br><br>周二晚些时候，郭台铭发布了有关已故苹果创始人史蒂夫·乔布斯（他称乔布斯为自己的偶像）的信息，以及他如何“珍惜”他们的关系，即使在制造 iPhone 时经常提出棘手的要求。</p>   <p>"If I had thought of quitting because Steve Jobs was too picky and the tasks given by Apple were too difficult, and had given up on doing Apple orders, I would have probably lost a great opportunity to participate in Apple's innovation in the future," he wrote.<br><br>“如果我当时因为乔布斯太挑剔，苹果给的任务太难，而放弃做苹果订单，那么我很可能就失去了未来参与苹果创新的大好机会。”他写了。</p>   <p>"Think big, but don't lose sight of details - this is the personality trait I noticed in Jobs. This is the trait in recent years I have come to expect in myself and encourage in every colleague around me."<br><br>“胸怀大志，但不要忽视细节——这是我在乔布斯身上注意到的性格特征。这是近年来我对自己的期望和鼓励我周围的每一位同事的性格特征。”</p>   <p>Foxconn said in a statement on Sunday legal compliance was a "fundamental principle" of its operations, and it would "actively cooperate with the relevant units on the related work and operations".<br><br>富士康周日在一份声明中表示，合规是其运营的“基本原则”，将“积极配合相关单位做好相关工作和运营”。</p>    <h 1="">'TAIWAN'S CEO'</h>  <p>Gou has positioned himself as "Taiwan's CEO" saying he wants to unite a fractured opposition amid rising tensions with China, which he blames on the ruling Democratic Progressive Party's (DPP) hostility to Beijing.<br><br>郭台铭将自己定位为“台湾的首席执行官”，表示他希望在与中国的紧张关系日益加剧的情况下团结分裂的反对派，他将此归咎于执政的民进党（DPP）对北京的敌意。</p>   <p>The DPP-led government has repeatedly offered talks with Beijing, but been rebuffed, and has blamed China for the tensions.<br><br>民进党领导的政府多次提出与北京进行会谈，但遭到拒绝，并将紧张局势归咎于中国。</p>   <p>But Gou has languished in the polls and the two main opposition parties, the Kuomintang and Taiwan People's Party, have instead been talking to each other about a possible joint ticket, though those talks have foundered.<br><br>但郭台铭在民意调查中的支持率一直处于低位，而两个主要反对党国民党和台湾人民党却一直在相互讨论可能的联合竞选，尽管这些谈判已经失败。</p>   <p>Gou was not born wealthy. After graduating from university, he worked in a series of factory jobs, as Taiwan in the late 1960s and early 1970s began using its cheap labour force to churn out consumer goods for the rich Western world.<br><br>郭台铭并非出身富裕。大学毕业后，他在一系列工厂工作，当时台湾在 20 世纪 60 年代末和 70 年代初开始利用其廉价劳动力为富裕的西方世界生产消费品。</p>   <p>He founded Hon Hai Precision Industry Co Ltd, better known as Foxconn, in 1974 with 11 elderly workers and a $7,500 loan from his mother. He first made cheap plastic parts for black-and-white television sets for a Chicago TV manufacturer, before a major deal in 1980 making joystick connectors for Atari games consoles.<br><br>1974 年，他与 11 名老年工人以及母亲借来的 7,500 美元创立了鸿海精密工业有限公司（更广为人知的名字是富士康）。他首先为芝加哥一家电视机制造商生产廉价的黑白电视机塑料部件，随后在 1980 年达成一项重大交易，为 Atari 游戏机生产操纵杆连接器。</p>   <p>In 2000, Foxconn won an order to make Apple's redesigned iMacs, after making a variety of parts for the likes of U.S. personal computer vendor Dell.<br><br>2000年，富士康在为美国个人电脑供应商戴尔等公司生产各种零部件后，赢得了生产苹果重新设计的iMac的订单。</p>   <p>Foxconn eventually became one of the world's largest private-sector employers with at times over a million workers assembling devices for global brands such as Sony Corp <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6758.T" target="_blank">(6758.T)</a>, Nintendo Co Ltd <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/7974.T" target="_blank">(7974.T)</a> and Microsoft Corp <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O" target="_blank">(MSFT.O)</a>.<br><br>富士康最终成为世界上最大的私营部门雇主之一，有时拥有超过 100 万名工人为索尼公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6758.T" target="_blank">(6758.T)</a> 、任天堂有限公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/7974.T" target="_blank">(7974.T)</a>和微软公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O" target="_blank">(MSFT.O) 等</a>全球品牌组装设备。 。</p>   <p>Gou remains a lauded figure at Foxconn after stepping down as chairman in 2019, referred to reverentially as "the founder".<br><br>2019 年辞去董事长职务后，郭台铭在富士康仍然是一位备受赞誉的人物，被尊称为“创始人”。</p>   <p>His connections reached as high as Chinese President Xi Jinping, whom he met in 2014 in Beijing, and whom in 2017 he described as a great leader, Taiwan media reported.<br><br>据台湾媒体报道，他的人脉关系与中国国家主席习近平一样高，他于 2014 年在北京会见了习近平，并于 2017 年称习近平为一位伟大的领导人。</p>   <p>Gou's parents were born in China and were of the generation that fled to Taiwan after the Communists won China's civil war in 1949, a year before Gou's birth on the island.<br><br>郭台铭的父母出生在中国，是1949年共产党赢得内战后逃往台湾的一代人，即郭台铭在台湾出生的前一年。</p>   <p>In an interview with the Communist Party's official People's Daily in 2018 to mark China's 40th anniversary of landmark economic reform, Gou said he was happy to have witnessed the changes.<br><br>2018年，在纪念中国具有里程碑意义的经济改革40周年之际，郭台铭在接受中共官方媒体《人民日报》采访时表示，他很高兴见证这些变化。</p>   <p>Earlier this year, Gou vowed to start negotiations with China if he was elected president on the basis that both sides belong to one single China but each can interpret what that means.<br><br>今年早些时候，郭台铭誓言，如果他当选总统，他将与中国开始谈判，其基础是双方同属一个中国，但每个人都可以解释这意味着什么。</p>   <p>Still, in August when announcing his run he struck a tougher tone when asked if his Foxconn shareholdings meant China could simply tell him what to do if he became president.<br><br>尽管如此，在八月宣布参选时，当被问及他持有的富士康股份是否意味着中国可以简单地告诉他如果他当选总统该怎么做时，他的语气变得更强硬。</p>   <p>"I have never been under the control of the People's Republic of China," he said. "I don't follow their instructions."<br><br>“我从未受过中华人民共和国的控制，”他说。 “我不听从他们的指示。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Ben Blanchard; Editing by Sonali Paul<br><br>本·布兰查德报道；索纳利·保罗编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:38:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">HFP2BCO455OUFFRDZHY26ZXIM4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/foxconn-founder-terry-gou-lies-low-taiwan-election-china-tax-probe-reverberates-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>FOXCONN</category>
                
                <category>PROBE/GOU (NEWSMAKER, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[保时捷确认北美和欧洲的强劲销售前景]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/SrTfbYyLaHKCvwtgPcK10L5MFCo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6WEEB5OS4FODVO7AA33GCI4KUY.jpg" alt="2023 Munich Auto Show IAA Mobility<br><br>2023 慕尼黑车展 IAA Mobility<br><br>2023 慕尼黑车展 IAA Mobility" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Porsche Mission X is displayed during an event a day ahead of the official opening of the 2023 Munich Auto Show IAA Mobility<br><br>2023 慕尼黑车展 IAA Mobility<br><br>2023 慕尼黑车展 IAA Mobility, in Munich, Germany, September 4, 2023. REUTERS/Angelika Warmuth</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/mMG1WDhBQKWYjM_N50MA1qPBmJ4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/UAEZGGACXJMS7HZMIHRATGE5ZQ.jpg" alt="2023 Munich Auto Show IAA Mobility<br><br>2023 慕尼黑车展 IAA Mobility<br><br>2023 慕尼黑车展 IAA Mobility" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Porsche logo is seen on a vehicle displayed during an event a day ahead of the official opening of the 2023 Munich Auto Show IAA Mobility<br><br>2023 慕尼黑车展 IAA Mobility<br><br>2023 慕尼黑车展 IAA Mobility, in Munich, Germany, September 4, 2023. REUTERS/Angelika Warmuth/File photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>Porsche AG <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/P911_p.DE" target="_blank">(P911_p.DE)</a> reported nine-month results in line with its annual forecast on Wednesday as strong demand in North America and Europe compensated for lower China sales.<br><br>保时捷公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/P911_p.DE" target="_blank">(P911_p.DE)</a>周三公布了 9 个月的业绩，与年度预测相符，北美和欧洲的强劲需求弥补了中国销量的下降。</p>   <p>The luxury carmaker reported an 18.3% return on sales with operating profit up 9% to 5.5 billion euros ($5.83 billion), even as it faced added costs of preparing for four upcoming product launches next year.<br><br>这家豪华汽车制造商的销售回报率为 18.3%，营业利润增长 9%，达到 55 亿欧元（58.3 亿美元），尽管该公司面临着准备明年即将推出的四款产品的额外成本。</p>   <p>Its 2023 forecast expects a 17-19% return on sales of 40 to 42 billion euros, betting on the resilience of luxury demand even amid high inflation and an uncertain global economy.<br><br>其预测 2023 年的销售额回报率为 17-19%，达 40 至 420 亿欧元，押注奢侈品需求的弹性，即使在高通胀和全球经济不确定的情况下也是如此。</p>   <p>The company had said in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/porsche-ag-confirms-2023-long-term-margin-outlook-2023-09-28/">late September</a> it expected to hit those forecasts despite interest rate rises and an uncertain economic outlook in China, where it suffered a 12% drop in deliveries from January to September.<br><br>该公司曾在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/porsche-ag-confirms-2023-long-term-margin-outlook-2023-09-28/">9 月底</a>表示，尽管中国利率上升且经济前景不确定，1 月至 9 月的交付量下降了 12%，但预计仍能达到这些预测。</p>   <p>Deliveries of its all-electric Taycan sports car grew 11% to 27,885 units, signalling a recovery from supply chain challenges in securing some parts for battery-electric vehicles that had clouded deliveries in the first half.<br><br>其全电动 Taycan 跑车的交付量增长了 11%，达到 27,885 辆，这表明该公司已从供应链挑战中恢复过来，这些挑战为确保上半年的交付量蒙上了阴影。</p>   <p>($1 = 0.9436 euros)<br><br>（1 美元 = 0.9436 欧元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Victoria Waldersee, Editing by Friederike Heine and Miranda Murray<br><br>维多利亚·瓦尔德西 (Victoria Waldersee) 报道，弗里德里克·海涅 (Friederike Heine) 和米兰达·默里 (Miranda Murray) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:26:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ETZBRATYABPL5NPGYYO3TMP2NI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/porsche-reports-183-operating-return-first-nine-months-confirms-forecast-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>PORSCHE AG</category>
                
                <category>RESULTS/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国国防部批评五角大楼年度报告]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/_hxVq59HIHjP5-Kp9Xnkxt7NJ_g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SPITPHHJCFKX7LFBV2AZZKDTYA.jpg" alt="The flags of the United States and China fly in Boston<br><br>美国和中国国旗在波士顿飘扬" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The flags of the United States and China fly from a lamppost in the Chinatown neighborhood of Boston, Massachusetts, U.S., November 1, 2021.   REUTERS/Brian Snyder<br><br>2021年11月1日，美国马萨诸塞州波士顿唐人街附近的灯柱上飘扬着中美两国国旗。路透社/Brian Snyder</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's defence ministry on Wednesday denounced the U.S. Defense Department's annual report on China, saying it distorts the country's security policy and military strategy.<br><br>中国国防部周三谴责美国国防部年度对华报告，称其歪曲中国安全政策和军事战略。</p>   <p>Over the next decade, the People's Republic of China will rapidly modernise, diversify, and expand its nuclear forces, the Pentagon said in its <a href="extension://bfdogplmndidlpjfhoijckpakkdjkkil/pdf/viewer.html?file=https%3A%2F%2Fmedia.defense.gov%2F2023%2FOct%2F19%2F2003323409%2F-1%2F-1%2F1%2F2023-MILITARY-AND-SECURITY-DEVELOPMENTS-INVOLVING-THE-PEOPLES-REPUBLIC-OF-CHINA.PDF" target="_blank">report</a> to U.S. Congress, laying out China's national ambitions, including its defence policy and military strategies.<br><br>五角大楼在向美国国会<a href="extension://bfdogplmndidlpjfhoijckpakkdjkkil/pdf/viewer.html?file=https%3A%2F%2Fmedia.defense.gov%2F2023%2FOct%2F19%2F2003323409%2F-1%2F-1%2F1%2F2023-MILITARY-AND-SECURITY-DEVELOPMENTS-INVOLVING-THE-PEOPLES-REPUBLIC-OF-CHINA.PDF" target="_blank">提交的报告</a>中表示，未来十年，中华人民共和国将迅速实现核力量现代化、多样化和扩张，阐述了中国的国家雄心，包括国防政策和军事战略。</p>   <p>The Pentagon said China has more than 500 nuclear warheads and will probably have more than 1,000 warheads by 2030. The report said China would use new fast-breeder reactors and reprocessing facilities to produce plutonium for its nuclear weapons, despite publicly saying the technologies are intended for peaceful purposes.<br><br>五角大楼表示，中国拥有超过 500 枚核弹头，到 2030 年可能会拥有超过 1,000 枚核弹头。该报告称，中国将使用新的快中子增殖反应堆和后处理设施来生产核武器所需的钚，尽管公开表示这些技术的目的是出于和平目的。</p>   <p>"We express our strong dissatisfaction and resolute opposition to this report," Chinese Defence Ministry spokesperson Wu Qian said in a statement, adding that it "exaggerates and hypes the non-existent 'Chinese military threat'".<br><br>中国国防部发言人吴谦在一份声明中表示，“我们对这份报告表示强烈不满和坚决反对”，并补充说，该报告“夸大和炒作了不存在的‘中国军事威胁’”。</p>   <p>Wu said the development of China's armed forces is aimed at containing the threat of war, safeguarding its own security and safeguarding world peace, and is not aimed at any specific country or target.<br><br>吴邦国表示，中国军队的发展是为了遏制战争威胁、维护自身安全、维护世界和平，不针对任何特定国家和目标。</p>   <p>China and the United States have recently traded barbs over global and national security concerns, military interactions in the South China Sea and over Taiwan, which China claims as its own territory.<br><br>中国和美国最近就全球和国家安全问题、南海军事互动以及中国声称拥有主权的台湾问题互相指责。</p>   <p>The Pentagon said in 2022 that China "amplified diplomatic, political, and military pressure against Taiwan".<br><br>五角大楼在2022年表示，中国“加大了对台湾的外交、政治和军事压力”。</p>   <p>"The so-called report on China's military power released by the United States is full of all kinds of wrong content, including the statement on the Taiwan issue," a spokesperson for China's Taiwan Affairs Office said at a media briefing on Wednesday.<br><br>中国国台办发言人周三在例行记者会上表示，美国发布的所谓中国军力报告充满了各种错误内容，包括有关台湾问题的表述。</p>   <p>Calling the military-to-military relationship an important part of Sino-U.S. relations, the Defence Ministry's Wu said, "we maintain frank and effective communication with the United States through military diplomacy".<br><br>吴仪表示，两军关系是中美关系的重要组成部分，“我们通过军事外交同美国保持着坦诚有效的沟通”。</p>   <p>But he added the difficulties and obstacles facing relations between the two militaries are created by the United States.<br><br>但他补充说，两军关系面临的困难和障碍是美国制造的。</p>   <p>"The United States pretends to be confused, while doing things that harm China's security interests, but at the same time shouting that it wants to manage the crisis and strengthen communication," Wu said.<br><br>“美国装糊涂，一边做损害中国安全利益的事情，一边喊着要管控危机、加强沟通，”吴说。</p>   <p>The latest exchange between the two countries comes days before China hosts foreign defence officials at the 10th Xiangshan Forum in Beijing from Oct. 29 to 31.<br><br>两国之间的最新交流是在中国于 10 月 29 日至 31 日在北京接待外国国防官员出席第十届香山论坛之前几天进行的。</p>   <p>The United States accepted China's invitation after China turned down a meeting a few months ago between the two countries' defence chiefs.<br><br>在中国几个月前拒绝两国国防部长会晤后，美国接受了中国的邀请。</p>    <span>Reporting by Bernard Orr; Editing by Gerry Doyle<br><br>伯纳德·奥尔报道；格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:11:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7KAE4YDU7JLMFJNC5DAI2H444A</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/chinas-defence-ministry-blasts-pentagons-annual-report-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Bernard Orr]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>USA/DEFENCE (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[官员表示，随着预算赤字上升，中国发行新债券将有助于经济复苏]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/mJl0sxhpGQWDAq2pAV82O_bVmt0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5F5ZIUA26VKSRB5GGBMFL3QBE4.jpg" alt="Chinese Yuan banknotes are seen behind illuminated stock graph in this illustration<br><br>在此插图中，可以在发光股票图后面看到人民币钞票" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Yuan banknotes are seen behind illuminated stock graph in this illustration<br><br>在此插图中，可以在发光股票图后面看到人民币钞票 taken February 10, 2020. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's new sovereign bonds will help bolster the economic recovery, China's vice finance minister Zhu Zhongming said on Wednesday, as the government's stepped-up fiscal stimulus sharply raises its budget deficit.<br><br>中国财政部副部长朱忠明周三表示，中国新发行的主权债券将有助于促进经济复苏，因为政府加大财政刺激力度，导致预算赤字大幅上升。</p>   <p>China's top parliament body has approved a 1 trillion yuan ($137 billion) in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/china-issue-137-bln-sovereign-debt-support-economy-2023-10-24/">sovereign bond issuance</a> to help rebuild areas hit by this year's floods and improve urban infrastructure to cope with future disasters, state media said on Tuesday.<br><br>官方媒体周二称，中国最高人大机构已批准<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/china-issue-137-bln-sovereign-debt-support-economy-2023-10-24/">发行1万亿元人民币（1370亿美元）的主权债券</a>，以帮助重建今年遭受洪水袭击的地区，并改善城市基础设施以应对未来的灾害。</p>   <p>"After the treasury bond funds are put into use, it will help drive domestic demand and further consolidate the recovery of the economy," Zhu said at a news conference.<br><br>朱镕基在新闻发布会上表示：“国债资金投入使用后，将有利于拉动内需，进一步巩固经济复苏。”</p>   <p>The world's second-largest economy grew faster than expected in the third quarter, improving the chances that Beijing can meet its growth target of around 5% for 2023. But economists say the crisis-hit property sector remains a drag on the economy and continues to cloud the growth outlook.<br><br>全球第二大经济体第三季度增长快于预期，提高了北京实现 2023 年 5% 左右增长目标的机会。但经济学家表示，遭受危机打击的房地产行业仍然拖累经济，并将继续拖累经济。增长前景蒙上阴影。</p>   <p>In a rare move, China sharply lifted its 2023 budget deficit to around 3.8% of gross domestic product from an originally set 3% due to the rise in central government debt, according to state media.<br><br>据官方媒体报道，由于中央政府债务增加，中国罕见地将2023年预算赤字占国内生产总值的比例从最初设定的3%大幅提高至3.8%左右。</p>   <p>The proposed increase in bond issuance comes as Beijing prepares to inject a fresh dose of fiscal stimulus to shore up the economic recovery, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-choose-fiscal-muscle-over-big-reforms-revive-economy-2023-10-24/">policy insiders</a> say, but there are worries reverting to debt-funded stimulus would undermine the move to a consumer-led economic growth model.<br><br><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-choose-fiscal-muscle-over-big-reforms-revive-economy-2023-10-24/">政策人士</a>表示，拟议增加债券发行之际，北京正准备注入新一剂财政刺激措施以支撑经济复苏，但有人担心，恢复债务融资刺激措施将破坏向消费者主导型经济增长的转变模型。</p>   <p>Some analysts played down the near-term positive economic impact of the new debt issuance.<br><br>一些分析师淡化了新债发行对近期经济的积极影响。</p>   <p>"We believe the economic impact of this 1 trillion yuan in additional CGBs (Chinese government bonds) should not be overstated, especially in the near term," Ting Lu, chief China economist at Nomura, said in a note.<br><br>野村证券首席中国经济学家陆挺在一份报告中表示：“我们认为，不应过分夸大新增1万亿元人民币国债的经济影响，尤其是在短期内。”</p>   <p>"Fiscal multiplier effects from spending on water conservancy projects is likely to be rather limited."<br><br>“水利工程支出的财政乘数效应可能相当有限。”</p>   <p>China will reasonably set the pace of bond insurance and match the issuance with spending, Zhu said, adding that authorities will take steps to prevent bond fund misuses.<br><br>朱表示，中国将合理安排债券保险节奏，实现发行与支出相匹配，并采取措施防止债券基金滥用。</p>   <p>The government's debt level is still within a reasonable range, the minister said, without giving details.<br><br>这位部长表示，政府债务水平仍处于合理范围内，但没有透露细节。</p>   <p>Some policy advisers say the central government has room to spend more as its debt as a share of GDP is just 21%, far lower than 76% for local governments.<br><br>一些政策顾问表示，中央政府有增加支出的空间，因为其债务占GDP的比重仅为21%，远低于地方政府的76%。</p>   <p>Half of the funds raised via the bond issuance will be spent this year and the other half will be used next year, according to state media said.<br><br>据官方媒体报道，通过债券发行筹集的资金一半将在今年使用，另一半将在明年使用。</p>   <p>Analysts at UBS expect the government to raise its budget deficit and special local bond quotas for 2024, alongside further cuts in interest rates and bank reserve requirement ratios.<br><br>瑞银分析师预计，政府将提高2024年的预算赤字和特别地方债券配额，同时进一步降低利率和银行存款准备金率。</p>   <p>China's parliament has also approved a bill to allow local governments to front load part of 2024 local bond quotas.<br><br>中国人大还批准了一项法案，允许地方政府提前加载部分2024年地方债券额度。</p>   <p>Local governments had been told to complete the issuance of the 2023 quota of 3.8 trillion yuan in special local bonds by September to fund infrastructure projects.<br><br>地方政府被告知要在9月份之前完成2023年3.8万亿元地方专项债券额度的发行，为基础设施项目提供资金。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.3098 Chinese yuan renminbi)<br><br>（1 美元 = 7.3098 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Ellen Zhang and Kevin Yao; Editing by Christopher Cushing &amp; Shri Navaratnam<br><br>张艾伦和姚凯文报道；克里斯托弗·库欣 (Christopher Cushing) 和 Shri Navaratnam 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:10:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">QZCJHSNXNZLNFHLLPFR3SPOC5I</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/chinas-new-bonds-help-economic-recovery-official-says-budget-deficit-rises-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/SOVEREIGNBONDS (UPDATE 3,PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国用新舰艇追赶美国和俄罗斯的导弹潜艇能力]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/iiHGGhyNnUsCpJeeADr96BCzwvE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YEI6LAN4D5IF7JFLYRWILI3JXY.jpg" alt="A Chinese Navy's submarine takes part in a naval parade off the eastern port city of Qingdao to mark the 70th anniversary of the founding of Chinese People's Liberation Army Navy<br><br>中国海军潜艇参加东部港口城市青岛举行的纪念中国人民解放军海军成立70周年海上阅兵" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Chinese Navy's submarine takes part in a naval parade off the eastern port city of Qingdao to mark the 70th anniversary of the founding of Chinese People's Liberation Army Navy<br><br>中国海军潜艇参加东部港口城市青岛举行的纪念中国人民解放军海军成立70周年海上阅兵, China, April 23, 2019. REUTERS/Jason Lee/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/EGAsRo6xr2-DKpJCe8PLdCc4Jq4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PLCXG4FJ25LGLESZ4M2NX6C5A4.jpg" alt="Illustration shows Chinese flag<br><br>插图显示中国国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The Chinese flag is seen in this illustration taken May 30, 2022. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo<br><br>这张摄于 2022 年 5 月 30 日的插图中可以看到中国国旗。 REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>China has launched its first nuclear-powered guided missile submarines, according to the Pentagon's latest report on China's military - giving it land and sea attack options once the sole province of U.S. and Russian vessels.<br><br>根据五角大楼关于中国军事的最新报告，中国已经下水了第一艘核动力导弹潜艇，这让中国拥有了曾经是美国和俄罗斯船只的唯一管辖范围的陆地和海上攻击选择。</p>   <p>The Pentagon report, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-most-significant-pentagons-china-military-report-2023-10-21/">published Oct. 20</a>, marks the first apparent confirmation that modified submarines seen in Chinese shipyards over the last 18 months are Type 093B guided missile submarines.<br><br>五角大楼<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-most-significant-pentagons-china-military-report-2023-10-21/">10月20日发布的</a>报告首次明显证实过去18个月在中国造船厂看到的改装潜艇是093B型导弹潜艇。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/satellite-images-raise-prospect-new-class-chinese-submarine-2022-05-10/">Reuters revealed in May 2022</a> that satellite images from Huludao shipyard in northeast China showed a new or upgraded class of submarine, possibly with vertical tubes for launching cruise missiles.<br><br><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/satellite-images-raise-prospect-new-class-chinese-submarine-2022-05-10/">路透社于 2022 年 5 月透露</a>，中国东北葫芦岛造船厂的卫星图像显示了一种新型或升级型潜艇，可能配有用于发射巡航导弹的垂直管。</p>      <p>The Pentagon report says that in the short term, the Chinese navy "will have the ability to conduct long-range precision strikes against land targets from its submarine and surface combatants using land-attack cruise missiles, notably enhancing (China's) power projection capability".<br><br>五角大楼的报告称，短期内，中国海军“将有能力使用对地攻击巡航导弹从潜艇和水面战舰上对陆地目标进行远程精确打击，特别是增强（中国的）力量投送能力” 。</p>   <p>Known as SSGNs, conventionally armed missile submarines were developed by the Soviet Union during the Cold War in part to target U.S. aircraft carriers, while the U.S. Navy developed its own version by converting ballistic missile boats to carry large numbers of land-attack Tomahawk cruise missiles.<br><br>常规武装导弹潜艇被称为SSGN，是苏联在冷战期间开发的，部分目的是针对美国航空母舰，而美国海军则通过将弹道导弹艇改装为携带大量对地攻击战斧巡航导弹来开发自己的版本。</p>   <p>Cruise missiles are typically long-range, precision weapons that, unlike ballistic weapons, fly at low altitudes or skim the surface of the sea.<br><br>巡航导弹通常是远程精确武器，与弹道武器不同，巡航导弹可以低空飞行或掠过海面。</p>   <p>The submarine USS Florida fired 93 Tomahawks against Libyan air defences in 2011 - the first combat strikes from a U.S. SSGN and an event that regional military attaches say was closely studied by Chinese strategists.<br><br>2011年，佛罗里达号潜艇向利比亚防空系统发射了93枚“战斧”导弹——这是美国战略核潜艇的首次战斗打击，地区武官称中国战略家对这一事件进行了密切研究。</p>   <p>Some analysts say the PLA navy will be eager to deploy the vessels as an extra weapon against aircraft carriers as well as a land-attack platform, allowing strikes from a far greater range than its fleets of smaller attack submarines.<br><br>一些分析人士表示，解放军海军将渴望部署这些舰艇，作为对抗航空母舰的额外武器以及对地攻击平台，与小型攻击潜艇舰队相比，可以从更远的范围进行攻击。</p>   <p>The report notes that three of the new SSGNs could be operational by next year, as part of a wider expansion of its submarine fleet - both nuclear and diesel powered - which could number 65 vessels in 2025.<br><br>报告指出，三艘新的弹道导弹核潜艇可能会在明年投入使用，作为其潜艇舰队（核动力和柴油动力）更广泛扩张的一部分，到 2025 年，潜艇舰队的数量可能达到 65 艘。</p>   <p>The Chinese defence ministry did not respond to questions from Reuters.<br><br>中国国防部没有回应路透社的提问。</p>   <p>The confirmation comes amid an <a href="" target="_blank">intensifying submarine arms race</a> as China constructs a new generation of nuclear-armed boats as part of its evolving deterrent force.<br><br>这一确认是在<a href="" target="_blank">潜艇军备竞赛加剧</a>之际做出的，中国正在建造新一代核潜艇，作为其不断发展的威慑力量的一部分。</p>   <p>The effort to track China's submarines at sea is one of the core drivers of increased deployments and contingency planning by the U.S. Navy and other militaries across the Indo-Pacific region.<br><br>在海上追踪中国潜艇的努力是美国海军和印太地区其他军队增加部署和应急计划的核心驱动力之一。</p>   <p>Singapore-based security scholar Collin Koh said the SSGNs were an important new capability for the Chinese navy.<br><br>新加坡安全学者科林·科(Collin Koh)表示，弹道导弹核潜艇是中国海军的一项重要新能力。</p>   <p>With an expected core armament of cruise missiles, "this potentially allows them to carry out saturated land and anti-ship attacks at standoff range”, he said, which would complicate strategic calculations by China's rivals.<br><br>他表示，凭借预期的巡航导弹核心武器，“这可能使他们能够在防区外范围内进行饱和陆地和反舰攻击”，这将使中国竞争对手的战略计算变得复杂。</p>   <p>"I would also expect the Chinese have learned from the Russian experience in using them to threaten U.S. aircraft carriers – with an SSGN, you can launch strikes at standoff range, unlike a typical attack submarine that could have more limited weapon options, and that is a real advantage," said Koh, of the S. Rajaratnam School of International Studies.<br><br>“我还希望中国人从俄罗斯使用它们威胁美国航空母舰的经验中吸取教训——使用弹道导弹核潜艇，你可以在防区外范围内发动攻击，这与典型的攻击潜艇不同，后者的武器选择可能更加有限，而且这是一个真正的优势，”拉惹勒南国际研究学院的 Koh 说。</p>   <p>Research discussed at the U.S. Naval War College in May noted that the PLA was close to breakthroughs in making its nuclear-powered submarines far quieter and more difficult for the U.S. and its allies to track.<br><br>美国海军战争学院五月份讨论的研究表明，解放军在使其核动力潜艇变得更安静、更难以被美国及其盟国追踪方面即将取得突破。</p>   <p>Some diplomats and analysts said, however, that it was unclear whether those breakthroughs had been incorporated into the recently launched SSGNs. The upgrades are expected in nuclear-powered boats launched before the end of the decade.<br><br>然而，一些外交官和分析人士表示，目前尚不清楚这些突破是否已被纳入最近发射的弹道导弹核潜艇中。预计本世纪末之前推出的核动力船将进行升级。</p>   <p>"Unless they are certain of improvements, we can expect the PLA navy to be cautious in how they initially deploy them," said an Asian military attache who is tracking China's submarine force. The attache declined to be named because of the sensitivity of the matter. "But we know the submarine force is a priority for Xi Jinping, and this is one more sign they are getting there."<br><br>一位正在跟踪中国潜艇部队的亚洲武官表示：“除非他们确定能取得改进，否则我们可以预期解放军海军在最初部署这些潜艇的方式上会持谨慎态度。”由于此事敏感，该专员拒绝透露姓名。 “但我们知道潜艇部队是习近平的首要任务，这是他们正在实现这一目标的又一个迹象。”</p>    <span>Reporting By Greg Torode. Editing by Gerry Doyle<br><br>格雷格·托罗德报道。格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:00:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZM7QZJLKLBJOVJXHWK262UHHCA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-chases-us-russia-guided-missile-submarine-capabilities-with-new-vessels-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Greg Torode]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>MILITARY/SUBMARINE (ANALYSIS, GRAPHIC)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美元反弹，澳元因利率风险上升而上涨]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/VdzHXP7EQXbHWnoHf_VonCA_-6g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SK3BLRAFTVLV3K7WQT5WDKNW3Y.jpg" alt="Illustration shows U.S. Dollar and Euro banknotes<br><br>插图显示美元和欧元纸币" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Dollar and Euro banknotes are seen in this illustration taken July 17, 2022. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo<br><br>这张摄于 2022 年 7 月 17 日的插图中可以看到美元和欧元纸币。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/pMyA3wlls8zAHA80v4_GFs3wc-A=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7K35XX6ECBPVBFAZ2MKRHAVPR4.jpg" alt="Illustration shows U.S. Dollar banknotes<br><br>插图显示美元纸币" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Woman holds U.S. dollar banknotes in this illustration taken May 30, 2022. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo<br><br>这张摄于 2022 年 5 月 30 日的插图中，一名妇女拿着美元钞票。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>The dollar drew support on Wednesday from a survey showing U.S. business pulling out of a five month contraction, while the Australian dollar strengthened on the likelihood of interest rate hikes after a surprisingly strong inflation print.<br><br>周三，一项调查显示美国企业摆脱了五个月的经济萎缩，美元因此受到支撑，而澳元则因通胀数据出奇强劲而加息的可能性而走强。</p>   <p>The dollar index , which measures the greenback against a basket of six peers, was steady at 106.17, rebounding from a one-month low of 105.35 struck during the previous session.<br><br>衡量美元兑一篮子六种货币的美元指数稳定在106.17，从前一交易日触及的一个月低点105.35反弹。</p>   <p>S&amp;P Global on Tuesday said its flash U.S. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-business-output-ticks-up-october-inflation-pressures-ease-2023-10-24/">Composite Purchasing Managers Index</a>, tracking both the manufacturing and service sectors, rose to its highest level since July, potentially giving the U.S. Federal Reserve more room to keep interest rates high.<br><br>标准普尔全球周二表示，追踪制造业和服务业的美国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-business-output-ticks-up-october-inflation-pressures-ease-2023-10-24/">综合采购经理人指数初值</a>升至7月份以来的最高水平，可能为美联储提供更多维持高利率的空间。</p>   <p>The buoyant dollar kept the yen pinned near the closely watched 150 threshold, with the Japanese currency last at 149.84 per dollar, having mostly traded sideways over the past month and keeping traders on their toes for any signs of intervention by Japanese authorities.<br><br>美元走强使日元保持在备受关注的 150 关口附近，日元兑美元最新价格为 149.84，过去一个月大部分时间横盘整理，交易员必须警惕日本当局是否有任何干预迹象。</p>   <p>Pressure is mounting on the Bank of Japan to change its bond yield control as global interest rates rise. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/rising-yields-may-pressure-boj-consider-raising-newly-set-cap-2023-10-23/">A hike</a> to an existing yield cap set just three months ago is being discussed as a possibility in the run up to next week's policy meeting, sources said earlier this week.<br><br>随着全球利率上升，日本央行改变债券收益率控制的压力越来越大。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/rising-yields-may-pressure-boj-consider-raising-newly-set-cap-2023-10-23/">消息人士</a>本周早些时候表示，在下周的政策会议之前，正在讨论提高三个月前设定的现有收益率上限的可能性。</p>   <p>The Aussie gained as much as 0.7% to touch a roughly two-week high of $0.6400 on Wednesday after <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/australia-inflation-surprisingly-strong-q3-adds-rate-risk-2023-10-25/">data showed</a> the country's consumer price index rising 1.2% in the third quarter, above market forecasts of 1.1% and up from a 0.8% increase the previous quarter.<br><br><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/australia-inflation-surprisingly-strong-q3-adds-rate-risk-2023-10-25/">数据显示</a>该国第三季度消费者价格指数上涨 1.2%，高于市场预期的 1.1%，高于 0.8% 的增幅，周三澳元兑美元上涨 0.7%，触及约两周高点 0.6400 美元。上一季度。</p>   <p>That left traders narrowing the odds on a possible rate increase by the Reserve Bank of Australia (RBA) next month, which would come after four rate pauses.<br><br>这使得交易员缩小了澳大利亚储备银行（RBA）下个月可能加息的可能性，而这将是在四次加息之后进行的。</p>   <p>"The RBA's November meeting is likely to be live, and the cash rate to be hiked to 4.35%. And I suspect it will be a hawkish hike," said Matt Simpson, senior market analyst at City Index.<br><br>City Index 高级市场分析师马特·辛普森 (Matt Simpson) 表示：“澳洲联储 11 月会议很可能召开，现金利率将上调至 4.35%。我怀疑这将是一次鹰派加息。”</p>   <p>In the broader market, the U.S. dollar held to most of its gains against the euro, after the single currency slid 0.75% in the previous session on data which showed the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/euro-zone-pmi-hits-lowest-nearly-3-years-stirs-recession-worries-2023-10-24/">euro zone's</a> business activity took a surprise turn for the worse this month.<br><br>大盘方面，由于数据显示<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/euro-zone-pmi-hits-lowest-nearly-3-years-stirs-recession-worries-2023-10-24/">欧元区</a>本月商业活动意外恶化，美元兑欧元前一交易日下跌0.75%，美元兑欧元守住了大部分涨幅。</p>   <p>The euro was last 0.13% higher at $1.0602.<br><br>欧元兑美元最后上涨 0.13%，至 1.0602 美元。</p>   <p>"The euro zone economy is kind of entering a recession, so this economic playout stiffens expectations that the European Central Bank might have (reached a) peak in interest rates," said Tina Teng, market analyst at CMC Markets.<br><br>CMC Markets市场分析师Tina Teng表示：“欧元区经济正在进入衰退，因此这种经济形势加剧了人们对欧洲央行利率可能已达到峰值的预期。”</p>   <p>"By contrast, the U.S. Federal Reserve could continue to raise interest rates just because the economic data looks strong."<br><br>“相比之下，美联储可能仅仅因为经济数据看起来强劲就继续加息。”</p>   <p>Elsewhere, sterling rose 0.13% to $1.2175, while the New Zealand dollar gained 0.1% to $0.58505.<br><br>其他方面，英镑上涨0.13%至1.2175美元，新西​​兰元上涨0.1%至0.58505美元。</p>   <p>In cryptocurrencies, Bitcoin was last 0.21% higher at $33,988, holding near a roughly <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/bitcoin-leaps-2023-high-etf-bets-2023-10-24/">18-month high</a> hit on Tuesday.<br><br>加密货币方面，比特币最新上涨 0.21%，至 33,988 美元，接近周二触及的约<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/bitcoin-leaps-2023-high-etf-bets-2023-10-24/">18 个月高</a>点。</p>   <p>The world's largest cryptocurrency has been on a tear this week, having <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/bitcoin-rises-395-31187-2023-10-23/">surged</a> 10% on Monday, fuelled by mounting speculation that an exchange-traded bitcoin fund is imminent.<br><br>由于人们越来越多地猜测交易所交易的比特币基金即将推出，全球最大的加密货币本周一直在飙升，周一<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/bitcoin-rises-395-31187-2023-10-23/">飙升了</a>10%。</p>   <p>"A growing spot ETF market would invariably mean a growing market across most of the cryptocurrency landscape," said John Glover, chief investment officer at crypto lender Ledn.<br><br>加密货币贷款机构 Ledn 的首席投资官约翰·格洛弗 (John Glover) 表示：“现货 ETF 市场的不断增长必然意味着大多数加密货币领域的市场不断增长。”</p>   <p>"If Bitcoin is being purchased for ETFs, the price will rise ... there is a very real possibility that the launch of one or more spot ETFs could lead to the next major bull run in the entire cryptocurrency ecosystem."<br><br>“如果比特币被用于 ETF 购买，价格将会上涨……一个或多个现货 ETF 的推出很有可能导致整个加密货币生态系统的下一次主要牛市。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Rae Wee; Editing by Lincoln Feast<br><br>林肯·盛宴编辑 &amp; Simon Cameron-Moore<br><br>Rae Wee 报道；林肯·菲斯特和西蒙·卡梅伦-摩尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 05:59:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BO6WGLSP3VPJ5PKLPM4GKSVCXM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/dollar-bounces-euro-heavy-useuro-zone-growth-outlook-divergence-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Rae Wee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>FOREX/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[在富士康调查中，中国要求台湾企业在关系中发挥积极作用]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/rJY0MYzB2j1TlGGN_-K_-HDcoo8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/S7NYPMMHPBLFHPK6IAX3Z64CKY.jpg" alt="A Foxconn shareholder poses for photos after the annual shareholder meeting in New Taipei City<br><br>富士康股东在新北市年度股东大会后合影留念" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Foxconn shareholder poses for photos after the annual shareholder meeting in New Taipei City<br><br>富士康股东在新北市年度股东大会后合影留念, Taiwan May 31, 2023. REUTERS/Ann Wang</figcaption></figure>       <p>Taiwanese companies should assume their social responsibilities and play a "positive role" in promoting the peaceful development of relations across the Taiwan Strait, China's government said on Wednesday, amid a probe into major Apple supplier Foxconn.<br><br>中国政府周三在对苹果主要供应商富士康进行调查时表示，台湾企业应承担社会责任，为促进台海关系和平发展发挥“积极作用”。</p>   <p>China's tax and land use investigations into Foxconn's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2317.TW" target="_blank">(2317.TW)</a> operations there have been seized on by the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/taiwan-presidential-frontrunner-lambastes-china-over-foxconn-probe-2023-10-24/">frontrunner</a> to be Taiwan's next president, Lai Ching-te, as an example of Chinese election interference and placing undue pressure on Taiwanese corporates who have invested billions into China.<br><br>中国对富士康<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2317.TW" target="_blank">（2317.TW）</a>在当地业务的税务和土地使用调查被台湾下一任总统<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/taiwan-presidential-frontrunner-lambastes-china-over-foxconn-probe-2023-10-24/">候选人</a>赖清德抓住，作为中国干预选举并对投资的台湾企业施加不当压力的一个例子数十亿美元进入中国。</p>   <p>The Chinese government has not officially confirmed the investigations, first reported by nationalistic, state-backed tabloid the Global Times on Sunday. China claims Taiwan as its own territory.<br><br>中国政府尚未正式证实这些调查，该调查最初是由国家支持的民族主义小报《环球时报》周日报道的。中国声称台湾是自己的领土。</p>   <p>Asked about the investigation at a routine news conference in Beijing, Zhu Fenglian, a spokesperson for China's Taiwan Affairs Office, did not confirm the probe or refer to Foxconn.<br><br>中国国台办发言人朱凤莲在北京举行的例行新闻发布会上被问及此次调查时，没有证实此次调查，也没有提及富士康。</p>   <p>"Relevant mainland departments treat all enterprises equally in accordance with the law and regulations, and it is a normal law enforcement act to carry out law-abiding investigations," she said.<br><br>她表示，内地有关部门依法依规对所有企业一视同仁，开展守法调查是正常执法行为。</p>   <p>China's policy of respecting, caring for and benefiting people from Taiwan will not change, and the government will as always support Taiwanese businessmen and companies to invest and create a good environment for their development, Zhu said.<br><br>朱镕基表示，中国尊重台湾人民、关心台湾人民、造福台湾人民的政策不会改变，政府将一如既往支持台商、台资企业投资兴业，为台商发展创造良好环境。</p>   <p>She signalled China expected these companies to play a political role.<br><br>她表示中国希望这些公司发挥政治作用。</p>   <p>"While sharing development benefits and growth dividends on the mainland and achieving rapid development, Taiwan enterprises should also assume corresponding social responsibilities and play a positive role in promoting the peaceful development of cross-Straits relations."<br><br>“台企在分享大陆发展红利、实现快速发展的同时，也应该承担相应的社会责任，为推动两岸关系和平发展发挥积极作用。”</p>   <p>Zhu did not elaborate.<br><br>朱没有详细说明。</p>   <p>On Tuesday, Taiwan Vice President Lai, the ruling Democratic Progressive Party's (DPP) candidate for president at January elections, hit out at China over its probe of Foxconn, saying Beijing should "cherish" Taiwanese companies and not put pressure on them during an election.<br><br>周二，台湾地区副总统、执政的民进党总统候选人赖智强就中国对富士康的调查进行了猛烈抨击，称北京应该“珍惜”台湾企业，而不是在选举期间向他们施加压力。</p>   <p>China believes Lai, who is leading opinion polls, is a separatist bent on a formal declaration of independence. Lai says he will maintain the status quo with China, and has repeatedly offered talks which Beijing has rebuffed.<br><br>中国认为，在民意调查中领先的黎智英是一个一心想正式宣布独立的分裂主义者。赖表示他将维持与中国的现状，并多次提出进行会谈，但遭到北京的拒绝。</p>   <p>Zhu, in a step up of China's attacks against Lai, said he was "duping people" by both trying to "use weapons to seek independence" and also calling for dialogue.<br><br>朱在中国对赖的攻击的升级中表示，他既试图“使用武器寻求独立”，又呼吁对话，这是在“欺骗人民”。</p>   <p>"As pointed out by the media on the island, Lai Ching-te has now changing from a Taiwan independence maniac to a Taiwan independence liar," she said.<br><br>她说：“正如岛内媒体指出的那样，赖清德现在已经从台独狂人变成了台独骗子。”</p>   <p>"This comment has hit the nail on the head and is appropriate. I believe that the majority of Taiwanese compatriots have a clear understanding of this."<br><br>“这个评论一针见血、恰如其分，相信广大台湾同胞对此都有清醒的认识。”</p>   <p>Foxconn shares closed up 0.7% on Wednesday, rebounding after two straight days of falls. The broader Taipei index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.TWII" target="_blank">(.TWII)</a> ended 0.3% higher.<br><br>富士康股价周三收涨 0.7%，在连续两天下跌后反弹。台北综合指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.TWII" target="_blank">(.TWII)</a>收高 0.3%。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ethan Wang and Bernard Orr; Writing and additional reporting by Ben Blanchard in Taipei; Editing by Jacqueline Wong, Lincoln Feast and Sonali Paul<br><br>Ethan Wang 和 Bernard Orr 报道；本·布兰查德 (Ben Blanchard) 在台北撰写的文章和补充报道；编辑：Jacqueline Wong、Lincoln Feast 和 Sonali Paul</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 05:55:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">IINURZBACZMXNONACXWKIU3COE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/amid-foxconn-probe-china-tells-taiwan-firms-play-positive-role-ties-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ethan Wang, Bernard Orr]]></author>
            
                
                <category>FOXCONN</category>
                
                <category>PROBE/ (UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[亚洲股市因中国支出计划而复苏；通胀冲击澳元]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Hang Seng up 1% on China bond issue and Huijin signal<br><br>恒生指数因中国债券发行和汇金信号而上涨1%</li>  <li>AUD hits $0.64 as inflation surprise follows hawkish RBA turn<br><br>澳大利亚央行转向鹰派后，通胀意外，澳元触及 0.64 美元</li>  <li>Google shares drop, Microsoft up after results<br><br>业绩公布后谷歌股价下跌，微软股价上涨</li> </ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/QnbJOxu5gUVMHe8xQOXdjwyq-RE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZZEBLODMXBILREQSQSAD5WZ5FA.jpg" alt="Chinese Yuan banknotes are seen in this illustration<br><br>在此插图中可以看到人民币纸币" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Yuan banknotes are seen in this illustration<br><br>在此插图中可以看到人民币纸币 taken February 10, 2020. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/-VsTvB7S1ZDStS_vSvJ7UAWvFaI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NHMJ6NDWB5PJPMEUUKGCJWH4DE.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of the app for China's digital currency<br><br>中国数字货币应用图示" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>China's official app for digital yuan is seen in this illustration picture taken October 16, 2020. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo<br><br>这张摄于 2020 年 10 月 16 日的插图图片中可以看到中国的数字人民币官方应用程序。REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>China helped Asian stocks rise from 11-month lows on Wednesday as investors cheered the approval of a trillion-yuan sovereign issue as a harbinger of stimulus, while the Aussie dollar jumped after hotter-than-expected inflation lifted rate forecasts.<br><br>周三，中国帮助亚洲股市从 11 个月低点回升，投资者对万亿人民币主权发行的批准表示欢迎，认为这是刺激措施的先兆​​，而澳元在高于预期的通胀提高了利率预测后上涨。</p>   <p>MSCI's broadest index of Asia-Pacific shares outside Japan <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIAPJ0000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIAPJ0000PUS)</a>, which hit its lowest since last November on Tuesday, rose 0.6% and the Hang Seng <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a> climbed more than 1%. Japan's Nikkei <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a> rose 1.2%.<br><br>MSCI 日本以外最广泛的亚太股市指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIAPJ0000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIAPJ0000PUS)</a>周二上涨 0.6%，触及去年 11 月以来的最低点，恒生指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a>上涨超过 1%。日本日经指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a>上涨 1.2%。</p>   <p>U.S. Treasuries held onto a bounce-back after the 10-year yield breached 5% on Monday, with the benchmark yield firm at 4.82%.<br><br>周一10年期国债收益率突破5%后，美国国债保持反弹，基准收益率稳定在4.82%。</p>   <p>Shares in Google parent Alphabet <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GOOGL.O" target="_blank">(GOOGL.O)</a> fell 6% in after-hours trade on investors' disappointment at its slowing cloud business, while Microsoft <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O" target="_blank">(MSFT.O)</a> shares rose nearly 4% - leaving Nasdaq 100 futures 0.4% lower in Asia trade.<br><br>由于投资者对其云业务放缓感到失望，谷歌母公司 Alphabet <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GOOGL.O" target="_blank">(GOOGL.O)</a>的股价在盘后交易中下跌 6%，而微软<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O" target="_blank">(MSFT.O) 的</a>股价上涨近 4%，导致亚洲纳斯达克 100 指数期货下跌 0.4%贸易。</p>   <p>European stock futures were steady, while oil and the euro were weighed by Tuesday's weaker-than-forecast purchasing managers surveys on the continent. Euro zone lending data and a German business survey are due later in the session.<br><br>欧洲股指期货稳定，而周二欧洲大陆采购经理人调查结果弱于预期，令石油和欧元承压。欧元区贷款数据和德国商业调查将于稍后公布。</p>   <p>China's blue-chip CSI300 index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI300" target="_blank">(.CSI300)</a>, which had been pinned near four-year lows, rose 0.5%.<br><br>中国蓝筹股沪深300指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI300" target="_blank">(.CSI300)</a>一度触及四年低点，上涨0.5%。</p>   <p>China's top parliament approved a 1 trillion yuan ($137 billion) bond issue, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/china-issue-137-bln-sovereign-debt-support-economy-2023-10-24/">state media reported</a>, adding the funds would be spent rebuilding disaster zones and improving infrastructure.<br><br><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/china-issue-137-bln-sovereign-debt-support-economy-2023-10-24/">据官方媒体报道</a>，中国最高人大批准发行 1 万亿元人民币（1370 亿美元）的债券，并补充说这些资金将用于重建灾区和改善基础设施。</p>   <p>Also helping the mood was state-owned investment company Central Huijin announcing it was buying exchange-traded funds, a move which has sparked strong rallies in the past.<br><br>国有投资公司中央汇金宣布将购买交易所交易基金，这一举措过去曾引发强劲反弹，这也提振了市场情绪。</p>   <p>"Government expenditure will help the economy to stabilise further and strengthen growth in the fourth quarter," said Steven Leung, executive director of institutional sales at broker UOB Kay Hian in Hong Kong.<br><br>“政府支出将有助于经济进一步稳定并加强第四季度的增长，”经纪商大华继显驻香港机构销售执行董事史蒂文·梁(Steven Leung)表示。</p>   <p>Central Huijin promising ETF purchases drove rallies of more than 20% in 2013 and 2015, according to UOB, and Leung said the signal had given a strong boost to sentiment. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-leader-focuses-economy-property-policy-address-2023-10-25/">Hong Kong leader</a> John Lee also said stock-trading duties and some property stamp duties would be cut in his annual policy statement.<br><br>据大华银行称，中央汇金承诺购买 ETF 推动 2013 年和 2015 年股市上涨超过 20%，梁表示，这一信号有力提振了市场情绪。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-leader-focuses-economy-property-policy-address-2023-10-25/">香港特首</a>李家超还在其年度政策声明中表示，将削减股票交易税和部分房产印花税。</p>    <h 1="">HIKE LOOMS DOWN UNDER</h>  <p>In currency markets, the euro nursed losses at $1.0601, having dropped when the euro zone composite PMI fell deeper into contractionary territory.<br><br>在货币市场，欧元跌至1.0601美元，因欧元区综合PMI进一步陷入收缩区域而下跌。</p>   <p>The yen sat at 149.84, perhaps steadied by the persistent selling pressure that is driving rock-bottom Japanese yields a little higher. Ten-year Japanese government bond yields touched a decade high of 0.865%.<br><br>日元汇率维持在 149.84 美元，或许是因为持续的抛售压力推动了日本国债收益率触底走高，从而稳定了日元汇率。日本十年期国债收益率触及十年高点0.865%。</p>   <p>The Australian dollar was the standout gainer, rising more than 0.5% to touch a two-week high of $0.64.<br><br>澳元涨幅最大，上涨超过0.5%，触及两周高点0.64美元。</p>   <p>The annual pace of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/australia-inflation-surprisingly-strong-q3-adds-rate-risk-2023-10-25/">inflation</a> in Australia slowed in the third quarter, but the Reserve Bank of Australia's (RBA)preferred core measure rose 1.2% to top forecasts of 1.1%.<br><br>澳大利亚第三季度<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/australia-inflation-surprisingly-strong-q3-adds-rate-risk-2023-10-25/">通胀</a>年度增速放缓，但澳大利亚储备银行(RBA)首选核心指标上涨1.2%，高于预期的1.1%。</p>   <p>"We consider the lift in underlying inflation over Q3 23 to be sufficiently strong for the RBA to act on their hiking bias at the upcoming Board meeting," said analysts at CBA.<br><br>CBA分析师表示：“我们认为23年第三季度基础通胀的提升足够强劲，足以让澳洲联储在即将召开的董事会会议上就其加息倾向采取行动。”</p>   <p>RBA Governor Michele Bullock is due to appear before a parliamentary committee on Thursday.<br><br>澳洲联储行长米歇尔·布洛克将于周四出席议会委员会会议。</p>   <p>Brent crude futures were steady at $87.92 a barrel, with Europe's faltering economy prompting traders to wind back gains made in the wake of conflict in the Middle East.<br><br>布伦特原油期货稳定在每桶 87.92 美元，欧洲经济步履蹒跚，促使交易商回吐中东冲突后的涨幅。</p>   <p>The United States and Russia were among several nations pushing for a pause in fighting between Israel and Hamas to allow aid into the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/world-leaders-seek-suspend-israel-hamas-fighting-gaza-aid-2023-10-24/">besieged Gaza Strip</a>.<br><br>美国和俄罗斯等几个国家敦促以色列和哈马斯暂停战斗，以便向<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/world-leaders-seek-suspend-israel-hamas-fighting-gaza-aid-2023-10-24/">被围困的加沙地带</a>提供援助。</p>   <p>After touching $1,997 an ounce last week, spot gold traded at $1,971. Bitcoin, meanwhile, seems to have awoken from long hibernation during the so-called "winter" that followed numerous scandals including the collapse of exchange FTX.<br><br>继上周触及 1,997 美元/盎司后，现货黄金交投于 1,971 美元。与此同时，在经历了包括交易所 FTX 倒闭在内的众多丑闻之后，比特币似乎已经从所谓的“冬天”的长期冬眠中醒来。</p>   <p>Bitcoin is up 15% this week mostly thanks to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/blackrocks-bitcoin-etf-added-dtcc-file-aug-dtcc-spokesperson-2023-10-24/">speculation</a> that exchange-traded fund applications from BlackRock and others will succeed and drive capital into the asset class. Bitcoin last bought $34,158.<br><br>比特币本周上涨了 15%，主要归功于贝莱德和其他公司的交易所交易基金申请将成功并推动资本进入该资产类别的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/blackrocks-bitcoin-etf-added-dtcc-file-aug-dtcc-spokesperson-2023-10-24/">猜测</a>。比特币最后买入 34,158 美元。</p>   <p>The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission has declined to comment on the speculation.<br><br>美国证券交易委员会拒绝对这一猜测发表评论。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.3090 Chinese yuan)<br><br>（1 美元 = 7.3090 人民币）</p>    <span>Editing by Lincoln Feast<br><br>林肯·盛宴编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 05:24:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">X3L6X2IB7ZP5VFT3TOQ3VAE7EA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/global-markets-wrapup-1-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Tom Westbrook]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/ (WRAPUP 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[菲律宾寻求多边努力避免南海冲突]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/BYvoI9UYmD5_BZr2jSvecpsm-JM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/J35PLM3W7VOVDCZAWX266PUKDY.jpg" alt="Collision between Philippine boat and Chinese Coast Guard vessel, in the South China Sea<br><br>菲律宾船只与中国海警船在南海相撞" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Philippine flagged boat is blocked by a China Coast Guard vessel during an incident that resulted in a collision between the two vessels, in the disputed waters of the South China Sea in this screen grab obtained from handout video released October 22, 2023. China Coast Guard/Handout via REUTERS/File Photo<br><br>2023 年 10 月 22 日发布的讲义视频中截屏显示，一艘悬挂菲律宾国旗的船只在南海争议海域被一艘中国海警船拦截，导致两艘船只相撞。警卫/路透社的讲义/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Philippines will boost multilateral activities including freedom of navigation patrols in the South China Sea, its defence minister said on Wednesday, expressing hope that more countries would "join our fight" after an altercation with China this week.<br><br>菲律宾国防部长周三表示，菲律宾将加强包括南海航行自由巡逻在内的多边活动，并在本周与中国发生争执后表示希望更多国家“加入我们的战斗”。</p>   <p>The Philippines and China earlier this week accused each other of raising tensions, with Manila saying China's coastguard <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-tells-china-stop-provocative-actions-south-china-sea-2023-10-23/">intentionally</a> collided with its boats on a resupply mission to a small contingent of troops stationed on a rusty ship grounded two decades ago.<br><br>菲律宾和中国本周早些时候互相指责对方加剧紧张局势，马尼拉表示，中国海岸警卫队在向二十年前搁浅的一艘生锈的船上驻扎的一小支部队执行补给任务时<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-tells-china-stop-provocative-actions-south-china-sea-2023-10-23/">故意</a>与其船只相撞。</p>   <p>The incident, near a disputed reef in the Philippines' exclusive economic zone, drew widespread condemnation of Beijing, which says it has sovereignty over almost the entire South China Sea, despite an international arbitration award declaring that claim has no legal basis.<br><br>这起事件发生在菲律宾专属经济区的一个有争议的珊瑚礁附近，引起了北京的广泛谴责。北京称其对几乎整个南海拥有主权，尽管国际仲裁裁决宣称这一主张没有法律依据。</p>   <p>The recent incident with China "could result in more willing nations to join our fight," Defence Secretary Gilberto Teodoro said in a televised interview on state-run PTV. He did not elaborate on what that would entail.<br><br>国防部长吉尔伯托·特奥多罗在接受国营 PTV 电视采访时表示，最近与中国发生的事件“可能会导致更多国家愿意加入我们的战斗”。他没有详细说明这将意味着什么。</p>   <p>Teodoro also said he is optimistic on the progress on reciprocal access agreement between Japan and the Philippines.<br><br>特奥多罗还表示，他对日本和菲律宾之间互惠准入协议的进展感到乐观。</p>   <p>Philippine ties with China have deteriorated this year, with more confrontations at sea, coinciding with Manila strengthening its decades-old military alliance with the United States, including <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/philippines-grants-us-greater-access-bases-amid-china-concerns-2023-02-02/">granting</a> Washington expanded access to its bases.<br><br>菲律宾与中国的关系今年恶化，海上对抗更多，同时马尼拉加强了与美国数十年的军事联盟，包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/philippines-grants-us-greater-access-bases-amid-china-concerns-2023-02-02/">允许</a>华盛顿扩大其基地的使用范围。</p>    <span>Reporting by Neil Jerome Morales, Karen Lema, and Mikhail Flores; Editing by Martin Petty<br><br>尼尔·杰罗姆·莫拉莱斯、凯伦·莱玛和米哈伊尔·弗洛雷斯报道；马丁·佩蒂编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 05:23:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">H2M2L6PDZBNI7I5FSTERSU6URM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-eyes-multilateral-effort-avert-south-china-sea-clashes-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SOUTHCHINASEA</category>
                
                <category>PHILIPPINES/CHINA (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早盘竞价：中国支出，关注欧洲是否放贷]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UFZvgV10evozFRO5YrgUPCvaWqI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OYR7OROA6RJV5KRCRFQLMLLUU4.jpg" alt="Illustration photo of a China yuan note<br><br>中国人民币纸币的插图照片" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A China yuan note is seen in this illustration photo May 31, 2017.     REUTERS/Thomas White/Illustration<br><br>这张2017年5月31日的插图照片中可以看到一张人民币纸币。路透社/Thomas White/插图</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/yj_z1dvrxCoLuojnfyi5-I9z5G4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/IMZJ7EOJOFI3BAMGE2E4JG65TM.jpg" alt="A man stands inside the Microsoft Experience Center in New York City<br><br>一名男子站在纽约市的微软体验中心内" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A man stands inside the Microsoft Experience Center in New York City<br><br>一名男子站在纽约市的微软体验中心内, U.S., January 18, 2023.  REUTERS/Shannon Stapleton</figcaption></figure>               <p>A look at the day ahead in European and global markets from Tom Westbrook:<br><br>汤姆·威斯布鲁克 (Tom Westbrook) 对欧洲和全球市场未来一天的展望：</p>   <p>Giants of tech and luxury goods have turned in mixed reports. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/microsoft-beats-quarterly-revenue-estimates-2023-10-24/">Microsoft</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O" target="_blank">(MSFT.O)</a> and Google parent Alphabet <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GOOGL.O" target="_blank">(GOOGL.O)</a> each beat forecasts, but their share prices went in opposite directions as investors zeroed in on cloud computing.<br><br>科技和奢侈品巨头的报告好坏参半。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/microsoft-beats-quarterly-revenue-estimates-2023-10-24/">微软</a><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O" target="_blank">（MSFT.O）</a>和谷歌母公司Alphabet <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GOOGL.O" target="_blank">（GOOGL.O）</a>均超出了预期，但随着投资者将注意力集中在云计算上，它们的股价走势相反。</p>   <p>Google shares fell 6% in after-hours trade. Microsoft shares rose 4%, leaving Nasdaq 100 futures down 0.3% in Asia.<br><br>谷歌股价在盘后交易中下跌 6%。微软股价上涨 4%，纳斯达克 100 指数亚洲期货下跌 0.3%。</p>   <p>Here's the <a href="https://reuters.com/technology/google-parent-alphabet-reports-quarterly-revenue-above-estimates-2023-10-24/" target="_blank">wrapup of the pair's results</a>.<br><br>这是<a href="https://reuters.com/technology/google-parent-alphabet-reports-quarterly-revenue-above-estimates-2023-10-24/" target="_blank">两人的结果总结</a>。</p>   <p>Facebook parent Meta <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/META.O" target="_blank">(META.O)</a> reports after-market on Wednesday. Its shares had fallen on Tuesday and slipped a little further after hours as dozens of U.S. states <a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/dozens-us-states-sue-meta-platforms-harming-mental-health-young-people-2023-10-24/">sued the company</a> and its Instagram business, accusing them of addicting teens.<br><br>Facebook 母公司 Meta <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/META.O" target="_blank">(META.O)</a>周三公布了售后市场报告。周二，随着美国数十个州<a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/dozens-us-states-sue-meta-platforms-harming-mental-health-young-people-2023-10-24/">起诉该公司</a>及其 Instagram 业务，指控它们让青少年上瘾，该公司股价周二下跌，盘后进一步下跌。</p>   <p>On the luxury front Kering <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PRTP.PA" target="_blank">(PRTP.PA)</a>, owner of Gucci and Balenciaga, reported a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/kering-sales-down-9-luxury-slowdown-weighs-turnaround-efforts-2023-10-24/">bigger-than-expected drop</a> in third-quarter sales. That was worse than the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/lvmh-q3-revenue-rises-9-slowing-post-pandemic-frenzy-2023-10-10/">slowdown</a> reported by LVMH <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LVMH.PA" target="_blank">(LVMH.PA)</a>, and the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/hermes-sales-rise-156-defying-luxury-downturn-us-posts-strong-growth-2023-10-24/">surprise jump in sales</a> logged by Birkin-bag maker Hermes <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/HRMS.PA" target="_blank">(HRMS.PA)</a> on Tuesday, which sent its shares up 3%.<br><br>在奢侈品领域，古驰 (Gucci) 和巴黎世家 (Balenciaga) 的所有者<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PRTP.PA" target="_blank">开云集团 (PRTP.PA)</a>报告称，第三季度销售额<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/kering-sales-down-9-luxury-slowdown-weighs-turnaround-efforts-2023-10-24/">降幅超出预期</a>。这比路威酩轩<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LVMH.PA" target="_blank">(LVMH.PA)</a>报告的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/lvmh-q3-revenue-rises-9-slowing-post-pandemic-frenzy-2023-10-10/">经济放缓</a>以及柏金包制造商爱马仕<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/HRMS.PA" target="_blank">(HRMS.PA)</a>周二<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/hermes-sales-rise-156-defying-luxury-downturn-us-posts-strong-growth-2023-10-24/">销售额的意外增长</a>更糟糕，后者导致其股价上涨 3%。</p>   <p>Gucci's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/lifestyle/new-designer-de-sarno-showcases-minimalist-glamour-gucci-debut-2023-09-22/">revamped look</a>, unveiled last month in Milan by designer Sabato De Sarno, is yet to hit stores.<br><br>设计师萨巴托·德萨诺 (Sabato De Sarno) 上个月在米兰推出了古驰 (Gucci) 的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/lifestyle/new-designer-de-sarno-showcases-minimalist-glamour-gucci-debut-2023-09-22/">全新外观</a>，但尚未上市。</p>   <p>European loans data and a survey of German business conditions will be closely watched later on Wednesday. Santander <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SAN.MC" target="_blank">(SAN.MC)</a>, Deutsche Bank <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DBKGn.DE" target="_blank">(DBKGn.DE)</a> and Dassault Systemes <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DAST.PA" target="_blank">(DAST.PA)</a> also report results.<br><br>周三晚些时候，欧洲贷款数据和德国商业状况调查将受到密切关注。桑坦德银行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SAN.MC" target="_blank">(SAN.MC)</a> 、德意志银行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DBKGn.DE" target="_blank">(DBKGn.DE)</a>和达索系统<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DAST.PA" target="_blank">(DAST.PA)</a>也公布了业绩。</p>   <p>In Asia, China's plans to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/china-issue-137-bln-sovereign-debt-support-economy-2023-10-24/">raise a trillion yuan</a> ($137 billion) in sovereign debt boosted Chinese shares in anticipation of spending and lifted MSCI's broad index of Asia ex-Japan stocks away from Tuesday's 11-month low.<br><br>在亚洲，中国计划<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/china-issue-137-bln-sovereign-debt-support-economy-2023-10-24/">筹集一万亿元人民币</a>（合1,370亿美元）的主权债务，提振了中国股市的支出预期，并推动摩根士丹利资本国际（MSCI）亚洲（日本除外）综合指数脱离周二的11个月低点。</p>   <p>Central Huijin's vow to buy exchange-traded funds and keep doing so was also reminiscent of similar announcements from the state fund that drove strong rallies in 2013 and 2015.<br><br>中央汇金誓言购买交易所交易基金并继续这样做，也让人想起国家基金在2013年和2015年推动股市强劲上涨的类似声明。</p>   <p>The Aussie dollar was the main mover in the foreign exchange market, rising as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/australia-inflation-surprisingly-strong-q3-adds-rate-risk-2023-10-25/">surprisingly strong inflation</a> data prompted traders to re-price the risk of another rate hike.<br><br>澳元是外汇市场的主要推动者，由于<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/australia-inflation-surprisingly-strong-q3-adds-rate-risk-2023-10-25/">令人惊讶的强劲通胀</a>数据促使交易员重新定价再次加息的风险，澳元上涨。</p>   <p>Just this week, RBA Governor Michele <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/australia-cbank-sees-risks-inflation-will-not-hesitate-rates-2023-10-24/">Bullock said the bank would not hesitate</a> to raise its 4.1% cash rate if there was a "material" upward revision to the inflation outlook.<br><br>就在本周，澳洲联储行长米歇尔<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/australia-cbank-sees-risks-inflation-will-not-hesitate-rates-2023-10-24/">·布洛克表示，如果通胀前景出现“实质性”上调，该行将毫不犹豫地</a>提高 4.1% 的现金利率。</p>   <p>Key developments that could influence markets on Wednesday:<br><br>周三可能影响市场的主要事态发展：</p>   <p>Economics: Euro zone lending, German business survey<br><br>经济学：欧元区贷款、德国商业调查</p>   <p>Earnings: Dassault Systemes, Deutsche Bank, CME Group, Hilton, Boeing and, after market close, IBM and Meta<br><br>盈利：达索系统、德意志银行、芝商所、希尔顿、波音，以及收盘后的 IBM 和 Meta</p>   <p>($1 = 7.3118 Chinese yuan)<br><br>（1 美元 = 7.3118 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Tom Westbrook. Editing by Sam Holmes<br><br>汤姆·威斯布鲁克报道。山姆·霍姆斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 05:14:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RYGEJFJZXRO7NNTRJ7BJSQABS4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/global-markets-view-europe-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>EUROPE</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国采取措施支撑摇摇欲坠的经济复苏]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>China has rolled out a slew of policy measures in recent months to revive a stumbling economy after its post-pandemic recovery fell away quickly.<br><br>在疫情后复苏迅速放缓后，中国近几个月推出了一系列政策措施，以重振陷入困境的经济。</p>   <p>Thanks to the government support, the world's second-largest economy staged a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">faster than expected growth</a> in the third quarter, improving the chances Beijing can meet its growth target of around 5% for 2023.<br><br>在政府的支持下，世界第二大经济体第三季度<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">的增长快于预期</a>，提高了北京实现2023年5%左右增长目标的机会。</p>   <p>But economists say a property crisis, depressed private sector confidence, a slowdown in global growth and Sino-U.S. tensions over technology and geopolitics still pose challenges to policymakers in Beijing as they seek to sustain the growth momentum.<br><br>但经济学家表示，房地产危机、私营部门信心低迷、全球经济增长放缓以及中美在技术和地缘政治方面的紧张局势仍然对北京决策者在寻求维持增长势头时构成挑战。</p>   <p>The following is a list of recent policy support measures:<br><br>以下为近期政策支持措施清单：</p>   <p>Oct. 24 - China's top parliament body approved a 1 trillion yuan ($137 billion) <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/china-issue-137-bln-sovereign-debt-support-economy-2023-10-24/">sovereign bond</a> issue and passed a bill to allow local governments to frontload part of their 2024 bond quotas.<br><br>10 月 24 日 - 中国最高人大机构批准发行 1 万亿元人民币（1,370 亿美元） <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/china-issue-137-bln-sovereign-debt-support-economy-2023-10-24/">的主权债券</a>，并通过一项法案，允许地方政府预付部分 2024 年债券配额。</p>   <p>Oct. 23 - China's state fund Central Huijin Investment said it had bought exchange-traded funds (ETFs) and would continue to do so, as Chinese stocks dropped to four-and-a-half-year lows.<br><br>10 月 23 日 - 随着中国股市跌至四年半低点，中国国家基金中央汇金投资表示已购买交易所交易基金 (ETF)，并将继续这样做。</p>   <p>Oct. 11 - China's "Big Four" state banks said that their state parent, Central Huijin Investment, had bought the lenders' Shanghai-traded shares, and planned to further increase holdings within the next six months.<br><br>10 月 11 日——中国“四大”国有银行表示，其国有母公司中央汇金投资有限公司已购买了该银行在上海上市交易的股票，并计划在未来六个月内进一步增持。</p>   <p>Sept. 22 - The country's top market regulator issued 22 measures to promote the development of the private economy, including breaking down barriers to market access for private firms.<br><br>9月22日，国家市场监管总局出台22条促进民营经济发展的措施，包括打破民营企业市场准入壁垒。</p>   <p>Sept. 14 - China's central bank said it would <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cuts-banks-reserve-ratio-second-time-2023-aid-recovery-2023-09-14/">cut</a> the amount of cash that banks must hold as reserves for the second time this year to boost liquidity and support the country's economic recovery.<br><br>9月14日，中国央行表示，今年将第二次<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cuts-banks-reserve-ratio-second-time-2023-aid-recovery-2023-09-14/">降低</a>银行存款准备金率，以增加流动性，支持中国经济复苏。</p>   <p>Sept. 4 - China's central government approved setting up a special bureau within the National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC) to promote the development of the private economy.<br><br>9月4日 - 中国中央政府批准在国家发展和改革委员会内设立促进私营经济发展的专门局。</p>   <p>Sept. 1 - China's central bank said it would <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cut-banks-fx-reserve-ratio-rein-yuan-weakness-2023-09-01/">cut</a> the amount of foreign exchange that financial institutions must hold as reserves for first time this year, a move seen aimed at slowing the pace of recent yuan depreciation.<br><br>9月1日——中国央行表示，今年将首次<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cut-banks-fx-reserve-ratio-rein-yuan-weakness-2023-09-01/">削减</a>金融机构外汇储备规模，此举被视为旨在减缓近期人民币贬值的步伐。</p>   <p>Sept. 1 - China is set to take <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-take-more-action-revive-property-sector-sources-2023-09-01/">further action</a> including relaxing home-purchase restrictions to try and stabilise its debt-riddled property sector, four people familiar with the matter said.<br><br>9 月 1 日 - 四位知情人士表示，中国将采取<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-take-more-action-revive-property-sector-sources-2023-09-01/">进一步行动</a>，包括放宽购房限制，以稳定债务缠身的房地产行业。</p>   <p>Sept. 1 - China stepped up measures to boost the country's faltering economy, with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/major-chinese-banks-cut-interest-rates-yuan-deposits-2023-09-01/">top banks</a> paving the way for further cuts in lending rates.<br><br>9月1日——中国加大了提振经济的力度， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/major-chinese-banks-cut-interest-rates-yuan-deposits-2023-09-01/">顶级银行</a>为进一步降低贷款利率铺平了道路。</p>   <p>Aug. 31 - China's central bank and financial regulator issued notices to ease some borrowing rules to aid <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/country-garden-faces-key-test-with-onshore-bondholders-set-vote-extension-2023-08-31/">homebuyers</a>, including lowering the existing mortgage rate for first-home buyers and the down payment ratio in some cities.<br><br>8月31日——中国央行和金融监管机构发布通知，放宽部分借贷规则以帮助<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/country-garden-faces-key-test-with-onshore-bondholders-set-vote-extension-2023-08-31/">购房者</a>，包括降低部分城市现有首次购房者抵押贷款利率和首付比例。</p>   <p>Aug. 31 - Major Chinese cities said they <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinese-cities-ease-mortgage-rules-revive-property-sector-2023-08-31/">will allow</a> people to take preferential loans for first-home purchases regardless of their credit records.<br><br>8月31日——中国主要城市表示，无论信用记录如何，他们<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinese-cities-ease-mortgage-rules-revive-property-sector-2023-08-31/">将允许</a>人们享受首次购房优惠贷款。</p>   <p>Aug. 25 - China's cabinet <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-cabinet-approves-guidelines-boost-affordable-housing-amid-property-woes-2023-08-25/">approved</a> guidelines for planning and construction of affordable housing at a meeting chaired by Premier Li Qiang.<br><br>8月25日，国务院总理李强主持召开国务院常务会议，审议<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-cabinet-approves-guidelines-boost-affordable-housing-amid-property-woes-2023-08-25/">通过了</a>保障性住房规划建设指导意见。</p>   <p>Aug. 21 - China cut its <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cuts-1-year-lending-benchmark-keeps-5-year-unchanged-2023-08-21/">one-year</a> benchmark lending rate but surprised markets by keeping the five-year rate unchanged amid broader concerns about a rapidly weakening currency.<br><br>8 月 21 日 - 中国下调了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cuts-1-year-lending-benchmark-keeps-5-year-unchanged-2023-08-21/">一年期</a>基准贷款利率，但在对货币迅速贬值的广泛担忧中保持五年期利率不变，令市场感到意外。</p>   <p>Aug. 15 - China's central bank <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-central-bank-cuts-rates-second-time-three-months-support-economy-2023-08-15/">unexpectedly chopped</a> one set of key interest rates, and followed it with cuts on other rates hours later.<br><br>8 月 15 日——中国央行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-central-bank-cuts-rates-second-time-three-months-support-economy-2023-08-15/">出人意料地下调了</a>一组关键利率，数小时后又下调了其他利率。</p>   <p>Aug. 2 - China's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-releases-package-tax-relief-measures-support-small-firms-2023-08-02/">finance ministry</a> unveiled a package of tax relief measures for small businesses and rural households.<br><br>8月2日——中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-releases-package-tax-relief-measures-support-small-firms-2023-08-02/">财政部</a>公布了针对小企业和农户的一揽子税收减免措施。</p>   <p>July 31 - China's cabinet issued measures to boost <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-state-council-issues-measures-expand-consumption-2023-07-31/">consumption</a> in the automobile, real estate and services sector, aiming to give full play to the "fundamental role" of consumption in economic development.<br><br>7月31日，国务院印发汽车、房地产、服务业<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-state-council-issues-measures-expand-consumption-2023-07-31/">消费</a>促进措施，充分发挥消费对经济发展的“基础性作用”。</p>   <p>July 28 - State media quoted the housing minister as saying that China needs to effectively take steps to lower home mortgage rates and down payment ratios for first-time buyers to help spur home purchases. Borrowers in some cities are still waiting for that to happen.<br><br>7月28日，官方媒体援引住房和城乡建设部部长的话说，中国需要有效采取措施降低住房抵押贷款利率和首付比例，以刺激购房。一些城市的借款人仍在等待这一情况的发生。</p>   <p>July 24 - China's top leaders, at a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-step-up-policy-adjustments-focus-demand-politburo-2023-07-24/">Politburo</a> meeting, pledged to step up support for the economy, signalling more stimulus steps. A rare omission of "housing for living, not for speculation" in the official readout fanned expectations of more measures to boost activity in the property market.<br><br>7月24日——中国最高领导人在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-step-up-policy-adjustments-focus-demand-politburo-2023-07-24/">政治局</a>会议上承诺加大对经济的支持力度，暗示将采取更多刺激措施。官方公告中罕见地省略了“房子是用来住的，不是用来炒的”，这引发了人们对采取更多措施促进房地产市场活动的预期。</p>   <p>July 24 - China's state planner unveiled measures to support <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-state-planner-unveils-steps-spur-private-investment-2023-07-24/">private investment</a> in some infrastructure sectors and said it will strengthen financing support for private projects.<br><br>7月24日，国家发改委公布了支持<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-state-planner-unveils-steps-spur-private-investment-2023-07-24/">民间投资</a>部分基础设施领域的措施，并表示将加强对民间项目的融资支持。</p>   <p>July 21 - The cabinet approved guidelines on transforming "urban villages", or <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-seeks-boost-demand-by-pushing-urban-development-state-media-2023-07-21/">underdeveloped areas</a>, in megacities, which will help underpin property investment.<br><br>7月21日——内阁批准了关于大城市“城中村”或<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-seeks-boost-demand-by-pushing-urban-development-state-media-2023-07-21/">欠发达地区</a>改造的指导方针，这将有助于支撑房地产投资。</p>   <p>July 19 - The Communist Party and the cabinet issued guidelines to support the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-increase-support-private-companies-bolster-economy-2023-07-19/">private economy</a>, pledging to make the sector "bigger, better and stronger" with a total of 31 policy measures.<br><br>7月19日，中共中央和国务院印发支持<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-increase-support-private-companies-bolster-economy-2023-07-19/">民营经济</a>发展的指导意见，承诺将民营经济做大、做优、做强，共31条政策措施。</p>   <p>July 18 - China's commerce ministry announced a series of measures aimed at boosting household consumption of goods and services.<br><br>7月18日——中国商务部宣布了一系列旨在促进居民商品和服务消费的措施。</p>   <p>July 14 - China's cabinet approved guidelines for improving the building of public infrastructure in megacities, to help support the economy and cope with future public health crises.<br><br>7月14日——中国国务院批准了关于改善特大城市公共基础设施建设的指导方针，以帮助支持经济并应对未来的公共卫生危机。</p>   <p>June 30 - China's central bank increased its relending and rediscount quotas by 200 billion yuan to support the farm sector and small firms.<br><br>6月30日——中国央行增加再贷款和再贴现额度2000亿元人民币，以支持农业和小企业。</p>   <p>June 20 - China's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cuts-lending-benchmarks-first-time-10-months-support-economy-2023-06-20/">central bank</a> cut its key lending benchmarks, or loan prime rates (LPR), for the first time in 10 months.<br><br>6 月 20 日——中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cuts-lending-benchmarks-first-time-10-months-support-economy-2023-06-20/">央行</a>10 个月来首次下调主要贷款基准，即贷款市场报价利率 (LPR)。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.3119 Chinese yuan renminbi)<br><br>（1 美元 = 7.3119 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Kevin Yao and Ellen Zhang; Editing by Christian Schmollinger<br><br>姚凯文和张艾伦报道；克里斯蒂安·施莫林格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 04:20:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2HQSIIW67FPL5CITBKUH5BXG4I</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-shaky-economic-recovery-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Kevin Yao, Ellen Zhang]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/POLICY</category>
                
                <category>MEASURES (FACTBOX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：越南借鉴中国模式寻求指数升级、刺激投资]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Vietnam seeks FTSE upgrade to emerging from frontier market<br><br>越南寻求将富时指数升级为新兴前沿市场</li>  <li>Upgrade would attract up to $800 mln from passive funds alone<br><br>仅被动基金升级就可吸引高达 8 亿美元的资金</li>  <li>Broker-based stopgap faces criticism from foreign funds in China<br><br>以经纪商为基础的权宜之计面临在华外资基金的批评</li> </ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/oL2zAl8LCeToPNkMCeBAkXL-Wr0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/Z6JBJMLKHVLTHMXDGCDZ6F7J64.jpg" alt="An investor sits in front of screens showing stock board information at a securities company in Hanoi, Vietnam<br><br>越南河内一家证券公司的投资者坐在显示股票董事会信息的屏幕前" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An investor sits in front of screens showing stock board information at a securities company in Hanoi, Vietnam<br><br>越南河内一家证券公司的投资者坐在显示股票董事会信息的屏幕前 July 6, 2018. Picture taken July 6, 2018. REUTERS/Kham/File photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Vietnam is planning to relax its stock market settlement procedures for foreign investors, a critical measure to convince equity index managers to uprade the country to emerging market status and attract hundreds of millions of dollars of new investment, sources said.<br><br>消息人士称，越南正计划放宽对外国投资者的股票市场结算程序，这是说服股指管理者将该国升级为新兴市场地位并吸引数亿美元新投资的关键措施。</p>   <p>Following a China model, Vietnam would allow brokers to vouch for foreign investors when they buy shares, a move that was seen as a progress by the FTSE index provider, and could lead to remove a regulatory hurdle that has hampered for years the upgrade of the Ho Chi Minh City Stock Exchange <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.VNI" target="_blank">(.VNI)</a>.<br><br>效仿中国模式，越南将允许经纪商在外国投资者购买股票时为其提供担保，富时指数提供商认为此举是一项进步，并可能消除多年来阻碍指数升级的监管障碍。胡志明市证券交易所<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.VNI" target="_blank">（.VNI）</a> 。</p>   <p>The bourse, the smallest among the main Southeast Asian economies, is now classified by both the MSCI and FTSE indices as a frontier market. That prevents many funds, investors and family offices from investing in companies listed there.<br><br>该交易所是东南亚主要经济体中最小的交易所，目前被摩根士丹利资本国际 (MSCI) 和富时指数 (FTSE) 指数列为前沿市场。这使得许多基金、投资者和家族办公室无法投资在那里上市的公司。</p>   <p>FTSE experts visited the country last week and were presented with details of the new plan to break the years-long deadlock, the people familiar with the talks said.<br><br>知情人士称，富时指数专家上周访问了该国，并听取了打破多年僵局的新计划的细节。</p>   <p>"Last week's meetings with FTSE were positive and could lead to a possible upgrade to the secondary emerging market status by September 2025," said Le Thi Le Hang, chief strategy officer at Vietnam's leading broker SSI, who is directly involved in the plans.<br><br>直接参与该计划的越南领先经纪商 SSI 首席战略官 Le Thi Le Hang 表示：“上周与 FTSE 的会议取得了积极成果，可能会导致到 2025 年 9 月升级为二级新兴市场地位。”</p>   <p>To meet that timeline, FTSE would need to announce the upgrade as early as September next year, six or twelve months before the actual promotion, according to its procedures on upgrades.<br><br>为了满足这一时间表，根据其升级程序，富时指数需要最早在明年 9 月宣布升级，即实际升级前六个月或十二个月。</p>   <p>If upgraded, Vietnam would <a href="https://research.ftserussell.com/Analytics/FactSheets/Home/DownloadSingleIssue?issueName=AWALLE&amp;isManual=False" target="_blank">join</a> the likes of Indonesia, Philippines, Qatar and China, moving up from the <a href="https://research.ftserussell.com/Analytics/Factsheets/Home/DownloadSingleIssue?issueName=FI&amp;IsManual=false" target="_blank">frontier index</a> which it shares now with less advanced markets such as Sri Lanka and Kenya, and where it accounts for an unwieldy 38% of total capitalisation.<br><br>如果升级，越南将<a href="https://research.ftserussell.com/Analytics/FactSheets/Home/DownloadSingleIssue?issueName=AWALLE&amp;isManual=False" target="_blank">加入</a>印度尼西亚、菲律宾、卡塔尔和中国等国家的行列，从目前与斯里兰卡和肯尼亚等欠发达市场共享的<a href="https://research.ftserussell.com/Analytics/Factsheets/Home/DownloadSingleIssue?issueName=FI&amp;IsManual=false" target="_blank">前沿指数</a>上升，越南在这些国家的总资本中所占比例高达38% 。</p>    <h 1="">MULTI-MILLION-DOLLAR PIE</h>  <p>Under the new plan, Vietnam would adopt a mechanism to settle payments on shares transactions that could meet the key requirement from FTSE for the upgrade.<br><br>根据新计划，越南将采用一种股票交易结算机制，以满足富时指数升级的关键要求。</p>   <p>In advanced markets, investors settle transactions two days after they buy shares, but in Vietnam they are required to make the money available the same day, causing higher costs and risks to foreign investors.<br><br>在发达市场，投资者在购买股票后两天进行交易结算，但在越南，他们必须在当天到位，这给外国投资者带来了更高的成本和风险。</p>   <p>To bypass the hurdle, Vietnamese authorities and brokers are devising a mechanism similar to one used in China under which securities firms would guarantee for foreign funds' payments, effectively giving them credit for the two days until transactions are completed.<br><br>为了绕过这一障碍，越南当局和经纪商正在设计一种类似于中国使用的机制，根据该机制，证券公司将为外国资金的付款提供担保，从而在交易完成之前的两天内有效地给予它们信用。</p>   <p>They would take some risks, but they stand to benefit from the new inflows, which SSI estimates could be around $800 million from passive funds alone, assuming Vietnam's weighting in the emerging market index at 1%.<br><br>他们会承担一些风险，但他们将从新的资金流入中受益，假设越南在新兴市场指数中的权重为 1%，SSI 估计仅来自被动基金的资金流入就可能达到约 8 亿美元。</p>   <p>Active funds are estimated to have five times more investments in the FTSE emerging market, which could lead to far bigger gains for the HCMC market, which has currently a $179 billion capitalisation.<br><br>据估计，主动型基金在富时新兴市场的投资是其五倍，这可能会为目前资本额为 1,790 亿美元的胡志明市市场带来更大的收益。</p>   <p>FTSE and Vietnam's market regulator, the State Securities Commission, did not reply to requests for comment.<br><br>富时指数和越南市场监管机构国家证券委员会没有回复置评请求。</p>   <p>In its latest update on Vietnam issued last month, FTSE said that while progress on planned market reforms had remained slow, a recommitment to the work required had been made by government.<br><br>富时指数在上个月发布的越南最新动态中表示，虽然计划中的市场改革进展仍然缓慢，但政府已重新承诺开展所需的工作。</p>   <p>"In addition, the State Securities Commission (SSC) has demonstrated renewed energy in seeking a workable solution that would remove the need for pre-funding," FTSE said.<br><br>富时表示：“此外，国家证券委员会（SSC）在寻求可行的解决方案方面表现出了新的活力，该解决方案将消除预先融资的需要。”</p>   <p>A simultaneous upgrade from managers at the much larger MSCI index is seen as out of the question at the moment because of MSCI's stricter requirements, the sources said.<br><br>消息人士称，由于摩根士丹利资本国际 (MSCI) 的要求更加严格，目前看来不可能同时升级规模大得多的摩根士丹利资本国际 (MSCI) 指数。</p>   <p>Under Vietnamese rules, banks are not allowed to offer credit to foreigners, which has barred their involvement and has complicated talks over the upgrade.<br><br>根据越南的规定，银行不得向外国人提供信贷，这限制了他们的参与，并使升级谈判变得复杂。</p>   <p>The mechanism still needs to be finalised and go through a months-long trial period while existing regulations are tweaked, the sources said.<br><br>消息人士称，该机制仍需最终确定，并经过长达数月的试用期，同时对现有法规进行调整。</p>   <p>Foreign investors need also to be consulted. They have urged China to scrap the prefunding requirement, or at least allow banks to get involved to make trades easier to transact and attract more investors.<br><br>还需要咨询外国投资者。他们敦促中国取消预先融资要求，或者至少允许银行参与，以使交易更容易进行并吸引更多投资者。</p>    <span>Reporting by Francesco Guarascio @fraguarascio; Editing by Lincoln Feast<br><br>Francesco Guarascio@fraguarascio 报道；林肯·盛宴编辑<br><br>林肯·盛宴编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 04:06:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">POSWLKW46VMBBFBYSBFUM5PGOA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/vietnam-eyes-china-model-seek-index-upgrade-boost-investment-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Francesco Guarascio]]></author>
            
                
                <category>VIETNAM</category>
                
                <category>STOCKS/INDEX (EXCLUSIVE)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[习近平：中方愿同美方合作管控分歧]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/atW1y53zdUYdycNArASc6RypFQo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3ZWEI6Y3BRPS3GW4WZC2YWEZP4.jpg" alt="BRICS Summit in Johannesburg<br><br>金砖国家领导人约翰内斯堡峰会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>President of China Xi Jinping attends the plenary session during the 2023 BRICS Summit at the Sandton Convention Centre in Johannesburg, South Africa on August 23, 2023. GIANLUIGI GUERCIA/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo<br><br>2023 年 8 月 23 日，中国国家主席习近平出席在南非约翰内斯堡桑顿会议中心举行的 2023 年金砖国家峰会全体会议。 GIANLUIGI GUERCIA/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Chinese President Xi Jinping said on Wednesday that China is willing to cooperate with the United States as both sides manage their differences and work together to respond to global challenges, according to Chinese state media.<br><br>据中国官方媒体报道，中国国家主席习近平周三表示，中国愿意与美国合作，管控分歧，共同应对全球挑战。</p>   <p>Whether or not the United States and China could establish the "right" way of getting along would be crucial to the world, Xi said in a letter delivered at an annual dinner of New York-headquartered National Committee on United States-China Relations.<br><br>习近平在总部位于纽约的美中关系全国委员会年度晚宴上发表的一封信中表示，美国和中国能否建立“正确”的相处之道对世界至关重要。</p>   <p>Xi's call for more stable bilateral ties, which he says should be built on the principles of "mutual respect, peaceful co-existence and win-win cooperation", comes before a key visit by Foreign Minister Wang Yi to Washington later this week.<br><br>在外交部长王毅本周晚些时候对华盛顿进行重要访问之前，习近平呼吁建立更加稳定的双边关系，并表示双边关系应建立在“相互尊重、和平共处、合作共赢”的原则之上。</p>   <p>The trip from Thursday through Saturday by the top Chinese diplomat will be the highest-level in-person engagement ahead of an expected meeting between U.S. President Joe Biden and Xi in San Francisco at the November Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit.<br><br>中国最高外交官周四至周六的访问将是美国总统乔·拜登和习近平预计将于 11 月亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会期间在旧金山举行会晤之前进行的最高级别的面对面接触。</p>   <p>Several top U.S. officials including U.S. State Secretary Antony Blinken met their Chinese counterparts in Beijing this summer.<br><br>今年夏天，包括美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯在内的多位美国高级官员在北京会见了中国同行。</p>   <p>Washington's top priority has been to ensure the intense competition between the world's two biggest economies and their disagreements over a host of issues from trade to Taiwan and the South China Sea does not veer into conflict.<br><br>华盛顿的首要任务是确保世界最大两个经济体之间的激烈竞争，以及它们在贸易、台湾和南海等一系列问题上的分歧不会演变成冲突。</p>   <p>"Chinese observers believe the visit (by Wang) will pave the way for a possible meeting between the heads of the two states but added that Washington needs to make concrete efforts to address Beijing's concerns and show its sincerity," China's state-controlled Global Times wrote in a commentary.<br><br>中国官方媒体《环球时报》表示：“中国观察人士认为，王毅的访问将为两国元首可能举行的会晤铺平道路，但他补充说，华盛顿需要做出具体努力，解决北京的担忧并展现其诚意。”在评论中写道。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ryan Woo; Editing by Muralikumar Anantharaman and Raju Gopalakrishnan<br><br>瑞恩·吴 (Ryan Woo) 报道； Muralikumar Anantharaman 和 Raju Gopalakrishnan 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 03:00:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TXZLRZGBSVN4FFCYAVOSGQDQ6U</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-willing-cooperate-with-us-manage-differences-xi-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>USA/XI (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国通过儿童和家庭爱国主义教育法-官方媒体]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/-YCMqjjicPSJ8OdrUWNVEfSFo5s=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6YEA5KDEIRLYBPT4YZSVYWMKDU.jpg" alt="Students stand at a school on the first day of new academic year in Shanghai<br><br>新学年第一天，上海，学生们站在学校里" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Students stand at a school during a flag-lowering ceremony on the first day of the new academic year in Shanghai, China, September 1, 2021. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo<br><br>2021 年 9 月 1 日，中国上海，新学年第一天，学生们站在学校举行的降旗仪式上。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's national legislature on Tuesday passed a law to strengthen patriotic education for children and families, state media reported, to counter challenges such as "historical nihilism" and safeguard "national unity".<br><br>据官方媒体报道，中国国家立法机关周二通过了一项加强对儿童和家庭的爱国主义教育的法律，以应对“历史虚无主义”等挑战，维护“国家统一”。</p>   <p>The Patriotic Education Law provides a legal guarantee for carrying out patriotic education, state-backed Xinhua news agency reported, adding that some people "are at a loss about what is patriotism."<br><br>据官方媒体新华社报道，《爱国主义教育法》为开展爱国主义教育提供了法律保障，并补充说，一些人“对什么是爱国主义感到困惑”。</p>   <p>"Historical nihilism" is a phrase used in China to describe public doubt and scepticism over the Chinese Communist Party's description of past events.<br><br>“历史虚无主义”是中国用来形容公众对中国共产党对过去事件的描述的怀疑和怀疑的一个短语。</p>   <p>The law, which will take effect on Jan. 1, 2024, outlines the responsibilities for central and local government departments as well as in schools and for families.<br><br>该法律将于 2024 年 1 月 1 日生效，概述了中央和地方政府部门以及学校和家庭的职责。</p>   <p>"While it is enacted to promote patriotism, the law stresses the need to be rational, inclusive and open-minded, open the country wider to the world and embrace other civilisations," Xinhua said.<br><br>新华社说：“制定这部法律的目的是弘扬爱国主义精神，但强调要理性、包容、开放，坚持对外开放、包容其他文明。”</p>   <p>The law mandates that patriotic education respects the "history and cultural traditions of other countries and draws inspiration from all of human civilization's outstanding achievements," it said.<br><br>该法规定，爱国主义教育尊重“其他国家的历史和文化传统，从人类文明的一切杰出成就中汲取灵感”。</p>   <p>The law also has targeted measures for different groups of people, including government officials, employees, villagers and residents in special administrative regions Hong Kong and Macau, as well as Taiwan, state-backed China Daily said.<br><br>据官方支持的《中国日报》报道，该法还针对不同人群制定了针对性措施，包括香港、澳门和台湾特别行政区的政府官员、雇员、村民和居民。</p>    <span>Reporting by Farah Master; Editing by Christian Schmollinger<br><br>法拉大师报道；克里斯蒂安·施莫林格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 02:24:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">M4LV4Z6AORJINNZELYIZS2SFWU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-passes-patriotic-education-law-children-families-state-media-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>EDUCATION/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[亚洲 反弹可喜，但大型科技信号好坏参半]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/RXFN_lfi8Gxz-OdwXfAFEFkwqq4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7QZ2LFRJRNIO7FMGFG72XMK2FM.jpg" alt="A woman walks past a man&nbsp;examining an electronic board showing Japan's Nikkei average and stock quotations in Tokyo<br><br>东京，一名女子走过一名正在检查显示日本日经平均指数和股票报价的电子板的男子。" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>FILE PHOTO:A woman walks past a man&nbsp;examining an electronic board showing Japan's Nikkei average and stock quotations outside a brokerage, in Tokyo, Japan, March 20, 2023. REUTERS/Androniki Christodoulou/File Photo<br><br>文件照片：2023 年 3 月 20 日，日本东京，一名女子走过一名男子，他正在经纪公司外检查显示日本日经平均指数和股票报价的电子板。路透社/Androniki Christodoulou/文件照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A look at the day ahead in Asian markets from Jamie McGeever, financial markets columnist.<br><br>金融市场专栏作家杰米·麦克吉弗 (Jamie McGeever) 对亚洲市场未来一天的展望。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-rise-treasury-yields-retreat-earnings-focus-2023-10-24/">Good news was good news</a> on Tuesday, as another surprisingly strong <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-business-output-ticks-up-october-inflation-pressures-ease-2023-10-24/">snapshot of U.S. business activity</a> boosted investor sentiment and risk appetite, which should pave the way for a positive open in Asian markets on Wednesday.<br><br>周二的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-rise-treasury-yields-retreat-earnings-focus-2023-10-24/">好消息就是好消息</a>， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-business-output-ticks-up-october-inflation-pressures-ease-2023-10-24/">美国商业活动的另一个令人惊讶的强劲表现</a>提振了投资者情绪和风险偏好，这应该为周三亚洲市场的积极开盘铺平道路。</p>   <p>Upbeat U.S. economic data often fuels <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/fed-done-hiking-rates-higher-longer-message-gaining-traction-2023-10-18/">Fed rate hike expectations</a>, dragging stocks and other asset markets lower. But not this time - investors cheered the unexpected expansion in manufacturing and service sector activity, and the gloom that has descended on markets recently lifted.<br><br>乐观的美国经济数据往往会加剧<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/fed-done-hiking-rates-higher-longer-message-gaining-traction-2023-10-18/">美联储加息的预期</a>，拖累股市和其他资产市场走低。但这一次并非如此——投资者对制造业和服务业活动的意外扩张感到高兴，最近笼罩市场的阴霾也随之消散。</p>   <p>Asian markets should follow suit, as there's not much locally for traders to get their teeth into - Australian consumer inflation for September and the third quarter are the only numbers likely to have any <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/australia-cbank-sees-risks-inflation-will-not-hesitate-rates-2023-10-24/">meaningful market impact</a>.<br><br>亚洲市场应该效仿，因为当地没有太多可供交易者深入研究的数据——澳大利亚九月份和第三季度的消费者通胀是唯一可能对<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/australia-cbank-sees-risks-inflation-will-not-hesitate-rates-2023-10-24/">市场产生有意义影响的</a>数据。</p>   <p>The three main U.S. indexes closed up between 0.6% and 0.9%, and U.S. tech giants <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/microsoft-beats-quarterly-revenue-estimates-2023-10-24/">Microsoft</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/google-parent-alphabet-reports-quarterly-revenue-above-estimates-2023-10-24/">Google-parent Alphabet</a> posted forecast-beating earnings after the bell.<br><br>美国三大股指收盘涨幅在0.6%至0.9%之间，美国科技巨头<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/microsoft-beats-quarterly-revenue-estimates-2023-10-24/">微软</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/google-parent-alphabet-reports-quarterly-revenue-above-estimates-2023-10-24/">谷歌母公司Alphabet</a>盘后公布了超出预期的财报。</p>   <p>Investors' immediate reaction, however, was mixed. Alphabet's cloud-based revenue fell short of analysts' expectations, pushing shares down more than 5% in after-hours trade, while Microsoft shares rose 4% after hours.<br><br>然而，投资者的立即反应却褒贬不一。 Alphabet 基于云的收入未达到分析师预期，导致盘后交易中股价下跌超过 5%，而微软股价盘后上涨 4%。</p>   <p>In Asia on Wednesday, South Korea's LG Display is expected to show a fall in quarterly revenue when it reports results. The Apple supplier has posted <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/lg-display-posts-5th-consecutive-quarterly-loss-2023-07-26/">losses for the last five quarters</a> but is eyeing a turnaround in the final quarter of the year.<br><br>周三在亚洲，韩国 LG Display 公布业绩时预计将出现季度收入下降。这家苹果供应商<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/lg-display-posts-5th-consecutive-quarterly-loss-2023-07-26/">在过去五个季度都出现了亏损</a>，但希望在今年最后一个季度实现扭亏为盈。</p>   <p>On the economic data front, annual consumer inflation in Australia is expected to slow to 5.3% in the third quarter from 6.0% in the April-June period.<br><br>经济数据方面，预计澳大利亚第三季度年度消费者通胀率将从 4 月至 6 月期间的 6.0% 放缓至 5.3%。</p>   <p>But on a monthly basis, it is expected to rise to 5.4% in September from 5.2% in August, which would mark the first time this year that inflation has risen two months in succession.<br><br>但从月度来看，预计9月通胀率将从8月的5.2%升至5.4%，这将标志着今年通胀率首次连续两个月上涨。</p>   <p>Reserve Bank of Australia governor Michele Bullock on Tuesday warned there were risks <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/australia-cbank-sees-risks-inflation-will-not-hesitate-rates-2023-10-24/">inflation would prove more stubborn</a> than expected and that interest rates might have to rise further to bring it to heel.<br><br>澳大利亚储备银行行长米歇尔·布洛克周二警告称， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/australia-cbank-sees-risks-inflation-will-not-hesitate-rates-2023-10-24/">通胀可能比预期更加顽固</a>，利率可能必须进一步上升才能让通胀回升。</p>   <p>The Australian dollar liked what it heard, bucked the global trend of widespread weakness against the U.S. dollar, and goes into the inflation data on the front foot around $0.6360.<br><br>澳元兑美元喜闻乐见，逆势逆势兑美元普遍疲软，在通胀数据中领先于0.6360美元附近。</p>   <p>Chinese assets remain under pressure, even though the blue chip CSI300 index snapped a four-day losing streak and rebounded from Monday's four and a half year low.<br><br>尽管蓝筹股沪深300指数结束了四连跌并从周一的四年半低点反弹，但中国资产仍然面临压力。</p>   <p>Meanwhile, there is a slew of China-related policy and political news for investors to digest.<br><br>与此同时，还有大量与中国相关的政策和政治新闻供投资者消化。</p>   <p>China's top parliament body has approved a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/china-issue-137-bln-sovereign-debt-support-economy-2023-10-24/">1 trillion yuan</a> sovereign bond issue and Beijing has appointed Lan Foan, a technocrat with little central government experience, as the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-names-lan-foan-new-finance-minister-amid-stimulus-push-2023-10-24/">new finance minister</a>.<br><br>中国最高人大批准了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/china-issue-137-bln-sovereign-debt-support-economy-2023-10-24/">1万亿元人民币</a>的主权债券发行，北京任命了缺乏中央政府经验的技术官僚兰福安为<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-names-lan-foan-new-finance-minister-amid-stimulus-push-2023-10-24/">新任财政部长</a>。</p>   <p>Chinese President Xi Jinping made his first known <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-xi-makes-first-known-visit-central-bank-sources-2023-10-24/">visit to the nation's central bank</a> since he became president a decade ago, also seen by some as reflection of the government's focus on supporting the economy.<br><br>中国国家主席习近平自十年前就任<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-xi-makes-first-known-visit-central-bank-sources-2023-10-24/">国家主席以来首次访问中国央行</a>，也被一些人视为政府重点支持经济的体现。</p>   <p>Here are key developments that could provide more direction to markets on Wednesday:<br><br>以下是周三可能为市场提供更多方向的关键进展：</p>   <p>- Australia CPI inflation (September/Q3)<br><br>- 澳大利亚 CPI 通胀（九月/第三季度）</p>   <p>- South Korea consumer sentiment (October)<br><br>- 韩国消费者信心（十月）</p>   <p>- South Korea LG earnings (Q3)<br><br>- 韩国 LG 盈利（第三季度）</p>    <span>By Jamie McGeever; Editing by Josie Kao<br><br>作者：杰米·麦克吉弗；编辑：高乔茜</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 23:50:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RBASP6OEAVKYZDRU4F3FGQDQVM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/global-markets-view-asia-graphics-pix-2023-10-24/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jamie McGeever]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>ASIA (GRAPHICS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[荷兰议员质疑美国对 ASML 芯片机的新出口限制]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Jv04kpTxIZjVRBb_gOCvdgHw6oY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VKHTLRPPWFN4NCM4XAMXNXZFI4.jpg" alt="Illustration shows ASML logo<br><br>插图显示 ASML 徽标" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>ASML logo is seen in this illustration taken February 28, 2022. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo<br><br>ASML 徽标在 2022 年 2 月 28 日拍摄的这张插图中可见。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Several Dutch lawmakers on Tuesday challenged the Netherlands' Trade Minister over whether the U.S. has acted correctly in unilaterally imposing new rules regulating the export to China of another chipmaking machine made by ASML Holding <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ASML.AS" target="_blank">(ASML.AS)</a>.<br><br>几位荷兰议员周二向荷兰贸易部长提出质疑，质疑美国单方面实施新规则来监管阿斯麦控股公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ASML.AS" target="_blank">（ASML.AS）</a>生产的另一款芯片制造机向中国出口是否正确。</p>   <p>Trade Minister Liesje Schreinemacher said during a parliamentary debate the Cabinet was not opposed to the new U.S. rules affecting Europe's largest tech firm but "this should be tackled in a much more European way."<br><br>贸易部长利耶·施赖内马赫(Liesje Schreinemacher)在议会辩论中表示，内阁并不反对影响欧洲最大科技公司的美国新规定，但“应该以更加欧洲化的方式来解决这个问题”。</p>   <p>The U.S. last week announced <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/biden-cut-china-off-more-nvidia-chips-expand-curbs-more-countries-2023-10-17/">new rules</a> giving Washington the right to restrict the export of Veldhoven-headquartered ASML's Twinscan NXT1930Di machine if it contains any U.S. parts at all.<br><br>美国上周宣布了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/biden-cut-china-off-more-nvidia-chips-expand-curbs-more-countries-2023-10-17/">新规定</a>，如果总部位于 Veldhoven 的 ASML 的 Twinscan NXT1930Di 机器含有任何美国零部件，华盛顿有权限制其出口。</p>   <p>The deep ultraviolet (DUV) lithography machine can be used to help make both relatively advanced computer chips as well as mid-range and older chips. U.S. policy is aimed at slowing China's technological and military advances.<br><br>深紫外（DUV）光刻机可用于帮助制造相对先进的计算机芯片以及中端和较旧的芯片。美国政策旨在减缓中国的技术和军事进步。</p>   <p>ASML said it would abide by the U.S. rules, and it believed in practice the new restrictions would apply only to a tools for a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/asml-ceo-says-he-expects-demand-china-will-remain-strong-2023-10-18/">small number of Chinese plants</a> capable of making "advanced semiconductors."<br><br>阿斯麦表示将遵守美国的规定，并相信实际上新的限制只会适用于<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/asml-ceo-says-he-expects-demand-china-will-remain-strong-2023-10-18/">少数能够制造“先进半导体”的中国工厂的</a>工具。</p>   <p>The U.S. has pressured the Dutch government not to export any of its most advanced machines to China since 2019, and in June the Dutch government introduced its own licensing requirement for slightly less advanced machines. Those do not cover the 1980di tool.<br><br>自 2019 年以来，美国一直向荷兰政府施压，要求其不得向中国出口任何最先进的机器，6 月，荷兰政府对稍微不太先进的机器提出了自己的许可要求。这些不包括 1980di 工具。</p>   <p>ASML dominates the market for lithography equipment, used by chipmakers such as TSMC <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2330.TW" target="_blank">(2330.TW)</a>, Samsung <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/005930.KS" target="_blank">(005930.KS)</a> and Intel <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/INTC.O" target="_blank">(INTC.O)</a> to help create the circuitry of chips. China is historically ASML's third-largest market after Taiwan and South Korea.<br><br>ASML 在光刻设备市场占据主导地位，台积电<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2330.TW" target="_blank">(2330.TW)</a> 、三星<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/005930.KS" target="_blank">(005930.KS)</a>和英特尔<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/INTC.O" target="_blank">(INTC.O)</a>等芯片制造商都使用该设备来帮助创建芯片电路。中国历来是ASML继台湾和韩国之后的第三大市场。</p>   <p>Schreienmacher said that the Netherlands has so far negotiated with the U.S. alone over restrictions but "naturally it's better to do that in coordination with other (EU) member states."<br><br>施赖恩马赫表示，荷兰迄今为止仅与美国就限制措施进行了谈判，但“当然最好与其他（欧盟）成员国协调”。</p>   <p>"I've had several conversations with my colleagues in other countries about this," she said, including with European Trade Commissioner Valdis Dombrovskis and Internal Market Commissioner Theirry Breton.<br><br>她说：“我已经与其他国家的同事就此进行了多次对话，其中包括与欧盟贸易专员瓦尔迪斯·东布罗夫斯基斯和内部市场专员泰里·布雷顿的对话。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Toby Sterling; Editing by Jamie Freed<br><br>托比·斯特林报道；杰米·弗里德编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 23:16:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TODNV2QAGZKQXB7INQFBAVUIHE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/dutch-lawmakers-question-new-us-export-restrictions-asml-chip-machine-2023-10-24/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ASML HOLDING</category>
                
                <category>US/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>CHIPS (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[折扣电商公司拼多多创始人跻身中国富豪榜]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/z1gKLlWB6N6LvUTA4YVr2xsYhms=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/QJO752NRGBLT5JCJ4PTXDTGKDY.jpg" alt="Colin Huang, founder and CEO of the online group discounter Pinduoduo, speaks during the company's stock trading debut at the Nasdaq Stock Market in New York, during an event in Shanghai<br><br>在线拼多多创始人兼首席执行官黄科林 (Colin Huang) 在上海举行的一次活动中，在纽约纳斯达克股票市场首次交易时发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Colin Huang, founder and CEO of the online group discounter Pinduoduo, speaks during the company's stock trading debut at the Nasdaq Stock Market in New York, during an event in Shanghai<br><br>在线拼多多创始人兼首席执行官黄科林 (Colin Huang) 在上海举行的一次活动中，在纽约纳斯达克股票市场首次交易时发表讲话, China July 26, 2018.  Yin Liqin/CNS via REUTERS/File photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/kk9bdkj1ilXorBHnICpuB-oYfwA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VKD4XS6UOJNDNLF5T73NQWPXNI.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of Chinese e-commerce platform Pinduoduo Inc<br><br>中国电子商务平台拼多多公司插图图片" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of Chinese e-commerce platform Pinduoduo Inc. is displayed next to the app on a mobile phone, in this illustration picture taken March 22, 2022. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo<br><br>在这张摄于 2022 年 3 月 22 日的插图中，中国电子商务平台拼多多公司的徽标显示在手机应用程序旁边。REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>The founder of PDD Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PDD.O" target="_blank">(PDD.O)</a> saw his wealth swell by $13.8 billion in a year, as a slowing global economy drove more shoppers to the Chinese company's discount e-commerce platforms Temu and Pinduoduo, an annual rich list showed on Tuesday.<br><br>周二公布的年度富豪榜显示，拼多多控股<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PDD.O" target="_blank">(PDD.O)</a>创始人的财富在一年内增加了 138 亿美元，原因是全球经济放缓促使更多消费者前往这家中国公司的折扣电子商务平台特木和拼多多。</p>   <p>Colin Huang, who founded PDD in 2015 and stepped down as CEO in 2020, was the fastest riser in this year's Hurun Rich List, leaping seven places to be ranked China's third richest man with a $37.2 billion fortune. It also marked the first time he had broken into the top 3 ranking.<br><br>黄科林于 2015 年创立拼多多，并于 2020 年卸任首席执行官，是今年胡润富豪榜上升最快的人，跃升七位，以 372 亿美元的财富位列中国第三富豪。这也标志着他首次闯入前三名。</p>   <p>The growth of his fortune reflects the changing e-commerce landscape both in China, where consumer confidence remains low after three years of COVID curbs, and abroad where shopping platforms such as Temu and Shein are gaining steam. PDD did not immediately respond to a request for comment.<br><br>他的财富增长反映了中国电子商务格局的变化，在中国，经过三年的新冠疫情限制，消费者信心仍然低迷，而在国外，Temu和Shein等购物平台正在蓬勃发展。 PDD 没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Jack Ma, founder of rival Alibaba <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">(9988.HK)</a> which is currently going through a restructuring and working to fend off competition from the likes of PDD, fell one place from 2022 to 10th spot and the number of Alibaba shareholders on the list fell from 18 last year, to 12 this year.<br><br>其竞争对手阿里巴巴<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">（9988.HK）</a>的创始人马云目前正在进行重组，并努力抵御来自拼多多等公司的竞争，其排名较 2022 年下降一位至第十位，上榜阿里巴巴股东数量也从 2022 年下降了一位。去年是18个，今年是12个。</p>   <p>Richard Liu, who founded e-commerce giant JD.com, also saw his wealth, and that of his wife Zhang Zetian, fall by $6.2 billion since last year to $8.26 billion, according to Hurun's list.<br><br>根据胡润百富榜，电商巨头京东的创始人刘强东及其妻子章泽天的财富也自去年以来减少了 62 亿美元，降至 82.6 亿美元。</p>   <p>JD.com's shares fell to a record low earlier this month after banks cut its price targets citing a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/jdcom-shares-hit-record-low-banks-cut-q3-growth-target-retail-slowdown-2023-10-13/">weaker-than-expected recovery</a> in consumer spending.<br><br>本月早些时候，银行以消费者支出<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/jdcom-shares-hit-record-low-banks-cut-q3-growth-target-retail-slowdown-2023-10-13/">复苏弱于预期为由</a>下调了价格目标，京东股价跌至历史新低。</p>   <p>"Going global has been one of the key sources of growth this year," said Rupert Hoogewerf, Hurun Report Chairman and Chief Researcher, citing PDD's Temu, ByteDance's short video platform TikTok and ultra-fast fashion brand Shein as examples.<br><br>胡润百富董事长兼首席研究员胡润表示，“出海是今年的主要增长源之一。”他以拼多多旗下Temu、字节跳动旗下短视频平台TikTok和超快时尚品牌Shein为例表示。</p>   <p>The founder of bottled water brand Nongfu Spring, Zhong Shanshan, retained his first place for the third year running on the list with a $62 billion fortune while Pony Ma, founder of social media and gaming giant Tencent <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0700.HK" target="_blank">(0700.HK)</a> was second with $38.6 billion.<br><br>瓶装水品牌农夫山泉的创始人钟珊珊以 620 亿美元的财富连续第三年蝉联榜首，社交媒体和游戏巨头腾讯<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0700.HK" target="_blank">（0700.HK）</a>创始人马化腾以 38.6 美元排名第二。十亿。</p>   <p>Hurun also said 179 individuals dropped off this year's list, which ranks China's wealthiest people with a minimum net worth of 5 billion yuan, 15% of which were in real estate, as the sector grapples with a prolonged debt crisis.<br><br>胡润还表示，今年有 179 人从净资产不低于 50 亿元人民币的中国最富有人士名单中跌出，其中 15% 从事房地产行业，因为该行业正在努力应对长期的债务危机。</p>   <p>Wang Jianlin, owner of Dalian Wanda Group and once China's richest man, saw his wealth and that of his family fall by $7.3 billion and 57 spots to be placed in 89th position with a $6.47 billion fortune.<br><br>大连万达集团老板、曾经的中国首富王健林发现，他和他的家族的财富减少了73亿美元，排名下降了57位，以64.7亿美元的财富排名第89位。</p>   <p>The founder of China Evergrande Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a>, the world's most indebted property developer, remained on the list at 268 place despite his company's woes, due to dividends paid out in previous years, Hurun said. Hui Ka Yan is currently being <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shares-china-evergrande-suspended-chairman-under-police-watch-2023-09-28/">investigated</a> over suspected "illegal crimes", Evergrande said last month.<br><br>胡润百富表示，尽管公司因前几年派发股息而陷入困境，但全球负债最多的房地产开发商中国恒大集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）</a>的创始人仍位居榜单第268位。恒大上个月表示，许家印目前因涉嫌“违法犯罪”正在接受<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shares-china-evergrande-suspended-chairman-under-police-watch-2023-09-28/">调查</a>。</p>    <span>Reporting by Casey Hall; editing by Brenda Goh and Miral Fahmy<br><br>凯西·霍尔报道；布伦达·吴 (Brenda Goh) 和米拉尔·法赫米 (Miral Fahmy) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:03:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ICPRL7NC4FP7DPSSILR2TCEDPA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/founder-discount-e-shopping-firm-pdd-races-up-chinas-rich-list-2023-10-24/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Casey Hall]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>BILLIONAIRES/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中美官员会晤讨论宏观经济发展]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/slhmzWrAQUGr8MCcbKpvD8PMuYw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VXFHK2QF6ZKRLFLJMHYEX7CX54.jpg" alt="Illustration shows U.S. and Chinese flags<br><br>插图显示美国和中国国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. and Chinese flags are seen in this illustration taken, January 30, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration<br><br>这张摄于 2023 年 1 月 30 日的插图中可以看到美国和中国国旗。 REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration</figcaption></figure>       <p>Officials from the United States and China on Monday held a two-hour long virtual meeting to discuss domestic and global macroeconomic developments, the U.S. Treasury Department said, calling the meeting "productive and substantive".<br><br>美国财政部表示，美国和中国官员周一举行了长达两个小时的虚拟会议，讨论国内和全球宏观经济发展，称会议“富有成效且具有实质性”。</p>    <h 1="">THE TAKE</h>  <p>Ties between the world's two largest economies have been strained in recent years due to a number of issues including Taiwan, the origins of the COVID-19 pandemic, allegations of spying, human rights issues and trade tariffs.<br><br>近年来，由于台湾、COVID-19 大流行的起源、间谍指控、人权问题和贸易关税等一系列问题，全球最大的两个经济体之间的关系一直紧张。</p>   <p>Senior officials from <a href="https://reut.rs/3SbY0X7" target="_blank">both sides</a> have been meeting each other in recent months to lay the ground for an expected meeting between U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese leader Xi Jinping in San Francisco in November.<br><br>近几个月来<a href="https://reut.rs/3SbY0X7" target="_blank">，双方</a>高级官员一直在会面，为美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平预计将于 11 月在旧金山举行的会晤奠定基础。</p>    <h 1="">KEY QUOTES</h>  <p>"Today, the United States and the People's Republic of China held the first meeting of the Economic Working Group (EWG), which serves as an ongoing channel to discuss and facilitate progress on bilateral economic policy matters," the Treasury Department said.<br><br>美国财政部表示：“今天，美国和中华人民共和国举行了经济工作组（EWG）第一次会议，该会议是讨论双边经济政策问题并促进取得进展的持续渠道。”</p>   <p>China's finance ministry said the two sides had "in-depth, frank and constructive" talks, and also discussed bilateral cooperation in "addressing global challenges".<br><br>中国财政部表示，双方进行了“深入、坦诚、建设性”的会谈，并讨论了两国在“应对全球挑战”方面的合作。</p>   <p>Both sides will continue to maintain communication, the ministry said.<br><br>外交部表示，双方将继续保持沟通。</p>   <p>U.S. and Chinese officials also raised "areas of concern," statements from the two sides said, without elaborating. The meeting was led by senior officials from the U.S. Treasury Department and China's finance ministry.<br><br>双方声明称，美国和中国官员还提出了“令人担忧的领域”，但没有详细说明。会议由美国财政部和中国财政部的高级官员主持。</p>   <p>The EWG was launched last month following U.S. Treasury Secretary <a href="https://reut.rs/44zlQPr" target="_blank">Janet Yellen</a>'s trip to Beijing in July. It was launched in parallel with a financial working group, which will hold its first meeting on Wednesday.<br><br>专家工作组于美国财政部长珍妮特<a href="https://reut.rs/44zlQPr" target="_blank">·耶伦 (Janet Yellen</a> ) 7 月访问北京后于上个月成立。它是与金融工作组同时启动的，该工作组将于周三举行第一次会议。</p>    <h 1="">CONTEXT</h>  <p>The economic meeting follows other <a href="https://reut.rs/3ZLTvEk" target="_blank">high-level engagements</a> between the two countries in recent months that have seen visits from U.S. officials to China like Secretary of State <a href="https://reut.rs/3pbpD6I" target="_blank">Antony Blinken</a> in June, <a href="https://reut.rs/44zlQPr" target="_blank">Yellen</a> in July and Commerce Secretary <a href="https://reut.rs/3rvbSAO" target="_blank">Gina Raimondo</a> in August.<br><br>这次经济会议是在近几个月两国举行其他<a href="https://reut.rs/3ZLTvEk" target="_blank">高层接触</a>之后举行的，美国官员如六月的国务卿<a href="https://reut.rs/3pbpD6I" target="_blank">安东尼·布林肯</a>、七月的<a href="https://reut.rs/44zlQPr" target="_blank">耶伦</a>和八月的商务部长<a href="https://reut.rs/3rvbSAO" target="_blank">吉娜·雷蒙多</a>都访问了中国。</p>   <p>More recently, Blinken met Chinese Vice President Han Zheng in New York and U.S. National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan met Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi in Malta. China's top diplomat will travel to the United States later this week to meet Blinken.<br><br>最近，布林肯在纽约会见了中国国家副主席韩正，美国国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文在马耳他会见了中国外交部长王毅。中国最高外交官将于本周晚些时候前往美国会见布林肯。</p>    <span>Reporting by Kanishka Singh in Washington, Liz Lee and Ethan Wang in Beijing; Editing by Christian Schmollinger and Miral Fahmy<br><br>Kanishka Singh 在华盛顿、Liz Lee 和 Ethan Wang 在北京的报道；克里斯蒂安·施莫林格和米拉尔·法赫米编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 03:14:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">JGCU7JDCVFMKRHN4ZB4QY5PIAY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-us-officials-discuss-macroeconomic-developments-meeting-2023-10-24/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Kanishka Singh]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/TALKS (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
