<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub-five-red.vercel.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 23:31:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[参议员以中国为由敦促美国采取措施提高电池产量]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/3Qd3Wh_xPuFjzFUrKxEqDCs4BCA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZMHKR3SP7BJMZIRNKIUKIEECFA.jpg" alt="Workers are seen at the production line of lithium-ion batteries for electric vehicles (EV) at a factory in Huzhou翻译:湖州一家工厂的电动汽车锂离子电池生产线上，工人们在工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Workers are seen at the production line of lithium-ion batteries for electric vehicles (EV) at a factory in Huzhou翻译:湖州一家工厂的电动汽车锂离子电池生产线上，工人们在工作, Zhejiang province, China August 28, 2018. REUTERS/Stringer/ File photo翻译:2018 年 8 月 28 日，中国浙江省湖州一家工厂的电动汽车锂离子电池生产线上，工人们在工作。 REUTERS/Stringer/ 资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Two influential Democratic U.S. senators urged the Energy Department to take steps to boost U.S. battery manufacturing and next-generation battery research, citing China's dominance and export controls, according to a letter seen by Reuters.翻译:路透社看到的一封信显示，两位有影响力的美国民主党参议员敦促能源部采取措施促进美国电池制造和下一代电池研究，理由是中国的主导地位和出口管制。</p>   <p>Senate Intelligence Committee Chair Mark Warner and Energy Committee Chair Joe Manchin cited experts saying that the United States is "ten to twenty years behind Asia in commercialization of battery technology," and noted that China accounts for more than 75% of battery cell production.翻译:参议院情报委员会主席马克·沃纳和能源委员会主席乔·曼钦援引专家的话称，美国“在电池技术商业化方面落后亚洲十到二十年”，并指出中国占电池产量的75%以上。</p>   <p>"The U.S. must become a leader in manufacturing batteries and battery components, while securing our supply chains for the materials that make up those components," the senators wrote in a previously unreported letter seen by Reuters, citing China's decision last month to restrict exports of graphite, critical to manufacturing battery anodes.翻译:参议员们在路透社看到的一封此前未报道的信中写道：“美国必须成为电池和电池组件制造领域的领导者，同时确保我们构成这些组件的材料的供应链安全。”信中援引了中国上个月限制电池出口的决定。石墨，对于制造电池阳极至关重要。</p>   <p>China dominates the global EV battery supply chain including production of graphite - the single largest component.翻译:中国在全球电动汽车电池供应链中占据主导地位，其中包括最大的单一零部件石墨的生产。</p>   <p>The letter noted in 2022 the United States produced less than 10% of lithium-ion batteries in 2022 and said demand is expected to grow over seven times by 2035.翻译:信中指出，2022年美国锂离子电池产量不足10%，并表示到2035年需求预计将增长七倍以上。</p>   <p>The letter wants a committee briefing by Dec. 1 "on ongoing research and development of next-generation battery technologies."翻译:这封信希望委员会在 12 月 1 日之前就“正在进行的下一代电池技术的研究和开发”进行简报。</p>   <p>Lithium-ion batteries, the Pentagon has said, are crucial to thousands of military systems from "handheld radios, to unmanned submersibles and to future capabilities like lasers, directed energy weapons and hybrid electric tactical vehicles," the letter noted.翻译:信中指出，五角大楼表示，锂离子电池对数千个军事系统至关重要，从“手持无线电到无人潜水器，再到激光、定向能武器和混合电动战术车辆等未来功能”。</p>   <p>China accounts for 70% of the global production of lithium-ion batteries, the letter said, noting of five critical minerals required for most lithium-ion batteries, China "controls between 60-100% of the mining or refining for these minerals."翻译:信中称，中国占全球锂离子电池产量的70%，并指出，在大多数锂离子电池所需的五种关键矿物中，中国“控制着这些矿物60-100%的开采或精炼”。</p>   <p>The letter also said "it is critical that the U.S. lead in next-generation battery technology and alternative chemistries" and coordinate with the Department of Defense and other national security agencies "to support procurement of innovative, U.S.-developed energy storage technologies."翻译:信中还表示，“美国在下一代电池技术和替代化学物质方面处于领先地位”，并与国防部和其他国家安全机构协调“以支持采购美国开发的创新能源存储技术”。</p>   <p>A spokesperson for Energy Secretary Jennifer Granholm did not immediately respond to a request for comment.翻译:能源部长詹妮弗·格兰霍姆的发言人没有立即回应置评请求。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Shepardson; Editing by Leslie Adler and Stephen Coates翻译:大卫·谢泼德森报道；莱斯利·阿德勒和斯蒂芬·科茨编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 23:24:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MPMBBJNNQBM57ICOUJPNRMSBFU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/senators-urge-us-take-steps-boost-battery-production-citing-china-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Shepardson]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/BATTERIES (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[欧洲的目标是太空发射协议中的竞争性重组]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/oXfb7fs_MzwW1jX-c9mfvlOO6F0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6IB422CTDBNHPGHF724NCKKN4M.jpg" alt="A model of Europe's next-generation space rocket Ariane 6 is pictured at the DLR in Lampoldshausen翻译:兰波尔德斯豪森 DLR 拍摄的欧洲下一代太空火箭阿丽亚娜 6 号模型" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A model of Europe's next-generation space rocket Ariane 6 is pictured at the German Aerospace Center (DLR) in Lampoldshausen near Heilbronn, Germany, February 26, 2019.   REUTERS/Ralph Orlowski/File Photo翻译:欧洲下一代太空火箭阿丽亚娜 6 号模型于 2019 年 2 月 26 日在德国海尔布隆附近兰波尔德斯豪森的德国航空航天中心 (DLR) 拍摄。 REUTERS/Ralph Orlowski/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/dl8DX-fP7qgG4bkbEVTv_-9e0Y4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KBGV763OEBLG7CN6VEZASQUP2E.jpg" alt="ESA Council at Ministerial level (CM22) in Paris翻译:欧空局部长级理事会（CM22）在巴黎举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>European Space Agency (ESA) General Director Josef Aschbacher speaks during the ESA Council at Ministerial level (CM22) at the Grand Palais Ephemere in Paris, France, November 23, 2022. REUTERS/Benoit Tessier/File Photo翻译:欧洲航天局 (ESA) 总干事约瑟夫·阿施巴赫 (Josef Aschbacher) 于 2022 年 11 月 23 日在法国巴黎大皇宫举行的欧洲航天局部长级理事会 (CM22) 上发表讲话。 REUTERS/Benoit Tessier/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>Europe on Monday challenged the private sector to develop services for small rockets that could <a href="https://www.reuters.com/science/indias-boom-russias-crunch-how-money-is-shaping-new-space-race-2023-08-22/">guide future space reform</a>, while stabilising finances for troubled medium and heavyweight launchers for the coming decade.翻译:欧洲周一要求私营部门开发小型火箭服务，以<a href="https://www.reuters.com/science/indias-boom-russias-crunch-how-money-is-shaping-new-space-race-2023-08-22/">指导未来的太空改革</a>，同时稳定未来十年陷入困境的中型和重型运载火箭的财务状况。</p>   <p>The head of the European Space Agency (ESA) said the decision to foster competition had long-term implications for the industry, which is wrestling with a short-term gap in space access due to delays and technical <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/europes-space-agency-boss-sees-progress-ariane-6-launcher-2023-10-31/">setbacks with Ariane 6</a> and Vega-C rockets.翻译:欧洲航天局 (ESA) 负责人表示，促进竞争的决定对该行业产生了长期影响，由于<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/europes-space-agency-boss-sees-progress-ariane-6-launcher-2023-10-31/">阿丽亚娜 6 号和织女星 C 的延误和技术挫折，</a>该行业正在努力解决太空准入方面的短期差距。火箭。</p>   <p>"We are in the midst of a paradigm shift for space transportation," Director General Josef Aschbacher said halfway through two days of space talks in Seville, Spain.翻译:“我们正处于太空运输范式转变之中，”总干事约瑟夫·阿施巴赫在西班牙塞维利亚举行的为期两天的太空会谈中途说道。</p>   <p>The announcement marks a new departure for the 22-nation agency which has previously designed and procured launchers and wants to move towards a leaner system of buying services to help Europe mimic the runaway growth of rivals like <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/elon-musk-says-starlink-has-achieved-breakeven-cash-flow-2023-11-02/">Elon Musk's SpaceX</a>.翻译:这一公告标志着这家由 22 个国家组成的机构的新起点，该机构此前曾设计和采购发射器，并希望转向更精简的购买服务系统，以帮助欧洲模仿<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/elon-musk-says-starlink-has-achieved-breakeven-cash-flow-2023-11-02/">埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 的 SpaceX</a>等竞争对手的快速增长。</p>   <p>"The launcher challenge...will lower the cost of public funding and stimulate a new market for European space entrepreneurs," Aschbacher told ministers.翻译:“发射器挑战……将降低公共资金成本，并为欧洲航天企业家刺激新市场，”阿施巴赫告诉部长们。</p>   <p>Such projects would start with a new generation of mini-launchers but could set the tone for longer-term replacements for Europe's heavier Ariane 6 and Vega-C, which remain Europe's only independent options for major payloads in coming years.翻译:此类项目将从新一代迷你发射器开始，但可能为欧洲较重的阿丽亚娜 6 和织女星 C 的长期替代奠定了基调，这仍然是欧洲未来几年主要有效载荷的唯一独立选择。</p>   <p>"It's a mini-revolution because what they want to do now is buy a service," said Antoine Meunier, author of a recent book on the "long road" to European crewed space flight.翻译:“这是一场小型革命，因为他们现在想做的是购买服务，”安托万·莫尼耶（Antoine Meunier）说，他最近出版了一本关于欧洲载人航天“漫长道路”的书。</p>   <p>The move is part of a broader deal easing months of tensions after <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/france-says-ariane-6-accord-calls-public-aid-11-cost-cuts-2023-11-06/">France lobbied for more support</a> for Ariane 6, Germany pressed for competition in the France-led launch sector and Italy <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/italy-france-germany-agree-launches-ariane-6-vega-c-2023-11-06/">demanded a bigger say</a> on its domestically produced Vega-C.</p>    <h 1="">LAUNCHER DEAL</h>  <p>In a side declaration, France, Germany and Italy took credit for breaking deadlock and forging an agreement backed by other ESA nations, though delegates said all 22 nations had a role.翻译:在一份侧面声明中，法国、德国和意大利因打破僵局并达成了其他欧空局国家支持的协议而受到赞誉，不过代表们表示，所有 22 个国家都发挥了作用。</p>   <p>"We have a stable future for heavy and medium-sized launchers. This is a big relief because a few days ago we did not have this situation yet," Aschbacher told reporters.翻译:“我们对于重型和中型发射器有一个稳定的未来。这让人松了一口气，因为几天前我们还没有出现这种情况，”阿施巴赫告诉记者。</p>   <p>The deal means countries involved in existing launchers will provide up to 340 million euros ($364.48 million) of annual support for Ariane 6 and 21 million euros for Vega-C from 2026, to help close a gap between rising costs and market prices.翻译:该协议意味着，从 2026 年起，参与现有发射器的国家将为阿丽亚娜 6 提供高达 3.4 亿欧元（3.6448 亿美元）的年度支持，为 Vega-C 提供高达 2100 万欧元的支持，以帮助缩小不断上升的成本与市场价格之间的差距。</p>   <p>They also guaranteed four institutional launches a year for Ariane 6 and three for Vega-C.翻译:他们还保证每年四次机构发射 Ariane 6 和 3 次 Vega-C。</p>   <p>The agreement secures a second batch of Ariane 6 launches from flights 16 to 42 after previous commitments covered an inaugural test flight and 14 commercial launches. That will give Airbus and other contractors more confidence to order parts.翻译:继之前的承诺包括首次试飞和 14 次商业发射后，该协议确保从第 16 至 42 次航班进行第二批阿丽亚娜 6 号发射。这将使空客和其他承包商更有信心订购零件。</p>   <p>In return, the industry will have to cut costs by 11%, French Finance Minister Bruno Le Maire told reporters. Ariane 6 is built by Airbus-Safran <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AIR.PA" target="_blank">(AIR.PA)</a>, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SAF.PA" target="_blank">(SAF.PA)</a> venture ArianeGroup.翻译:法国财政部长布鲁诺·勒梅尔 (Bruno Le Maire) 告诉记者，作为回报，该行业必须削减 11% 的成本。阿丽亚娜 6 由空中客车赛峰集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AIR.PA" target="_blank">(AIR.PA)</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SAF.PA" target="_blank">(SAF.PA)</a>合资企业阿丽亚娜集团 (ArianeGroup) 建造。</p>   <p>Italy <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/italy-france-germany-agree-launches-ariane-6-vega-c-2023-11-06/">said earlier</a> the deal could also lead to Vega-C being operated by Italian manufacturer Avio <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AVI.MI" target="_blank">(AVI.MI)</a> in addition to Arianespace, which is currently the sole European operator.翻译:意大利<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/italy-france-germany-agree-launches-ariane-6-vega-c-2023-11-06/">早些时候表示，</a>除了目前唯一的欧洲运营商 Arianespace 之外，该交易还可能导致 Vega-C 由意大利制造商 Avio <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AVI.MI" target="_blank">(AVI.MI)</a>运营。</p>   <p>Ministers also agreed to breathe new life into exploration by inviting private funding for a potential space plane to ferry cargo to and from the International Space Station.翻译:部长们还同意邀请私人资金建造一架潜在的太空飞机，以在国际空间站之间运送货物，从而为探索注入新的活力。</p>   <p>Until now, Europe has carved out a leading role in climate and scientific observation but <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/europe-urged-not-repeat-tech-underdog-role-ahead-space-talks-2023-11-06/">rarely targeted a prime role</a> in human exploration - opting instead for a junior role in projects led by U.S. space agency NASA or until recently Russia.翻译:到目前为止，欧洲已经在气候和科学观测方面发挥了主导作用，但<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/europe-urged-not-repeat-tech-underdog-role-ahead-space-talks-2023-11-06/">很少在人类探索中发挥主要作用</a>，而是选择在美国航天局或直到最近的俄罗斯领导的项目中扮演次要角色。</p>   <p>However the new initiative, backed by 75 million euros of public seed funding, fell short of recent calls by experts including former NATO Secretary General Anders Fogh Rasmussen for a radical European plan to catch up with dominant space powers like the U.S., Russia, China and increasingly India.翻译:然而，这项由 7500 万欧元公共种子资金支持的新举措，未能满足包括前北约秘书长安德斯·福格·拉斯穆森在内的专家最近的呼吁，要求欧洲采取一项激进的计划，以赶上美国、俄罗斯、中国和日本等主导太空强国。越来越印度。</p>   <p>Aschbacher, who has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/europe-urged-not-repeat-tech-underdog-role-ahead-space-talks-2023-11-06/">warned Europe</a> against falling behind on space as it did on IT, described the plane as a "first step" and said it could be eventually be adapted to include human flight.翻译:阿施巴赫<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/europe-urged-not-repeat-tech-underdog-role-ahead-space-talks-2023-11-06/">警告欧洲</a>不要像在信息技术领域那样在太空领域落后，他将这架飞机描述为“第一步”，并表示它最终可能会适应载人飞行。</p>   <p>The proposal echoes the Hermes space plane, which never got off the drawing board. Europe's answer to the U.S. Space Shuttle was designed to carry three astronauts but was scrapped in 1992.翻译:该提案与从未脱离设计阶段的赫尔墨斯太空飞机相呼应。欧洲仿效美国航天飞机的设计目的是搭载三名宇航员，但于 1992 年被废弃。</p>   <p>($1 = 0.9328 euros)翻译:（1 美元 = 0.9328 欧元）</p>   <p>(This story has been refiled to delete an unnecessary hyphen in paragraph 7)翻译:（这个故事已重新归档，删除了第 7 段中不必要的连字符）</p>    <span>Reporting by Tim Hepher, Giuseppe Fonte, Charlotte Van Campenhout; editing by Robert Birsel, Barbara Lewis, Josie Kao and Rod Nickel翻译:Tim Hepher、Giuseppe Fonte、Charlotte Van Campenhout 报道；编辑：Robert Birsel、Barbara Lewis、Josie Kao 和 Rod Nickel</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 22:25:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FNGCVWAEBBLBJIMOB7H3HKEEME</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/europe-urged-not-repeat-tech-underdog-role-ahead-space-talks-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Tim Hepher, Giuseppe Fonte]]></author>
            
                
                <category>EUROPE</category>
                
                <category>SPACE/ (CORRECTED, UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早间竞价：数据洪流可能会浇灭本周开局的火热]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/yErMgO-r9LcIzB1mfkVEwnjT7u0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GWHIYBY24ZNFNE5YJHZ62ELY3Y.jpg" alt="FILE PHOTO: An electronic board shows stock indexes at the Lujiazui financial district in Shanghai翻译:资料图片：上海陆家嘴金融区的电子板显示股票指数" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An electronic board shows stock indexes at the Lujiazui financial district in Shanghai, China, March 21, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo 翻译:2023 年 3 月 21 日，中国上海陆家嘴金融区的电子板显示股票指数。路透社/Aly Song/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A look at the day ahead in Asian markets from Jamie McGeever, financial markets columnist.翻译:金融市场专栏作家杰米·麦克吉弗 (Jamie McGeever) 对亚洲市场未来一天的展望。</p>   <p>Tuesday will be one of the busiest days of the year for Asian markets in terms of top-tier regional economic data and events, and investors could not be going into it on a stronger footing.翻译:就顶级区域经济数据和事件而言，周二将是亚洲市场一年中最繁忙的日子之一，投资者不可能以更强劲的基础入市。</p>   <p>Asian and emerging market stocks rose more than 2% on Monday, bringing their gains over the last three trading sessions up to almost 6%.翻译:亚洲和新兴市场股市周一上涨超过 2%，过去三个交易日涨幅接近 6%。</p>   <p>This is their best run in a year, powered by easing financial conditions in the form of lower U.S. bond yields and a weaker dollar, and renewed faith in the U.S. economic 'soft landing' scenario.翻译:这是它们一年来最好的表现，其动力来自于美国债券收益率下降和美元疲软等金融环境的放松，以及人们对美国经济“软着陆”情景的新信心。</p>   <p>Aggregate financial conditions across emerging markets and in China have slumped in recent days to their loosest in nearly two months, or in the case of India, the easiest in three months, Goldman Sachs financial conditions indices show.翻译:高盛金融状况指数显示，新兴市场和中国的总体金融状况最近几天已降至近两个月来的最低水平，而印度的总体金融状况则为三个月来最宽松的水平。</p>   <p>South Korean shares got an added injection of rocket fuel on Monday, surging 5.7% in their biggest leap since early 2020 after authorities re-imposed a ban on short-selling through the first half of 2024 to promote a "level playing field".翻译:周一，韩国股市再次注入火箭燃料，飙升 5.7%，创下 2020 年初以来的最大涨幅，此前当局重新实施了 2024 年上半年的卖空禁令，以促进“公平竞争环境”。</p>   <p>Having under-performed global and developed market benchmarks last week, Asian stocks could be set to outperform this week. That is how markets played out on Monday, as the MSCI World Index and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-edge-up-rate-cut-hopes-fed-speakers-awaited-2023-11-06/">Wall Street</a> eked out gains of no more than 0.3%.翻译:亚洲股市上周表现不佳，但本周可能会跑赢全球和发达市场基准。这就是周一市场的表现，MSCI 世界指数和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-edge-up-rate-cut-hopes-fed-speakers-awaited-2023-11-06/">华尔街的</a>涨幅不超过 0.3%。</p>   <p>That may temper some of the bullishness across Asia on Tuesday, however, and there is certainly no shortage of event risk to keep investors and traders on their toes.翻译:然而，这可能会缓和周二整个亚洲的一些看涨情绪，而且肯定不乏让投资者和交易员保持警惕的事件风险。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/rba-deliver-25-bp-interest-rate-hike-nov-7-2023-11-03/">Australia's central bank</a> is expected to raise its benchmark cash rate by 25 basis points to 4.35%, the highest since 2011 and breaking a run of four meetings on hold. Sticky inflation is keeping a hawkish bias in Aussie money markets, which are pricing in at least one more quarter point hike next year.翻译:预计<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/rba-deliver-25-bp-interest-rate-hike-nov-7-2023-11-03/">澳大利亚央行</a>将基准现金利率上调25个基点至4.35%，为2011年以来的最高水平，并打破连续四次会议搁置的局面。粘性通胀使澳大利亚货币市场保持鹰派倾向，预计明年至少还会加息四分之一个百分点。</p>   <p>Also on Tuesday the Bank of Korea publishes the minutes from its last policy meeting, while on the data front consumer inflation figures from Taiwan and the Philippines, trade data from Taiwan, industrial production figures from Indonesia, and household spending figures from Japan are all on tap.翻译:同样在周二，韩国央行公布了上次政策会议纪要，而在数据方面，台湾和菲律宾的消费者通胀数据、台湾的贸易数据、印度尼西亚的工业生产数据以及日本的家庭支出数据都在公布。轻敲。</p>   <p>The big one, however, could be China's trade report for October. Steep year-on-year declines in imports and exports for most of this year - especially imports - have been a pretty good barometer of the overall economy's underlying weakness.翻译:然而，最重要的可能是中国十月份的贸易报告。今年大部分时间进出口同比大幅下降——尤其是进口——是整体经济潜在疲软的一个很好的晴雨表。</p>   <p>But a trough looks to have been reached, the trend is improving, and the economy grew faster than expected in the third quarter. China bulls will be hoping for more encouraging signs.翻译:但看起来已经触底，趋势正在改善，第三季度经济增长快于预期。看好中国的人士将希望看到更多令人鼓舞的迹象。</p>   <p>Skeptical foreign investors will need more than one month of slowing imports and exports decline though. Figures on Monday showed that China recorded its first-ever quarterly deficit in foreign direct investment (FDI) since China's foreign exchange regulator began compiling the data in 1998.翻译:不过，持怀疑态度的外国投资者需要一个多月的时间来减缓进出口下滑。周一的数据显示，自中国外汇监管机构自1998年开始编制数据以来，中国首次出现外国直接投资(FDI)季度赤字。</p>   <p>Here are key developments that could provide more direction to markets on Tuesday:翻译:以下是可能为周二市场提供更多方向的关键进展：</p>   <p>- Australia central bank policy meeting翻译:- 澳大利亚央行政策会议</p>   <p>- China trade (October)翻译:- 中国贸易（10月）</p>   <p>- Japan household spending (September)翻译:- 日本家庭支出（九月）</p>    <span>By Jamie McGeever; Editing by Deepa Babington翻译:作者：杰米·麦克吉弗；迪帕·巴宾顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 21:53:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">SNIOBS5TQFL53GNTQFB2R773LE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/global-markets-view-asia-graphics-pix-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jamie McGeever]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>ASIA (GRAPHICS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[路透调查显示中国10月份贸易下滑可能进一步缓解]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>China's exports likely fell more slowly for a third consecutive month in October, a Reuters poll showed, adding to signs that the economy is stabilising even if the trade performance remains weaker than it was before Beijing removed anti-COVID curbs.翻译:路透调查显示，中国10月份出口可能连续第三个月放缓，这进一步表明经济正在企稳，尽管贸易表现仍弱于北京取消新冠疫情限制措施之前。</p>   <p>Exports are expected to show a 3.3% fall in October from a year earlier, following a 6.2% drop in September, according to the median forecast of 34 economists polled.翻译:根据接受调查的 34 名经济学家的预测中位数，继 9 月份下降 6.2% 后，10 月份出口预计将同比下降 3.3%。</p>   <p>Recent economic indicators suggest the policy support measures introduced since June to shore up economic growth are beginning to take effect, although China's manufacturing activity unexpectedly contracted again last month.翻译:近期经济指标显示，尽管中国制造业活动上个月再次意外收缩，但自6月份以来出台的支持经济增长的政策支持措施已开始发挥作用。</p>   <p>Policymakers are contending with a domestic property crisis, high youth unemployment, depressed private sector confidence, a slowdown in global growth and Sino-U.S. tensions over trade technology and geopolitics.翻译:政策制定者正在应对国内房地产危机、青年失业率高、私营部门信心低迷、全球经济增长放缓以及中美在贸易技术和地缘政治方面的紧张局势。</p>   <p>As a result, analysts anticipate policymakers will have to introduce further stimulus measures to ensure the economy hits Beijing's annual growth target of around 5%, not least because trade remains weaker than during the pandemic when the government deployed strict curbs on the movement of people and goods. Those curbs were finally removed in December 2022.翻译:因此，分析人士预计，政策制定者将不得不采取进一步的刺激措施，以确保经济达到北京设定的 5% 左右的年度增长目标，尤其是因为贸易仍然弱于疫情期间，当时政府对人员流动和人员流动采取了严格限制。商品。这些限制最终于 2022 年 12 月取消。</p>   <p>Economists at BNP Paribas projected that exports fell by just 1% last month, while Barclays returned the most pessimistic forecast that outbound shipments fell by 5.5% in October compared with the same period a year earlier.翻译:法国巴黎银行经济学家预测上个月出口仅下降1%，而巴克莱银行则返回了最悲观的预测，即10月份出境货运量较去年同期下降5.5%。</p>   <p>Both new export and import orders shrank for an eighth consecutive month in October, a sub-index in the official purchasing managers' index survey showed, suggesting that manufacturers are still struggling for buyers overseas and ordering fewer components used in finished goods for re-export.翻译:官方采购经理人指数调查的一项分项指数显示，10月份新出口和进口订单连续第八个月萎缩，这表明制造商仍在为海外买家而苦苦挣扎，并且订购用于再出口的制成品的零部件数量减少。</p>   <p>Global trade activities, represented by the Baltic Dry Index, reported falling demand in October as it dropped to its lowest rate since December 2020, owing to congestion in North American and European ports.翻译:以波罗的海干散货指数为代表的全球贸易活动报告称，由于北美和欧洲港口拥堵，10月份需求下降，跌至2020年12月以来的最低水平。</p>   <p>But South Korean exports to China, a leading indicator of China's imports, fell at their slowest pace in 13 months in October, dropping 9.5% compared with the same period last year.翻译:但韩国对中国的出口（中国进口的领先指标）10月份的跌幅为13个月以来最慢，与去年同期相比下降了9.5%。</p>   <p>China's imports are expected to have shrunk by 4.8%, after dropping 6.2% in September, reflecting improving domestic demand.翻译:中国进口继 9 月份下降 6.2% 后，预计将萎缩 4.8%，反映出内需改善。</p>   <p>The median estimate in the poll indicated that China's trade surplus would increase, with analysts predicting it will come in at $82.00 billion, compared with $77.71 billion in September.翻译:调查的中值估计显示，中国的贸易顺差将增加，分析师预测其贸易顺差将达到 820 亿美元，而 9 月份为 777.1 亿美元。</p>   <p>China's trade data will be released on Tuesday.翻译:中国贸易数据将于周二公布。</p>    <span>Reporting by Joe Cash; Polling by Devayani Sathyan &amp; Sujith Pai in Bengaluru; Editing by Simon Cameron-Moore翻译:乔·卡什报道； Devayani Sathyan 和 Sujith Pai 在班加罗尔进行的民意调查；西蒙·卡梅伦-摩尔 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 18:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">VCH3DBPSCNLQBAVWWGG47IGRQA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-trade-slump-likely-eased-further-october-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Joe Cash]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/TRADE (POLL)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国财政部长耶伦将在亚太经合组织峰会前会见中国国务院副总理]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/PnrwiDL6nD2h27Fr_nO1pl0OXAk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4YZ6HUB2KJP3NHOPLUHJ7N2OLE.jpg" alt="Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen speaks on China at Johns Hopkins in Washington翻译:财政部长珍妮特·耶伦在华盛顿约翰·霍普金斯大学就中国发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen discusses "U.S.-China Economic Relationship" during a forum hosted by the Johns Hopkins University at the Nitze Building in Washington, U.S., April 20, 2023. REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger/File Photo翻译:2023 年 4 月 20 日，美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦在美国华盛顿尼茨大厦由约翰·霍普金斯大学主办的论坛上讨论“美中经济关系”。 REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/NjNqpuireLGpWmf0-t_AkRRFs14=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/N6FQQSPRK5LNTHIWC3KGYCQZ6U.jpg" alt="Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng in Beijing翻译:中国国务院副总理何立峰在北京" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng attends a joint press conference following the 10th China-EU High-Level Economic and Trade Dialogue at the Diaoyutai State Guesthouse in Beijing, China September 25, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo翻译:2023年9月25日，中国国务院副总理何立峰在中国北京钓鱼台国宾馆出席第十次中欧经贸高层对话后举行的联合新闻发布会。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen will meet with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng in San Francisco this week to try to deepen a fledgling economic dialogue between the world's two largest economies ahead of a U.S.-hosted summit of Pacific Rim leaders.翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦本周将在旧金山会见中国国务院副总理何立峰，试图在美国主办的环太平洋地区领导人峰会之前深化世界最大两个经济体之间刚刚起步的经济对话。</p>   <p>The Treasury said on Monday the Nov. 9-10 meetings will also convene the new economic and financial forums launched in October by the Treasury and China's finance ministry and central bank.翻译:美国财政部周一表示，11 月 9 日至 10 日的会议还将召开由美国财政部、中国财政部和央行于 10 月发起的新经济和金融论坛。</p>   <p>Yellen first met with He, China's new economic czar, in July, when she <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/yellen-says-china-us-have-significant-disagreements-that-must-be-communicated-2023-07-09/">visited Beijing</a> to try to stabilize a deteriorating U.S.-China relationship amid growing U.S. restrictions on sensitive technologies.翻译:耶伦于7月份首次会见了中国新任经济沙皇贺建奎，当时她<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/yellen-says-china-us-have-significant-disagreements-that-must-be-communicated-2023-07-09/">访问北京</a>，试图在美国对敏感技术限制日益严格的情况下稳定不断恶化的中美关系。</p>   <p>The San Francisco meetings will take place just before the Biden administration hosts ministers and leaders of Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation countries from Nov. 11-17 -- a gathering during which U.S. President Joe Biden is aiming to meet with Chinese President Xi Jinping.翻译:旧金山会议将在拜登政府于 11 月 11 日至 17 日接待亚太经济合作组织国家部长和领导人之前举行，美国总统乔·拜登计划在这次聚会期间会见中国国家主席习近平。</p>   <p>A senior U.S. Treasury official downplayed the idea that there would be specific "deliverables" from the Yellen-He meetings, saying it was not a "policy trade" situation "where we trade one thing for another."翻译:一位美国财政部高级官员淡化了耶伦与贺会议将产生具体“成果”的想法，称这不是“我们以一物换另一物”的“政策贸易”情况。</p>   <p>But the official said a key aim for Yellen was gaining a better understanding of how the new U.S.-China economic communication line will work, and how to make sure that "it is not vulnerable to shocks," adding that there will be more frequent interactions.翻译:但这位官员表示，耶伦的一个关键目标是更好地了解新的美中经济沟通渠道将如何运作，以及如何确保“它不易受到冲击”，并补充说，双方的互动将会更加频繁。</p>   <p>Yellen also is keen to discuss what steps Chinese officials are contemplating to support their flagging economic growth, and what circumstances might change their policy path.</p>    <h 1="">'NON-MARKET' TOOLS</h>  <p>Amid growing concerns that China will try to dump more manufactured goods on U.S. and global markets, Yellen is expected to warn He against using massive industrial subsidies to state firms and shutting U.S. companies out of domestic markets, the official said.翻译:这位官员表示，由于人们越来越担心中国将试图向美国和全球市场倾销更多制成品，预计耶伦将警告贺建奎不要对国有企业进行大规模工业补贴，并将美国企业拒之门外。</p>   <p>"This week, I will speak to my counterpart about our serious concerns with Beijing's unfair economic practices, including its large-scale use of non-market tools, its barriers to market access, and its coercive actions against U.S. firms in China," Yellen said in an <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2023/11/06/china-relationship-good-american-economy/" target="_blank">opinion piece</a> published by the Washington Post.翻译:耶伦表示：“本周，我将与我的同行谈论我们对北京不公平经济行为的严重关切，包括大规模使用非市场工具、市场准入壁垒以及对在华美国企业采取的强制行动。” 《华盛顿邮报》发表的一篇<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2023/11/06/china-relationship-good-american-economy/" target="_blank">评论文章</a>中说道。</p>   <p>She reiterated that the U.S. was seeking "healthy competition" with China and was not trying to "trigger a "disorderly wholesale private-sector pullback from China with actions to diversify supply chains and protect U.S. national security."翻译:她重申，美国正在寻求与中国的“良性竞争”，而不是试图“通过供应链多元化和保护美国国家安全的行动，引发“私营部门无序大规模撤出中国”。</p>   <p>A brief statement from a Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson said only that He would visit the U.S. from Nov. 8-12 at Yellen's invitation, describing him as China's "lead person for China-U.S. economic and trade affairs." It provided no details of any meetings.</p>    <h 1="">NOT S&amp;ED</h>  <p>The communications so far have helped U.S. officials to explain national security policies to counterparts in Beijing, including on export controls on sensitive technologies that could have military uses and restrictions on outbound U.S. investment to China.翻译:迄今为止的通信已帮助美国官员向北京同行解释国家安全政策，包括对可能用于军事用途的敏感技术的出口管制以及对美国对华投资的限制。</p>   <p>But Yellen said her engagement with He was not meant to reconstitute the broad, Obama-era U.S.-China Strategic and Economic Dialogue, which was widely criticized for its ineffectiveness.翻译:但耶伦表示，她与贺建奎的接触并不是为了重建奥巴马时代广泛的美中战略与经济对话，该对话因其无效而受到广泛批评。</p>   <p>Instead, Yellen said she was "focusing on specific, high-priority economic topics on which we can make tangible progress."翻译:相反，耶伦表示，她“专注于我们可以取得切实进展的具体、高度优先的经济主题”。</p>   <p>Among these are cooperating on global challenges such as tackling climate change, speeding debt relief to poor countries, and reducing illicit financial flows that support terrorism and the illegal drug trade.翻译:其中包括合作应对全球挑战，例如应对气候变化、加快减免穷国债务以及减少支持恐怖主义和非法毒品贸易的非法资金流动。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Lawder; Editing by Simon Cameron-Moore and Deepa Babington翻译:大卫·劳德报道；西蒙·卡梅伦-摩尔和迪帕·巴宾顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 18:11:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CJDERBLMHZOSRPOEZ6FGMK3GJQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-treasurys-yellen-meet-chinese-vice-premier-ahead-apec-summit-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Lawder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/YELLEN (UPDATE 2,PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[在预期的峰会之前，民意调查对拜登的解读比对中国习近平的解读更好]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lCQ72Nn45RmL3tG_0Hu_kWDYvNw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VZA4L2TMZ5KV7KRF2CALIQRA3A.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden departs Mass at St. Edmond's Catholic Church in Rehoboth Beach翻译:美国总统乔·拜登离开里霍博斯比奇圣埃德蒙天主教堂的弥撒" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden gives a thumbs-up in response to questions about Israel following Mass at St. Edmond's Catholic Church in Rehoboth Beach, Delaware, U.S., November 4, 2023. REUTERS/Ken Cedeno/File Photo翻译:2023年11月4日，美国特拉华州里霍博斯比奇圣埃德蒙天主教堂举行弥撒后，美国总统乔·拜登在回答有关以色列的问题时竖起大拇指。路透社/肯·塞德诺/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/atW1y53zdUYdycNArASc6RypFQo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3ZWEI6Y3BRPS3GW4WZC2YWEZP4.jpg" alt="BRICS Summit in Johannesburg翻译:金砖国家领导人约翰内斯堡峰会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>President of China Xi Jinping attends the plenary session during the 2023 BRICS Summit at the Sandton Convention Centre in Johannesburg, South Africa on August 23, 2023. GIANLUIGI GUERCIA/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:2023 年 8 月 23 日，中国国家主席习近平出席在南非约翰内斯堡桑顿会议中心举行的 2023 年金砖国家峰会全体会议。 GIANLUIGI GUERCIA/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>Ahead of an expected meeting between U.S. President Joe Biden and China's President Xi Jinping next week, a U.S. think tank says data it has collected from two dozen countries shows the American leader is winning the battle for public opinion.翻译:在美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平下周预计会晤之前，一家美国智库表示，从二十几个国家收集的数据显示，这位美国领导人正在赢得舆论之战。</p>   <p>The Pew Research Center says it surveyed 30,861 adults in 24 countries between Feb. 20 and May 22 about their attitudes to the world's two largest economies and their leadership.翻译:皮尤研究中心表示，它在 2 月 20 日至 5 月 22 日期间对 24 个国家的 30,861 名成年人进行了调查，了解他们对世界最大的两个经济体及其领导力的态度。</p>   <p>"People in 23 countries tend to see U.S. President Joe Biden more positively than Chinese President Xi Jinping," it said in a <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/global/2023/11/06/comparing-views-of-the-u-s-and-china-in-24-countries/" target="_blank">report</a> released on Monday. "A median of 54% have confidence in Biden to do the right thing regarding world affairs, compared with 19% who say the same of Xi."翻译:该组织在周一发布的一份<a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/global/2023/11/06/comparing-views-of-the-u-s-and-china-in-24-countries/" target="_blank">报告</a>中表示，“23个国家的人们对美国总统乔·拜登的看法往往比中国国家主席习近平更积极”。 “中位数为 54% 的人相信拜登会在国际事务上做正确的事情，而对习近平持同样看法的人为 19%。”</p>   <p>Pew said it did not ask people in the United States about their confidence in Biden's handling of world affairs and says it is no longer able to conduct independent surveys in China, so does not survey there.翻译:皮尤表示，它没有询问美国民众对拜登处理国际事务的信心，并表示无法再在中国进行独立调查，因此不会在中国进行调查。</p>   <p>The countries surveyed were the United States, Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Britain, Canada, France, Germany, Greece, Hungary, India, Indonesia, Israel, Italy, Japan, Kenya, Mexico, the Netherlands, Nigeria, Poland, South Africa, South Korea, Spain and Sweden.翻译:接受调查的国家包括美国、阿根廷、澳大利亚、巴西、英国、加拿大、法国、德国、希腊、匈牙利、印度、印度尼西亚、以色列、意大利、日本、肯尼亚、墨西哥、荷兰、尼日利亚、波兰、南非、韩国、西班牙和瑞典。</p>   <p>Pew said its findings showed China was seen unfavorably in North America, Europe, and Asia but more favorably in Africa and Latin America.翻译:皮尤研究中心表示，其调查结果显示，中国在北美、欧洲和亚洲的形象较差，但在非洲和拉丁美洲的形象较好。</p>   <p>The gap in favor of Biden tended to be quite large in high-income contries, but even in most middle-income countries more had confidence in Biden than Xi, with Indonesia and Hungary being notable exceptions. The leaders received nearly identical marks in those countries, Pew said.翻译:在高收入国家，支持拜登的差距往往相当大，但即使在大多数中等收入国家，对拜登的信心也高于对习近平的信心，印度尼西亚和匈牙利是明显的例外。皮尤表示，两位领导人在这些国家获得的分数几乎相同。</p>   <p>"This year, overall views of the United States are much more positive than views of China in most places surveyed," it said.翻译:报告称：“今年，大多数受访地区对美国的总体看法比对中国的看法要积极得多。”</p>   <p>"A median of 59% offer positive evaluations of the U.S., compared with a median of 28% who say the same of China."翻译:“对美国持积极评价的中位数为 59%，而对中国持积极评价的中位数为 28%。”</p>   <p>Pew said that in nearly two decades of its favorability polling, views of the countries have fluctuated alongside views of their leaders, but those of the U.S. under Biden had rebounded dramatically in many of the countries surveyed, while those of China were at their most negative levels.翻译:皮尤研究中心表示，在近二十年的好感度民意调查中，各国的看法随着其领导人的看法而波动，但在许多接受调查的国家中，拜登领导下的美国的好感度大幅反弹，而中国的好感度则处于最负面的时期。水平。</p>   <p>While majorities in most countries saw both the U.S. and China as prone to interfere in the affairs of other countries, the U.S. was almost always more likely to be described that way.翻译:尽管大多数国家的大多数人都认为美国和中国都倾向于干涉其他国家的事务，但美国几乎总是更有可能被这样描述。</p>   <p>However, the U.S. "gets higher marks for contributing to global peace and stability than China," the survey said.翻译:然而，调查称，美国“在对全球和平与稳定的贡献方面获得比中国更高的分数”。</p>   <p>"On balance, views of the U.S. are much more positive than views of China," Pew said.翻译:皮尤表示：“总的来说，美国的看法比中国的看法积极得多。”</p>   <p>Biden and Xi are expected to meet on the sidelines of the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">APEC summit</a> in San Francisco next week, although China has yet to confirm this, and a senior <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/white-house-aims-biden-xi-meeting-san-francisco-november-2023-10-31/">Biden administration official</a> said last week important details had still to be hammered out.翻译:拜登和习近平预计将于下周在旧金山举行的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">亚太经合组织峰会</a>期间会面，尽管中国尚未证实这一点， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/white-house-aims-biden-xi-meeting-san-francisco-november-2023-10-31/">拜登政府一名高级官员</a>上周表示，重要细节仍有待敲定。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Brunnstrom; editing by Jonathan Oatis翻译:大卫·布伦斯特罗姆报道；乔纳森·奥蒂斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 16:03:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ANZJVMDOENL2RGBKJWKUHJN7QM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/poll-makes-better-reading-biden-than-chinas-xi-before-expected-summit-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Brunnstrom]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/SURVEY (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着紧张局势缓和，中国和澳大利亚同意翻开新的一页]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Xi: China, Australia should develop strategic partnership</li>  <li>Both sides should build up mutual trust, Xi says</li>  <li>Albanese: Strong relations 'will be beneficial into the future'</li>  <li>Albanese: Recognise differences but also 'mutual benefit'</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>习近平：中澳要发展战略伙伴关系</li><li>习近平：双方要增进互信</li><li>阿尔巴尼斯：牢固的关系“将有益于未来”</li><li> Albanese：承认差异但也“互惠互利”</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Ekmz-7DesXBcNOQSLUx46KJ3Vh8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GGPNBVIRL5MJRFRGU6S5MBJHYA.jpg" alt="Australia's Albanese retraces historic Beijing walk on visit to mend ties翻译:澳大利亚阿尔巴内斯访华重回历史性的北京徒步之旅，以修复两国关系" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese speaks during the bilateral meeting with Indonesia's President Joko Widodo on the sidelines of the 43rd Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) Summit in Jakarta, Indonesia, 07 September 2023. BAGUS INDAHONO/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞于 2023 年 9 月 7 日在印度尼西亚雅加达举行的第 43 届东南亚国家联盟（东盟）峰会期间与印度尼西亚总统佐科·维多多举行双边会晤。BAGUS INDAHONO/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/FQjrKue3GW6l3X6W6yqHULdwsZ4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4JW3DR2IRVICBNMM6UDIV6R2HI.jpg" alt="Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese meets with China's President Xi Jinping at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内斯在北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese shakes hands with China's President Xi Jinping at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS  翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞于 2023 年 11 月 6 日在中国北京人民大会堂与中国国家主席习近平握手。AAP 图片/Lukas Coch via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/S8RGQ7qV6WfJnR89PdexwT-U_S0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TDZTYFX6U5OQLPNKE4LKERU4IA.jpg" alt="Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese meets with China's President Xi Jinping at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内斯在北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese meets with China's President Xi Jinping at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内斯在北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS  </figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/dQgM15EWA12fyLiiD8nYejdP4_I=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PRPVDRTVONJ3HKTVNPY5QNVB5A.jpg" alt="Australia’s Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia’s Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛, China, November 6, 2023.  AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS  </figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/BJvp0NolcJPLPg1C_xJN2LhRMjs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DFQLHIG7BNL6TBM5YVFUZDTQMQ.jpg" alt="Australia’s Foreign Minister Penny Wong and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese attend a press conference after visiting the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤和总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛后出席新闻发布会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia’s Foreign Minister Penny Wong and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese attend a press conference after visiting the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤和总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛后出席新闻发布会, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS  </figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/VKg2-1veHY4AQfmJKxzSqP7DmMo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SFJSUHDLI5MSNFJLONLIEHKT54.jpg" alt="Australia’s Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Foreign Minister Penny Wong visit the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博尼斯和外交部长黄英贤参观北京天坛" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia’s Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Foreign Minister Penny Wong Penny Wong visit the Temple of Heaven in Beijing, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS 翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博尼斯和外交部长黄英贤于 2023 年 11 月 6 日参观中国北京天坛。AAP 图片/Lukas Coch via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/VOb6rBXaVW1DicsQpknPwltFc_g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FPP3E7STCVHSPF2KCLMPXT7QSA.JPG" alt="Australia’s Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia’s Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>                         <p>President Xi Jinping said on Monday stable ties between China and Australia served each other's interests and both should expand their cooperation, sending a clear signal that Beijing was ready to move on from recent tensions.翻译:习近平主席周一表示，中澳之间稳定的关系符合彼此的利益，双方应扩大合作，发出明确信号，表明北京已准备好摆脱近期的紧张局势。</p>   <p>China and Australia should promote the development of their strategic partnership as they build up mutual understanding and trust, Xi told Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese, the first Australian leader to visit Beijing since 2016, at the Great Hall of the People in the heart of the Chinese capital.翻译:习近平在北京人民大会堂对澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞说，中澳两国要推动战略伙伴关系发展，增进相互了解和信任。他是自2016年以来第一位访问北京的澳大利亚领导人。中国资本。</p>   <p>A strong relationship "will be beneficial into the future," Albanese told Xi in their second face-to-face talks in a year, a meeting that lasted more than an hour.翻译:阿尔巴尼斯在一年内第二次面对面会谈中对习近平表示，牢固的关系“对未来有利”，这次会议持续了一个多小时。</p>   <p>For decades, China and Australia built a relationship on trade, with Beijing becoming Canberra's biggest commercial partner with purchases of Australian food and natural resources.翻译:几十年来，中国和澳大利亚建立了贸易关系，北京通过购买澳大利亚食品和自然资源成为堪培拉最大的商业伙伴。</p>   <p>But ties soured after Australia <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australia-china-rocky-road-back-trade-visits-2023-11-03/">in 2017</a> accused China of meddling in its politics. The following year, Australia banned equipment from Chinese tech giant Huawei Technologies Co (HWT.UL) for its 5G network out of national security fears.翻译:但<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australia-china-rocky-road-back-trade-visits-2023-11-03/">2017年</a>澳大利亚指责中国干涉其政治后，两国关系恶化。次年，出于国家安全担忧，澳大利亚禁止将中国科技巨头华为技术有限公司（HWT.UL）的设备用于其 5G 网络。</p>   <p>An Australian call in 2020 for an international inquiry into the origin of the COVID pandemic, which emerged in the Chinese city of Wuhan in late 2019, infuriated Beijing, which responded with blocks on various Australian imports.翻译:2020 年，澳大利亚呼吁对 2019 年底在中国武汉出现的新冠病毒大流行的起源进行国际调查，此举激怒了北京，北京方面以封锁澳大利亚多种进口产品作为回应。</p>   <p>As relations deteriorated, China warned its students against studying in Australia, citing racist incidents, threatening a multi-billion-dollar education market.翻译:随着关系恶化，中国以种族主义事件为由警告学生不要去澳大利亚学习，这威胁到数十亿美元的教育市场。</p>   <p>Earlier on Monday, Albanese stopped by Beijing's iconic Temple of Heaven and posed for a photograph at the circular Echo Wall where Australia's then prime minister, Gough Whitlam, stood in 1973, a year after the two countries established ties.翻译:周一早些时候，阿尔巴尼斯在北京标志性的天坛停留，并在圆形回音墙前拍照留念，1973 年，即两国建交一年后，时任澳大利亚总理高夫·惠特拉姆 (Gough Whitlam) 曾站过这里。</p>      <p>"In China we often say that when drinking water, we should not forget those who dug the well," Xi said. "The Chinese people will not forget Prime Minister Whitlam for digging the well for us."</p>    <h 1="">'VERY POSITIVE'</h>  <p>Albanese took steps to stabilise relations after he became prime minister in May last year and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-looks-forward-constructive-dialogue-with-china-pm-albanese-2022-11-15/">met Xi</a> on the sidelines of a G20 summit in Indonesia in November.翻译:阿尔巴内斯去年5月就任总理后采取了稳定关系的措施，并于11月在印度尼西亚G20峰会期间<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-looks-forward-constructive-dialogue-with-china-pm-albanese-2022-11-15/">会见了习近平</a>。</p>   <p>China soon began lowering trade barriers, allowing imports of coal in January and ending tariffs on barley in August. Last month, Beijing agreed to review dumping tariffs of 218% on Australian wine.翻译:中国很快开始降低贸易壁垒，一月份允许进口煤炭，八月份取消了大麦关税。上个月，北京同意对澳大利亚葡萄酒征收218%的倾销关税进行复审。</p>   <p>"I noted very much unimpeded trade was in the interest of both countries, was good for Chinese consumers as well as Australian exporters," Albanese told reporters after the meeting. "He certainly agreed that Australian wine is good."翻译:阿尔巴内塞在会后对记者表示：“我指出，畅通无阻的贸易符合两国利益，对中国消费者和澳大利亚出口商都有好处。” “他当然同意澳大利亚葡萄酒很好。”</p>   <p>China's January-September imports from Australia increased 8.1% from a year earlier to $116.9 billion, Chinese customs data show. In 2022, imports plunged 12.7% to $142.1 billion.翻译:中国海关数据显示，1-9月中国从澳大利亚进口同比增长8.1%，达到1169亿美元。 2022年，进口下降12.7%至1421亿美元。</p>   <p>The meeting was "very positive", Albanese said, adding that he had invited Xi to visit Australia.翻译:阿尔巴内斯说，这次会面“非常积极”，并补充说他邀请习近平访问澳大利亚。</p>   <p>"Both of us certainly agreed that we shouldn't be defined by our differences, recognise that they are there, but also recognise the mutual benefit that we have."翻译:“我们双方当然都同意，我们不应该被分歧所定义，认识到分歧的存在，但也认识到我们拥有的共同利益。”</p>   <p>Obstacles remain in their relationship.翻译:他们的关系中仍然存在障碍。</p>   <p>Australian backing of a U.N. ruling rejecting China's territorial claims in the <a href="https://www.un.org/depts/los/clcs_new/submissions_files/mys_12_12_2019/2020_07_23_AUS_NV_UN_001_OLA-2020-00373.pdf" target="_blank">South China Sea</a> has angered Beijing, which has told Canberra the issue is not its concern.翻译:澳大利亚支持联合国拒绝中国在<a href="https://www.un.org/depts/los/clcs_new/submissions_files/mys_12_12_2019/2020_07_23_AUS_NV_UN_001_OLA-2020-00373.pdf" target="_blank">南海的</a>领土主张的裁决激怒了北京，北京已告诉堪培拉这个问题不是它关心的问题。</p>   <p>Australia says the South China Sea is an important passageway for its trade with Japan and South Korea.翻译:澳大利亚表示，南海是其与日本和韩国贸易的重要通道。</p>   <p>Beijing's projection of power among <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/three-pacific-islands-say-their-leaders-will-skip-annual-bloc-meeting-2023-11-06/">Pacific island nations</a> also alarmed Australia, while Canberra's <a href="https://www.defense.gov/News/News-Stories/Article/Article/3407275/us-partnership-with-uk-australia-enhances-security/" target="_blank">security alliance</a> with the United States and Britain in the Indo-Pacific - known as AUKUS - stoked Chinese worries about containment.翻译:北京在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/three-pacific-islands-say-their-leaders-will-skip-annual-bloc-meeting-2023-11-06/">太平洋岛国</a>之间的力量投射也令澳大利亚感到震惊，而堪培拉与美国和英国在印度-太平洋地区的<a href="https://www.defense.gov/News/News-Stories/Article/Article/3407275/us-partnership-with-uk-australia-enhances-security/" target="_blank">安全联盟</a>（称为AUKUS）则引发了中国对遏制的担忧。</p>   <p>"AUKUS didn't come up explicitly. We discussed, though, regional stability," Albanese said, without giving specifics. "I spoke about guardrails and military-to-military cooperation between the United States and China. That's important."翻译:“AUKUS 没有明确提出。不过，我们讨论了地区稳定，”阿尔巴内塞说，但没有透露具体细节。 “我谈到了美中之间的护栏和军事合作。这很重要。”</p>   <p>Albanese also raised the case of Australian writer <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/sons-australian-yang-hengjun-ask-his-release-ahead-pms-visit-china-2023-10-31/">Yang Hengjun</a>, who has been jailed in Beijing for four years on espionage charges.翻译:阿尔巴尼斯还提到了澳大利亚作家<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/sons-australian-yang-hengjun-ask-his-release-ahead-pms-visit-china-2023-10-31/">杨恒均</a>的案件，杨恒均因间谍罪名在北京被判入狱四年。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ryan Woo; additional reporting by Kirsty Needham in Sydney; editing by Robert Birsel and Mark Heinrich翻译:瑞恩·吴 (Ryan Woo) 报道； Kirsty Needham 在悉尼的补充报道；罗伯特·伯塞尔和马克·海因里希编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 15:39:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZMLIPMHVCBJRFMVIRMRE52W2CM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-albanese-retraces-historic-beijing-walk-visit-mend-ties-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ryan Woo]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA/ (UPDATE 2, TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国东北地面航班遭遇暴风雪，学校被迫停课]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/zgU-g3ojXvNwkmwM7rgOIF3mpNM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PA2OE5S5SROEDFCEXV2LUN2UJU.jpg" alt="Snow removal vehicles move on a street amid a blizzard in Harbin翻译:哈尔滨暴风雪中，除雪车在街道上行驶" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Snow removal vehicles move on a street amid a blizzard in Harbin翻译:哈尔滨暴风雪中，除雪车在街道上行驶, Heilongjiang province, China November 6, 2023. cnsphoto via REUTERS翻译:2023年11月6日，中国黑龙江省哈尔滨市，除雪车在暴风雪中在街道上行驶。 cnsphoto via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>       <p>Unseasonably cold weather and blizzards hit northeast China on Monday, forcing hundreds of flights to be rescheduled and closing schools as several cities issued heightened weather alerts and warned people to stay indoors.翻译:周一，反常的寒冷天气和暴风雪袭击了中国东北地区，迫使数百个航班重新安排时间，并关闭了学校，一些城市发布了加强的天气警报并警告人们留在室内。</p>   <p>With snowfall of as much as 25 centimetres, over 90% of expressway entrances in Jilin province had been closed as of 7 p.m. (1100GMT), state television CCTV said.翻译:据中央电视台报道，截至晚上 7 点（格林威治标准时间 1100），吉林省 90% 以上的高速公路入口已关闭，降雪量高达 25 厘米。</p>   <p>In the country's northernmost province Heilongjiang, the local railway operator halted 51 passenger lines over safety concerns.翻译:在中国最北部的省份黑龙江，当地铁路运营商出于安全考虑暂停了 51 条客运线路。</p>   <p>A gymnasium in Heilongjiang's Jiamusi city collapsed, trapping three inside, according to CCTV.翻译:据央视报道，黑龙江佳木斯市一座体育馆倒塌，三人被困在里面。</p>   <p>State-run Jimu News said there were children at the venue at the time of the incident. It is unclear if the collapse was related to the snowfall, the report said. A rescue operation is underway.翻译:国营吉姆新闻网称，事发时现场有儿童。报告称，目前尚不清楚塌方是否与降雪有关。救援行动正在进行中。</p>   <p>Schools, kindergartens, and off-campus training institutions in most parts of Harbin, capital of Heilongjiang, will remain suspended on Tuesday, after they were cancelled on Monday, CCTV said.翻译:据央视报道，黑龙江省省会哈尔滨市大部分地区的学校、幼儿园和校外培训机构继周一停课后，将于周二继续停课。</p>   <p>China's national weather forecaster renewed its orange blizzard alert - the second highest tier of its color-coded warning system - at 6 p.m, as more snow is expected from Monday night to Tuesday in parts of Jilin and Heilongjiang.翻译:中国国家气象局于下午 6 点再次发布暴风雪橙色警报，这是其颜色编码警报系统的第二高级别，预计从周一晚间到周二，吉林和黑龙江部分地区将有更多降雪。</p>   <p>Earlier on Monday, 405 flights were cancelled at Harbin Taiping International Airport, according to data from third-party travel app Flight Master.翻译:根据第三方旅游应用飞行大师的数据，周一早些时候，哈尔滨太平国际机场取消了 405 架航班。</p>   <p>Many flights were also cancelled in Jilin and Liaoning provinces, and in the Inner Mongolia region, Flight Master showed.翻译:Flight Master显示，吉林省、辽宁省以及内蒙古地区的许多航班也被取消。</p>   <p>Video from a local newspaper showed travellers stranded in a railway station as heavy snow lashed Jilin's Changchun city, with some trains from the city suspended.翻译:当地报纸的视频显示，大雪袭击吉林省长春市，旅客被困在火车站，部分列车停运。</p>   <p>China's weather authority warned of a drastic drop in temperature in coming days, along with blizzards, state media reported.翻译:据官方媒体报道，中国气象部门警告未来几天气温将急剧下降，并伴有暴风雪。</p>   <p>"The season changed outside overnight," a netizen from Heilongjiang complained on Weibo, China's popular social media platform.翻译:“外面的季节一夜之间就变了，”一位黑龙江网友在中国热门社交媒体平台微博上抱怨道。</p>   <p>Provinces and cities upgraded weather response protocols, with heavy snowfall expected in parts of Inner Mongolia, and Hebei, Jilin and Liaoning provinces, China Daily reported.翻译:据《中国日报》报道，各省市升级了天气应对方案，预计内蒙古部分地区以及河北、吉林和辽宁省将出现大雪。</p>   <p>On Monday, Inner Mongolia, and Liaoning and Jilin provinces also suspended schools.翻译:周一，内蒙古、辽宁和吉林省也停课。</p>   <p>Late on Sunday, Heilongjiang issued a red alert - the country's highest weather advisory - as cities in the province were expected to see 20 mm (0.787 inches) to 40 mm (1.575 inches) of blizzard precipitation into Monday evening, China Daily reported.翻译:据《中国日报》报道，周日晚间，黑龙江省发布了红色预警——该国最高级别的天气预警——预计该省各城市周一晚间将出现 20 毫米（0.787 英寸）至 40 毫米（1.575 英寸）的暴风雪降水。</p>   <p>The Central Meteorological Observatory said some areas could see 8-10 cm (3.14 to 3.94 inches) of snow and temperatures in many regions would drop sharply.翻译:中央气象台表示，部分地区可能会出现8-10厘米（3.14至3.94英寸）的降雪，许多地区气温将急剧下降。</p>   <p>In Harbin, social media video footage showed residents battling gale force winds and sliding and stumbling as they made their way down icy streets.翻译:在哈尔滨，社交媒体视频显示，居民在冰冷的街道上与强风搏斗，滑倒、绊倒。</p>   <p>The cold forced governments in Beijing and Tianjin to make preparations to supply heat earlier than usual, according to city government notices.翻译:据北京市政府通知，寒冷迫使北京和天津政府比平常更早做好供暖准备。</p>   <p>Over the past week, northern China has experienced unseasonably odd contrasts in weather from smog to logging the second-warmest <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-set-abrupt-switch-warm-freezing-weather-year-extremes-2023-11-03/">October</a> in decades and then a sharp drop in temperatures over the weekend.翻译:过去一周，中国北方经历了反常的反常天气，从雾霾到数十年来第二热的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-set-abrupt-switch-warm-freezing-weather-year-extremes-2023-11-03/">十月</a>，再到周末气温急剧下降。</p>   <p>The Central Meteorological Administration said most of the northeast is expected to see temperatures dive to single digits or below freezing this week as cold air moves east and south.翻译:中央气象局表示，随着冷空气向东和向南移动，预计本周东北大部分地区气温将降至个位数或零度以下。</p>    <span>Reporting by Bernard Orr, Ella Cao; Additional reporting by Judy Hua, Sophie Yu, Ethan Wang and Shanghai newsroom; Editing by Raju Gopalakrishnan and Christina Fincher翻译:伯纳德·奥尔、艾拉·曹报道； Judy Hua、Sophie Yu、Ethan Wang 和上海新闻编辑室的补充报道；编辑：拉朱·戈帕拉克里希南和克里斯蒂娜·芬奇</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 14:26:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">INKIZIDXJVOUNIAXH2DBBA3KZM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/northeast-china-blizzards-cancel-flights-force-school-closures-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Bernard Orr, Ella Cao]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ASIA</category>
                
                <category>WEATHER/CHINA (UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[澳大利亚总理阿尔巴内斯表示与中国沟通很重要]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/EuBKraZQBTo4F9DeYv0y1XtrhCE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YOTL6SMEQFKZHGACEZ3TSSZN7A.jpg" alt="Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese meets with China's President Xi Jinping at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内斯在北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese meets with China's President Xi Jinping at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内斯在北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS </figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/mfI92R8j9gHGx_cxNshbSGuhgxo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BWIDIGQHGVIMLGKR77UWEMGVN4.jpg" alt="Australia’s Foreign Minister Penny Wong and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese attend a news conference after visiting the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤和总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛后出席新闻发布会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia’s Foreign Minister Penny Wong and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese attend a news conference after visiting the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤和总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛后出席新闻发布会, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS  翻译:2023 年 11 月 6 日，澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤和总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观中国北京天坛后出席新闻发布会。AAP 图片/Lukas Coch via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>               <p>Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese told Chinese President Xi Jinping in Beijing on Monday that Australia has an interest in the continued stable growth of China's economy and its ongoing engagement with the world.翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞周一在北京对中国国家主席习近平表示，中国经济的持续稳定增长及其与世界的持续接触符合澳大利亚的利益。</p>   <p>In opening remarks as the two leaders met at the Great Hall of the People, Albanese said a strong relationship between the two countries was "beneficial into the future".翻译:两国领导人在人民大会堂会面时，阿尔巴尼斯在开幕致辞中表示，两国之间牢固的关系“有利于未来”。</p>   <p>"Australia, along with other countries in the region, has an interest in continued stable growth in the Chinese economy, and its ongoing engagement with the world ," he said, according to an official transcript from the Australian Prime Minister's Office.翻译:根据澳大利亚总理办公室的官方记录，他表示：“澳大利亚与该地区其他国家一样，对中国经济的持续稳定增长及其与世界的持续接触感兴趣。”</p>   <p>Albanese said it was "important that we have communication" where differences arise.翻译:阿尔巴内塞表示，在出现分歧时“保持沟通非常重要”。</p>    <span>Reporting by Kirsty Needham; Editing by Christian Schmollinger翻译:科斯蒂·李约瑟报道；克里斯蒂安·施莫林格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 12:43:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">G3KIRBWVRNPXJDTYY3ZGWKGICU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-pm-albanese-says-important-have-communication-with-china-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA/ALBANESE (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[欧盟布雷顿要求 TikTok 首席执行官“不遗余力”打击虚假信息]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/xepFNLAUSk5atorvki42ObrDC_s=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WEI3DOYNBJPOPFI5HKFTAWPNQ4.jpg" alt="A TikTok logo is displayed on a smartphone in this illustration翻译:在此插图中，智能手机上显示 TikTok 徽标" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A TikTok logo is displayed on a smartphone in this illustration翻译:在此插图中，智能手机上显示 TikTok 徽标 taken January 6, 2020. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration//File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/LneUP-ucxWpFPR28eFOWHX7ROOY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/T4SQAZVLZZJXXJ7Z72OK6ZN6IM.jpg" alt="European flags fly outside the European Commission headquarters in Brussels翻译:布鲁塞尔欧盟委员会总部外飘扬着欧洲旗帜" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>European flags fly outside the European Commission headquarters in Brussels翻译:布鲁塞尔欧盟委员会总部外飘扬着欧洲旗帜, Belgium September 20, 2023. REUTERS/Yves Herman/File Photo翻译:2023 年 9 月 20 日，欧洲旗帜在比利时布鲁塞尔欧盟委员会总部外飘扬。REUTERS/Yves Herman/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>TikTok must "spare no effort" to counter the spread of disinformation on the short video sharing app, EU industry chief Thierry Breton told the company's CEO on Monday, as the European Union steps up its efforts to curb the powers of Big Tech.翻译:欧盟行业负责人蒂埃里·布雷顿(Thierry Breton)周一对TikTok首席执行官表示，随着欧盟加大力度遏制大型科技公司的权力，TikTok必须“不遗余力”打击短视频共享应用程序上虚假信息的传播。</p>   <p>Breton last month gave TikTok, owned by China's ByteDance, an Oct. 25 deadline to provide information on its crisis response measures and also ordered the company to provide details by Nov. 8 on how it protects the integrity of elections and minors online on its platform.翻译:布雷顿上个月给中国字节跳动旗下的 TikTok 规定了 10 月 25 日的最后期限，要求其提供有关其危机应对措施的信息，并命令该公司在 11 月 8 日之前提供有关如何在其平台上保护选举和未成年人在线的完整性的详细信息。</p>   <p>The European Commissioner pointed to changes on TikTok's platform in the past months with new features to protect users and investments made in content moderation and trust and safety.翻译:欧盟专员指出，过去几个月 TikTok 平台发生了变化，推出了保护用户的新功能以及在内容审核、信任和安全方面的投资。</p>   <p>"My services and I are now investigating whether this is enough to ensure compliance with the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/big-tech-braces-roll-out-eus-digital-services-act-2023-08-24/">DSA (Digital Services Act)</a>," Breton told Reuters in written comments after a video call with TikTok CEO Shou Zi Chew.翻译:在与 TikTok 首席执行官 Shou Zi Chew 进行视频通话后，布雷顿在书面评论中对路透社表示：“我和我的服务部门现在正在调查这是否足以确保遵守<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/big-tech-braces-roll-out-eus-digital-services-act-2023-08-24/">DSA（数字服务法）</a> 。”</p>   <p>"Because now more than ever, we must spare no effort to protect our citizens – especially children and teenagers – against illegal content and disinformation," he said.翻译:他说：“因为现在我们比以往任何时候都更必须不遗余力地保护我们的公民，特别是儿童和青少年，免受非法内容和虚假信息的侵害。”</p>   <p>TikTok Public Policy Director Caroline Greer said in a post on social media platform X that the company was pleased that Breton recognised its compliance efforts.翻译:TikTok 公共政策总监 Caroline Greer 在社交媒体平台 X 上发帖表示，公司很高兴 Breton 认可其合规努力。</p>   <p>The DSA requires large online platforms to do more to tackle illegal and harmful online content on their platforms. It is one of a slew of recent EU rules aimed at reining in the power of Big Tech.翻译:DSA 要求大型网络平台采取更多措施，打击其平台上的非法和有害网络内容。这是欧盟最近出台的一系列旨在限制大型科技力量的规则之一。</p>   <p>Chew is scheduled to meet EU Vice-President for Values and Transparency, Vera Jourova, and EU antitrust head Didier Ryenders in Brussels on Tuesday.翻译:周计划于周二在布鲁塞尔会见欧盟负责价值观和透明度的副主席维拉·朱罗娃（Vera Jourova）和欧盟反垄断负责人迪迪埃·赖恩德斯（Didier Ryenders）。</p>    <span>Reporting by Foo Yun Chee; Editing by Sharon Singleton翻译:符润芝报道；莎朗·辛格尔顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 12:23:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TSVYYLFLKZL4LFJH4SEZMM7IKM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/eus-breton-tells-tiktok-ceo-ramp-up-efforts-against-disinformation-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Foo Yun Chee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>EU</category>
                
                <category>TIKTOK/ (UPDATE 2,PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[欧盟要求阿里巴巴速卖通提供打击非法产品措施的细节]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/FfRoRSVsGfWQ4QnmsEq_y1xiCMc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MP6H46MMKNPKRH2S6WLECHKTOA.jpg" alt="Illustration shows AliExpress logo翻译:插图显示 AliExpress 徽标" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Shopping trolley is seen in front of AliExpress logo in this illustration, July 24, 2022. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张 2022 年 7 月 24 日的插图中，购物车位于全球速卖通标志前。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>The European Commission on Monday ordered Alibaba's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">(9988.HK)</a> AliExpress to provide information on how it tackles illegal products, such as counterfeit goods, sold on its platform by Nov. 27 or face an investigation that could result in fines.翻译:欧盟委员会周一责令阿里巴巴<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">（9988.HK）</a>速卖通在 11 月 27 日之前提供有关如何处理其平台上销售的非法产品（例如假冒商品）的信息，否则将面临可能导致罚款的调查。</p>   <p>The EU executive said it had sent a request for information to AliExpress in line with newly adopted EU rules called the Digital Services Act (DSA), which requires Big Tech to do more to counter illegal and harmful content on their platforms.翻译:欧盟高管表示，已根据欧盟新通过的《数字服务法》(DSA) 规则向全球速卖通发出信息请求，该法案要求大型科技公司采取更多措施打击其平台上的非法和有害内容。</p>   <p>The Commission said it wants to know what measures AliExpress has taken to comply with DSA rules against the dissemination and sale of illegal products online, such as fake medicines.翻译:欧盟委员会表示，它想知道全球速卖通采取了哪些措施来遵守 DSA 规则，打击在线传播和销售假药等非法产品。</p>   <p>It said AliExpress must provide the requested information by Nov. 27 after which the Commission will assess its next steps.翻译:它表示速卖通必须在 11 月 27 日之前提供所要求的信息，之后委员会将评估其下一步行动。</p>   <p>"It (DSA) is also there to ensure removal of illegal or unsafe products sold in the EU via e-commerce platforms, including the growing number of fake and potentially life-threatening medicines and pharmaceuticals sold online," EU industry chief Thierry Breton said in a statement.翻译:欧盟行业负责人蒂埃里·布雷顿 (Thierry Breton) 表示：“DSA 还旨在确保清除通过电子商务平台在欧盟销售的非法或不安全产品，包括网上销售的假冒药品和可能危及生命的药品数量不断增加。”在一份声明中。</p>   <p>Breton has in recent weeks sent similar requests for information to Elon Musk's X platform, Meta Platforms <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/META.O" target="_blank">(META.O)</a> and TikTok, asking what they are doing to fight the spread of disinformation.翻译:最近几周，布雷顿向埃隆·马斯克的 X 平台、Meta Platforms <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/META.O" target="_blank">(META.O)</a>和 TikTok 发出了类似的信息请求，询问他们正在采取哪些措施来打击虚假信息的传播。</p>    <span>Reporting by Foo Yun Chee; Editing by Sharon Singleton翻译:符润芝报道；莎朗·辛格尔顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 11:59:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">IIJKPTSSV5PHBDCXQ2SA3VPA44</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/eu-asks-alibabas-aliexpress-information-illegal-products-sold-its-platform-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Foo Yun Chee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>EU</category>
                
                <category>ALIBABA/ALIEXPRESS (UPDATE 1,PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国首次出现外国投资赤字，标志着西方的“去风险”压力]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/iDq6_Z5cQGVIz9IKhRCzqO6toDA=/728x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5WOLXZL72VJSBH3XTZ7HET6UNY.jpg" alt="People walk at the venue of the China International Import Expo (CIIE) in Shanghai翻译:人们在上海中国国际进口博览会（CIIE）场馆内行走" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk at the venue of the China International Import Expo (CIIE) in Shanghai翻译:人们在上海中国国际进口博览会（CIIE）场馆内行走, China November 6, 2023. REUTERS/Casey Hall翻译:2023年11月6日，人们在中国上海举行的中国国际进口博览会（CIIE）会场散步。路透社/Casey Hall</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ILU9r1NGPrhVWgJ5i0NLt-1jJEM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JIGF575IKZNENL5HADWUWHFGGA.jpg" alt="View of the city skyline in Shanghai翻译:上海城市天际线景观" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view of the city skyline, ahead of the annual National People's Congress (NPC), in Shanghai, China February 24, 2022. Picture taken February 24, 2022. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2022 年 2 月 24 日，中国上海，一年一度的全国人民代表大会 (NPC) 召开之前，城市天际线的景色。照片拍摄于 2022 年 2 月 24 日。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>China recorded its first-ever quarterly deficit in foreign direct investment (FDI), according to balance of payments data, underscoring capital outflow pressure and Beijing's challenge in wooing overseas companies in the wake of a "<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/no-decoupling-west-china-drift-apart-2023-08-08/">de-risking"</a> move by Western governments.翻译:国际收支数据显示，中国首次出现季度外国直接投资（FDI）赤字，突显出资本外流压力以及西方政府采取“<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/no-decoupling-west-china-drift-apart-2023-08-08/">去风险”</a>举措后北京在吸引海外企业方面面临的挑战。</p>   <p>Direct investment liabilities - a broad measure of FDI that includes foreign companies' retained earnings in China - were a deficit of $11.8 billion during the July-September period, according to preliminary balance of payments data.翻译:根据初步国际收支数据，7月至9月期间，直接投资负债（衡量外国直接投资的广泛指标，包括外国公司在中国的留存收益）为赤字118亿美元。</p>   <p>That's the first quarterly shortfall since China's foreign exchange regulator began compiling the data in 1998, which could be linked to the impact of "de-risking" by Western countries from China, as well as China's interest rate disadvantage.翻译:这是中国外汇监管机构自1998年开始编制数据以来首次出现季度缺口，这可能与西方国家对中国“去风险化”的影响以及中国的利率劣势有关。</p>   <p>"Some of the weakness in China's inward FDI may be due to multinational companies repatriating earnings," Goldman Sachs wrote.翻译:高盛写道：“中国外国直接投资流入的疲软可能是由于跨国公司将利润汇回国内造成的。”</p>   <p>"With interest rates in China 'lower for longer' while interest rates outside of China 'higher for longer', capital outflow pressures are likely to persist."翻译:“由于中国的利率‘持续较低水平’，而中国以外的利率‘持续较高水平’，资本外流压力可能会持续存在。”</p>   <p>Julian Evans-Pritchard, head of China economics at Capital Economics, said the unusually-large interest rate gap "has led firms to remit their retained earnings out of the country".翻译:凯投宏观(Capital Economics)中国经济主管朱利安·埃文斯-普里查德(Julian Evans-Pritchard)表示，异常大的利差“导致企业将留存收益汇出中国”。</p>   <p>Although he sees little evidence that foreign companies are, on aggregate, reducing their presence in China, "we do think that, over the medium-term at least, increasing geopolitical tensions will hamper China's ability to attract FDI and instead favour emerging markets that are more friendly to the West."翻译:尽管他没有看到任何证据表明外国公司总体上正在减少在中国的业务，但“我们确实认为，至少从中期来看，日益加剧的地缘政治紧张局势将阻碍中国吸引外国直接投资的能力，反而有利于新兴市场对西方更加友好。”</p>   <p>Driven by the FDI outflows, China's basic balance - which encompasses current account and direct investment balances and are more stable than volatile portfolio investments - recorded a deficit of $3.2 billion, the second quarterly shortfall on record.翻译:在FDI流出的推动下，中国的基本平衡（包括经常项目和直接投资平衡，比波动性较大的证券投资更稳定）出现赤字32亿美元，这是有记录以来第二个季度出现赤字。</p>   <p>"Given these unfolding dynamics, which are poised to exert pressure on the RMB, we anticipate a sustained strategic response from China's authorities," Tommy Xie, head of Greater China Research at OCBC wrote.翻译:华侨银行大中华区研究主管Tommy Xie写道：“鉴于这些即将对人民币施加压力的动态，我们预计中国当局将做出持续的战略反应。”</p>   <p>Onshore yuan trading against the dollar also hit record-low volume in October, official data showed, highlighting authorities' stepped-up efforts to curb yuan selling.翻译:官方数据显示，十月份在岸人民币兑美元交易量也创下历史新低，凸显当局加大力度遏制人民币抛售。</p>   <p>Xie expects China's central bank to continue counter-cyclical interventions - including a strong bias in daily yuan fixings and managing yuan liquidity in the offshore market- to support the currency in the face of these headwinds.翻译:谢预计，中国央行将继续采取反周期干预措施，包括对人民币每日定盘价的强烈偏向以及管理离岸市场的人民币流动性，以在面临这些不利因素时为人民币提供支撑。</p>   <p>Latest data shows that onshore volume of yuan trading against the dollar slumped to a record low of 1.85 trillion yuan ($254.05 billion) in October, a 73% drop from the August level.翻译:最新数据显示，10月份人民币兑美元在岸交易量跌至历史新低1.85万亿元人民币（合2540.5亿美元），较8月份水平下降73%。</p>   <p>The People's Bank of China has urged major banks to limit trading and dissuade clients to exchange the yuan for the dollar, sources have told Reuters.翻译:消息人士告诉路透社，中国人民银行已敦促主要银行限制交易并劝阻客户将人民币兑换成美元。</p>   <p>In September, foreign exchange outflows from China rose sharply to $75 billion, the biggest monthly figure since 2016, Goldman Sachs data showed.翻译:高盛数据显示，9月份中国外汇流出大幅增至750亿美元，为2016年以来最大月度数字。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2819 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2819 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Shanghai newsroom;
Editing by Shri Navaratnam and Emelia Sithole-Matarise翻译:上海新闻编辑室报道；编辑：Shri Navaratnam 和 Emelia Sithole-Matarise</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 11:55:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ITUB22U3SRJR7FU2FLAMDPMAHM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-first-deficit-foreign-investment-signals-wests-de-risking-pressure-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>YUAN/FDI (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[习近平主席在北京会见古巴总理马雷罗]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/91XSGYJkWJ0cAIi2FlV1zQxtteM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/I3CQPXP66ZNR3JN72RSZ6EOLIY.jpg" alt="Opening ceremony of the Belt and Road Forum (BRF) in Beijing翻译:一带一路高峰论坛（BRF）在北京开幕" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping speaks at the opening ceremony of the Belt and Road Forum (BRF) to mark the 10th anniversary of the Belt and Road Initiative at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, October 18, 2023. REUTERS/Edgar Su/File Photo/File Photo翻译:2023 年 10 月 18 日，中国国家主席习近平在北京人民大会堂举行的纪念“一带一路”倡议十周年“一带一路”高峰论坛开幕式上发表讲话。 REUTERS/Edgar Su/File照片/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's President Xi Jinping met Cuban Prime Minister Manuel Marrero at Beijing's Great Hall of the People on Monday, Chinese state media reported, a day after the Cuban leader signed cooperation documents with Xi's deputy at a trade fair.翻译:据中国官方媒体报道，中国国家主席习近平周一在北京人民大会堂会见了古巴总理曼努埃尔·马雷罗，此前一天，古巴领导人在一次贸易展览会上与习近平副手签署了合作文件。</p>   <p>Marrero's visit comes as Cuba's economy, which is heavily dependent on food, fuel and other imports, is close to collapse amid a more than 50% decline in its export earnings, which are needed to purchase imports. The Cuban government blames U.S. sanctions and COVID for the economic downturn.翻译:马雷罗此行之际，古巴经济严重依赖食品、燃料和其他进口，由于出口收入下降了 50% 以上，而古巴经济接近崩溃，而出口收入则用于购买进口产品。古巴政府将经济低迷归咎于美国的制裁和新冠疫情。</p>   <p>"China will continue to firmly support the Cuban people, oppose foreign interference and the embargo, and safeguard (Cuba's) national sovereignty and dignity," Xi said, according to state media.翻译:据官方媒体报道，习近平表示：“中方将继续坚定支持古巴人民，反对外国干涉和封锁，维护（古巴）国家主权和尊严。”</p>   <p>Marrero was among foreign dignitaries attending the opening ceremony of the International Import Expo (CIIE) on Sunday in Shanghai, a week-long trade fair where countries and companies often strike deals resulting in the world's second-largest economy buying more of their wares.翻译:马雷罗是周日在上海出席国际进口博览会（CIIE）开幕式的外国政要之一，这是一个为期一周的贸易博览会，各国和企业经常在会上达成交易，导致世界第二大经济体购买更多他们的商品。</p>   <p>Following a meeting between Marrero and China's Premier Li Qiang on the sidelines of the CIIE, Chinese and Cuban officials signed several unspecified cooperation documents, according to a state media report.翻译:据官方媒体报道，马雷罗与中国总理李强在进博会期间会晤后，中国和古巴官员签署了几份未具体说明的合作文件。</p>   <p>"It is hoped that Cuba will continue to make good use of the important platform of the CIIE to bring more of its products to the China market," Xi told Marrero on Monday.翻译:习近平周一对马雷罗表示：“希望古巴继续利用好进博会这一重要平台，将更多古巴产品推向中国市场。”</p>   <p>Cuban officials often laud relations with China as "outstanding" or "historic", and President Miguel Diaz-Canel told China's Xi on the sidelines of a BRICS Summit in Johannesburg翻译:金砖国家领导人约翰内斯堡峰会 in August that ties were at an "all-time high".翻译:古巴官员经常称赞与中国的关系“杰出”或“历史性”，古巴总统米格尔·迪亚斯-卡内尔在八月份约翰内斯堡举行的金砖国家峰会期间对中国习近平表示，两国关系处于“历史最高水平”。</p>   <p>But analysts doubt China can take its relationship with the diplomatically isolated island much further or do anything significant to support it, not least because Cuba lacks the means to pay back any loans China might be willing to extend.翻译:但分析人士怀疑，中国能否进一步深化与这个在外交上孤立的岛屿的关系，或采取任何重大措施来支持它，尤其是因为古巴缺乏偿还中国可能愿意提供的任何贷款的手段。</p>   <p>Still, supporting Cuba could reap significant strategic and diplomatic dividends for China.翻译:尽管如此，支持古巴仍能为中国带来重大的战略和外交红利。</p>   <p>In June, a report claimed China had reached a deal with Cuba to establish an electronic <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-post-spy-facility-cuba-off-southeastern-us-wsj-2023-06-08/">eavesdropping</a> facility on the island, about 100 miles from the U.S. state of Florida. China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-says-allegations-chinese-spying-cuba-are-false-2023-06-12/">denied the report</a> as being false.翻译:6月，一份报告称中国已与古巴达成协议，将在距离美国佛罗里达州约100英里的岛上建立一个电子<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-post-spy-facility-cuba-off-southeastern-us-wsj-2023-06-08/">窃听</a>设施。中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-says-allegations-chinese-spying-cuba-are-false-2023-06-12/">否认该报道</a>不实。</p>    <span>Reporting by Joe Cash; Editing by Robert Birsel and Bernadette Baum翻译:乔·卡什报道；罗伯特·伯塞尔和伯纳黛特·鲍姆编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 11:41:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">VFF6JVOJZBMJFMTVQER5KNXD6Y</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-president-xi-meets-cuban-prime-minister-beijing-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>CUBA/MARRERO (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[欧洲央行调查显示跨国公司计划采取行动尽量减少中国风险]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/H2-gzmZaKH7GRWHL1s6GRqqNXUw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YDDUR5CTYBNORGP6YJ4OXRWI6U.jpg" alt="European Central Bank (ECB) headquarters in Frankfurt翻译:欧洲中央银行 (ECB) 总部位于法兰克福" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view shows the logo of the European Central Bank (ECB) outside its headquarters in Frankfurt, Germany March 16, 2023. REUTERS/Heiko Becker/File Photo翻译:2023 年 3 月 16 日，欧洲中央银行 (ECB) 位于德国法兰克福总部外的标志。REUTERS/Heiko Becker/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>More than 40% of multinational firms surveyed by the European Central Bank expect to move production to politically friendlier countries in the coming years, with risk related to China cited as the main concern, a paper showed on Monday.翻译:周一的一份文件显示，接受欧洲央行调查的跨国公司中，超过 40% 预计未来几年将生产转移到政治上更加友好的国家，其中与中国相关的风险被视为主要担忧。</p>   <p>Firms have increasingly discussed shifting production sites after the pandemic and Russia's war in Ukraine disrupted value chains, but there has been little empirical evidence of mass relocations.翻译:在大流行和俄罗斯乌克兰战争扰乱价值链之后，企业越来越多地讨论转移生产地点，但几乎没有大规模搬迁的经验证据。</p>   <p>Seeking on-the-ground confirmation, the ECB surveyed 65 very large firms with a global footprint and 49% said they were looking to "near-shore", or bring production closer to the point of sales.翻译:为了寻求实地确认，欧洲央行对 65 家业务遍及全球的大型企业进行了调查，其中 49% 的企业表示，他们正在寻求“近岸”生产，或者使生产更接近销售点。</p>   <p>In total, 42% wanted to "friend-shore" some operations, or move them to more welcoming locations.翻译:总共有 42% 的受访者希望“友好支持”一些业务，或者将其转移到更受欢迎的地点。</p>   <p>"As to those countries which posed – or could pose – a risk to supply chains in their sector more generally, two-thirds of all respondents cited China," the ECB said in an Economic Bulletin article.翻译:欧洲央行在《经济公报》的一篇文章中表示：“对于那些对其行业供应链构成或可能构成风险的国家，三分之二的受访者提到了中国。”</p>   <p>More than half of the firms sourced critical materials from a specific country or small number of countries, and nearly all said that these supplies now faced elevated risk.翻译:超过一半的公司从特定国家或少数国家采购关键材料，几乎所有公司都表示这些供应现在面临更高的风险。</p>   <p>"A large majority of these identified China as that country, or one of those countries, with all of them considering this an elevated risk," the ECB added.翻译:欧洲央行补充说：“其中绝大多数将中国视为该国家或其中之一，他们都认为这是一个较高的风险。”</p>   <p>Near-shoring was already a tendency in recent years but friend-shoring is a new phenomenon as only 11% said they were already pursuing such a strategy in the past five years.翻译:近几年来，近岸外包已成为一种趋势，但友岸外包是一种新现象，只有 11% 的受访者表示，他们在过去五年中已经采取了这种策略。</p>   <p>The European Union is still likely to be a loser in such corporate movements as the number or firms looking to move production out of the bloc remains larger than the number moving it in, and this could have a "significant" impact on employment.翻译:欧盟仍然可能成为此类企业迁移的输家，因为希望将生产转移出欧盟的企业数量仍然多于将其转移到欧盟的企业数量，这可能对就业产生“重大”影响。</p>   <p>The moves could also fuel inflation as close to half of firms said they expected the changes to result in higher prices, the paper added.翻译:该报补充说，这些举措还可能加剧通胀，因为近一半的公司表示，他们预计这些变化将导致价格上涨。</p>    <span>Reporting by Balazs Koranyi; Editing by Andrew Heavens翻译:巴拉兹·科兰尼 (Balazs Koranyi) 报道；安德鲁·天堂编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 11:25:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ES5SZT3TDNIHPPCDHZEHS2YZ3E</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/multinationals-plan-moves-minimise-china-risk-ecb-survey-shows-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ECB</category>
                
                <category>SURVEY/CHINA</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[何立峰出任中央金融委员会重要职务]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ujSDkUXlKwmftVaZ8I9Sqe2Sy6Y=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/V6NMNCXEWVK5LCVY7AIVIICF3I.jpg" alt="Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng in Beijing翻译:中国国务院副总理何立峰在北京" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng attends a joint press conference following the 10th China-EU High-Level Economic and Trade Dialogue at the Diaoyutai State Guesthouse in Beijing, China September 25, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo翻译:2023年9月25日，中国国务院副总理何立峰在中国北京钓鱼台国宾馆出席第十次中欧经贸高层对话后举行的联合新闻发布会。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A Chinese vice premier, He Lifeng, has been appointed head of the office of the Central Financial Commission (CFC), which is responsible for running day-to-day affairs of a new regulator tasked with overseeing a vast financial sector.翻译:中国副总理何立峰被任命为中央金融委员会（CFC）办公室主任，负责管理新监管机构的日常事务，该监管机构的任务是监管庞大的金融部门。</p>   <p>He was also appointed as party chief of a separate Central Financial Work Commission (CFWC), which has been set up to strengthen the ideological and political role of the party in China's overall financial system.翻译:他还被任命为中央金融工作委员会（CFWC）党组书记，该委员会的成立是为了加强党在中国整个金融体系中的思想和政治作用。</p>   <p>The appointments, announced by the central bank's Financial News publication, underscore how the ruling Communist Party has taken direct control of supervising the financial sector.翻译:央行的《金融新闻》刊物宣布的这些任命突显了执政的共产党如何直接控制金融业的监管。</p>   <p>The appointments mean He will tackle local government debt and the downturn in the property sector, two crises that threaten financial stability and the long-term growth potential of the world's second-largest economy.翻译:这些任命意味着贺建奎将解决地方政府债务和房地产行业低迷的问题，这两场危机威胁着世界第二大经济体的金融稳定和长期增长潜力。</p>   <p>China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-set-up-new-financial-regulator-major-supervisory-overhaul-2023-03-07/">announced</a> in March it would set up the CFC under a broad restructuring of both party and government entities to tighten the party's supervision of the industry.翻译:中国三月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-set-up-new-financial-regulator-major-supervisory-overhaul-2023-03-07/">宣布，</a>将在党政机构的广泛重组下成立CFC，以加强党对行业的监管。</p>   <p>The head of the CFC has yet to be named.翻译:CFC 主席尚未被任命。</p>   <p>He, regarded as a confidant of President Xi Jinping, has been playing a prominent role in handling financial, economic and trade issues since being named a vice premier in a cabinet reshuffle in March.翻译:他被视为习近平主席的心腹，自3月份内阁改组中被任命为副总理以来，在处理金融、经济和贸易问题上一直发挥着重要作用。</p>   <p>He has also been appointed director of a key ruling Communist Party <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/he-lifeng-chinas-economy-tsar-made-director-key-party-commission-2023-10-30/">economic body</a>, the Central Finance and Economic Affairs Commission, replacing Liu He.翻译:他还被任命为中共主要执政<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/he-lifeng-chinas-economy-tsar-made-director-key-party-commission-2023-10-30/">经济机构</a>中央财经委员会主任，接替刘鹤。</p>   <p>Last week, state media reported that the Communist Party would <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-step-up-financial-supervision-cut-risks-2023-10-31/">step up</a> its leadership of the finance industry and strengthen efforts to reduce local government debt risks, citing a twice-a-decade financial policy meeting that was held on Oct. 30-31.翻译:上周，官方媒体援引10月30日至31日召开的十年两次金融政策会议报道称，中国共产党将<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-step-up-financial-supervision-cut-risks-2023-10-31/">加强</a>对金融业的领导，并加大力度降低地方政府债务风险。</p>   <p>The CFWC would "comprehensively strengthen the party's leadership over financial work" and strive to "promote strong financial supervision", according to a summary of a CFWC meeting last week.翻译:根据上周的 CFWC 会议纪要，CFWC 将“全面加强党对金融工作的领导”，努力“推动强有力的金融监管”。</p>   <p>An economist who studied finance at Xiamen University from 1978 to 1984, He obtained a doctorate in economics in 1998, when he was the party chief of Quanzhou city in Fujian province. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-new-economic-tsar-faces-challenges-emulating-his-predecessor-2023-11-01/"> read more </a>翻译:经济学家，1978年至1984年就读于厦门大学金融系，1998年获经济学博士学位，时任福建省泉州市委书记。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-new-economic-tsar-faces-challenges-emulating-his-predecessor-2023-11-01/">阅读更多</a></p>   <p>He's relationship with Xi dates back four decades. He first worked under Xi in the coastal city of Xiamen and later in the northern municipality of Tianjin.翻译:他与习近平的关系可以追溯到四十年前。他首先在沿海城市厦门在习近平手下工作，后来又到北方直辖市天津工作。</p>   <p>In 2014, He was named vice chairman of the National Development and Reform Commission, the state planning agency, before taking full control in 2017. Since then, He has joined Xi on domestic tours, in diplomatic meetings and at other engagements.翻译:2014年，贺建奎被任命为国家发展和改革委员会副主任，并于2017年全面掌管国家发展和改革委员会。此后，贺建奎与习近平一起进行国内访问、外交会议和其他活动。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ziyi Tang, Kevin Yao and Ryan Woo; Editing by Edwina Gibbs, Robert Birsel翻译:唐子仪、姚凯文和吴瑞安报道；编辑：埃德温娜·吉布斯、罗伯特·伯塞尔</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 10:21:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RJDFNKNE6VKYNAENGVBDSKDVEQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-appoints-he-lifeng-head-office-central-financial-commission-cbank-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>FINANCE/ (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[迪诺拉苏州工厂产量增至三倍，以满足快速增长的亚洲市场]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Italy's Industrie De Nora <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DNR.MI" target="_blank">(DNR.MI)</a> said its plant in Souzhou, in China, would triple its production capacity, in line with the electrode maker's plans to increase manufacturing in the fast-growing Asian market.翻译:意大利迪诺拉工业公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DNR.MI" target="_blank">(DNR.MI)</a>表示，其位于中国苏州的工厂的产能将增加两倍，以符合该电极制造商在快速增长的亚洲市场增加产量的计划。</p>   <p>The project is part of De Nora's plan to expand in Asia, where the group is facing increasing demand, and be able to face request for technologies used to produce green hydrogen, the group said in a statement on Monday.翻译:该集团在周一的一份声明中表示，该项目是迪诺拉在亚洲扩张计划的一部分，该集团在亚洲面临不断增长的需求，并能够满足对用于生产绿色氢的技术的要求。</p>   <p>The Souzhou site, 70 km (43.5 miles) from Shanghai, was opened in 2005 and is De Nora's main site in China, serving Asian and Chinese clients as well as high-tech business partners.翻译:苏州工厂距离上海 70 公里（43.5 英里），于 2005 年开业，是迪诺拉在中国的主要工厂，为亚洲和中国客户以及高科技业务合作伙伴提供服务。</p>   <p>In particular, De Nora aims to strengthen its positioning in the maintenance services of chlor-alkali plants in China, which represent 45% of the global market, in the high-growth sector of electrodes for the production of the copper foil, used both in the manufacture of lithium batteries for electric cars and as a raw material for printed circuit boards.翻译:特别是，迪诺拉旨在加强其在中国氯碱工厂维护服务中的地位，该工厂占全球市场的 45%，在铜箔生产电极的高增长领域，铜箔用于生产铜箔。电动汽车锂电池的制造以及印刷电路板的原材料。</p>    <span>Reporting by Giulia Segreti, Editing by Louise Heavens翻译:Giulia Segreti 报道，Louise Heavens 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 10:20:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZILKNNFE65KHLP52QSLXQTIUUQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/de-noras-souzhou-plant-production-triple-fast-growing-asian-market-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>INDUSTRIE DENORA</category>
                
                <category>PRODUCTION/CHINA</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国表示将努力恢复巴勒斯坦领土的和平]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/kxAnhmGrixlweKkU1vxpVpYPpVU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5JN6OPXNTFJBHGZ7DWXMEN4ZMU.jpg" alt="A view of military action at a location given as Gaza, amid the conflict between Israel and the Palestinian Islamist group Hamas翻译:在以色列和巴勒斯坦伊斯兰组织哈马斯之间的冲突中，对加沙地带采取军事行动的看法" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view of military action at a location given as Gaza, amid the conflict between Israel and the Palestinian Islamist group Hamas翻译:在以色列和巴勒斯坦伊斯兰组织哈马斯之间的冲突中，对加沙地带采取军事行动的看法, in this screengrab obtained from a handout video released on November 6, 2023. Israel Defense Forces/Handout via REUTERS    </figcaption></figure>       <p>China will do its utmost to restore peace in the Palestinian territories as it takes over the presidency of the U.N. Security Council (UNSC), its foreign ministry said on Monday, as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/pressure-israel-over-civilians-steps-up-ceasefire-calls-rebuffed-2023-11-06/">tensions intensify</a> in the Middle East.翻译:中国外交部周一表示，随着中东<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/pressure-israel-over-civilians-steps-up-ceasefire-calls-rebuffed-2023-11-06/">紧张局势加剧</a>，中国将在接任联合国安理会主席国期间尽最大努力恢复巴勒斯坦领土的和平。</p>   <p>"China will do its utmost to encourage the Security Council to fulfil its responsibilities, play its role, build consensus and take responsible and meaningful actions as soon as possible to ease the current crisis and safeguard the safety of civilians in order to restore peace," ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin told a regular news conference.翻译:中方将全力推动安理会履行职责，发挥作用，凝聚共识，尽快采取负责任、有意义的行动，缓解当前危机，维护平民安全，恢复和平。外交部发言人汪文斌在例行新闻发布会上表示。</p>   <p>China's statement comes as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israels-netanyahu-says-no-gaza-ceasefire-until-hostages-returned-2023-11-05/">Israel</a> ratchets up its military offensive against the Palestinian Islamist group Hamas.翻译:中国发表声明之际， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israels-netanyahu-says-no-gaza-ceasefire-until-hostages-returned-2023-11-05/">以色列</a>加大了对巴勒斯坦伊斯兰组织哈马斯的军事攻势。</p>   <p>China took over the rotating presidency of the UNSC last week.翻译:中国上周接任联合国安理会轮值主席。</p>   <p>The conflict in the Middle East tops the Security Council's agenda in November, said Zhang Jun, China's permanent representative to the UN, according to state media.翻译:据官方媒体报道，中国常驻联合国代表张军表示，中东冲突是 11 月份安理会议程的首要议题。</p>   <p>"It is imperative to promote a cease-fire and halt the fighting, prevent further civilian casualties, prevent a larger-scale humanitarian disaster and prevent the conflict from spilling over," Zhang was quoted as saying, the China Daily reported.翻译:据《中国日报》报道，张军说：“当务之急是推动停火止战，防止更多平民伤亡，防止发生更大规模的人道主义灾难，防止冲突蔓延。”</p>   <p>China's special envoy to the Middle East, Zhai Jun, has just wrapped a tour of the region.翻译:中国中东问题特使翟隽刚刚结束对该地区的访问。</p>   <p>Zhai, who met leaders of several countries over the crisis, pinned the cause of the Israel-Gaza crisis on the lack of guarantees for Palestinian rights.翻译:翟隽就危机会见了多国领导人，他将以色列和加沙危机的原因归咎于巴勒斯坦权利缺乏保障。</p>   <p>The presidency of the UNSC rotates among the 15 member states of the council monthly. China last held it in August 2022.翻译:联合国安理会主席每月由安理会 15 个成员国轮流担任。中国上次举办是在2022年8月。</p>    <span>Reporting by Beijing newsroom; Writing by Bernard Orr; Editing by Christian Schmollinger翻译:北京新闻编辑室报道；伯纳德·奥尔撰写；克里斯蒂安·施莫林格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 08:22:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">K37RSVM5CBMHDJ5HWYBKRCLAFY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/china-says-will-work-restore-peace-palestinian-territories-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ISRAEL</category>
                
                <category>PALESTINIAN/CHINA (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中方敦促缅方合作维护边境稳定]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/7s3nfZyxwSmRcNU2bbHv8vPA_nk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/45POJ7WRMZI35M6HQRSXL77T2A.jpg" alt="Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin attends a news conference in Beijing翻译:外交部发言人汪文斌在北京出席记者会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin attends a news conference in Beijing翻译:外交部发言人汪文斌在北京出席记者会, China March 3, 2022. REUTERS/Carlos Garcia Rawlins/File Photo翻译:中国外交部发言人汪文斌于2022年3月3日在中国北京出席新闻发布会。路透社/卡洛斯·加西亚·罗林斯/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Myanmar should cooperate with China to maintain stability on their common border, a Chinese official said on Monday, after a surge of fighting in Myanmar between junta forces and insurgents rocked the region.翻译:一名中国官员周一表示，在缅甸军政府部队和叛乱分子之间的战斗激增震惊该地区后，缅甸应与中国合作，维护共同边界的稳定。</p>   <p>Last week, Myanmar's ruling military said it was trying to restore order near the border after an alliance of ethnic minority armies battling for self-determination launched a series of coordinated attacks on junta targets.翻译:上周，缅甸执政军方表示，在争取自决的少数民族军队联盟对军政府目标发动一系列协调一致的袭击后，他们正在努力恢复边境附近的秩序。</p>   <p>"Myanmar is called on to cooperate with China to maintain stability along the China-Myanmar border, earnestly ensure the safety of the lives and property of Chinese border residents, and take effective measures to strengthen the security of Chinese personnel," said Nong Rong, assistant Chinese foreign minister.翻译:我们呼吁缅方同中方合作维护中缅边境稳定，切实保障中方边境居民生命财产安全，采取有效措施加强中方人员安全。中国外交部部长助理。</p>   <p>A spokesperson for Myanmar's ruling military was not immediately available for comment.翻译:缅甸执政军方发言人未能立即发表评论。</p>   <p>The Asia Times news site <a href="https://asiatimes.com/2023/11/myanmar-junta-artillery-attack-fatally-lands-on-china/" target="_blank">reported</a> that one Chinese citizen was killed and several were wounded on Saturday when a shell fired by the Myanmar military over-shot its target and struck on the Chinese side of the border.翻译:《亚洲时报》新闻网站<a href="https://asiatimes.com/2023/11/myanmar-junta-artillery-attack-fatally-lands-on-china/" target="_blank">报道称</a>，周六，缅甸军方发射的一枚炮弹击中目标，击中边境中国一侧，造成一名中国公民死亡，多人受伤。</p>   <p>Nong, who visited Myanmar on Nov. 3-5, said China hoped Myanmar would restore stability, and it supported all parties to properly handle differences and achieve reconciliation through dialogue as soon as possible.翻译:农农于11月3日至5日访问缅甸表示，中方希望缅甸恢复稳定，支持各方妥善处理分歧，尽快通过对话实现和解。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/thailand-tries-rescue-162-nationals-trapped-myanmar-fighting-2023-11-03/">Thailand</a> is trying to bring home 162 of its nationals trapped by the fighting in Myanmar.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/thailand-tries-rescue-162-nationals-trapped-myanmar-fighting-2023-11-03/">泰国</a>正试图将 162 名被困在缅甸战事中的泰国国民接回国。</p>   <p>Myanmar has been in chaos since a military coup in February 2021 unseated a democratically elected government led by Nobel laureate Aung San Suu Kyi.翻译:自 2021 年 2 月的军事政变推翻由诺贝尔奖获得者昂山素季领导的民选政府以来，缅甸一直处于混乱之中。</p>   <p>Pro-democracy insurgent groups have in some areas teamed up with ethnic minority guerrillas who have been campaigning for decades for greater autonomy to battle junta forces.翻译:在一些地区，亲民主叛乱组织与少数民族游击队联手，这些游击队几十年来一直在争取更大的自治权，以对抗军政府部队。</p>   <p>While Western governments have condemned the Myanmar military and imposed sanctions on it, China, along with Russia, have been <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/un-expert-says-russia-china-sending-deadly-aid-myanmars-military-2023-05-17/">supportive of the generals</a>. China says it supports Myanmar in finding its own path and has urged the international community to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/chinese-foreign-minister-visit-myanmar-india-this-week-2023-05-02/">respect its sovereignty</a>.翻译:尽管西方政府谴责缅甸军方并对其实施制裁，但中国和俄罗斯一直<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/un-expert-says-russia-china-sending-deadly-aid-myanmars-military-2023-05-17/">支持缅甸军方的将军们</a>。中国表示支持缅甸探索自己的道路，并敦促国际社会<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/chinese-foreign-minister-visit-myanmar-india-this-week-2023-05-02/">尊重其主权</a>。</p>   <p>China's foreign ministry said last week it was翻译:中国外交部上周表示</p>   <p>closely following the conflict in Myanmar.翻译:密切关注缅甸冲突。</p>   <p>"We urge parties to immediately stop the fighting, settle differences peacefully through dialogue and consultation, and avoid escalation," spokesperson Wang Wenbin said at a regular press briefing.翻译:汪文斌在例行记者会上表示，我们敦促有关各方立即停止战斗，通过对话协商和平解决分歧，避免事态升级。</p>   <p>Nong, during his visit, urged Myanmar to strengthen the security of Chinese institutions and projects there.翻译:农在访问期间敦促缅甸加强中国机构和项目的安全。</p>   <p>He also visited a 793-km natural gas pipeline, part of China's Belt and Road infrastructure and energy network, linking Ramree Island on the Myanmar west coast with the Chinese border city Ruili in Yunnan Province.翻译:他还参观了一条全长793公里的天然气管道，该管道是中国“一带一路”基础设施和能源网络的一部分，连接缅甸西海岸的拉姆里岛和中国边境城市云南省瑞丽。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ella Cao and Bernard Orr; Editing by Tom Hogue, Robert Birsel翻译:Ella Cao 和 Bernard Orr 报道；汤姆·霍格、罗伯特·伯塞尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 04:42:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">HYUN33EJUVLS5KOTKA7OFL6NQY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-calls-myanmar-maintain-stability-along-border-through-cooperation-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>MYANMAR/BORDER (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[蚂蚁集团获准向中国公众发布人工智能产品]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/gyFuwyBOFyiz4AupppJpa42Rqfs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KORYRTLQXFN6JEZ2NSGGDLMFFA.jpg" alt="China International Fair for Trade in Services in Beijing翻译:北京中国国际服务贸易交易会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People stand at the booth of Ant Group at the China International Fair for Trade in Services (CIFTIS) in Beijing, China September 2, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo翻译:2023年9月2日，在中国北京举行的中国国际服务贸易交易会（服贸会）上，人们站在蚂蚁集团的展位前。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Ant Group has received Chinese government approval to release products powered by its "Bailing" artificial intelligence (AI) large language model to the public, a spokesperson for the Chinese firm said on Monday.翻译:蚂蚁集团发言人周一表示，该公司已获得中国政府批准，可以向公众发布由“百灵”人工智能（AI）大语言模型支持的产品。</p>   <p>Unlike other countries, China requires companies to submit security assessments and receive <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/baidu-among-first-win-china-approval-ai-models-bloomberg-news-2023-08-30/">clearance</a> before releasing AI products to the public.翻译:与其他国家不同，中国要求企业在向公众发布人工智能产品之前提交安全评估并获得<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/baidu-among-first-win-china-approval-ai-models-bloomberg-news-2023-08-30/">许可</a>。</p>   <p>The financial affiliate of e-commerce giant Alibaba Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">(9988.HK)</a> in September <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-ant-group-unveils-finance-ai-model-race-heats-up-2023-09-08/">unveiled</a> a finance-specific AI model and started testing consumer and professional apps for the products.翻译:电子商务巨头阿里巴巴集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">（9988.HK）</a>的金融子公司于 9 月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-ant-group-unveils-finance-ai-model-race-heats-up-2023-09-08/">推出了</a>金融专用人工智能模型，并开始测试该产品的消费者和专业应用程序。</p>    <span>Reporting by Brenda Goh; Editing by Christian Schmollinger翻译:布伦达·吴报道；克里斯蒂安·施莫林格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 02:37:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZTZQTNQHPVKO7NUBRUNZUSOP2Q</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/ant-group-wins-approval-release-ai-products-chinese-public-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ANT GROUP</category>
                
                <category>AI/ (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[财政部长表示中国将加快发行国债]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/-UxwvQfOf6HYjSEbftdTf0A1XVE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7C4544VKRJN35CBVK5NYVI5I7A.jpg" alt="A woman walks in the Central Business District (CBD) on a hazy morning in Beijing翻译:北京一个雾蒙蒙的早晨，一名女子在中央商务区（CBD）散步" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A woman walks in the Central Business District (CBD) on a hazy morning in Beijing翻译:北京一个雾蒙蒙的早晨，一名女子在中央商务区（CBD）散步, China, October 25, 2021.   REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2021 年 10 月 25 日，中国北京，一个雾蒙蒙的早晨，一名妇女在中央商务区 (CBD) 散步。路透社/Thomas Peter/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China will accelerate the issuance and use of government bonds, state-run news agency Xinhua reported on Sunday citing an interview with new finance minister Lan Foan.翻译:官方通讯社新华社周日援引新任财政部长兰福安的采访报道称，中国将加快政府债券的发行和使用。</p>   <p>The finance ministry will steadily promote the resolution of local government debt risk and increase efforts to better leverage the role of special bonds to boost the economy, Xinhua cited Foan as saying.翻译:新华社援引福安的话说，财政部将稳步推进化解地方政府债务风险，加大力度更好发挥专项债券对经济的拉动作用。</p>   <p>"The Ministry of Finance will continue to implement a proactive fiscal policy, focus on improving efficiency, and better play the effectiveness of fiscal policy," said Lan, who also noted the "complex domestic and international situation".翻译:兰说：“财政部将继续实施积极的财政政策，以提高效率为重点，更好地发挥财政政策的有效性。”他还指出了“复杂的国内外形势”。</p>   <p>Some new local government debt quotas for 2024 have been issued in advance to reasonably ensure local financing needs, he said.翻译:他表示，部分2024年新增地方政府债务指标已提前下达，合理保障地方融资需求。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-names-lan-foan-new-finance-minister-amid-stimulus-push-2023-10-24/">Lan</a>, a 61-year-old technocrat with little central government experience, was named finance minister in state media last month, at a time when the government is ramping up fiscal stimulus to revive the world's second-biggest economy.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-names-lan-foan-new-finance-minister-amid-stimulus-push-2023-10-24/">兰</a>是一位没有多少中央政府经验的61岁技术官僚，上个月被官方媒体任命为财政部长，当时政府正在加大财政刺激力度以重振世界第二大经济体。</p>   <p>He succeeded Liu Kun who had held the position since 2018. Previously, Lan was party chief of the northern province of Shanxi.翻译:他接替了自 2018 年起担任该职务的刘昆。此前，兰曾担任北方省份山西省委书记。</p>   <p>His appointment comes as the central government draws on a well-used playbook that relies heavily on debt and state spending but that analysts said falls short on deeper reform.翻译:他的任命正值中央政府借鉴了一套常用的策略，该策略严重依赖债务和国家支出，但分析人士表示，该策略缺乏更深层次的改革。</p>   <p>The top parliamentary body last month approved the issuance of 1 trillion yuan ($137 billion) in sovereign bonds in the fourth quarter to fund rebuilding of areas affected by floods, state media reported.翻译:据官方媒体报道，最高人民会议机构上个月批准在第四季度发行 1 万亿元人民币（合 1,370 亿美元）的主权债券，为受洪水影响地区的重建提供资金。</p>   <p>The economy grew faster than analyst estimates in the third quarter, improving the chances the government can meet its full-year growth target of around 5%.翻译:第三季度经济增长快于分析师预期，提高了政府实现 5% 左右的全年增长目标的机会。</p>   <p>But headwinds persist as a property crisis deepens and private firms are reluctant to spend amid weak confidence.翻译:但随着房地产危机加深以及私营企业因信心疲弱而不愿支出，不利因素依然存在。</p>   <p>The ruling Communist Party will <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-step-up-financial-supervision-cut-risks-2023-10-31/">step up</a> leadership of China's $61 trillion finance industry and strengthen efforts to reduce local debt risk, state media reported, citing a twice-a-decade financial policy meeting held Oct. 30-31.翻译:官方媒体援引10月30日至31日举行的十年两次金融政策会议报道称，执政的共产党将<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-step-up-financial-supervision-cut-risks-2023-10-31/">加强</a>对中国61万亿美元金融业的领导，并加大力度降低地方债务风险。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.3005 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.3005 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Martin Quin Pollard and Wang Shuyan; Editing by William Mallard and Christopher Cushing翻译:马丁·奎因·波拉德、王淑艳报道；威廉·马拉德和克里斯托弗·库欣编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 08:37:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">G6A2VYJMAJK5FCKLK2M2JFYBUA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-accelerate-issuance-government-bonds-finance-minister-says-2023-11-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>FINANCE/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
