<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 16:36:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[最古老的蚊子化石带来吸血惊喜]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/shfrYY5WN0X14xPtViposlre0vc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6TYQT5LW7JNCXBASFI33X3OYK4.jpg" alt="A view from below of the head of a fossilized male mosquito, trapped in amber found in central Lebanon dating to about 130 million years ago翻译:从下方看一只雄性蚊子化石，它被困在黎巴嫩中部发现的琥珀中，其历史可追溯至约 1.3 亿年前" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An undated handout image of a view from below of the head of a fossilized male mosquito, including elongated sucking-piercing mouthparts, trapped in amber found in central Lebanon dating to about 130 million years ago. Dany Azar/Handout via REUTERS   翻译:一张未注明日期的讲义图片，显示了一只雄性蚊子化石头部下方的景象，其中包括细长的吸吮式口器，这些口器被困在黎巴嫩中部发现的琥珀中，其历史可追溯至约 1.3 亿年前。丹尼·阿扎尔/路透社讲义</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/YUuqsmvUtYscxjdIZesxtSZtMfU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FJULGZXCYJIZNENVZUG3VZGEOE.jpg" alt="A view from above of the body of a fossilized male mosquito trapped in amber found in central Lebanon dating to about 130 million years ago翻译:从上方看黎巴嫩中部发现的被困在琥珀中的雄性蚊子化石，其历史可追溯至约 1.3 亿年前" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An undated handout image of a view from above of the body of a fossilized male mosquito trapped in amber found in central Lebanon dating to about 130 million years ago. Dany Azar/Handout via REUTERS  翻译:一张未标注日期的讲义图片，显示的是黎巴嫩中部发现的一只被困在琥珀中的雄性蚊子化石，其年代可追溯到约 1.3 亿年前。丹尼·阿扎尔/路透社讲义</figcaption></figure>               <p>Hundreds of thousands of people worldwide are killed annually by malaria and other diseases spread through the bite of mosquitoes, insects that date back to the age of dinosaurs. All of these bites are inflicted by females, which possess specialized mouth anatomy that their male counterparts lack.翻译:全世界每年有数十万人死于疟疾和其他通过蚊子（可追溯到恐龙时代的昆虫）叮咬传播的疾病。所有这些咬伤都是由雌性造成的，雌性拥有雄性同类所缺乏的特殊口腔解剖结构。</p>   <p>But it has not always been that way. Researchers said they have discovered the oldest-known fossils of mosquitoes - two males entombed in pieces of amber dating to 130 million years ago during the Cretaceous Period and found near the town of Hammana in Lebanon. To their surprise, the male mosquitoes possessed elongated piercing-sucking mouthparts seen now only in females.翻译:但情况并非总是如此。研究人员表示，他们发现了已知最古老的蚊子化石——在黎巴嫩哈马纳镇附近发现的两只雄性蚊子化石，埋在可追溯到 1.3 亿年前白垩纪时期的琥珀中。令他们惊讶的是，雄性蚊子拥有细长的刺吸式口器，而这种口器现在只出现在雌性身上。</p>   <p>"Clearly they were hematophagous," meaning blood-eaters, said paleontologist Dany Azar of the Chinese Academy of Sciences' Nanjing Institute of Geology and Paleontology and Lebanese University, lead author of the study published this week in the journal <a href="https://www.cell.com/current-biology/fulltext/S0960-9822(23)01448-3" target="_blank">Current Biology</a>. "So this discovery is a major one in the evolutionary history of mosquitoes."翻译:本周发表在<a href="https://www.cell.com/current-biology/fulltext/S0960-9822(23)01448-3" target="_blank">《当代生物学》</a>杂志上的这项研究的主要作者、中国科学院南京地质古生物研究所和黎巴嫩大学的古生物学家丹尼·阿扎尔说，“显然它们是噬血性的”，即食血者。 “所以这一发现是蚊子进化史上的重大发现。”</p>   <p>The two fossilized mosquitoes, both representing the same extinct species, are similar in size and appearance to modern mosquitoes, though the mouthparts used for obtaining blood are shorter than in today's female mosquitoes.翻译:这两种蚊子化石均代表同一已灭绝物种，其大小和外观与现代蚊子相似，但用于获取血液的口器比今天的雌性蚊子短。</p>   <p>"Mosquitoes are the most notorious blood-feeders on humans and most terrestrial vertebrates, and they transmit a certain number of parasites and diseases to their hosts," Azar said.翻译:阿扎尔说：“蚊子是人类和大多数陆生脊椎动物中最臭名昭著的吸血动物，它们会将一定数量的寄生虫和疾病传播给宿主。”</p>   <p>"Only fertilized female mosquitoes will suck blood, because they need proteins to make their eggs develop. Males and unfertilized females will eat some nectar from plants. And some males do not feed at all," Azar added.翻译:“只有受精的雌性蚊子才会吸血，因为它们需要蛋白质来使卵发育。雄性和未受精的雌性蚊子会吃一些植物的花蜜。有些雄性根本不吃东西，”阿扎尔补充道。</p>   <p>Some flying insects - tsetse flies, for instance - have hematophagous males. But not modern mosquitoes.翻译:一些飞行昆虫——例如采采蝇——有吸血的雄性。但不是现代蚊子。</p>   <p>"Finding this behavior in the Cretaceous is quite surprising," said paleontologist and study co-author André Nel of the National Museum of Natural History of Paris.翻译:“在白垩纪发现这种行为相当令人惊讶，”巴黎国家自然历史博物馆的古生物学家和研究合著者安德烈·内尔说。</p>   <p>The delicate anatomy of the two mosquitoes was beautifully preserved in the fossils. Both displayed exceptionally sharp and triangle-shaped jaw anatomy and an elongated structure with tooth-like projections.翻译:化石中完美地保存了两只蚊子精致的解剖结构。两者都显示出异常锋利的三角形下颌解剖结构以及带有齿状突起的细长结构。</p>   <p>The researchers said they suspect that mosquitoes evolved from insects that did not consume blood. They hypothesize that the mouthparts that became adapted for obtaining blood meals originally were used to pierce plants to get access to nutritious fluids.翻译:研究人员表示，他们怀疑蚊子是从不吸食血液的昆虫进化而来的。他们推测，适应获取血粉的口器最初是用来刺穿植物以获得营养液的。</p>   <p>Plant evolution may have played a role in the feeding divergence between male and female mosquitoes. At the time when these two mosquitoes became stuck in tree sap that eventually became amber, flowering plants were beginning to flourish for the first time on the Cretaceous landscape.翻译:植物进化可能在雄性和雌性蚊子之间的摄食差异中发挥了作用。当这两只蚊子被困在树液中并最终变成琥珀时，白垩纪景观上开花植物第一次开始茂盛。</p>   <p>"In all hematophagous insects, we believe that hematophagy was a shift from plant liquid sucking to bloodsucking," Azar said.翻译:“在所有吸血昆虫中，我们认为吸血是从吸植物液体到吸血的转变，”阿扎尔说。</p>   <p>The fact that these earliest-known mosquitoes are bloodsucking males, Azar added, "means that originally the first mosquitoes were all hematophagous - no matter whether they were males or females - and hematophagy was later lost in males, maybe due to the appearance of flowering plants, which are contemporaneous with the formation of Lebanese amber."翻译:阿扎尔补充说，这些已知最早的蚊子是吸血雄性，“这意味着最初的第一批蚊子都是吸血的——无论它们是雄性还是雌性——后来雄性的吸血能力消失了，可能是因为开花的出现植物，与黎巴嫩琥珀的形成同时发生。”</p>   <p>Plenty of animals were present to provide blood meals: dinosaurs, flying reptiles called pterosaurs, other reptiles, birds and mammals.翻译:许多动物都在场提供血餐：恐龙、翼龙、其他爬行动物、鸟类和哺乳动物。</p>   <p>The researchers said while these are the oldest fossils, mosquitoes probably originated millions of years earlier. They noted that molecular evidence suggests mosquitoes arose during the Jurassic Period, which ran from about 200 million to 145 million years ago.翻译:研究人员表示，虽然这些是最古老的化石，但蚊子可能起源于数百万年前。他们指出，分子证据表明蚊子出现在侏罗纪时期，距今约 2 亿至 1.45 亿年前。</p>   <p>There are more than 3,500 species of mosquitoes worldwide, found everywhere except Antarctica. Some become disease vectors transmitting malaria, yellow fever, Zika fever, dengue and other diseases. According to the World Health Organization, more than 400,000 people die annually from malaria - a parasitic infection - mostly children under age 5.翻译:全世界有超过 3,500 种蚊子，除南极洲外，到处都有蚊子的踪迹。有些成为传播疟疾、黄热病、寨卡热、登革热和其他疾病的疾病媒介。据世界卫生组织称，每年有超过 40 万人死于疟疾（一种寄生虫感染），其中大多数是 5 岁以下的儿童。</p>   <p>"On the other side, mosquitoes help to purify the water in ponds, lakes and rivers," Nel said. "In general, an animal can be a problem but also can be helpful."翻译:“另一方面，蚊子有助于净化池塘、湖泊和河流中的水，”内尔说。 “一般来说，动物可能会带来问题，但也可能会有所帮助。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Will Dunham, Editing by Rosalba O'Brien翻译:威尔·邓纳姆报道，罗萨尔巴·奥布莱恩编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 16:23:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7FQU5DBKPNPBDJ2GPGIYPR3NTQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/science/oldest-mosquito-fossil-comes-with-bloodsucking-surprise-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Will Dunham]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SCIENCE</category>
                
                <category>MOSQUITO/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[全球风电前景因美国疲软和中国经济放缓而受到打击-WoodMac]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/8hqEweXlGKIV4BTbJ3ndGzct8Vo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JB5HXSKNEJKFXH6YO57NZAR3YQ.jpg" alt="Tatanka Wind Farm in Brandt, South Dakota翻译:南达科他州布兰特的塔坦卡风电场" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Acciona Windpower 1.5 MW wind turbine generators are seen on Tatanka Wind Farm as the coronavirus disease (COVID-19) outbreak continues in Brandt, South Dakota, U.S., October 27, 2020. REUTERS/Bing Guan/File Photo翻译:2020 年 10 月 27 日，美国南达科他州布兰特市新型冠状病毒肺炎 (COVID-19) 疫情持续爆发，Tatanka 风电场安装 Acciona Windpower 1.5 兆瓦风力发电机。 REUTERS/Bingguan/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The global wind power sector will add less capacity in the next decade than previously expected due to financial trouble in the U.S. offshore wind industry and sluggish approval and project execution in China, consultancy Wood Mackenzie said on Tuesday.翻译:咨询公司Wood Mackenzie周二表示，由于美国海上风电行业的财务困难以及中国审批和项目执行缓慢，未来十年全球风电行业新增装机容量将低于此前预期。</p>   <p>Orsted <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ORSTED.CO" target="_blank">(ORSTED.CO)</a>, the world's largest offshore windfarm developer, energy giants BP <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BP.L" target="_blank">(BP.L)</a> and Norway's Equinor <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/EQNR.OL" target="_blank">(EQNR.OL)</a> have booked hundreds of millions of dollars worth of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/why-us-offshore-wind-industry-is-doldrums-2023-10-31/">impairments</a> on their U.S. offshore wind power portfolios, citing spiralling financing costs and supply delays.翻译:全球最大的海上风电场开发商 Orsted <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ORSTED.CO" target="_blank">(ORSTED.CO)</a> 、能源巨头 BP <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BP.L" target="_blank">(BP.L)</a>和挪威 Equinor <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/EQNR.OL" target="_blank">(EQNR.OL)</a>已对其美国海上风电投资组合计入价值数亿美元的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/why-us-offshore-wind-industry-is-doldrums-2023-10-31/">减值</a>，理由是螺旋式上升融资成本和供应延迟。</p>   <p>Wood Mackenzie cut by 29 gigawatts (GW) its forecast for global wind power capacity by end-2032, downgrading cumulative installed capacity to 2.35 terawatts.翻译:Wood Mackenzie 将 2032 年底全球风电装机容量预测下调了 29 吉瓦 (GW)，累计装机容量降至 2.35 太瓦。</p>   <p>The downgrade makes up less than a 2% change in expected capacity, with more than 80% of the cut stemming from headwinds including in key markets like the United States and China.翻译:此次降级仅导致预期运力发生不到 2% 的变化，其中超过 80% 的降幅是由于包括美国和中国等主要市场在内的不利因素造成的。</p>   <p>"Long-term market fundamentals remain strong globally despite near-term challenges in project execution in China and offshore market maturation in the U.S.," said Luke Lewandowski, Vice President, Global Renewables Research at Wood Mackenzie said in a statement.翻译:伍德麦肯兹全球可再生能源研究副总裁卢克·莱万多夫斯基(Luke Lewandowski)在一份声明中表示：“尽管中国项目执行和美国离岸市场成熟度近期面临挑战，但全球长期市场基本面仍然强劲。”</p>   <p>Orsted's cancellation of its Ocean Wind project in New Jersey and supply chain issues are expected to push nearly 8 GW of U.S. offshore projects beyond 2032, WoodMac said. This means that the United States will reach around half of its goal to install 30 GW of offshore wind by 2030.翻译:WoodMac 表示，Orsted 取消新泽西州的海洋风电项目以及供应链问题预计将使美国近 8 吉瓦的海上项目推迟到 2032 年之后。这意味着美国将实现到2030年安装30吉瓦海上风电目标的一半左右。</p>   <p>WoodMac said near-term headwinds from a slow Chinese project market led to its 12 GW reduction in the global wind capacity forecast due to tightened permit requirements and project cancellations, but China's onshore wind outlook from 2026 to 2032 remained unchanged despite the short-term challenges.翻译:WoodMac表示，由于许可证要求收紧和项目取消，中国项目市场放缓带来的短期阻力导致全球风电装机容量预测减少12吉瓦，但尽管存在短期挑战，但中国2026年至2032年陆上风电的前景保持不变。</p>    <span>Reporting by Anushree Mukherjee and Deep Vakil in Bengaluru; Editing by Emelia Sithole-Matarise翻译:Anushree Mukherjee 和 Deep Vakil 在班加罗尔的报道；编辑：埃米莉亚·西托尔-马塔里斯</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 16:23:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">KGVQGXGYWROJREZHQVFLEZLIMQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/global-wind-power-outlook-takes-hit-us-weakness-china-slowdown-woodmac-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>WINDPOWER/OUTLOOK</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[穆迪下调中国信贷前景，理由是经济增长放缓和房地产风险]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/WDwjuJTfojue9CkpS7a75cuxrlQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KFAJWWAST5N7RK5QWKER2ZVTLU.jpg" alt="Chinese national flag flutters at the headquarters of a commercial bank on a financial street near the headquarters of the People's Bank of China, China's central bank, in central Beijing翻译:位于北京市中心中国人民银行总部附近的金融街上，中国国旗在一家商业银行总部飘扬" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Chinese national flag flutters at the headquarters of a commercial bank on a financial street near the headquarters of the People's Bank of China, China's central bank, in central Beijing翻译:位于北京市中心中国人民银行总部附近的金融街上，中国国旗在一家商业银行总部飘扬 November 24, 2014. REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/m6X12UWexYPh8qKO7fVksXbuc0Q=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GM262RZCLBJI3K4YRH47BUT2BU.jpg" alt="An Evergrande sign is seen near residential buildings at an Evergrande residential complex in Beijing翻译:北京恒大住宅小区附近的恒大标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An Evergrande sign is seen near residential buildings at an Evergrande residential complex in Beijing翻译:北京恒大住宅小区附近的恒大标志, China September 27, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo翻译:2023 年 9 月 27 日，中国北京恒大住宅小区的住宅楼附近出现了恒大标志。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>Ratings agency Moody's cut its outlook on China's government credit ratings to negative from stable on Tuesday, in the latest sign of mounting global concern over the impact of surging local government debt and a deepening property crisis on the world's second-largest economy.翻译:评级机构穆迪周二将中国政府信用评级展望从稳定下调至负面，这是全球对地方政府债务激增和房地产危机加深对世界第二大经济体影响日益担忧的最新迹象。</p>   <p>The downgrade reflects growing evidence that authorities will have to provide more financial support for debt-laden local governments and state firms, posing broad risks to China's fiscal, economic and institutional strength, Moody's said in a statement.翻译:穆迪在一份声明中表示，此次降级反映了越来越多的证据表明，当局将不得不为负债累累的地方政府和国有企业提供更多财政支持，这对中国的财政、经济和机构实力构成广泛风险。</p>   <p>"The outlook change also reflects the increased risks related to structurally and persistently lower medium-term economic growth and the ongoing downsizing of the property sector," Moody's said.翻译:穆迪表示：“前景的变化还反映出与结构性和持续较低的中期经济增长以及房地产行业持续缩减相关的风险增加。”</p>   <p>China's blue-chip stocks slumped to nearly five-year lows on Tuesday amid worries about the country's growth, with talk of a possible cut by Moody's denting sentiment during the session, while Hong Kong stocks extended losses.翻译:由于对中国经济增长的担忧，中国蓝筹股周二跌至近五年低点，穆迪可能在盘中降息的传闻削弱了市场情绪，而港股则扩大跌幅。</p>   <p>China's major state-owned banks, which had been seen supporting the yuan currency all day, stepped up U.S. dollar selling very forcefully after the Moody's statement, one source with knowledge of the matter said. The yuan was little changed by late afternoon.翻译:一位知情人士称，穆迪发表声明后，中国主要国有银行一整天都在支持人民币，它们加大了美元抛售力度。到下午晚些时候，人民币汇率几乎没有变化。</p>   <p>The cost of insuring China's sovereign debt against a default rose to its highest since mid-November.翻译:中国主权债务违约的保险成本升至11月中旬以来的最高水平。</p>   <p>"Now the markets are more concerned with the property crisis and weak growth, rather than the immediate sovereign debt risk," said Ken Cheung, chief Asian FX strategist at Mizuho Bank in Hong Kong.翻译:瑞穗银行(Mizuho Bank)驻香港首席亚洲外汇策略师Ken Cheung表示，“现在市场更关心房地产危机和增长疲软，而不是眼前的主权债务风险。”</p>   <p>U.S.-listed shares of Chinese companies fell, with Baidu off 0.5%, Alibaba Group Holding down 1.1%, and JD.com dropping 1.9%.翻译:在美上市的中国公司股价下跌，其中百度下跌0.5%，阿里巴巴集团下跌1.1%，京东下跌1.9%。</p>   <p>The move by Moody's was the first change on its China view since it cut its rating by one notch to A1 in 2017, also citing expectations of slowing growth and rising debt.翻译:穆迪此举是自2017年将中国评级下调一级至A1以来首次改变其中国评级，理由也是经济增长放缓和债务上升的预期。</p>   <p>While Moody's <a href="https://tinyurl.com/3e8ttwn4" target="_blank">affirmed</a> China's A1 long-term local and foreign-currency issuer ratings on Tuesday -- saying the economy still has a high shock-absorption capacity -- it said it expects the country's annual GDP growth to slow to 4.0% in 2024 and 2025, and to average 3.8% from 2026 to 2030.翻译:尽管穆迪周二<a href="https://tinyurl.com/3e8ttwn4" target="_blank">确认了</a>中国 A1 长期本外币发行人评级，并表示经济仍具有较高的冲击吸收能力，但预计中国 2024 年和 2025 年 GDP 增速将放缓至 4.0% ，2026 年至 2030 年平均增长 3.8%。</p>   <p>Moody's outlook downgrade comes ahead of the annual agenda-setting Central Economic Work Conference, which is expected around mid-December, with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-govt-advisers-call-steady-growth-target-2024-more-stimulus-2023-11-22/">government advisers</a> calling for a steady growth target for 2024 and more stimulus.翻译:穆迪下调展望是在年度中央经济工作会议召开之前进行的，该会议预计将于 12 月中旬召开， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-govt-advisers-call-steady-growth-target-2024-more-stimulus-2023-11-22/">政府顾问</a>呼吁制定 2024 年稳定增长目标并采取更多刺激措施。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/3-moodys-cuts-china-credit-outlook-2023-12-05/">Analysts</a> say the A1 rating is high enough in investment-grade territory that a downgrade is unlikely to trigger forced selling by global funds. The other two major rating agencies, Fitch and Standard &amp; Poor's, rate China A+, which is equivalent to Moody's. Both have a stable outlook.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/3-moodys-cuts-china-credit-outlook-2023-12-05/">分析师</a>表示，A1 评级在投资级领域已经足够高，降级不太可能引发全球基金的强制抛售。另外两大评级机构惠誉和标准普尔对中国的评级为A+，相当于穆迪。两者的前景都是稳定的。</p>   <p>China's Finance Ministry said it was disappointed by Moody's decision, adding that the economy will maintain its rebound and positive trend. It also said property and local government risks are controllable.翻译:中国财政部表示对穆迪的决定感到失望，并补充说经济将保持反弹和积极的趋势。它还表示，房地产和地方政府风险可控。</p>   <p>"Moody's concerns about China's economic growth prospects, fiscal sustainability and other aspects are unnecessary," the ministry said.</p>    <h 1="">STRUGGLING FOR TRACTION</h>  <p>Most analysts believe China's growth is on track to hit the government's target of around 5% this year, but that compares with a COVID-weakened 2022 and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-activity-surprisingly-expands-november-caixin-pmi-2023-12-01/">activity is highly uneven</a>.翻译:大多数分析师认为，中国今年的经济增长有望达到政府设定的 5% 左右的目标，但与受新冠疫情影响而减弱的 2022 年相比， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-activity-surprisingly-expands-november-caixin-pmi-2023-12-01/">经济活动极不平衡</a>。</p>   <p>The economy has struggled to mount a strong post-pandemic recovery as the deepening crisis in the housing market, local government debt concerns, slowing global growth and geopolitical tensions have dented momentum.翻译:由于房地产市场危机加深、地方政府债务担忧、全球经济增长放缓和地缘政治紧张局势削弱了经济增长势头，经济在疫情后难以实现强劲复苏。</p>   <p>A flurry of policy support measures have proven only modestly beneficial, raising pressure on authorities to roll out more stimulus.翻译:事实证明，一系列政策支持措施的效果有限，这加大了当局推出更多刺激措施的压力。</p>   <p>"We spent the better part of three years watching China have this sort of off-and-on reopening from the pandemic, and this was the year they finally sort of officially reopened," said Art Hogan, chief market strategist at B Riley Wealth in New York. "But the pace at which the economy has recovered from that has been disappointing."翻译:B Riley Wealth 首席市场策略师阿特·霍根 (Art Hogan) 表示：“我们花了三年的大部分时间看着中国从疫情中断断续续地重新开放，今年他们终于正式重新开放了。”纽约。 “但经济从中复苏的速度令人失望。”</p>   <p>Analysts widely agree that China's growth is downshifting from breakneck expansion in the past few decades. Many believe Beijing needs to transform its economic model from an over-reliance on debt-fuelled investment to one driven more by consumer demand.翻译:分析人士普遍认为，中国的增长速度正在从过去几十年的高速扩张中放缓。许多人认为，北京需要将其经济模式从过度依赖债务驱动的投资转变为更多由消费者需求驱动的经济模式。</p>   <p>Last week, China's central bank head <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">Pan Gongsheng</a> pledged to keep monetary policy accommodative to support the economy, but also urged structural reforms to reduce a reliance on infrastructure and property for growth.</p>    <h 1="">DEEPER IN DEBT</h>  <p>After years of over-investment, plummeting returns from land sales, and soaring costs to battle COVID, economists say debt-laden municipalities now represent a major risk to the economy.翻译:经济学家表示，经过多年的过度投资、土地出售回报大幅下降以及抗击新冠疫情的成本飙升，负债累累的城市现在对经济构成了重大风险。</p>   <p>Local government debt reached 92 trillion yuan ($12.6 trillion), or 76% of China's economic output in 2022, up from 62.2% in 2019, according to the latest data from the International Monetary Fund (IMF).翻译:国际货币基金组织 (IMF) 的最新数据显示，到 2022 年，地方政府债务将达到 92 万亿元人民币（12.6 万亿美元），占中国经济产出的 76%，高于 2019 年的 62.2%。</p>   <p>In October, China unveiled a plan to issue 1 trillion yuan ($139.84 billion) in sovereign bonds by the end of the year to help kick-start activity, raising the 2023 budget deficit target to 3.8% of gross domestic product (GDP) from the original 3%.翻译:10 月，中国公布了一项计划，将在年底前发行 1 万亿元人民币（合 1,398.4 亿美元）的主权债券，以帮助启动经济活动，将 2023 年预算赤字目标从占国内生产总值 (GDP) 的 3.8% 提高到原来的3%。</p>   <p>The central bank has also implemented modest interest rate cuts and pumped more cash into the economy in recent months.翻译:近几个月来，央行还实施了小幅降息并向经济注入更多现金。</p>   <p>Nevertheless, foreign investors have been sour on China almost all year.翻译:尽管如此，外国投资者几乎全年都对中国持不满态度。</p>   <p>Capital outflows from China rose sharply to $75 billion in September, the biggest monthly figure since 2016, according to Goldman Sachs.翻译:高盛(Goldman Sachs)的数据显示，9月份中国的资本外流大幅增至750亿美元，这是自2016年以来的最大月度数字。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1430 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.1430 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Gnaneshwar Rajan and Shristi Achar A in Bengaluru, Kevin Yao in Beijing and Lewis Krauskopf in New York; Editing by Tom Hogue, Kim Coghill and Nick Zieminski翻译:Gnaneshwar Rajan 和 Shristi Achar A 在班加罗尔、Kevin Yao 在北京和 Lewis Krauskopf 在纽约报道；汤姆·霍格 (Tom Hogue)、金·科吉尔 (Kim Coghill) 和尼克·齐明斯基 (Nick Zieminski) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 15:59:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">HTBZLY6F25MIRP4TUL2HPOA6NU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/moodys-cuts-chinas-credit-outlook-negative-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>MOODY&#39;S/OUTLOOK (UPDATE 6, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[英国卡梅伦与中国易纲讨论建立“建设性关系”的意图]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tCqZbiNCsY6n7NUpJbQub3NJSs4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WJ4XV4QKZVKCBMRVRP6ABPY5D4.jpg" alt="Cabinet meeting at Number 10 Downing Street, in London翻译:内阁会议在伦敦唐宁街 10 号举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>British Foreign Secretary David Cameron leaves Number 10 Downing Street after a Cabinet meeting in London, Britain, December 5, 2023. REUTERS/Hollie Adams翻译:2023 年 12 月 5 日，英国外交大臣戴维·卡梅伦在英国伦敦举行内阁会议后离开唐宁街 10 号。REUTERS/Hollie Adams</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0r779RfG6e_ZvKrHAE-XXlvrw9s=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PE7B3HRFU5IX7HW66UOBQHU3TA.jpg" alt="Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi sign condolence book for Henry Kissinger at the U.S. embassy, in Beijing翻译:中国外交部长王毅在北京美国大使馆为亨利·基辛格签署吊唁簿" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi leaves after signing a condolence book for the late Henry Kissinger at the U.S. embassy in Beijing, Tuesday, Dec. 5, 2023.   Ng Han Guan/Pool via REUTERS翻译:2023 年 12 月 5 日星期二，中国外交部长王毅在美国驻北京大使馆为已故亨利·基辛格签署吊唁书后离开。Ng Hanguan / Pool via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>               <p>British Foreign Secretary David Cameron said he had spoken to his Chinese counterpart Wang Yi on Tuesday and the pair discussed their "intention to have a constructive relationship".翻译:英国外交大臣戴维·卡梅伦表示，他周二已与中国外长王毅进行了交谈，两人讨论了“建立建设性关系的意图”。</p>   <p>"The UK will continue to engage with China where it furthers our interests," Cameron said in a post on X, adding that they had also discussed the situation in Israel and Gaza, and the war in Ukraine.翻译:卡梅伦在 X 上的一篇帖子中表示：“英国将继续与中国接触，以促进我们的利益。”他补充说，他们还讨论了以色列和加沙的局势以及乌克兰的战争。</p>   <p>Prime Minister Rishi Sunak's appointment of former British leader Cameron as foreign minister last month caused concern among some lawmakers in his Conservative Party about what it would mean for the government's approach to China.翻译:英国首相苏纳克上个月任命前英国领导人卡梅伦为外交部长，引起保守党内一些议员的担忧，担心这对政府对华政策意味着什么。</p>   <p>As prime minister, Cameron heralded a "golden era" in relations with China in 2015, something Sunak has said is over. Sunak has instead sought to balance national security interests with better cooperation on trade and climate change.翻译:作为首相，卡梅伦预示着 2015 年与中国关系的“黄金时代”，而苏纳克则表示这一时代已经结束。相反，苏纳克寻求在国家安全利益与贸易和气候变化方面更好的合作之间取得平衡。</p>    <span>Reporting by Kylie MacLellan and Sarah Young; Editing by Kate Holton翻译:凯莉·麦克莱伦和莎拉·杨的报道；凯特·霍尔顿 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 15:06:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">XVKRUH5VGZI3PPU5NDBEL6WW7A</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/uks-cameron-chinas-yi-discussed-intention-have-constructive-relationship-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>BRITAIN</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[如果实施制裁，莫斯科交易所将停止美元交易]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ZGlahKOu6SILNgfWCPXPtEo-LUw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GP5KPIBR6FNA5NYJOFGLCR7I4Y.jpg" alt="A view shows the headquarters of Moscow Exchange翻译:莫斯科交易所总部视图" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An interior view shows the headquarters of Moscow Exchange in the city of Moscow, Russia, December 14, 2022. REUTERS/Shamil Zhumatov/File Photo翻译:2022 年 12 月 14 日，俄罗斯莫斯科市莫斯科交易所总部的内部景观。路透社/Shamil Zhumatov/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Moscow Exchange <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MOEX.MM" target="_blank">(MOEX.MM)</a>, Russia's largest bourse, said on Tuesday it would halt trading in the U.S. dollar should sanctions be imposed, after Washington targeted another Russian exchange, SPB, with restrictive measures last month.翻译:俄罗斯最大的交易所莫斯科交易所<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MOEX.MM" target="_blank">(MOEX.MM)</a>周二表示，在华盛顿上个月对另一家俄罗斯交易所SPB采取限制措施后，如果实施制裁，该交易所将停止美元交易。</p>   <p>The U.S. Treasury in early November targeted SPB, Russia's second-largest stock exchange as part of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/russias-spb-exchange-clients-get-third-fx-funds-back-after-us-sanctions-2023-11-28/">sweeping new measures</a> that also aim to curb Russia's future energy capabilities and sanctions evasion. Some Russian market players believe Moscow Exchange could be targeted next.翻译:美国财政部11月初将俄罗斯第二大证券交易所SPB列为<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/russias-spb-exchange-clients-get-third-fx-funds-back-after-us-sanctions-2023-11-28/">全面新措施的一部分，这些新措施</a>的目的还在于遏制俄罗斯未来的能源能力和逃避制裁的行为。一些俄罗斯市场参与者认为，莫斯科交易所可能是下一个目标。</p>   <p>The sanctions forced SPB, which specialises in trading foreign shares, to halt trading of shares on its exchange and tweak its strategy to focus on settlements in roubles. More than two thirds of clients' foreign currency funds are now <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/russias-spb-exchange-clients-get-third-fx-funds-back-after-us-sanctions-2023-11-28/">blocked</a>.翻译:制裁迫使专门从事外国股票交易的 SPB 停止其交易所的股票交易，并调整策略以专注于卢布结算。目前，超过三分之二的客户外币资金被<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/russias-spb-exchange-clients-get-third-fx-funds-back-after-us-sanctions-2023-11-28/">冻结</a>。</p>   <p>"The U.S. dollar will not be traded if there are American sanctions, but it no longer plays such a role in the structure of the exchange's FX market (as it used to)," Igor Marich of Moscow Exchange told reporters.翻译:莫斯科交易所的伊戈尔·马里奇（Igor Marich）对记者表示：“如果美国实施制裁，美元将无法交易，但它在交易所外汇市场结构中不再发挥作用（像以前那样）。”</p>   <p>"The central bank in this case can count on the official exchange rate on over-the-counter transactions."翻译:“在这种情况下，央行可以依靠场外交易的官方汇率。”</p>   <p>The USD/RUB currency pair accounted for 78% of trading on Moscow Exchange in the first quarter of 2022. In October-November 2023, its share of trading was 32%, exchange data showed.翻译:2022年第一季度，美元/卢布货币对占莫斯科交易所交易量的78%。交易所数据显示，2023年10月至2023年11月，其交易量占比为32%。</p>   <p>Meanwhile, China's yuan has become the largest player. From a share of 1% in early 2022, CNY/RUB now accounts for 43% of trading on Moscow's FX market.翻译:与此同时，中国的人民币已成为最大的参与者。人民币/卢布从 2022 年初的 1% 上升到目前占莫斯科外汇市场交易量的 43%。</p>    <span>Reporting by Elena Fabrichnaya; Writing by Alexander Marrow; Editing by Susan Fenton翻译:埃琳娜·法布里纳亚 (Elena Fabrichnaya) 报道；亚历山大·马罗 (Alexander Marrow) 撰写；苏珊·芬顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 15:05:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">36IEFHYWCZPSDCLHIWZENLFURM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/moscow-exchange-would-halt-usd-trading-if-sanctions-imposed-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>RUSSIA</category>
                
                <category>MOEX/SANCTIONS</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国恒大收到有关其2.8亿美元追偿索赔的法院通知]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/y4PSDoQD1KfOqsOZjMuMFzUkWU8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YTDVTB5G3VNMNKYABRQG6VLK4A.jpg" alt="Headquarters of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen翻译:中国恒大集团深圳总部" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A crane stands at a construction site near the headquarters of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen, Guangdong province, China, Sept. 26, 2021. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2021 年 9 月 26 日，中国广东省深圳市中国恒大集团总部附近的一个建筑工地上，一台起重机停在工地。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China Evergrande Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a> said on Tuesday it received notices from court of Guangdong Province over a claim by a unit of Evergrande Property Services for the recovery of about 2 billion yuan ($280 million) in deposit certificate pledge guarantees.翻译:中国恒大集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）</a>周二表示，收到广东省法院的通知，要求恒大物业服务旗下子公司追回约20亿元人民币（合2.8亿美元）的存单质押担保。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-evergrande-unit-commences-legal-proceedings-against-parent-2023-11-28/">proceedings</a> brought by unit Jinbi Property Management Company are related to the enforcement of Evergrande Property Services' <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">(6666.HK)</a> deposit pledge of about 13.4 billion yuan.翻译:单位金碧物业管理公司提起的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-evergrande-unit-commences-legal-proceedings-against-parent-2023-11-28/">诉讼</a>涉及恒大物业<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">（6666.HK）</a>约134亿元存款质押的执行。</p>   <p>The embattled property developer said the notices regarding the claim also includes an estimated interest of 152.1 million yuan.翻译:这家陷入困境的房地产开发商表示，有关索赔的通知还包括预计利息1.521亿元人民币。</p>   <p>Last week, Evergrande Property Services received a notice from the Guangzhou Intermediate People's Court of Guangdong Province formally accepting the filing of the case.翻译:上周，恒大物业收到广东省广州市中级人民法院正式立案通知书。</p>   <p>Parent Evergrande had said in February it was in talks with Evergrande Property Services to repay the funds.翻译:母公司恒大二月份曾表示，正在与恒大物业就偿还资金进行谈判。</p>   <p>In July 2022, Evergrande's chief executive and its finance head resigned after a preliminary probe found their involvement in diverting loans secured by Evergrande Property Services.翻译:2022年7月，恒大首席执行官和财务负责人在初步调查发现涉嫌挪用恒大物业担保贷款后辞职。</p>   <p>Evergrande was investigating how deposits worth 13.4 billion yuan belonging to Evergrande Property Services were used as collateral for pledge guarantees and seized by banks.翻译:恒大正在调查恒大物业的134亿元存款如何被用作质押担保的抵押品，并被银行扣押。</p>   <p>Evergrande said it would seek legal advice regarding the notices.翻译:恒大表示将就这些通知寻求法律意见。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1429 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.1429 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Ayushman Ojha翻译:阿尤斯曼·奥贾报道</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 14:48:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2IVIANYWBVIC5FVCRJV5OI2OPM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-gets-court-notice-regarding-units-recovery-claim-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/DEBT</category>
                
                <category>EVERGRANDE (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 穆迪下调中国信用前景]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/WDwjuJTfojue9CkpS7a75cuxrlQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KFAJWWAST5N7RK5QWKER2ZVTLU.jpg" alt="Chinese national flag flutters at the headquarters of a commercial bank on a financial street near the headquarters of the People's Bank of China, China's central bank, in central Beijing翻译:位于北京市中心中国人民银行总部附近的金融街上，中国国旗在一家商业银行总部飘扬" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Chinese national flag flutters at the headquarters of a commercial bank on a financial street near the headquarters of the People's Bank of China, China's central bank, in central Beijing翻译:位于北京市中心中国人民银行总部附近的金融街上，中国国旗在一家商业银行总部飘扬 November 24, 2014. REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/m6X12UWexYPh8qKO7fVksXbuc0Q=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GM262RZCLBJI3K4YRH47BUT2BU.jpg" alt="An Evergrande sign is seen near residential buildings at an Evergrande residential complex in Beijing翻译:北京恒大住宅小区附近的恒大标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An Evergrande sign is seen near residential buildings at an Evergrande residential complex in Beijing翻译:北京恒大住宅小区附近的恒大标志, China September 27, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo翻译:2023 年 9 月 27 日，中国北京恒大住宅小区的住宅楼附近出现了恒大标志。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>Ratings agency Moody's cut its outlook on China's government credit ratings to negative from stable on Tuesday, in the latest sign of mounting global concern over the impact of surging local government debt and a deepening property crisis on the world's second-largest economy.翻译:评级机构穆迪周二将中国政府信用评级展望从稳定下调至负面，这是全球对地方政府债务激增和房地产危机加深对世界第二大经济体影响日益担忧的最新迹象。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/moodys-cuts-chinas-credit-outlook-negative-2023-12-05/"> read more </a>翻译:评级机构穆迪周二将中国政府信用评级展望从稳定下调至负面，这是全球对地方政府债务激增和房地产危机加深对世界第二大经济体影响日益担忧的最新迹象。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/moodys-cuts-chinas-credit-outlook-negative-2023-12-05/">阅读更多</a></p>   <p>COMMENTS:</p>    <h 1="">JAKOB EKHOLDT CHRISTENSEN, SENIOR EM STRATEGIST, BANKINVEST, DENMARK</h>  <p>"From Moody's side, what's challenging is the lower growth perspectives, both in terms of the debt overhang that's weighing on economic growth potential, but also foreign investors pulling out of China and the tightening of U.S. sanctions."</p>    <h 1="">WIN THIN, GLOBAL HEAD OF CURRENCY STRATEGY, BROWN BROTHERS HARRIMAN, NEW YORK</h>  <p>"We have been expecting downward pressure on the sovereign rating after the PBOC finally acknowledged earlier this year that China’s debt to GDP ratio was approaching 300%. Moody’s last downgraded China’s sovereign rating in 2017 to A1 vs. Aa3 previously due to the rising debt load."</p>    <h 1="">ART HOGAN, CHIEF MARKET STRATEGIST, B RILEY WEALTH, NEW YORK</h>  <p>"We spent the better part of three years watching China have this sort of off and on reopening from the pandemic, and this was the year they finally sort of officially reopened. But the pace at which the economy has recovered from that has been disappointing. They're doing everything they can to try to stimulate economic growth, but it just hasn't worked yet."翻译:“我们花了三年的大部分时间看着中国从大流行中断断续续地重新开放，今年他们终于正式重新开放。但经济从中复苏的速度令人失望。他们正在尽一切努力刺激经济增长，但还没有奏效。”</p>   <p>"It's important to note that the second largest economy in the world struggling is likely going to affect the global economy. If they continue to struggle well into next year and aren't able to find the right formula to stimulate the economic growth, it's going to be a problem for the global economy and likely to be a headwind."翻译:“值得注意的是，世界第二大经济体的困境可能会影响全球经济。如果他们在明年继续陷入困境，并且无法找到刺激经济增长的正确方案，那么他们就会陷入困境。”成为全球经济的一个问题，并可能成为逆风。”</p>   <p>CHRIS SCICLUNA, HEAD OF RESEARCH DIVISION, DAIWA CAPITAL MARKETS, LONDON:翻译:CHRIS SCICLUNA，伦敦 DAIWA CAPITAL MARKETS 研究部主管：</p>   <p>"The market realises that China is reluctant to provide stimulus.翻译:“市场意识到中国不愿提供刺激措施。</p>   <p>"So, China is data dependent and will only provide stimulus if there is not a recovery.翻译:“因此，中国依赖数据，只有在没有复苏的情况下才会提供刺激。</p>   <p>"I wouldn't expect the Chinese authorities to respond to a foreign ratings agency's actions.翻译:“我不认为中国当局会对外国评级机构的行为做出回应。</p>   <p>"In a way, the move is a lagged indicator in terms of how markets have already reacted to China and foreign investors have taken an arms length approach to the country翻译:“在某种程度上，这一举措是一个滞后指标，表明市场对中国的反应以及外国投资者对中国采取了一定的距离</p>   <p>"So this is a little bit behind the curve."翻译:“所以这有点落后于曲线。”</p>   <p>VICTORIA SCHOLAR, HEAD OF INVESTMENT, INTERACTIVE INVESTOR, LEEDS, UK (email)翻译:VICTORIA SCHOLAR，英国利兹 INTERACTIVE INVESTOR 投资主管（电子邮件）</p>   <p>“Moody’s has cut China’s government credit rating to negative from stable. The ratings agency says this reflects the risks related to its persistently lower medium-term economic growth and ongoing downsizing of the property sector. It expects China’s annual GDP to come in at 4% in 2024 and 2025 and average 3.8% between 2026 and 2030. China’s finance ministry said it is disappointed by the downgrade and said Moody’s concerns are unnecessary."翻译:“穆迪已将中国政府信用评级从稳定下调至负面。该评级机构表示，这反映了与中期经济增长持续较低和房地产行业持续缩减相关的风险。预计2024年和2025年中国GDP年均增长4%，2026年至2030年平均增长3.8%。中国财政部表示对评级下调感到失望，并表示穆迪的担忧是不必要的。</p>   <p>"China has struggled with a bumpier than expected post covid recovery. It has been grappling with weak demand, an embattled property sector, declining imports and exports, and heavy debts from long-term infrastructure spending. The government has stopped publishing youth unemployment figures, after they hit a record high in the summer. While the authorities have been attempting to bolster demand through stimulus measures, more needs to be done to support the world’s second largest economy particularly amid the backdrop of sluggish global demand.”翻译:“中国在新冠疫情后的复苏中遇到了比预期更为坎坷的困境。它一直在努力应对需求疲软、房地产行业陷入困境、进出口下降以及长期基础设施支出带来的沉重债务的问题。政府已停止发布青年失业率数据， “在夏季创下历史新高后。尽管当局一直试图通过刺激措施提振需求，但仍需要采取更多措施来支持世界第二大经济体，特别是在全球需求低迷的背景下。”</p>    <span>Compiled by the Global Finance &amp; Markets Breaking News team翻译:由全球金融与市场突发新闻团队编译</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 14:27:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F3CS5ZFNTZNPTBT32IBWNDWA44</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/3-moodys-cuts-china-credit-outlook-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>MOODY&#39;S/OUTLOOK (QUOTES 3)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[香港活动人士称，对自由的渴望导致她逃往加拿大]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/laUf3kgYhbBkIPbar5uvaFR8f18=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MNVS5CZOTFNP5KGD7RTSXMA3ZY.jpg" alt="Pro-democracy activist Agnes Chow releases from prison after serving nearly seven months for her role in an unauthorised assembly during the city's 2019 anti-government protests, in Hong Kong翻译:民主活动人士周庭因在 2019 年香港反政府抗议期间参与未经授权的集会而入狱近七个月后出狱" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Pro-democracy activist Agnes Chow releases from prison after serving nearly seven months for her role in an unauthorised assembly during the city's 2019 anti-government protests, in Hong Kong翻译:民主活动人士周庭因在 2019 年香港反政府抗议期间参与未经授权的集会而入狱近七个月后出狱, China June 12, 2021. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Hong Kong pro-democracy activist Agnes Chow, who fled to Canada while free on bail, says she won't return home amid a crackdown that curbed her freedoms, defying a warning from Hong Kong's leader that she would be pursued for life.翻译:香港民主活动人士周庭在保释期间逃往加拿大，她表示，在一场限制她自由的镇压中，她不会回家，无视香港领导人关于她将被终身追捕的警告。</p>   <p>Chow said that she faced intense scrutiny from authorities for several years and that with her passport confiscated, she constantly lived in fear and had to remain silent.翻译:周说，她多年来一直面临当局的严格审查，护照被没收，她一直生活在恐惧之中，不得不保持沉默。</p>   <p>"I feel like I was forced to stay in such kind of severe environment that I couldn't escape," said Chow, who spoke from Toronto, where she has been for three months.翻译:“我觉得我被迫呆在如此严峻的环境中，无法逃脱，”周女士在多伦多说道，她已经在那里呆了三个月了。</p>   <p>"In consideration of the political situation in Hong Kong and my personal health, my mental health, my physical health, and the high political risk of not being allowed to leave Hong Kong again, I've decided not to go back."翻译:“考虑到香港的政治局势以及我的个人健康、心理健康、身体健康，以及不被允许再次离开香港的高政治风险，我决定不再回去。”</p>   <p>Chow was released <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-democracy-activist-agnes-chow-released-prison-2021-06-12/">from prison in June 2021</a> after being jailed for unauthorised assembly.翻译:周先生因未经授权集会<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-democracy-activist-agnes-chow-released-prison-2021-06-12/">入狱，于 2021 年 6 月出狱</a>。</p>   <p>But a separate allegation of collusion with foreign forces under a China-imposed national security law meant her passport was confiscated, her movements closely monitored, and she had difficulties finding a full-time job, opening a bank account or renting an apartment.翻译:但根据中国实施的国家安全法，另一项与外国势力勾结的指控意味着她的护照被没收，她的行动受到严密监控，而且她很难找到全职工作、开立银行账户或租房。</p>   <p>The security law has drawn criticism from Western governments as a tool of repression, but China says it has restored stability after mass pro-democracy protests in 2019.翻译:该国安法因作为镇压工具而受到西方政府的批评，但中国表示，该法在 2019 年大规模民主抗议活动后恢复了稳定。</p>   <p>Chow said the fear of being jailed again meant she suffered from panic attacks, and she was diagnosed with depression and post-traumatic stress disorder at a time when authorities continued to make more arrests - with many fellow democrats <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/landmark-hong-kong-national-security-case-verdict-expected-3-4-months-judge-2023-11-29/">facing stiff jail terms</a> or forced into exile.翻译:周说，由于担心再次入狱，她遭受了恐慌，她被诊断出患有抑郁症和创伤后应激障碍，当时当局继续逮捕更多人，许多民主党同僚<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/landmark-hong-kong-national-security-case-verdict-expected-3-4-months-judge-2023-11-29/">面临严厉的监禁</a>或被迫流亡。</p>   <p>Hong Kong authorities agreed to allow her to travel to Toronto for a master's degree programme this year, but only if she agreed to a one-day trip to the Chinese city of Shenzhen, where Chow said she was chaperoned by five police officers and photographed at a "patriotic" exhibition showcasing China's achievements, and the headquarters of technology firm Tencent.翻译:香港当局同意她今年前往多伦多攻读硕士学位，但前提是她同意前往中国深圳进行一日游。周说，她在深圳有五名警察陪同，并在展示中国成就的“爱国”展览，以及科技公司腾讯的总部。</p>   <p>She said she was required to write and sign several letters her police handlers had drafted, including one of repentance and one of thanks to authorities.翻译:她说，她被要求写下并签署几封她的警察起草的信，其中包括一封悔罪信和一封对当局的感谢信。</p>   <p>A cheaper flight Chow intended to book that transited through Japan - where she has a sizable following - was deemed unacceptable by police, and she had to buy a direct flight to Toronto.翻译:周原本打算预订一架经日本转机的更便宜的航班——她在日本拥有大量粉丝——但警方认为不可接受，她不得不购买直飞多伦多的航班。</p>   <p>"The national security police are not doing their job according to the legal system in Hong Kong," she told Reuters.翻译:“国安警察没有按照香港的法律制度履行职责，”她告诉路透社。</p>   <p>Hong Kong leader John Lee on Tuesday described Chow as a "liar" and "devoid of integrity".翻译:香港特首李家超周二称周恩来是“骗子”和“缺乏诚信”。</p>   <p>"The police will do their utmost to pursue her, to arrest her. Fugitives will be pursued for life," Lee told reporters.翻译:“警方将尽最大努力追捕她，逮捕她。逃犯将被终身追捕，”李告诉记者。</p>   <p>This year, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-police-issue-arrest-warrants-eight-activists-2023-07-03/">Hong Kong police issued arrest warrants</a> and bounties of HK$1 million ($127,656) for eight overseas activists, including Nathan Law and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/wanted-hong-kong-activist-fears-safety-hopes-us-asylum-2023-07-13/">Anna Kwok</a>, saying their assets would be frozen where possible.翻译:今年， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-police-issue-arrest-warrants-eight-activists-2023-07-03/">香港警方</a>对包括罗冠聪和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/wanted-hong-kong-activist-fears-safety-hopes-us-asylum-2023-07-13/">郭安娜在内</a>的八名海外活动人士发出逮捕令，并悬赏 100 万港元（合 127,656 美元），并表示将尽可能冻结他们的资产。</p>   <p>A request for comment from Hong Kong's police and security bureau wasn't immediately answered.翻译:香港警察和保安局的置评请求没有立即得到回复。</p>   <p>"I hope that my story could remind everyone in the world that ... there are still many, many, many people in Hong Kong being sent to prison, being suppressed, not able to even to speak a word," said Chow, who was dressed in a yellow hoodie and turned 27 on Sunday.翻译:“我希望我的故事能够提醒世界上每个人……香港还有很多很多人被送进监狱，被镇压，甚至不能说话，”周说。周日，她身穿黄色连帽衫，27 岁了。</p>   <p>"To be freed physically and mentally," is my birthday wish, she added.翻译:“身心得到解放”是我的生日愿望，她补充道。</p>    <span>Writing by James Pomfret; Editing by Gerry Doyle翻译:詹姆斯·庞弗雷特 (James Pomfret) 撰写；格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 12:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZBTJFOJEZJNXLO7Q5G3HHQPYHE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/hong-kong-activist-says-desire-freedom-led-her-flee-canada-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jessie Pang, Joyce Zhou]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HONGKONG</category>
                
                <category>SECURITY/ACTIVIST (TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[倍耐力高管排除沙特主权基金入股公司的可能性]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/WIV8GuuL84yY-JSy8j7NKC-QaIU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/QTCIKMOTBBJ6PBCXDRFTSKXOY4.jpg" alt="A tyre produced by the Italian company Pirelli is on display at a dealership in Moscow翻译:莫斯科一家经销商展示意大利倍耐力公司生产的轮胎" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A tyre produced by the Italian company Pirelli is on display at a dealership in Moscow翻译:莫斯科一家经销商展示意大利倍耐力公司生产的轮胎, Russia, March 23, 2023. REUTERS/Maxim Shemetov/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Saudi Arabia's Public Investment Fund (PIF) will not take a stake in Italy's Pirelli <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PIRC.MI" target="_blank">(PIRC.MI)</a>, the tyremaker's Executive Vice Chairman Marco Tronchetti Provera said on Tuesday.翻译:意大利倍耐力 ( <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PIRC.MI" target="_blank">PIRC.MI) 执行副主席 Marco Tronchetti Provera 周二表示，沙特阿拉伯公共投资基金 (PIF) 将不会入股意大利倍耐力 (PIRC.MI)</a> 。</p>   <p>"It's what you see, there's nothing more," he said referring to Pirelli's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/italys-pirelli-make-tyres-saudi-arabia-with-saudi-wealth-fund-2023-10-26/">joint venture</a> with the Saudi sovereign wealth fund to build a tyre manufacturing facility in the Gulf country.翻译:“这就是你所看到的，仅此而已，”他指的是倍耐力与沙特主权财富基金在这个海湾国家建立轮胎制造工厂的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/italys-pirelli-make-tyres-saudi-arabia-with-saudi-wealth-fund-2023-10-26/">合资企业</a>。</p>   <p>"There isn't going to be anything else," Tronchetti Provera said when asked about a potential entry of PIF in Pirelli's shareholding.翻译:当被问及 PIF 是否有可能入股倍耐力时，Tronchetti Provera 表示：“不会再有其他事情了。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Giulio Piovaccari, writing by Federico Maccioni, editing by Giulia Segreti翻译:朱利奥·皮奥瓦卡里报道，费德里科·马乔尼撰稿，朱利亚·塞格雷蒂编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 11:51:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">EQPFCY4XTVJCNNLZINMVXINZWE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/pirelli-rules-out-saudi-sovereign-fund-taking-stake-company-exec-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>PIRELLI</category>
                
                <category>SAUDI/ (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[上海希望微软在城市推广人工智能技术 - 政府]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/i8-tpyDIz2TXvRDjuNeJ8201cH8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SFPBDB5N4BMUREWIJYTLMJZPAA.jpg" alt="A Microsoft sign at the U.S. tech giant's offices in Issy-les-Moulineaux, near Paris翻译:微软位于巴黎附近伊西莱穆利诺的美国科技巨头办公室的标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Microsoft sign at the U.S. tech giant's offices in Issy-les-Moulineaux, near Paris翻译:微软位于巴黎附近伊西莱穆利诺的美国科技巨头办公室的标志, France, January 25, 2023. REUTERS/Gonzalo Fuentes/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Shanghai authorities told Microsoft's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O" target="_blank">(MSFT.O)</a> visiting president on Tuesday they want his company to promote artificial intelligence technology to boost businesses there, the Chinese financial hub's government said.翻译:中国金融中心政府表示，上海当局周二告诉微软<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O" target="_blank">(MSFT.O)</a>来访的总裁，他们希望微软推广人工智能技术，以促进当地业务。</p>   <p>Chen Jining, Shanghai's Communist party Secretary, made the remarks while meeting Microsoft President and Vice Chair Brad Smith, the government said.翻译:政府表示，上海市委书记陈吉宁是在会见微软总裁兼副主席布拉德·史密斯时发表上述言论的。</p>   <p>Shanghai was also open to Microsoft collaborating on studying technology-related governance frameworks and standards, Chen said.翻译:陈说，上海也对微软合作研究技术相关的治理框架和标准持开放态度。</p>    <span>Reporting by Beijing Newsroom;翻译:北京新闻编辑室报道；</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 11:28:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BC6OCONVSZI2DFI4KKBJXKZYFM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/shanghai-wants-microsoft-promote-ai-tech-city-govt-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>MICROSOFT/SHANGHAI (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早盘竞价：小盘股接力棒，中国评级受挫]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/62vGAaRqH6qGE2_nwzAHQijjnaE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2K5MG2S3UFJOHNIKLKWA57OI2Q.jpg" alt="Traders work on the floor of the NYSE in New York翻译:交易员在纽约证券交易所工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Traders work on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) in New York City, U.S., September 26, 2023.  REUTERS/Brendan McDermid/File Photo翻译:2023 年 9 月 26 日，交易员在美国纽约市纽约证券交易所 (NYSE) 的交易大厅内工作。REUTERS/Brendan McDermid/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A look at the day ahead in U.S. and global markets from Mike Dolan翻译:迈克·多兰 (Mike Dolan) 对美国和全球市场未来一天的展望</p>   <p>As the S&amp;P500 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-dip-focus-shifts-economic-data-policy-cues-2023-12-04/">stalled</a> on Monday at its high for the year, taking a breather from last week's 'peak rates' rally, smaller U.S. stocks picked up the baton and are playing catchup into the yearend.翻译:随着标准普尔 500 指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a>周一在年内高点<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-dip-focus-shifts-economic-data-policy-cues-2023-12-04/">停滞不前</a>，从上周的“峰值利率”反弹中稍作喘息，美国小型股接起了接力棒，并在年底前奋力追赶。</p>   <p>Global stock markets were off somewhat again on Tuesday, with Moody's decision to cut the outlook for <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/moodys-cuts-chinas-credit-outlook-negative-2023-12-05/">China's sovereign</a> credit rating on Tuesday adding even more pressure to the year's alarming market underperformance <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI300" target="_blank">(.CSI300)</a> there and clocking a five-year closing low for its benchmark stock index.翻译:全球股市周二再次小幅下跌，穆迪周二决定下调<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/moodys-cuts-chinas-credit-outlook-negative-2023-12-05/">中国主权</a>信用评级前景，这给今年令人震惊的市场表现不佳<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI300" target="_blank">（.CSI300）</a>带来了更大的压力，并创下了五年来收盘新低。股票指数。</p>   <p>Monday proved to be a step back for the main U.S. stock indices <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a> and bond markets as they consolidated last week's surge on hopes the Federal Reserve is finally done tightening and ready to ease in 2024.翻译:事实证明，周一美国主要股指<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a>和债券市场出现了回调，因为人们希望美联储最终完成紧缩政策并准备在 2024 年放松货币政策，从而巩固了上周的飙升势头。</p>   <p>But while some suspect the rates market ebullience may have jumped the gun - and two Fed cuts by June are still more than fully priced - the emphasis merely shifted to small caps that have underperformed all year due to a disproportionate hit from higher borrowing costs.翻译:不过，尽管一些人怀疑利率市场的热情可能有些过头了——而且美联储六月份之前的两次降息仍然超出了市场的充分消化——但重点只是转移到了全年表现不佳的小盘股，因为借贷成本上升造成了不成比例的打击。</p>   <p>As the S&amp;P500 fell back about 0.5% from Friday's 2023 closing peak, the Russell 2000 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.RUT" target="_blank">(.RUT)</a> raced 1% higher to its highest in three months - and is now clocking annual gains of close to 7%.翻译:随着标准普尔 500 指数从周五 2023 年收盘峰值回落约 0.5%，罗素 2000 指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.RUT" target="_blank">(.RUT)</a>上涨 1%，达到三个月来的最高水平，目前年涨幅接近 7%。</p>   <p>While that's still less than half the main benchmark, a late year rotation in search of value seems to be on - with the year's megacap tech winners scaling back a bit.翻译:虽然这仍不到主要基准的一半，但年底似乎开始寻找价值——今年的大型科技股获胜者规模有所缩减。</p>   <p>The New York FANG+TM index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.NYFANG" target="_blank">(.NYFANG)</a> of tech and digital giants has now fallen back for four sessions in a row, shaving about 3% off its peaks since the start of the month but still sustaining eye-popping 82% year-to-date gains.翻译:科技和数字巨头纽约 FANG+TM 指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.NYFANG" target="_blank">(.NYFANG)</a>目前已连续四个交易日回落，较本月初的峰值下跌约 3%，但仍维持去年令人瞠目结舌的 82%。迄今为止的收益。</p>   <p>The likes of Microsoft <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O" target="_blank">(MSFT.O)</a>, Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a>, Nvidia <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NVDA.O" target="_blank">(NVDA.O)</a> and Amazon <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AMZN.O" target="_blank">(AMZN.O)</a> fell back over 1%, pressured by a modest bounceback in U.S. Treasury yields.翻译:受美国国债收益率小幅反弹的压力，微软<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O" target="_blank">(MSFT.O)</a> 、苹果<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a> 、英伟达<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NVDA.O" target="_blank">(NVDA.O)</a>和亚马逊<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AMZN.O" target="_blank">(AMZN.O) 等公司</a>股价下跌超过 1%。</p>   <p>And despite some concerns in Treasuries about a heavy investment grade corporate bond sale diary this week, yields fell back again ahead of Tuesday's bell as attention turned to this week's series of critical U.S. jobs market updates.翻译:尽管美国国债市场对本周大量投资级公司债券发行感到担忧，但随着注意力转向本周一系列关键的美国就业市场更新，收益率在周二开盘前再次回落。</p>   <p>October job openings are reported later in the day, before a private sector hiring update for November tomorrow, weekly jobless on Thursday and the national payrolls report Friday.翻译:当天晚些时候将公布 10 月份的职位空缺，明天将公布 11 月份私营部门招聘情况，周四公布每周失业人数，周五公布全国就业报告。</p>   <p>Oil prices hovered just above 5-month lows, with global demand concerns outweighing some output cuts.#翻译:油价徘徊在 5 个月低点上方，全球需求担忧超过了部分减产。#</p>   <p>And demand worries are front and centre for the world's second biggest economy.翻译:需求担忧是世界第二大经济体的首要和核心问题。</p>   <p>China's blue-chip stocks slumped to their lowest since February 2019 amid fears of a possible cut to China's sovereign credit rating cut after Moody's outlook reduction.翻译:由于担心穆迪下调前景后中国主权信用评级可能被下调，中国蓝筹股跌至2019年2月以来的最低水平。</p>   <p>Moody's said the downgrade reflected growing evidence that authorities will have to provide more financial support for debt-laden local governments and state firms, posing broad risks to China's fiscal, economic and institutional strength.翻译:穆迪表示，评级下调反映出越来越多的证据表明，当局将不得不为负债累累的地方政府和国有企业提供更多财政支持，这对中国的财政、经济和机构实力构成广泛风险。</p>   <p>"The outlook change also reflects the increased risks related to structurally and persistently lower medium-term economic growth and the ongoing downsizing of the property sector," Moody's said.翻译:穆迪表示：“前景的变化还反映出与结构性和持续较低的中期经济增长以及房地产行业持续缩减相关的风险增加。”</p>   <p>The yuan weakened slightly against a broadly softer dollar <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DXY" target="_blank">(.DXY)</a>翻译:人民币兑美元小幅走软<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DXY" target="_blank">(.DXY)</a></p>   <p>The ratings news overshadowed a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-nov-services-activity-accelerates-boost-new-orders-caixin-pmi-2023-12-05/">private-sector survey</a> that China's services activity expanded at a quicker pace in November - confusing a picture where official surveys show the sector contracting for the first time since December.翻译:评级消息掩盖了一项<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-nov-services-activity-accelerates-boost-new-orders-caixin-pmi-2023-12-05/">私营部门调查</a>显示中国服务业活动在 11 月份以更快的速度扩张的消息，这使得官方调查显示该行业自 12 月以来首次出现收缩的情况令人困惑。</p>   <p>Elsewhere, the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/australias-central-bank-holds-rates-steady-retains-hiking-bias-2023-12-05/">Reserve Bank of Australia</a> held interest rates steady as expected - buying it more time to assess the state of the economy and decide whether to tighten further next year even as the U.S. and Europe are expected to ease. The Aussie dollar fell back.翻译:其他方面， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/australias-central-bank-holds-rates-steady-retains-hiking-bias-2023-12-05/">澳大利亚储备银行</a>如预期维持利率稳定，为它赢得了更多时间来评估经济状况并决定明年是否进一步收紧政策，尽管美国和欧洲预计将放松政策。澳元兑美元回落。</p>   <p>In Europe, hawkish <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/ecb-hawk-schnabel-scraps-more-rate-hikes-after-remarkable-inflation-drop-2023-12-05/">European Central Bank</a> board member Isabel Schnabel told Reuters the ECB can take further interest rate hikes off the table given a "remarkable" fall in inflation.翻译:在欧洲，鹰派的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/ecb-hawk-schnabel-scraps-more-rate-hikes-after-remarkable-inflation-drop-2023-12-05/">欧洲央行</a>董事会成员伊莎贝尔·施纳贝尔告诉路透社，鉴于通胀“显着”下降，欧洲央行可能不会进一步加息。</p>   <p>Deep annual producer price deflation eased somewhat last month.翻译:上个月，年度生产者价格通缩有所缓解。</p>   <p>And <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/barclays-shares-open-down-45-after-qatar-cuts-stake-2023-12-05/">Barclays</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BARC.L" target="_blank">(BARC.L)</a> shares opened 4.5% lower, eventually paring some of the losses, after one of its largest shareholders Qatar Holding moved to sell around 510 million pound ($644 million) of its stock.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/barclays-shares-open-down-45-after-qatar-cuts-stake-2023-12-05/">巴克莱银行</a>(Barclays <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BARC.L" target="_blank">) (BARC.L)</a>股价开盘下跌 4.5%，最终收复部分跌幅，此前其最大股东之一卡塔尔控股公司 (Qatar Holding) 出售了约 5.1 亿英镑（6.44 亿美元）的股票。</p>   <p>U.S. stock futures were marginally in the red before Tuesday's open.翻译:美国股指期货在周二开盘前小幅下跌。</p>   <p>Key developments that should provide more direction to U.S. markets later on Tuesday:翻译:周二晚些时候将为美国市场提供更多方向的关键事态发展：</p>   <p>* U.S. Oct JOLTS data on job openings, U.S. Nov S&amp;P Global service sector survey翻译:* 美国 10 月 JOLTS 职位空缺数据，美国 11 月标准普尔全球服务业调查</p>   <p>* Federal Reserve Division of Supervision and Regulation Director Michael Gibson testifies to Congress on Financial Innovation. European Central Bank President Christine Laggard speaks翻译:* 美联储监督和监管司司长迈克尔·吉布森 (Michael Gibson) 就金融创新向国会作证。欧洲央行行长克里斯蒂娜·拉加德讲话</p>   <p>* U.S. Treasury auctions 3-, 6-month bills翻译:* 美国财政部拍卖3个月、6个月期国债</p>   <p>* U.S. corporate earnings: JAM Smacker, Auto zone, Descartes Systems, Health, Apportionment, Rent the Runway, Mongo, Stitch Fix, Powell Industries, Dave &amp; Buster's Entertainment, Patronymics, G-III Apparel. Zero Fox, D Market Electronics Lands End, America's CAR-MART.翻译:* 美国企业盈利：JAM Smacker、Auto zone、笛卡尔系统、Health、Apportionment、Rent the Runway、Mongo、Stitch Fix、Powell Industries、Dave &amp; Buster&#39;s Entertainment、Patronymics、G-III Apparel。零狐、D Market Electronics Lands End、美国的 CAR-MAR​​T。</p>                <span>By Mike Dolan, Editing by Bernadette Baum; &lt;a href="mailto:mike.dolan@thomsonreuters.com" target="_blank"&gt;mike.dolan@thomsonreuters.com&lt;/a&gt;翻译:作者：迈克·多兰，伯纳黛特·鲍姆编辑； &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mike.dolan@thomsonreuters.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mike.dolan@thomsonreuters.com&lt;/a&gt;</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 11:04:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FL2U66NI3ZMOBDNZPIDOMB3UXM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/global-markets-view-usa-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国表示免签旅行政策促进了旅游业]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Eimm7UxOlfGi8r6Oa9H40vDm2R8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SGF5PG5AYBO5DNRWFCRV4R56WA.jpg" alt="Travellers at Beijing Daxing International Airport翻译:北京大兴国际机场的旅客" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Travellers walk past an installation in the shape of five stars, at Beijing Daxing International Airport in Beijing, China April 24, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/file photo翻译:2023年4月24日，中国北京大兴国际机场，旅客走过五颗星形状的装置。路透社/Tingshu Wang/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's foreign ministry said on Tuesday its visa-free travel policy has produced a clear effect, making things easier for travellers.翻译:中国外交部周二表示，免签旅行政策已产生明显效果，为游客提供了便利。</p>   <p>"Going forward, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs will continue to adjust visa policies to create more favourable conditions and further facilitate cross-border travel," spokesperson Wang Wenbin told a press briefing when asked for an update on tourism after China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-offers-visa-free-entry-citizens-france-germany-italy-2023-11-24/">announced</a> the policy, which covers several European countries and Malaysia.翻译:“下一步，外交部将继续调整签证政策， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-offers-visa-free-entry-citizens-france-germany-italy-2023-11-24/">创造</a>更多便利条件，进一步便利跨境旅游。”覆盖多个欧洲国家和马来西亚。</p>   <p>The policy came into effect Dec. 1 and the ministry, citing immigration data, said about 7,000 of nearly 18,000 travellers from France, Germany, Italy, the Netherlands, Spain and Malaysia - the countries covered by the visa waiver - entered China in the first three days of the month.翻译:该政策于 12 月 1 日生效，商务部援引出入境数据称，来自法国、德国、意大利、荷兰、西班牙和马来西亚等免签国家的近 18,000 名旅客中，约有 7,000 人首次入境中国。该月的三天。</p>   <p>Daily average tourist numbers from those countries have risen by 39% on the first three days of December compared to on the last day of November, Wang said.翻译:王说，与11月最后一天相比，12月前三天来自这些国家的日均游客人数增加了39%。</p>   <p>Germany's ambassador to China had expressed hope that China would extend the measures to all European Union members.翻译:德国驻华大使曾表示希望中国将这些措施扩大到所有欧盟成员国。</p>    <span>Reporting by Andrew Hayley; Writing by Liz Lee and Bernard Orr; Editing by Tom Hogue and Miral Fahmy翻译:安德鲁·海利报道；莉兹·李和伯纳德·奥尔撰写；汤姆·霍格和米拉尔·法赫米编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 10:48:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FPTXLYQ4NROOXDHP6X63UONPQM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-says-visa-free-travel-policy-has-boosted-tourism-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>TOURISM/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[德国企业在亚洲多元化以降低中国风险——调查]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/oiX6aXAtvN5WoRi-JJ30A7_qddQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2ZDBFIYAAJMBHD4IJDFJV3QD5Y.jpg" alt="Auto Shanghai show, in Shanghai翻译:上海车展，上海" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view shows the flags of China and Germany at a booth of a German automaker at the Auto Shanghai show, in Shanghai翻译:上海车展，上海, China, April 19, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song//File Photo翻译:2023 年 4 月 19 日，中国上海，上海车展上，一家德国汽车制造商的展位上展示着中德两国国旗。路透社/Aly Song//资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Nearly half of German companies operating in China are taking measures to reduce the risk of doing business there largely due to growing geopolitical tensions, according to a new survey by the German Chamber of Commerce in China.翻译:中国德国商会的一项最新调查显示，近一半在华经营的德国企业正在采取措施降低在华开展业务的风险，这主要是由于地缘政治紧张局势日益加剧。</p>   <p>Firms are building supply chains that are independent of China, shifting some operations away from the country and growing markets elsewhere in Asia, according to the survey of 566 companies conducted between Sept. 5 and Oct. 6.翻译:9月5日至10月6日期间对566家公司进行的调查显示，企业正在建立独立于中国的供应链，将部分业务从中国转移，并在亚洲其他地区不断发展市场。</p>   <p>Some 83% of companies cited geopolitical tensions as the main reason for their steps to mitigate risks related to China business, while 45% and 24% respectively put it down to the country's economic slowdown and greater focus on self-reliance.翻译:约83%的企业将地缘政治紧张局势视为采取措施降低中国业务相关风险的主要原因，而分别有45%和24%的企业将其归因于中国经济放缓和更加注重自力更生。</p>   <p>Other countries are benefiting from this risk mitigation strategy, according to the survey - with 57.5% of companies surveyed saying they would be investing more in India, followed by 37.9% for Vietnam, 30.1% for Thailand, 23.3% for Malaysia and 20.1% for Singapore.翻译:调查显示，其他国家也从这一风险缓解策略中受益——57.5%的受访企业表示将加大对印度的投资，其次是越南（37.9%）、泰国（30.1%）、马来西亚（23.3%）和印度（20.1%）。新加坡。</p>   <p>The survey comes five months after the government unveiled a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/german-cabinet-pass-china-strategy-thursday-govt-sources-2023-07-12/">strategy</a> toward de-risking Germany's economic relationship with China, its biggest trade partner and confirms <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/derisking-dilemma-how-german-companies-are-tackling-china-risk-2023-10-19/">anecdotal evidence</a> reported by Reuters of German firms reducing their dependence on China.翻译:五个月前，德国政府公布了一项降低德国与其最大贸易伙伴中国经济关系风险的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/german-cabinet-pass-china-strategy-thursday-govt-sources-2023-07-12/">战略</a>，并证实了路透社报道的德国企业减少对中国依赖的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/derisking-dilemma-how-german-companies-are-tackling-china-risk-2023-10-19/">传闻证据</a>。</p>   <p>Other countries in the West are also promoting greater risk mitigation, amid growing concerns about China's increasingly assertive attitude toward Taiwan and in the South China seas, as well as its tightening grip over its domestic economy.翻译:随着中国对台湾和南海日益强硬的态度以及对国内经济的控制日益加强，西方其他国家也在推动加大风险缓解力度。</p>   <p>This in turn is beginning to have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/wests-de-risking-starts-bite-chinas-prospects-2023-11-27/">an impact</a> on the world's second-largest economy, with China recording its first-ever quarterly deficit in foreign direct investment in July-September.翻译:这反过来又开始对世界第二大经济体产生<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/wests-de-risking-starts-bite-chinas-prospects-2023-11-27/">影响</a>，中国在 7 月至 9 月期间首次出现外国直接投资季度赤字。</p>   <p>Still, of the German companies surveyed, some 54% said they wanted to invest further in China - up from 51% last year- to localise production - in effect also potentially shielding it from the repercussions of geopolitical spats, according to economists.翻译:尽管如此，经济学家表示，在接受调查的德国公司中，约有 54% 表示他们希望在中国进一步投资（高于去年的 51%），实现生产本地化，这实际上也有可能使其免受地缘政治争端的影响。</p>   <p>That was more than the 44% that said they were pursuing risk mitigation strategies.翻译:这高于表示正在采取风险缓解策略的 44%。</p>    <span>Reporting by Sarah Marsh; Editing by Sharon Singleton翻译:莎拉·马什报道；莎朗·辛格尔顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 10:22:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6Z56CITW7ROS5DGUSO375KCTI4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/german-firms-diversify-asia-reduce-china-risk-survey-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Sarah Marsh]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GERMANY</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[穆迪下调前景，中国国有银行预计将支持人民币 - 消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Uucs0vIIJzOjfBlJhxHY6ackXhs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DWLVRDPCK5OSVK6I7HDXTA5MO4.jpg" alt="Illustration shows U.S. dollar and Chinese Yuan banknotes翻译:插图显示美元和人民币纸币" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Dollar and Chinese Yuan banknotes are seen in this illustration taken January 30, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:这张摄于 2023 年 1 月 30 日的插图中可以看到美元和人民币纸币。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's major state-owned banks were busy buying the yuan in currency markets on Tuesday to prevent it from weakening too much, two sources with knowledge of the matter said, with buying intensifying after rating agency Moody's cut China's outlook to negative in the afternoon.翻译:两位知情人士表示，中国主要国有银行周二忙于在货币市场买入人民币，以防止人民币大幅贬值，在评级机构穆迪下午将中国前景下调至负面后，买入力度加大。</p>   <p>State banks were spotted swapping yuan for U.S. dollars in the onshore swap market and quickly selling those dollars in the spot market to support the yuan throughout the whole trading session, the sources said.翻译:消息人士称，国有银行被发现在境内掉期市场上将人民币兑换成美元，并在现货市场上迅速出售这些美元，以在整个交易时段支撑人民币。</p>   <p>But the banks' dollar selling became very forceful after the Moody's statement, one source said.翻译:但一位消息人士称，在穆迪发表声明后，银行的美元抛售变得非常猛烈。</p>   <p>China state banks have in the past year often sold dollars to slow the yuan's decline against the U.S. dollar. Markets have often seen the moves as a sign of official attempts to relieve pressure on the currency, though banks could also be trading for their own accounts.翻译:去年，中国国有银行经常抛售美元，以减缓人民币兑美元汇率的下跌。市场经常将这些举措视为官方试图缓解货币压力的迹象，尽管银行也可能在为自己的账户进行交易。</p>   <p>Moody's on Tuesday <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/moodys-cuts-chinas-credit-outlook-negative-2023-12-05/">cut</a> its outlook on China's government credit ratings to negative from stable, citing expectations of lower medium-term economic growth and risks from a deep correction in the country's vast property sector.翻译:穆迪周二将中国政府信用评级展望从稳定<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/moodys-cuts-chinas-credit-outlook-negative-2023-12-05/">下调</a>至负面，理由是中期经济增长放缓的预期以及中国庞大房地产行业深度调整的风险。</p>   <p>With China's economy sputtering and the U.S. dollar surging until recently, the yuan has had a volatile year, having weakened 6.14% to the dollar at one point before giving back much of the losses on recent views that U.S. interest rates have peaked.翻译:直到最近，随着中国经济的低迷和美元的飙升，人民币经历了动荡的一年，兑美元一度贬值6.14%，之后又因近期美国利率已见顶的观点而回吐了大部分损失。</p>   <p>The yuan strengthened 2.55% in November, its best month this year, but it is still down 3% year-to-date.翻译:人民币11月升值2.55%，为今年表现最好的一个月，但今年迄今仍下跌3%。</p>   <p>However, some analysts said the impact on the yuan from the Moody's decision will not be sustainable.翻译:不过，也有分析人士表示，穆迪决定对人民币的影响不会持续。</p>   <p>"The issues plaguing the property sector are not new," said Khoon Goh, head of Asia research at ANZ.翻译:澳新银行亚洲研究主管孔吴表示：“困扰房地产行业的问题并不新鲜。”</p>   <p>"The steps taken by the authorities recently should see a bottom soon. The upcoming U.S. data will be more important for the near-term direction of the yuan," Goh said, referring to a spate of government measures to revive the real estate market.翻译:“当局最近采取的措施应该很快就会见底。即将公布的美国数据对于人民币的近期走向更为重要，”吴说，他指的是政府为重振房地产市场而采取的一系列措施。</p>    <span>Reporting by Shanghai Newsroom and Tom Westbrook; Editing by Jacqueline Wong and Kim Coghill翻译:上海新闻室和汤姆·威斯布鲁克的报道；编辑：Jacqueline Wong 和 Kim Coghill</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 09:26:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5TRUHVPGZZJPLJGXKICQFCSZDI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-state-banks-seen-swapping-selling-dollars-yuan-sources-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>YUAN/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国蓝箭航天准备用甲烷燃料火箭发射卫星]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Beijing-based LandSpace Technology, one of China's private space companies, is preparing to launch satellite payloads to orbit in a key commercial test of its methane and liquid oxygen fuelled rocket.翻译:总部位于北京的蓝箭航天科技有限公司是中国私营航天公司之一，该公司正准备将卫星有效载荷送入轨道，对其甲烷和液氧燃料火箭进行一项重要的商业测试。</p>   <p>Investors and rocket developers have said methane could offer a way to help slash costs and support reusable rockets in a cleaner and more efficient manner.翻译:投资者和火箭开发商表示，甲烷可以提供一种帮助削减成本并以更清洁、更高效的方式支持可重复使用火箭的方法。</p>   <p>LandSpace's Zhuque-2 carrier rocket was transferred to the launch area of a space facility in the Gobi Desert on Friday and is readying for launch, designated Y-3, the company said on its Weibo social media account.翻译:蓝箭航天在其微博社交媒体账户上表示，朱雀二号运载火箭已于周五转移至戈壁沙漠的航天设施发射区，并准备发射，代号为Y-3。</p>   <p>The company did not specify a launch window for the rocket, which will blast off from Jiuquan Satellite Launch Center in Inner Mongolia.翻译:该公司没有具体说明火箭的发射窗口，该火箭将从内蒙古酒泉卫星发射中心发射。</p>   <p>LandSpace aims to prove the feasibility of Zhuque-2 with three test launches; the first two were Y-1 and Y-2, a company representative said on Tuesday.翻译:蓝箭航天旨在通过三次发射验证朱雀二号的可行性；公司代表周二表示，前两个是 Y-1 和 Y-2。</p>   <p>If Zhuque-2 is validated, LandSpace plans to provide clients about three launches in 2024 and double that number in 2025, the representative said.翻译:该代表表示，如果“朱雀二号”获得验证，蓝箭航天计划在 2024 年为客户提供约 3 次发射，并在 2025 年将这一数字增加一倍。</p>   <p>LandSpace declined to provide details on the launch date or the number and type of the satellites to be carried by Y-3.翻译:蓝箭航天拒绝透露发射日期或运三号运载卫星的数量和类型的详细信息。</p>   <p>Chinese commercial space firms have rushed into the sector since 2014, when the government allowed private investment in an industry now dominated by Elon Musk's SpaceX.翻译:自 2014 年以来，中国商业航天公司纷纷涌入该领域，当时政府允许私人投资该行业，目前该行业由埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 的 SpaceX 主导。</p>   <p>LandSpace was one of the earliest and best funded of the Chinese space startups aiming to tap into the demand for rocket launches amid growing competition to place satellites in low-Earth orbit as an alternative to Musk's Starlink.翻译:蓝箭航天是中国最早、资金最充足的航天初创公司之一，旨在满足火箭发射的需求，因为将卫星送入近地轨道以替代马斯克的星链的竞争日益激烈。</p>   <p>In July, LandSpace hit a benchmark in that race with the launch of the world's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/china-beats-rivals-successfully-launch-first-methane-liquid-rocket-2023-07-12/">first methane-liquid oxygen rocket</a>, the Zhuque-2 Y-2, putting China ahead of U.S. rivals including SpaceX and Jeff Bezos' Blue Origin.翻译:7月，蓝箭航天在这场竞赛中创下了基准，发射了世界<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/china-beats-rivals-successfully-launch-first-methane-liquid-rocket-2023-07-12/">上第一枚甲烷液氧火箭“</a>朱雀二号Y-2”，使中国领先于包括SpaceX和杰夫·贝索斯的蓝色起源在内的美国竞争对手。</p>   <p>Before Y-2, which didn't carry a usable satellite, LandSpace said that Zhuque-2 Y-1, the first test rocket, failed a launch last year, without specifying whether it carried any satellite payloads.翻译:在运二号没有携带可用卫星之前，蓝箭航天表示，第一枚试验火箭朱雀二号运一号去年发射失败，但没有具体说明它是否携带任何卫星有效载荷。</p>   <p>Founded in 2015, LandSpace has secured funding from investors including venture capital firm HongShan, known at that time as Sequoia Capital China, the investment arm of Chinese property developer Country Garden and the state-backed China SME Development Fund.翻译:蓝箭空间成立于 2015 年，已获得投资者的融资，包括风险投资公司红杉资本（当时称为红杉资本中国）、中国房地产开发商碧桂园的投资部门以及国家支持的中国中小企业发展基金。</p>   <p>LandSpace's latest announced fundraising was in 2020, when it raised 1.2 billion yuan ($168.14 million). The company has had fundraising rounds of undisclosed sizes since, Chinese company record tracking database Tianyancha showed.翻译:蓝箭航天最新宣布的融资是在 2020 年，当时筹集了 12 亿元人民币（1.6814 亿美元）。中国公司记录追踪数据库天眼查显示，自此以来，该公司已进行过几轮未公开融资规模的融资。</p>   <p>In July, LandSpace founder and CEO Zhang Changwu told Chinese publication Yicai the company had started developing reusable rockets and expected to conduct a test launch in the second half of 2025.翻译:今年7月，蓝箭航天创始人兼首席执行官张昌武告诉第一财经，该公司已开始研发可重复使用火箭，预计于2025年下半年进行试射。</p>   <p>LandSpace rival OrienSpace, founded in 2020, said it plans to launch its first solid-fuel rocket, Gravity-1, in December.翻译:LandSpace 的竞争对手 OrienSpace 成立于 2020 年，表示计划于 12 月发射第一枚固体燃料火箭 Gravity-1。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1368 yuan)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.1368 元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Ella Cao, Roxanne Liu and Bernard Orr; Editing by Kevin Krolicki, Miral Fahmy and Gerry Doyle翻译:Ella Cao、Roxanne Liu 和 Bernard Orr 报道；编辑：Kevin Krolicki、Miral Fahmy 和 Gerry Doyle</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 07:26:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">E6MBXTNT7FNO5BKBUSUCGBCXI4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/space/chinas-landspace-readies-satellite-launch-with-methane-rocket-2023-12-04/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ella Cao, Roxanne Liu, Bernard Orr]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AEROSPACE/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[财新PMI显示，中国11月服务业活动在新订单的推动下加速]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Gls-ogSSQx58ec7FZTFH5V_NXYI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NHYYUVXV7BK7ZIYZ3CYHL4TX3Q.jpg" alt="People dine at a restaurant in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家餐馆用餐" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People dine at a restaurant in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家餐馆用餐, China September 5, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's services activity expanded at a quicker pace in November, a private-sector survey showed on Tuesday, as the upturn in new businesses were the best seen for three months amid reports of firmer market conditions.翻译:周二的一项私营部门调查显示，中国 11 月份服务业活动扩张速度加快，因有报道称市场状况走强，新业务增长创三个月来最好水平。</p>   <p>The findings present a mixed picture of the vast services sector as an official survey last week showed the sector unexpectedly <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-factory-activity-contracts-second-month-november-2023-11-30/">contracted</a> for the first time since December last year, prompting calls for more stimulus measures.翻译:调查结果显示，庞大的服务业情况好坏参半，上周的一项官方调查显示，该行业自去年 12 月以来首次<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-factory-activity-contracts-second-month-november-2023-11-30/">出现</a>意外收缩，促使人们呼吁采取更多刺激措施。</p>   <p>The Caixin/S&amp;P Global services purchasing managers' index (PMI) rose to a three-month high of 51.5 in November from October's 50.4, but it remained softer than the long-run series average.翻译:财新/标普全球服务业采购经理人指数（PMI）从 10 月的 50.4 升至 11 月的三个月高点 51.5，但仍低于长期系列平均水平。</p>   <p>"Both services supply and demand expanded, as the market continued to heal," said Wang Zhe, economist at Caixin Insight Group.翻译:财新智库经济学家王哲表示：“随着市场持续复苏，服务供给和需求均扩大。”</p>   <p>Taken together with the better-than-expected <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-activity-surprisingly-expands-november-caixin-pmi-2023-12-01/">Caixin manufacturing PMI</a>, Wang said the world's second-biggest economy showed signs of an encouraging recovery, with steady growth in consumer spending, solid improvement in industrial production and an uptick in market confidence.翻译:结合好于预期的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-activity-surprisingly-expands-november-caixin-pmi-2023-12-01/">财新制造业PMI</a> ，王表示，世界第二大经济体显示出令人鼓舞的复苏迹象，消费支出稳定增长，工业生产稳步改善，市场信心回升。</p>   <p>Analysts say the different survey sizes and composition of surveyed companies might explain the discrepancy between the Caixin and official PMI readings.翻译:分析人士表示，不同的调查规模和受访企业的构成可能解释了财新和官方PMI数据之间的差异。</p>   <p>Caixin/S&amp;P's composite PMI, which includes both manufacturing and services activity, grew to 51.6 from 50.0 in October, marking the strongest reading since August.翻译:财新/标准普尔综合 PMI（包括制造业和服务业活动）从 10 月份的 50.0 升至 51.6，创下 8 月份以来的最强读数。</p>   <p>Service providers were upbeat about business activity over the year ahead in November and the degree of positive sentiment picked up for the first time in five months.翻译:服务提供商对 11 月份未来一年的商业活动持乐观态度，积极情绪程度五个月来首次回升。</p>   <p>However, Oxford Economics lead economist Louise Loo said while China heads into 2024 with relatively loose policy settings, the country's private sector confidence was constrained by property pessimism.翻译:然而，牛津经济研究院首席经济学家Louise Loo表示，尽管中国进入2024年的政策相对宽松，但该国私营部门的信心却受到房地产悲观情绪的制约。</p>   <p>Property sales, investment, and home prices extended declines in October and piled more pressure on authorities to step up efforts to prevent contagion across the broader financial sector.翻译:十月份房地产销售、投资和房价继续下跌，给当局带来了更大的压力，要求当局加大力度防止疫情蔓延到更广泛的金融领域。</p>   <p>The country's central bank governor last week said monetary policy will remain accommodative to support growth but <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">urged</a> structural reforms over time to reduce the economy's reliance on infrastructure and property.翻译:该国央行行长上周表示，货币政策将保持宽松以支持增长，但<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">敦促</a>随着时间的推移进行结构性改革，以减少经济对基础设施和房地产的依赖。</p>   <p>According to the Caixin services survey, employment fell for the first time since the start of 2023 as some firms maintained a cautious approach to hiring.翻译:财新服务业调查显示，由于一些企业对招聘保持谨慎态度，就业人数出现 2023 年初以来的首次下降。</p>   <p>November also witnessed a further slowdown in the rate of input cost inflation across China's service sector.翻译:11月份，中国服务业投入成本通胀率进一步放缓。</p>   <p>"China is no longer the spender of last resort for the global economy, so don't expect robust reflation," Oxford Economics' Loo said.翻译:牛津经济研究院的卢表示：“中国不再是全球经济的最后消费国，因此不要指望出现强劲的通货再膨胀。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Ellen Zhang and Ryan Woo
Editing by Shri Navaratnam翻译:Ellen 张和 Ryan Woo 报道 Shri Navaratnam 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 01:48:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZNNA3EGMVZIEJKGGAEAMFOOOBY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-nov-services-activity-accelerates-boost-new-orders-caixin-pmi-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/PMI</category>
                
                <category>SERVICES (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[外交部长表示中国希望在峰会上深化欧盟关系]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/CZZUGATUAySU1xofM9RA-_RWBXo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PUVXUNG5SBNLVJ4R5IW2RLWVKU.jpg" alt="10th trilateral foreign ministers' meeting in Busan翻译:第十次中日韩外长会议在釜山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>File Photo: Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi speaks during the 10th trilateral foreign ministers' meeting in Busan翻译:第十次中日韩外长会议在釜山举行, South Korea, Sunday, Nov. 26, 2023. Ahn Young-joon/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:资料照片：2023 年 11 月 26 日星期日，中国外交部长王毅在韩国釜山举行的第十次中日韩外长会议上发表讲话。Ahn Young-joon/Pool via REUTERS/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China hopes to boost relations with the European Union at an upcoming summit, with a firm focus on pragmatic cooperation in the face of complex situations and severe challenges, its foreign minister Wang Yi said.翻译:中国外交部长王毅表示，中方希望在即将举行的峰会上加强同欧盟的关系，面对复杂形势和严峻挑战，坚定不移开展务实合作。</p>   <p>In a meeting on Monday with EU diplomatic envoys to China in Beijing, Wang said the two sides should view bilateral relations from a strategic perspective and added that China's policy toward Europe remains stable, according to Xinhua news agency.翻译:据新华社报道，王毅周一在北京会见欧盟驻华使节时表示，双方应从战略高度看待双边关系，并表示中国对欧政策保持稳定。</p>   <p>"China and the EU have not completely the same point of view on international and regional issues, and only by adhering to communication and coordination can we play a constructive role in maintaining world peace and stability and addressing global challenges," Wang said, according to the Xinhua report.翻译:王毅表示，中欧在国际和地区问题上看法并不完全一致，只有坚持沟通协调，才能为维护世界和平稳定、应对全球性挑战发挥建设性作用。新华社报道。</p>   <p>The remarks came ahead of a highly-anticipated <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-says-summit-with-eu-leaders-discuss-global-economic-issues-2023-12-04/">summit on Thursday</a> between Chinese President Xi Jinping and President of the European Council Charles Michel and President of the European Commission Ursula von der Leyen.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-says-summit-with-eu-leaders-discuss-global-economic-issues-2023-12-04/">周四，中国国家主席习近平与欧洲理事会主席查尔斯·米歇尔和欧盟委员会主席乌尔苏拉·冯德莱恩将举行备受期待的峰会</a>。</p>   <p>The two sides are trying to mend frayed relations on several trade issues, such as an EU anti-subsidy <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-rebukes-eus-rushed-request-consultations-over-ev-subsidy-probe-2023-10-04/">investigation</a> on electric vehicles and a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/eu-plans-anti-subsidy-probe-into-chinese-steelmakers-ft-2023-10-10/">looming probe</a> on Chinese steelmakers.翻译:双方正试图修复在多个贸易问题上的紧张关系，例如欧盟对电动汽车的反补贴<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-rebukes-eus-rushed-request-consultations-over-ev-subsidy-probe-2023-10-04/">调查</a>以及<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/eu-plans-anti-subsidy-probe-into-chinese-steelmakers-ft-2023-10-10/">即将对中国钢铁制造商进行的调查</a>。</p>   <p>The head of the EU delegation to China and the envoys of EU member states to China said the EU is committed to developing constructive and stable EU-China relations, and is willing to maintain mutual respect and dialogue with China, according to the report.翻译:欧盟驻华代表团团长和欧盟成员国驻华使节表示，欧盟致力于发展建设性、稳定的欧中关系，愿同中方保持相互尊重和对话。</p>   <p>The envoys said the EU has no intention of decoupling from China and hopes to establish "mutually beneficial and balanced economic and trade relations with China", according to Xinhua.翻译:据新华社报道，特使们表示，欧盟无意与中国脱钩，希望与中国建立“互利、平衡的经贸关系”。</p>   <p>In the meeting on Monday, the two sides also exchanged views on the Ukraine crisis and Palestinian-Israeli conflict, according to the report, without elaborating.翻译:报道称，在周一的会晤中，双方还就乌克兰危机和巴以冲突交换了意见，但没有详细说明。</p>    <span>Reporting by Bernard Orr and Shanghai newsroom; Editing by Sonali Paul翻译:伯纳德·奥尔和上海新闻编辑室的报道；索纳利·保罗编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:59:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F7X4QSWTBVN3FLDQJADKXT6PSA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-looks-deepen-eu-ties-summit-foreign-minister-says-2023-12-05/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>EU/SUMMIT</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[洞察：西方初创企业寻求打破中国对稀土精炼的控制]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/nMH5I-0r-pqMG8Pc72GXOES5F1g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/INP6IYETJVOMTHSNHFM6P5TAFY.jpg" alt="Canada's Prime Minister Justin Trudeau visits rare earths producer Vital Metals in Saskatoon翻译:加拿大总理贾斯汀·特鲁多访问位于萨斯卡通的稀土生产商 Vital Metals" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Raw Rare Earth ore waiting to be processed at Vital Metals in Saskatoon, Saskatchewan, Canada January 16, 2023.  REUTERS/Nayan Sthankiya/File Photo翻译:2023 年 1 月 16 日，加拿大萨斯喀彻温省萨斯卡通的 Vital Metals 等待加工的稀土矿石原料。REUTERS/Nayan Sthankiya/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/c7LTuxMjeIaAZvFSogVNtXzFTqE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FJ36277VLFNSRIIB4AM2BFIQGU.jpg" alt="A view of the MP Materials rare earth open-pit mine in Mountain Pass翻译:MP Materials 芒廷帕斯稀土露天矿一景" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view of the MP Materials rare earth open-pit mine in Mountain Pass翻译:MP Materials 芒廷帕斯稀土露天矿一景, California, U.S. January 30, 2020. Picture taken January 30, 2020. REUTERS/Steve Marcus翻译:2020 年 1 月 30 日，美国加利福尼亚州帕斯山 MP Materials 稀土露天矿一景。照片摄于 2020 年 1 月 30 日。路透社/Steve Marcus</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tomg8Quaiq_Gd-f63oOMe_F6hI8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XZU4J7D2UVNKNDTVSVMZMUF4QI.jpg" alt="A shipping area is filled with 1,500 kg bags of bastnasite concentrate at the MP Materials rare earth mine in Mountain Pass翻译:帕斯山 MP Materials 稀土矿的装运区装满了 1,500 公斤袋的氟碳铈矿精矿" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A shipping area is filled with 1,500 kg bags of bastnasite concentrate at the MP Materials rare earth mine in Mountain Pass翻译:帕斯山 MP Materials 稀土矿的装运区装满了 1,500 公斤袋的氟碳铈矿精矿, California, U.S. January 30, 2020. Picture taken January 30, 2020. REUTERS/Steve Marcus</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/oX9h9LeiBT93aVuKo8FI2JRuzjc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BJLKFQDINVKXVGH66NQGUEJNAA.jpg" alt="A wheel loader operator fills a truck with ore at the MP Materials rare earth mine in Mountain Pass翻译:一名轮式装载机操作员在帕斯山 MP Materials 稀土矿向卡车装满矿石" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A wheel loader operator fills a truck with ore at the MP Materials rare earth mine in Mountain Pass翻译:一名轮式装载机操作员在帕斯山 MP Materials 稀土矿向卡车装满矿石, California, U.S. January 30, 2020. Picture taken January 30, 2020. REUTERS/Steve Marcus翻译:2020 年 1 月 30 日，美国加利福尼亚州帕斯山 MP Materials 稀土矿，一名轮式装载机操作员正在向卡车装满矿石。照片拍摄于 2020 年 1 月 30 日。路透社/Steve Marcus</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/5L6qi0QRv1n9W3jBhRjinfq1xPo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NBIN5I6VSVNP3P4Q6NI7VZ3A6U.jpg" alt="UCore executives pose with blueprints for new rare earth processing equipment in Alexandria翻译:UCore 高管与亚历山大的新型稀土加工设备蓝图合影" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>UCore Chief Operating Officer Michael Schrider and Vice President of Business Development Geoff Atkins pose with blueprints for new rare earth processing equipment that they plan to install at a former U.S. Air Force base in Alexandria, Louisiana, U.S. October 17, 2023. REUTERS/Ernest Scheyder翻译:UCore 首席运营官 Michael Schrider 和业务开发副总裁 Geoff Atkins 展示了新稀土加工设备的蓝图，他们计划于 2023 年 10 月 17 日在美国路易斯安那州亚历山大的前美国空军基地安装这些设备。 REUTERS/Ernest Scheyder</figcaption></figure>                     <p>Start-up tech firms are racing to transform the way rare earths are refined for the clean energy transition, a push aimed at turbocharging the West's expansion into the niche sector that underpins billions of electronic devices.翻译:初创科技公司正在竞相改变稀土精炼方式，以实现清洁能源转型，此举旨在加速西方向支撑数十亿电子设备的利基行业的扩张。</p>   <p>The existing standard to refine these strategic minerals, known as solvent extraction, is an expensive and dirty process that China has spent the past 30 years mastering. MP Materials <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MP.N" target="_blank">(MP.N)</a>, Lynas Rare Earths <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LYC.AX" target="_blank">(LYC.AX)</a> and other Western rare earths companies have struggled at times to deploy it due to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/world-battles-loosen-chinas-grip-vital-rare-earths-clean-energy-transition-2023-08-02/">technical complexities and pollution concerns</a>.翻译:提炼这些战略矿物的现有标准，即溶剂萃取，是一个昂贵且肮脏的过程，中国在过去 30 年里一直在掌握。由于<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/world-battles-loosen-chinas-grip-vital-rare-earths-clean-energy-transition-2023-08-02/">技术复杂性和污染问题，</a> MP Materials <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MP.N" target="_blank">(MP.N)</a> 、莱纳斯稀土公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LYC.AX" target="_blank">(LYC.AX)</a>和其他西方稀土公司有时很难部署它。</p>   <p>Rare earths are a group of 17 metals used to make magnets that turn power into motion for electric vehicles, cell phones and other electronics. While U.S. scientists helped develop solvent extraction for rare earths in the 1950s, radioactive waste from the process gradually made it unpopular in the United States.翻译:稀土是一组 17 种金属，用于制造磁铁，将电力转化为电动汽车、手机和其他电子产品的运动。虽然美国科学家在 20 世纪 50 年代帮助开发了稀土溶剂萃取法，但该过程中产生的放射性废物逐渐使其在美国不再受欢迎。</p>   <p>China began to rapidly expand in the industry starting during the 1980s and now controls 87% of global rare earths refining capacity, according to the International Energy Agency. That prowess has helped propel the country's economy to the second-largest in the world.翻译:据国际能源署称，中国从 20 世纪 80 年代开始在该行业迅速扩张，目前控制着全球 87% 的稀土精炼能力。这种实力帮助该国经济跃升为世界第二大经济体。</p>   <p>Emerging Western rivals now offer the tantalizing prospect of processing the minerals in faster, cleaner and cheaper ways, if they can successfully launch.翻译:如果新兴的西方竞争对手能够成功推出的话，他们现在将提供以更快、更清洁和更便宜的方式加工矿物的诱人前景。</p>   <p>"The existing rare earths refining process is a nightmare," said Isabel Barton, a mining and geological engineering professor at the University of Arizona. "That's why there are so many companies promising new methods, because we need new ones."翻译:“现有的稀土精炼工艺是一场噩梦，”亚利桑那大学采矿和地质工程教授伊莎贝尔·巴顿说。 “这就是为什么有这么多公司承诺新方法，因为我们需要新方法。”</p>   <p>Interviews with nearly two dozen industry consultants, academics and executives show that if one or more of these novel processing technologies succeed as hoped by 2025, they could slash reliance on Chinese rare earths technology and its toxic by-products while also bolstering plans by Western firms to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/western-miners-seek-premium-pricing-rare-earth-metals-break-china-grip-2023-11-08/">charge premium prices</a> for the strategic minerals.翻译:对近二十位行业顾问、学者和高管的采访表明，如果这些新颖的加工技术中的一种或多种在 2025 年之前取得成功，它们可以减少对中国稀土技术及其有毒副产品的依赖，同时也支持西方公司的计划对战略矿产<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/western-miners-seek-premium-pricing-rare-earth-metals-break-china-grip-2023-11-08/">收取溢价</a>。</p>   <p>While none have launched commercially - and some industry consultants and analysts question whether they will be able to do so soon - a cadre of firms are pushing forward with aggressive development plans.翻译:虽然还没有一家公司推出商业化——而且一些行业顾问和分析师质疑他们是否能够很快这样做——但一批公司正在推进积极的开发计划。</p>   <p>On a former U.S. Air Force base in Louisiana, Ucore Rare Metals <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/UCU.V" target="_blank">(UCU.V)</a> aims to process rare earths by mid-2025 using a technology known as RapidSX that it says is at least three times faster than solvent extraction, produces no hazardous chemical waste and requires only a third of the physical space.翻译:在路易斯安那州的前美国空军基地，Ucore Rare Metals <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/UCU.V" target="_blank">(UCU.V)</a>的目标是到 2025 年中期使用名为 RapidSX 的技术加工稀土，据称该技术比溶剂萃取速度至少快三倍，且不产生危险化学品浪费，只需要三分之一的物理空间。</p>   <p>"Our goal is to re-establish a North American rare earths supply chain," Michael Schrider, Ucore's chief operating officer, said during a visit to the site.翻译:Ucore 首席运营官 Michael Schrider 在参观该工厂时表示：“我们的目标是重建北美稀土供应链。”</p>   <p>Formed in 2006, Ucore initially planned to mine a rare earths deposit in Alaska. But the company changed tack in 2022 to focus on refining, not mining, a pivot born from what two executives said they saw as a flaw in the West's strategy to weaken China's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/world-battles-loosen-chinas-grip-vital-rare-earths-clean-energy-transition-2023-08-02/">minerals dominance</a> by trying to master both steps simultaneously.翻译:Ucore 成立于 2006 年，最初计划开采阿拉斯加的稀土矿床。但该公司在 2022 年改变了策略，将重点放在炼油上，而不是采矿上，这一重心源于两位高管表示，他们认为西方试图同时掌握这两个步骤来削弱中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/world-battles-loosen-chinas-grip-vital-rare-earths-clean-energy-transition-2023-08-02/">矿产主导地位</a>的战略存在缺陷。</p>   <p>Ucore, which has been testing its process with Pentagon funding, is in talks now with 17 mining companies to buy lightly processed supplies of rare earths known as concentrate, ship them to the Port of New Orleans, then truck them to a 80,800-square foot warehouse that will be outfitted with the RapidSX technology beginning in January.翻译:Ucore 一直在五角大楼的资助下测试其工艺，目前正在与 17 家矿业公司进行谈判，购买轻加工的稀土（称为精矿）供应，将其运至新奥尔良港，然后用卡车运至 80,800 平方英尺的工厂。该仓库将从一月份开始配备 RapidSX 技术。</p>   <p>Rare earths miners increasingly say they are content to focus on digging up rock - rather than compounding their operations with the added step of processing.翻译:越来越多的稀土矿商表示，他们满足于专注于开采岩石，而不是将其业务与额外的加工步骤相结合。</p>   <p>"Mining companies should focus on finding new deposits," said Luisa Moreno, president of Defense Metals <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DEFN.V" target="_blank">(DEFN.V)</a>, which aims to open a rare earths mine in British Columbia within four years and is interested in licensing Ucore's technology. "You probably should let refining be handled by others that specialize in that."翻译:国防金属公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DEFN.V" target="_blank">(DEFN.V)</a>总裁路易莎·莫雷诺 (Luisa Moreno) 表示：“矿业公司应专注于寻找新矿床。”该公司的目标是四年内在不列颠哥伦比亚省开设一座稀土矿，并有兴趣获得 Ucore 技术的许可。 “你可能应该让其他专门从事精炼工作的人来处理。”</p>   <p>Rainbow Rare Earths <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RBWR.L" target="_blank">(RBWR.L)</a> plans by 2026 to deploy rare earths refining technology in South Africa developed by its Florida-based partner K-Technologies that uses a process known as continuous ion exchange, used by some lithium producers.翻译:Rainbow Rare Earths <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RBWR.L" target="_blank">(RBWR.L)</a>计划到 2026 年在南非部署由其位于佛罗里达州的合作伙伴 K-Technologies 开发的稀土精炼技术，该技术采用了一些锂生产商使用的称为连续离子交换的工艺。</p>   <p>Startup Aether is developing nanotechnology that programs proteins to selectively bind with and extract rare earths from ore deposits.翻译:初创公司 Aether 正在开发纳米技术，对蛋白质进行编程，使其选择性地与矿床结合并提取稀土。</p>   <p>In Norway, privately-held REETec says its proprietary refining process emits 90% less carbon dioxide than solvent extraction and should be operational by late 2024.翻译:在挪威，私营 REETec 表示，其专有精炼工艺的二氧化碳排放量比溶剂萃取法少 90%，预计将于 2024 年底投入运营。</p>   <p>And privately-held Phoenix Tailings earlier this year began refining small amounts of rare earths in Massachusetts using a process that it says is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/mine-waste-finds-new-life-source-rare-earths-2023-04-04/">free of emissions and waste</a>.翻译:今年早些时候，私人控股的 Phoenix Tailings 开始在马萨诸塞州使用一种据称<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/mine-waste-finds-new-life-source-rare-earths-2023-04-04/">没有排放和废物的</a>工艺精炼少量稀土。</p>   <p>"There are technologies that can be developed that are far better than solvent extraction," said Robert Fox, a scientist at the U.S. Department of Energy's Idaho National Laboratory. The lab last month agreed to research new refining techniques for privately-held U.S. Critical Materials, which is developing a rare earths deposit.</p>    <h 1="">SKEPTICISM</h>  <p>Despite the hunger for new refining techniques, industry consultants warned that manufacturers may be expecting too much and too soon from this so-far unproven group of nascent technologies, especially given the world's aggressive electrification targets.翻译:尽管渴望新的炼油技术，但行业顾问警告说，制造商可能对这组迄今为止未经证实的新兴技术期望过高且过早，特别是考虑到世界雄心勃勃的电气化目标。</p>   <p>Ucore's technology, for example, has never worked at commercial scale and is not expected to gain patent protection until next year, a timeline that industry consultants flagged as a cause for concern given strong rivalries for intellectual property.翻译:例如，Ucore 的技术从未在商业规模上发挥过作用，预计要到明年才能获得专利保护，鉴于知识产权竞争激烈，行业顾问将这一时间表标记为令人担忧的原因。</p>   <p>"The time horizon needed to develop all these new refining technologies will be longer than many expect," said Frank Fannon, a minerals industry consultant and former U.S. assistant secretary of state. Talks of production within a few years "creates a false sense of security for policymakers."翻译:矿产行业顾问、美国前助理国务卿弗兰克·范农 (Frank Fannon) 表示：“开发所有这些新炼油技术所需的时间将比许多人预期的要长。”几年内的生产谈判“给政策制定者制造了一种错误的安全感”。</p>   <p>Yet the need for alternatives is rising, especially in the wake of Beijing's decision earlier this year to curb exports of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-export-curbs-choke-off-shipments-gallium-germanium-second-month-2023-10-20/">germanium</a>, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-ups-critical-minerals-heat-with-graphite-controls-2023-10-24/">graphite</a> and other metals. That has sparked concerns that rare earths could be next.翻译:然而，对替代品的需求正在上升，特别是在北京今年早些时候决定限制<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-export-curbs-choke-off-shipments-gallium-germanium-second-month-2023-10-20/">锗</a>、 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-ups-critical-minerals-heat-with-graphite-controls-2023-10-24/">石墨</a>和其他金属的出口之后。这引发了人们对稀土可能成为下一个的担忧。</p>   <p>Fannon and several <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/western-start-ups-seek-break-chinas-grip-rare-earths-refining-2023-12-04/Thanks%20much%20for%20all%20the%20coordination%20and%20internal%20advocacy/strategy" target="_blank">U.S. politicians</a> have called for Western governments to create central rare earths processing hubs, a plan already being pursued by Canada.翻译:范农和几位<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/western-start-ups-seek-break-chinas-grip-rare-earths-refining-2023-12-04/Thanks%20much%20for%20all%20the%20coordination%20and%20internal%20advocacy/strategy" target="_blank">美国政界人士</a>呼吁西方政府建立中央稀土加工中心，加拿大已经在实施这一计划。</p>   <p>In Saskatchewan, government scientists are working to launch their own rare earths processing technology after attempts to buy Chinese technology sputtered in 2020.翻译:在萨斯喀彻温省，政府科学家在 2020 年试图购买中国技术失败后，正在努力推出自己的稀土加工技术。</p>   <p>"We looked at existing technologies and said, 'There's a better way of doing this,'" said Mike Crabtree, CEO of the Saskatchewan Research Council (SRC), which is funded by the provincial government. "We wanted to put our own spin on it."翻译:萨斯喀彻温省研究委员会 (SRC) 由省政府资助，其首席执行官迈克·克拉布特里 (Mike Crabtree) 表示：“我们研究了现有技术并表示，‘有更好的方法可以做到这一点。’” “我们想加入我们自己的想法。”</p>   <p>Using artificial intelligence, the company designed processing equipment it believes is more efficient than Chinese rivals. Rather than needing up to 100 people to run, as with traditional solvent extraction, the SRC estimates that only four people will be needed to run its plant, which it hopes to open by the end of 2024.翻译:该公司利用人工智能设计了其认为比中国竞争对手更高效的处理设备。 SRC 估计只需要 4 个人来运营其工厂，而不是像传统的溶剂萃取那样需要多达 100 人来运营，该工厂希望在 2024 年底前开业。</p>   <p>While the SRC's goal is to spur mining across Canada, Crabtree said he is open to licensing the technology for use anywhere in the world.翻译:虽然 SRC 的目标是刺激加拿大各地的采矿业，但 Crabtree 表示，他愿意授权该技术在世界任何地方使用。</p>   <p>"This entire sector as a whole needs to grow outside of China in order to support the energy transition," he said.翻译:他说：“整个行业需要在中国境外发展，以支持能源转型。”</p>   <p>Crabtree and the SRC expect their facility to cost more to build than Chinese rivals but less to operate, a function of their desire to make processing equipment that has no waste and recycles acid and other key chemicals.翻译:Crabtree 和 SRC 预计，他们的工厂建设成本比中国竞争对手更高，但运营成本更低，因为他们希望制造无废物并回收酸和其他关键化学品的加工设备。</p>   <p>And while MP Materials and others have struggled to tailor their processing equipment to specific geological deposits, SRC, Ucore and others say they believe their new refining processes will be able to process the critical minerals from multiple locations across the globe.翻译:尽管 MP Materials 和其他公司一直在努力根据特定的地质矿床定制加工设备，但 SRC、Ucore 和其他公司表示，他们相信他们的新精炼工艺将能够加工来自全球多个地点的关键矿物。</p>   <p>"These new sources for rare earths are going to be paramount if we're going to reach global net zero targets," said Steve Schoffstall of the Sprott Energy Transition Materials ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SETM.O" target="_blank">(SETM.O)</a>, which holds shares in several rare earths companies.翻译:Sprott Energy Transition Materials ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SETM.O" target="_blank">(SETM.O) 的 Steve Schoffstall 表示：“如果我们要实现全球净零目标，这些新的稀土来源将至关重要。”Sprott Energy Transition Materials ETF (SETM.O)</a>持有多家稀土公司的股份。</p>   <p>Shares of Ucore rose more than 6% on Monday in Canadian trading after the Reuters story, while shares traded over-the-counter in the United States gained nearly 8%.翻译:路透社报道后，周一加拿大交易市场 Ucore 股价上涨逾 6%，而美国场外交易股价上涨近 8%。</p>   <p>- For daily comprehensive coverage of COP28 in your inbox, sign up for the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/newsletters/reuters-sustainable-switch/?utm_source=site&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=cop28">Reuters Sustainable Switch newsletter here</a>.翻译:- 如需在您的收件箱中获取 COP28 的每日全面报道，请<a href="https://www.reuters.com/newsletters/reuters-sustainable-switch/?utm_source=site&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=cop28">在此处注册路透社 Sustainable Switch 时事通讯</a>。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ernest Scheyder; Editing by Veronica Brown and Claudia Parsons翻译:欧内斯特·谢德报道；维罗妮卡·布朗和克劳迪娅·帕森斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 19:52:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B4GSIAEK75MPFAJ4FMI4KX5J5Y</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/western-start-ups-seek-break-chinas-grip-rare-earths-refining-2023-12-04/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ernest Scheyder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>MINING</category>
                
                <category>RAREEARTHS/ (UPDATE 1, INSIGHT, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着亏损和债务的增加，中国大型养猪企业纷纷进军]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/uRMNVUbsk1MAge_hmgEbYPTCDRo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MEJSLLGKGZNLJHKAD36G7XCZR4.jpg" alt="Piglets drink milk from a sow at a pig farm in Yaji翻译:雅集养猪场的小猪正在喝母猪的奶" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Piglets drink milk from a sow at a pig farm in Yaji翻译:雅集养猪场的小猪正在喝母猪的奶, Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, China, March 21, 2018. REUTERS/Thomas Suen/File Photo/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/OtyJplppFN9KK3MQPTbuy8KuXnA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/B4C5YB6Q7VPPROATXNJYAGK6JY.jpg" alt="The wife of pig farmer Han Yi prepares feed for pigs on his farm at a village in Changtu翻译:昌图某村养猪户韩毅的妻子正在自家农场准备猪饲料" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The wife of pig farmer Han Yi prepares feed for pigs on his farm at a village in Changtu翻译:昌图某村养猪户韩毅的妻子正在自家农场准备猪饲料 county, Liaoning province, China January 17, 2019. REUTERS/Ryan Woo/File Photo翻译:2019年1月17日，中国辽宁省昌图县一个村庄的养猪户韩毅的妻子在他的农场里为猪准备饲料。REUTERS/Ryan Woo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TKOTZEOTOQr1J5AeI9hlmJwleas=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WZS7A4KLFJPL5EGPXOUMX6XEOE.jpg" alt="Pigs are seen on a family farm in Xiaoxinzhuang village, Hebei翻译:河北小辛庄村的一个家庭农场里看到了猪" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Pigs are seen on a family farm in  Xiaoxinzhuang village, Hebei province, China January 25, 2018. Picture taken January 25, 2018.  REUTERS/Dominique Patton翻译:2018年1月25日，中国河北省小辛庄村的一个家庭农场里看到猪。照片拍摄于2018年1月25日。路透社/Dominique Patton</figcaption></figure>                 <p>The biggest pig breeders in China, consumer of fully half the world's pork, seem to have bitten off more than they can chew.翻译:中国最大的养猪企业消耗了全球一半的猪肉，但它们似乎已经吃不消了。</p>   <p>Big agribusinesses have elbowed their way into the sector and are rapidly modernising it, but have expanded pig herds so aggressively that, with demand now in a downturn, their hog prices are falling, losses are mounting, and debt is rising.翻译:大型农业综合企业纷纷涌入该行业，并迅速实现现代化，但其生猪存栏规模却过于激进，在需求低迷的情况下，它们的生猪价格不断下跌，损失不断增加，债务不断增加。</p>   <p>More huge losses are expected next year, putting China's pig enterprises under pressure to slim down their breeding herds and sell off farms, many of which are sitting empty.翻译:预计明年将出现更多巨额亏损，这将使中国养猪企业面临减少种猪存栏和出售养殖场的压力，其中许多养殖场已空置。</p>   <p>For now, however, they are digging in, hoping to wait out the market downturn and reap a bonanza when prices eventually recover. And that is raising the stakes, not just for themselves but for their overseas feed suppliers, genetics firms, and the struggling global pork trade.翻译:然而，目前他们正在深耕，希望等待市场低迷结束，并在价格最终回升时收获丰厚的回报。这不仅增加了他们自己的风险，也增加了他们的海外饲料供应商、基因公司和陷入困境的全球猪肉贸易的风险。</p>   <p>"It all comes down to how deep these companies' pockets are," said Lyle Jones, China sales director at U.S.-based Genesus Inc, which supplies breeding pigs to the leading producers.翻译:“这一切都取决于这些公司的财力有多雄厚，”美国加裕公司中国销售总监莱尔琼斯说，该公司向领先的生产商供应种猪。</p>   <p>Hog farming, like other Chinese sectors from homebuilding to electric vehicles, has in recent years prioritised growth and market share over profits, creating a surplus that has driven pig prices lower and is now crowding out imports.翻译:与从住宅建筑到电动汽车等中国其他行业一样，生猪养殖近年来将增长和市场份额置于利润之上，造成的盈余导致生猪价格下跌，目前正在挤出进口。</p>   <p>China's cash hog prices have averaged well below even the most efficient producers' costs this year, for the first time in nearly a decade, and in the past three months alone have dropped 15% to 14.5 yuan per kilogram.翻译:今年，中国的生猪现金平均价格甚至远低于最高效生产者的成本，这是近十年来的首次，并且仅在过去三个月就下跌了15%，至每公斤14.5元。</p>   <p>The most-active live hog futures on the Dalian Commodity Exchange have tumbled 7.3% since the beginning of last week to 13,910 yuan ($1,949) per metric ton, the lowest since they began trading almost three years ago.翻译:大连商品交易所最活跃的生猪期货自上周初以来已下跌 7.3%，至每吨 13,910 元人民币（1,949 美元），为近三年前开始交易以来的最低水平。</p>      <p>The downdraft has defied both state efforts to prop up prices with token purchases for official reserves, and the start of the peak winter season for pork consumption.翻译:国家通过象征性购买官方储备来提振价格的努力，以及冬季猪肉消费旺季的开始，都无济于事。</p>   <p>And it is squeezing a number of big producers in the $200 billion-a-year industry, with the top 10 producers alone recording a 13% increase in net debt this year as of end-September, according to state-run media.翻译:据官方媒体报道，这一年产值达 2000 亿美元的行业中的一些大型生产商受到挤压，截至 9 月底，仅前 10 名生产商的净债务就增加了 13%。</p>   <p>New Hope Liuhe <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/000876.SZ" target="_blank">(000876.SZ)</a>, China's third-largest producer and the world's fifth largest, sold off farms last year and told investors in July it wanted to sell more, while bringing in strategic investors to its poultry and food units.翻译:中国第三大、全球第五大生产商新希望六和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/000876.SZ" target="_blank">（000876.SZ）</a>去年出售了农场，并于7月告诉投资者希望出售更多，同时为其家禽和食品业务引入战略投资者。</p>   <p>The company has made "some progress" on those fronts, it told investors on Friday, but gave no details. It also said a 7.35 billion yuan private share issue announced on Nov. 30 would help it to repay loans and rein in debt.翻译:该公司周五告诉投资者，在这些方面已经取得了“一些进展”，但没有透露细节。该公司还表示，11月30日宣布的73.5亿元非公开发行股票将有助于其偿还贷款和控制债务。</p>   <p>Major producers Tech-Bank <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002124.SZ" target="_blank">(002124.SZ)</a> and Fujian Aonong <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/603363.SS" target="_blank">(603363.SS)</a> have been selling off stakes in themselves or in subsidiaries to raise cash, while Aonong's debt-to-equity ratio reached a hefty 8.26 in the third quarter according to LSEG data. Neither company responded to requests for comment about their current challenges and working capital requirements.</p>    <h 1="">EXPANDING DEBT</h>  <p>Jiangxi Zhengbang Technology <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002157.SZ" target="_blank">(002157.SZ)</a>, which became China's second-largest producer after a rapid expansion drive, was forced into a restructuring last year despite <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/troubled-chinese-hog-breeder-zhengbang-gets-support-from-railway-firm" target="_blank">support from</a> local government-run firms.翻译:江西正邦科技<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002157.SZ" target="_blank">（002157.SZ）</a>经过快速扩张成为中国第二大生产商，尽管<a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/troubled-chinese-hog-breeder-zhengbang-gets-support-from-railway-firm" target="_blank">有地方政府企业的支持</a>，但去年仍被迫进行重组。</p>   <p>Moreover, with debt levels swelling across the Chinese economy, banks and local governments have become less willing or able to offer support.翻译:此外，随着中国经济的债务水平不断膨胀，银行和地方政府提供支持的意愿或能力越来越低。</p>   <p>"Over the past two years, banks could lend them a lot so these companies expanded very fast," said an analyst at an equity research firm, who was not authorised to speak to the media and declined to be named.翻译:一家股票研究公司的分析师表示：“过去两年，银行可以向他们提供大量贷款，因此这些公司扩张得非常快。”该分析师未获授权接受媒体采访，但拒绝透露姓名。</p>   <p>But now, especially given the companies' high debt levels, the analyst said: "It's hard for them to borrow any money from the banks."翻译:但现在，特别是考虑到这些公司的高债务水平，分析师表示：“他们很难从银行借到任何钱。”</p>   <p>Analysts say the biggest players - industry leader Muyuan Foods Co , a low-cost producer and one of the few generating cashflow, and No. 2 Wens Foodstuff Group Co <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300498.SZ" target="_blank">(300498.SZ)</a>, which has reduced costs significantly - may be well-positioned for a shake-out.翻译:分析师表示，最大的参与者——行业领先者牧原食品有限公司（一家低成本生产商，也是为数不多的产生现金流的公司之一）和排名第二的温氏食品集团有限公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300498.SZ" target="_blank">（300498.SZ）</a> ——成本大幅降低——可能处于有利地位。进行一次洗牌。</p>   <p>But challenges are mounting as China produces record volumes of pork, in part a legacy of past encouragement from Beijing, which fears food price volatility and urged a major expansion of sow herds after an African swine fever outbreak in the late 2010s killed half the country's pigs.翻译:但随着中国猪肉产量创历史新高，挑战也越来越大，这在一定程度上是北京过去鼓励政策的结果。北京担心食品价格波动，并在2010年代末非洲猪瘟爆发导致中国一半生猪死亡后敦促大幅扩大母猪存栏量。</p>   <p>Muyuan alone has more than tripled its sow herd since 2018, chasing after market share along with other big publicly listed firms, and now has three times as many sows as WH Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0288.HK" target="_blank">(0288.HK)</a>, which owns top U.S. producer Smithfield Foods.翻译:自2018年以来，仅牧原公司的母猪存栏量就增加了两倍多，与其他大型上市公司一起争夺市场份额，目前母猪数量是万洲国际<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0288.HK" target="_blank">（0288.HK）</a>的三倍，后者拥有美国顶级生产商史密斯菲尔德食品公司。</p>   <p>Analysts at Hua'an Securities forecast that hog output would jump 10% in the first half of 2024. That follows a 17% surge in the first nine months of this year at China's 15 big market-listed breeders even as they reported 200 billion yuan in combined net losses.翻译:华安证券分析师预测，2024年上半年生猪产量将增长10%。今年前9个月，中国15家大型上市养殖企业的产值达2000亿元，但生猪产量仍增长17%。合并净亏损。</p>   <p>To make matters worse, pork consumption in China has been hit both by <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">slowing economic growth</a> and by diners' changing preferences, as more health-conscious consumers - especially young people and urbanites - switch to poultry and other foods.翻译:更糟糕的是，中国的猪肉消费受到<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">经济增长放缓</a>和食客偏好变化的打击，越来越多注重健康的消费者——尤其是年轻人和城市居民——转向家禽和其他食品。</p>   <p>And the costs of battling disease have risen substantially, with African swine fever now endemic and a constant threat to all farms.翻译:与疾病作斗争的成本大幅上升，非洲猪瘟现已流行，并对所有农场构成持续威胁。</p>   <p>China's agriculture ministry has warned of heavier losses for the sector in early 2024 than a year ago and urged pig producers to cut output.翻译:中国农业部警告称，2024年初该行业的损失将比一年前更严重，并敦促生猪生产者减产。</p>   <p>While the big producers have slashed spending on new equipment and taken other cost-cutting measures, most remain reluctant to unload idle farms and reduce breeding herds.翻译:尽管大型生产商已经削减了新设备的支出并采取了其他削减成本的措施，但大多数生产商仍然不愿意出售闲置农场并减少种猪群。</p>   <p>"Leading companies aggressively expanded in 2020-21, the capex was huge, and they're not willing to reduce capacity, even under the current weak price," said Flora Zhu, director of China Corporate Research at Fitch Ratings.翻译:惠誉国际评级中国企业研究总监朱芙表示：“2020-21年，龙头企业积极扩张，资本支出巨大，即使在当前疲软的价格下，他们也不愿意减少产能。”</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1364 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.1364 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Dominique Patton; Additional reporting by Beijing Newsroom; Editing by Edmund Klamann翻译:多米尼克·巴顿报道；北京新闻编辑室补充报道；编辑：埃德蒙·克拉曼</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 11:46:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">SIALONVXVNOBTL2LSTR7BKGBJM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-big-pig-breeders-dig-losses-debts-mount-2023-12-04/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Dominique Patton]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>HOGS/ (ANALYSIS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
