<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 18:31:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国和墨西哥将合作加强投资安全审查]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/NbtrGQrr1iTdoV8b4Dm_kDr5unk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3HTVIECICJJJZFPVDFRIASMPW4.jpg" alt="U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen visits Mexico City翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦访问墨西哥城" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen gives a statement to the press during her visit in Mexico City, Mexico December 6, 2023. REUTERS/Daniel Becerril翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦于 2023 年 12 月 6 日访问墨西哥墨西哥城期间向新闻界发表声明。 REUTERS/Daniel Becerril</figcaption></figure>       <p>The U.S. Treasury said on Thursday it signed an agreement with Mexico's finance ministry to cooperate on strengthening screening of foreign investments to enhance national security, including regularly sharing information on best practices.翻译:美国财政部周四表示，它与墨西哥财政部签署了一项协议，合作加强对外国投资的审查，以加强国家安全，包括定期分享最佳实践信息。</p>   <p>The Biden administration is promoting Mexico as a premier investment destination for U.S. supply chains and wants to ensure that the country has a robust screening regime in place to handle the influx.翻译:拜登政府正在将墨西哥宣传为美国供应链的首要投资目的地，并希望确保该国拥有健全的筛查制度来应对涌入的人潮。</p>   <p>The effort is aimed at helping Mexico develop a screening body similar to the Treasury-run Committee on Foreign Investment the U.S. (CFIUS), which reviews purchases of American companies by foreign-owned entities and other inbound investments.翻译:这项工作旨在帮助墨西哥建立一个类似于美国财政部管理的外国投资委员会（CFIUS）的审查机构，该委员会负责审查外资实体对美国公司的收购和其他入境投资。</p>   <p>"Like our own investment screening regime, CFIUS, increased engagement with Mexico will help maintain an open investment climate while monitoring and addressing security risks, making both our countries safer," Yellen said in announcing the memorandum of intent with Mexican Finance Minister Rogelio Ramirez de la O.翻译:耶伦在宣布与墨西哥财政部长罗赫利奥·拉米雷斯·德（Rogelio Ramirez de）的意向备忘录时表示：“就像我们自己的投资审查制度（CFIUS）一样，加强与墨西哥的接触将有助于维持开放的投资环境，同时监控和应对安全风险，使我们两国更加安全。”拉奥.</p>   <p>Yellen wraps up a three-day visit to Mexico City to enhance economic ties and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/yellen-mexico-announce-new-actions-stemming-fentanyl-flows-2023-12-06/">boost cooperation</a> to stem the flow of the deadly opioid fentanyl to the United States via Mexico, where precursor chemicals from China are often mixed.</p>    <h 1="">"NEAR-SHORING" BOOM</h>  <p>Mexico is attracting a major influx of manufacturing investments to supply the U.S. market, raising concerns that China or other countries could use it as a back door to get around restrictions on U.S. export controls for sensitive technologies such as semiconductors.翻译:墨西哥正在吸引大量制造业投资涌入，以供应美国市场，这引发了人们的担忧，即中国或其他国家可能会利用墨西哥作为后门，绕过美国对半导体等敏感技术的出口管制限制。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/mexican-businesses-warmed-by-glow-nearshoring-dawn-2023-11-06/">near-shoring boom</a> brought Mexico $32.2 billion in foreign direct investment in the first three quarters of 2023, close to the full-year 2022 total of $36 billion.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/mexican-businesses-warmed-by-glow-nearshoring-dawn-2023-11-06/">近岸投资热潮</a>在 2023 年前三季度为墨西哥带来了 322 亿美元的外国直接投资，接近 2022 年全年 360 亿美元的总额。</p>   <p>High profile projects include an estimated $5 billion Tesla <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a> electric vehicle factory that has prompted Chinese suppliers to announce plans to invest over $1 billion nearby.翻译:引人注目的项目包括估计价值 50 亿美元的特斯拉<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a>电动汽车工厂，该工厂已促使中国供应商宣布计划在附近投资超过 10 亿美元。</p>   <p>While CFIUS' increased scrutiny in recent years has sharply reduced Chinese investment in the United States, Yellen told reporters she does not want to preclude China from injecting funds into Mexico or the U.S. when there are no national security concerns.</p>    <h 1="">CHINESE INVESTMENT WELCOMED</h>  <p>If Chinese firms want to produce in Mexico for the U.S. electric vehicle battery market, they would have to comply with the Treasury's new "foreign entity of concern" rules that limit Chinese control of a producing subsidiary to 25%.翻译:如果中国公司想在墨西哥为美国电动汽车电池市场生产，他们就必须遵守财政部新的“外国关注实体”规则，该规则将中国对生产子公司的控制权限制在25%。</p>   <p>"If Chinese involvement triggered those rules, which are meant to avoid undue dependence on China, then that's a no," Yellen said.翻译:耶伦表示：“如果中国的参与引发了这些旨在避免过度依赖中国的规则，那么那就不行。”</p>   <p>Private Chinese firms are also investing in the U.S. production of other clean energy goods to take advantage of domestic tax credits, and "they can play a role" in creating a diverse supply base in the sector, she said.翻译:她说，中国私营企业也在投资美国其他清洁能源产品的生产，以利用国内税收抵免，并且“它们可以在创建该行业多元化的供应基础方面发挥作用”。</p>   <p>The Treasury and other members of CFIUS, which include the of the U.S. departments of State, Defense, Homeland Security, and Commerce, regularly work with governments to improve their investment screening. More than 20 countries, including Mexico, have implemented or enhanced their regimes over the past decade.</p>    <h 1="">PAYMENTS COOPERATION</h>  <p>Yellen said that Treasury and Mexican Finance Ministry officials on Thursday also discussed cross border payment systems, including possibly integrating them more deeply, which could enhance trade and investment benefits.翻译:耶伦表示，财政部和墨西哥财政部官员周四还讨论了跨境支付系统，包括可能更深入地整合它们，这可能会增强贸易和投资效益。</p>   <p>"I see real potential here and potential here and welcome further exploration of the possibility of interlinkage and other ways to improve connectivity between the U.S. and Mexican payment systems," Yellen added in prepared remarks.翻译:耶伦在准备好的讲话中补充道：“我看到了这里的真正潜力和潜力，并欢迎进一步探索互连的可能性以及改善美国和墨西哥支付系统之间连通性的其他方式。”</p>    <span>Reporting by David Lawder; Editing by Richard Chang翻译:大卫·劳德报道；编辑：张理查德</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 18:06:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">YMPETP6HNNOX7FP5WXTMVG47LI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/us-mexico-cooperate-strengthening-security-screening-investments-2023-12-07/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Lawder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>MEXICO/YELLEN (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[坎贝尔强调美国需要批准与太平洋岛屿的交易]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/R4hJXTiTi1kQgPjqFYF8wpj8nCY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/K52BVLS37RLY7K3JIFYN7ONX3Y.jpg" alt="China Development Forum in Beijing翻译:中国发展高层论坛在北京举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Kurt Campbell attends the China Development Forum in Beijing翻译:中国发展高层论坛在北京举行, China March 23, 2019. REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:库尔特·坎贝尔于 2019 年 3 月 23 日出席在中国北京举行的中国发展高层论坛。路透社/Thomas Peter/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>It is essential the United States moves ahead in approving new agreements with three Pacific island states, the U.S. Indo-Pacific coordinator Kurt Campbell said on Thursday, stressing that China is waiting to take advantage if the United States fails to fulfill its commitments.翻译:美国印太协调员库尔特·坎贝尔周四表示，美国必须继续批准与三个太平洋岛国的新协议，并强调，如果美国未能履行其承诺，中国将伺机而动。</p>   <p>Campbell made the comments about new 20-year funding programs for the Federated States of Micronesia (FSM), the Marshall Islands (RMI) and Palau awaiting<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/spending-fight-imperils-us-pacific-island-funding-meant-counter-china-2023-11-29/"> congressional approval</a> while testifying at a Senate hearing on his nomination to become the Biden administration's next deputy secretary of state.翻译:坎贝尔在参议院关于他被提名为拜登政府下任副国务卿的听证会上作证时，就密克罗尼西亚联邦（FSM）、马绍尔群岛（RMI）和帕劳等待<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/spending-fight-imperils-us-pacific-island-funding-meant-counter-china-2023-11-29/">国会</a>批准的新20年资助计划发表了评论。状态。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Brunnstrom翻译:大卫·布伦斯特罗姆报道</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 17:45:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Q2LDO7BUUJPNTMBE4YA63S7UOE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/campbell-stresses-need-us-approve-deals-with-pacific-islands-2023-12-07/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CAMPBELL/PACIFIC (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[台湾报告中国在附近进行罕见的夜间军事活动]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0MmJoAIClCRDJdREHpjrhFkFADs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GANHRPL4K5JANEISKNFV6PHBKM.jpg" alt="Illustration shows Chinese and Taiwanese flags翻译:插图显示中国和台湾国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese and Taiwanese printed flags are seen in this illustration taken, April 28, 2022. Picture taken April 28, 2022.  REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration翻译:这张摄于 2022 年 4 月 28 日的插图中可以看到中国和台湾印刷的旗帜。照片摄于 2022 年 4 月 28 日。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration</figcaption></figure>       <p>Taiwan reported rare nighttime Chinese military activity around the island on Thursday, including aircraft crossing the sensitive median line of the Taiwan Strait, as Beijing continues such missions ahead of Taiwan's January election.翻译:台湾周四报道称，中国在该岛周围进行了罕见的夜间军事活动，其中包括飞机穿越台湾海峡敏感的中线，而北京在台湾一月份大选之前继续执行此类任务。</p>   <p>Democratically governed Taiwan, which China claims as its own territory, has complained for the past four years of regular Chinese military patrols and drills near the island.翻译:中国声称台湾是民主统治的台湾，过去四年来，台湾一直抱怨中国在台湾附近定期进行军事巡逻和演习。</p>   <p>Taiwan holds presidential and parliamentary polls on Jan. 13 and campaigning has kicked into high gear.翻译:台湾将于 1 月 13 日举行总统和议会选举，竞选活动已进入紧锣密鼓的阶段。</p>   <p>Relations with China are a major point of contention.翻译:与中国的关系是一个主要争论点。</p>   <p>Taiwan's defence ministry said that starting around 7.30 pm (1130 GMT) on Thursday evening it had detected Su-30, J-10 and J-11 fighters as well as nuclear capable H-6 bombers and early warning aircraft operating off northern and central Taiwan and to the island's southwest.翻译:台湾国防部表示，从周四晚上 7 点 30 分左右（格林威治标准时间 1130 点）开始，它发现了在台湾北部和中部海域执行任务的 Su-30、J-10 和 J-11 战斗机以及具有核能力的 H-6 轰炸机和预警机和岛的西南部。</p>   <p>Thirteen of those aircraft crossed the Taiwan Strait's median line, or areas close by, working with Chinese warships to carry out "joint combat readiness patrols", the ministry added.翻译:国防部补充说，其中 13 架飞机飞越台湾海峡中线或附近地区，与中国军舰一起进行“联合战备巡逻”。</p>   <p>The strait's median line once served as an unofficial barrier between the two sides, but Chinese planes now regularly fly over it.翻译:海峡中线曾经是两岸之间的非正式屏障，但中国飞机​​现在经常飞越该海峡。</p>   <p>Taiwan sent its own forces to monitor, the ministry said.翻译:国防部表示，台湾派出自己的部队进行监视。</p>   <p>Over the past month, Taiwan has reported at least four other similar large-scale sorties by China's air force, which Beijing has not commented on, though those took place during the day.翻译:过去一个月，台湾报告称中国空军至少进行了另外四次类似的大规模飞行，北京方面没有对此发表评论，尽管这些都是在白天进行的。</p>   <p>China says its activities near Taiwan are aimed at preventing "collusion" between Taiwan separatists and the United States, and protecting China's territorial integrity.翻译:中国表示，其在台湾附近的活动旨在防止台湾分裂分子与美国“勾结”，保护中国的领土完整。</p>   <p>Taiwan's government, which has repeatedly offered talks with China, rejects Beijing's sovereignty claims and says only the island's people can decide their future.翻译:台湾政府多次提出与中国进行谈判，拒绝北京的主权主张，并表示只有台湾人民才能决定他们的未来。</p>   <p>The ruling Democratic Progressive Party's Lai Ching-te, whom Beijing has denounced as a separatist, is the frontrunner to be Taiwan's next president, according to opinion polls.翻译:民意调查显示，执政党民进党的赖清德是台湾下届总统的热门人选，北京方面谴责赖清德为分裂分子。</p>   <p>Taiwan's main opposition party, the Kuomintang, traditionally supports close ties with Beijing, and has pledged to reopen dialogue with China if it wins the election.翻译:台湾主要反对党国民党传统上支持与北京保持密切关系，并承诺如果赢得选举将与中国重新开放对话。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ben Blanchard
Editing by Mark Potter翻译:本·布兰查德 (Ben Blanchard) 报道 马克·波特 (Mark Potter) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 13:35:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2KSXXYGEPVKOVNOWEKANTZN4ZI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-reports-rare-nighttime-chinese-military-activity-nearby-2023-12-07/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>TAIWAN</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/DEFENCE (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[印尼考虑对美国、中国、印度等20个国家实行签证豁免]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/b3duDxCfW_WXq5C-KwJepEBRPx4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/24TR2DLLCZPLZCYS7INCHJQBUE.jpg" alt="Passengers arrive at the I Gusti Ngurah Rai International Airport in Badung, Bali翻译:乘客抵达巴厘岛巴东 I Gusti Ngurah Rai 国际机场" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Passengers arrive at the I Gusti Ngurah Rai International Airport in Badung, Bali翻译:乘客抵达巴厘岛巴东 I Gusti Ngurah Rai 国际机场, Indonesia, September 2, 2022. REUTERS/Willy Kurniawan翻译:2022 年 9 月 2 日，乘客抵达印度尼西亚巴厘岛巴东的 I Gusti Ngurah Rai 国际机场。 REUTERS/Willy Kurniawan</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/EdsVgi6A96yqjtwFi3d468Vrl_0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5437MVQXTVIRJGJYHQBINHMN4Y.jpg" alt="Vendors sell bandanas as tourists watch the sunset on Seminyak beach in Bali翻译:巴厘岛塞米亚克海滩上，游客观看日落时，商贩们出售头巾" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Vendors sell bandanas as tourists watch the sunset on Seminyak beach in Bali翻译:巴厘岛塞米亚克海滩上，游客观看日落时，商贩们出售头巾, Indonesia August 17, 2017.   REUTERS/Thomas White/File Photo翻译:2017 年 8 月 17 日，印度尼西亚巴厘岛塞米亚克海滩上，游客们在观看日落时，商贩们在出售头巾。路透社/Thomas White/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>Indonesia is considering granting visa-free entry to nationals of 20 countries, including the United States, China, Australia, India, South Korea, Germany, Britain and France, to boost its tourism and economy, its tourism minister said on Thursday.翻译:印尼旅游部长周四表示，印尼正在考虑向美国、中国、澳大利亚、印度、韩国、德国、英国和法国等 20 个国家的国民提供免签证入境，以促进旅游业和经济发展。</p>   <p>The government will finalise the list of countries included in the provision within one month, according to a statement.翻译:一份声明称，政府将在一个月内最终确定该条款所涵盖的国家名单。</p>   <p>Minister Sandiaga Uno said the president had instructed the government to consider the visa waiver as a means of boosting the economy, tourism visits and investment.翻译:桑迪亚加·乌诺部长表示，总统已指示政府考虑将免签证作为促进经济、旅游和投资的一种手段。</p>   <p>There were more than 16 million foreign arrivals in Indonesia in pre-pandemic 2019, according to official data.翻译:根据官方数据，2019 年疫情爆发前，有超过 1600 万外国游客抵达印度尼西亚。</p>   <p>From January to October this year, Indonesia received 9.49 million foreign visitors, an increase of 124.3% from the same period in 2022.翻译:今年1月至10月，印尼接待外国游客949万人次，比2022年同期增长124.3%。</p>   <p>Indonesia is the latest country in Southeast Asia to consider waiving visas for China, a major travel market, following Singapore, which on Thursday said a 30-day mutual visa exemption with China will be implemented early next year.翻译:继新加坡周四表示将于明年初实施与中国的 30 天互免签证政策后，印度尼西亚成为最新一个考虑对主要旅游市场中国免签的东南亚国家。</p>   <p>Thailand and recently Malaysia have also waived visas for visitors from China and India.翻译:泰国和马来西亚最近也对来自中国和印度的游客免签。</p>    <span>Reporting by Stanley Widianto; Editing by Martin Petty翻译:斯坦利·维迪安托报道；马丁·佩蒂编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 12:18:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">PMQMWY3WLNOHNNKBAQDTE4JHV4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/indonesia-eyes-visa-waivers-20-countries-including-us-china-india-2023-12-07/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>INDONESIA</category>
                
                <category>TOURISM/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国放松毛泽东时代居住规定的努力遇到障碍]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/zPgRUbrc5WUNtmo12K-BdPXN8Zw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/K2XIGG3OFRJR7HBBWFTBTXBF6A.jpg" alt="Traveller is seen with his belongings at a railway station in Beijing翻译:在北京的一个火车站，有人看到旅客带着他的物品" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A traveller is seen with his belongings at a railway station, following the coronavirus disease (COVID-19) outbreak, in Beijing, China January 13, 2021. Picture taken January 13, 2021. REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2021 年 1 月 13 日，中国北京，冠状病毒病 (COVID-19) 爆发后，一名旅客在火车站携带行李。照片拍摄于 2021 年 1 月 13 日。路透社/Thomas Peter/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/6KHuVnYRTeMOIQvk19rpAWwokCw=/728x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2Q4XK4T3HZL6NKXTDQPVVQUMIA.jpg" alt="People wait to board trains at the Shanghai Hongqiao railway station ahead of the National Day holiday, in Shanghai翻译:国庆长假前，上海虹桥火车站，人们等待上车。" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People wait to board trains at the Shanghai Hongqiao railway station ahead of the National Day holiday, in Shanghai翻译:国庆长假前，上海虹桥火车站，人们等待上车。, China September 28, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/files</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/G0W_VkC1QtHooizMyxU1d7vc3AA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/V5FBCLPR6VIAZIVMNAMD55SJ7I.jpg" alt="People wait to board trains at the Shanghai Hongqiao railway station ahead of the National Day holiday, in Shanghai翻译:国庆长假前，上海虹桥火车站，人们等待上车。" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People wait to board trains at the Shanghai Hongqiao railway station ahead of the National Day holiday, in Shanghai翻译:国庆长假前，上海虹桥火车站，人们等待上车。, China September 28, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2023年9月28日，中国上海，国庆节假期前，人们在上海虹桥火车站等待上车。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>                 <p>Yang Guang's rise from a village farmer to an Audi-driving businessman with two properties hinged largely on one of the most coveted documents in China: an urban hukou, or residency permit.翻译:杨光从一名乡村农民成长为一名拥有两处房产、开奥迪的商人，很大程度上取决于中国最令人垂涎​​的证件之一：城市户口或居住证。</p>   <p>The 45-year-old who lives in the central city of Zhengzhou likens the permit - which typically ties a person's access to health, education, loans and other services to their birthplace - to a "cattle ear-tag the state clipped us with".翻译:这位住在市中心郑州的 45 岁男子将许可证比作“国家给我们剪的牛耳标”——它通常将一个人获得医疗、教育、贷款和其他服务的机会与其出生地联系起来。 。</p>   <p>"It uses this tag to sort us into different categories of people entitled to different sets of privileges and subjected to different obligations," he said.翻译:“它使用这个标签将我们分为不同类别的人，这些人有权享有不同的特权并承担不同的义务，”他说。</p>   <p>When Zhengzhou in the early 2000s temporarily allowed those who bought an apartment to also qualify for a city hukou, Yang seized the opportunity, allowing him to register a business and open stores across Henan province's capital, transforming his fortunes.翻译:2000年代初，郑州暂时允许购房者获得城市户口，杨抓住了这个机会，允许他在河南省会城市注册企业并开设商店，改变了他的命运。</p>   <p>In recent months, Chinese authorities have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-make-it-easier-citizens-settle-small-medium-cities-2023-08-03/">fanned hopes</a> among some economists that the internal passport system that has largely tethered people's destinies to their place of origin since the 1950s may be in its dying days. A <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">distressed</a> property market and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-has-no-pain-free-solutions-its-slowing-economy-2023-08-24/">sluggish</a> consumption have injected new urgency into a drive to loosen restrictions and grant more people the opportunities that urban registration affords.翻译:近几个月来，中国当局在一些经济学家中<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-make-it-easier-citizens-settle-small-medium-cities-2023-08-03/">激起了希望</a>，即自 20 世纪 50 年代以来在很大程度上将人们的命运与原籍地联系在一起的内部护照制度可能已到了消亡的时候。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">低迷的</a>房地产市场和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-has-no-pain-free-solutions-its-slowing-economy-2023-08-24/">低迷的</a>消费为放松限制、为更多人提供落户机会注入了新的紧迫性。</p>   <p>The Ministry of Public Security in August called on cities with up to 3 million people to abolish hukou, and those with 3-5 million to significantly relax issuance. Zhejiang and Jiangsu provinces have announced plans for an almost complete opening to new residents.翻译:公安部8月呼吁人口300万以下的城市取消户口，人口3-500万的城市大幅放宽户口发放。浙江和江苏省已宣布计划几乎全面向新居民开放。</p>   <p>But two people involved in hukou policy discussions within the central government told Reuters that progress is stalling, making further significant breakthroughs unlikely, especially in China's larger cities.翻译:但两名参与中央政府内部户口政策讨论的人士告诉路透社，进展正在停滞，不可能取得进一步的重大突破，尤其是在中国的大城市。</p>   <p>The accounts described previously unreported tensions over hukou reform, with Chinese officials acknowledging a strong economic rationale for change but hesitant to take decisive moves that might disrupt social stability and burden indebted cities with added costs.翻译:这些报道描述了此前未报道过的户口改革紧张局势，中国官员承认改革有强有力的经济理由，但不愿采取果断行动，因为这可能会破坏社会稳定并给负债城市带来额外成本。</p>   <p>"Hukou reform is a hard bone to chew," said Jia Kang, founding president of the China Academy of New Supply-Side Economics, who advises the government on policies including hukou. "It should be a natural process, it's not something you can do simply because you want to."翻译:“户口改革是一块难啃的骨头，”中国新供给侧经济研究院创始院长贾康说，他为政府提供包括户口在内的政策建议。 “这应该是一个自然的过程，不是你想做就能做的事情。”</p>   <p>"Currently, all reforms are difficult."翻译:“目前，一切改革都困难重重。”</p>   <p>Jia said that while neither the central government nor local governments oppose further hukou easing, implementation depends on cities having the funds and public service capacity.翻译:贾庆林表示，虽然中央政府和地方政府都不反对进一步放宽户口，但具体实施取决于城市有资金和公共服务能力。</p>   <p>China's Ministry of Public Security and the National Development and Reform Commission, the top planning agency, did not respond to requests for comment.翻译:中国公安部和最高规划机构国家发展和改革委员会没有回应置评请求。</p>   <p>The advisers said China's largest cities have limited residential supply and face pollution and congestion, affecting their ability to absorb more people. Medium-sized and smaller cities have excess housing stock they would gladly offer to new residents, but due to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/debt-laden-chinas-local-governments-scramble-rescue-small-banks-with-21-bln-2023-11-28/">surging debt</a> they lack the funds to expand access to health facilities, elderly care and education.翻译:顾问们表示，中国最大的城市住宅供应有限，并面临污染和拥堵，影响了它们吸纳更多人口的能力。中小城市拥有过剩的住房存量，他们很乐意向新居民提供，但由于<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/debt-laden-chinas-local-governments-scramble-rescue-small-banks-with-21-bln-2023-11-28/">债务激增，</a>他们缺乏资金来扩大医疗设施、养老和教育的覆盖范围。</p>   <p>"The quality of our urbanisation is poor," said the second government adviser, who spoke on the condition of anonymity due to the topic's sensitivity.翻译:“我们的城市化质量很差，”第二位政府顾问说，由于该话题的敏感性，他要求匿名。</p>   <p>Most Chinese cities grew dramatically over the past four decades as the country opened up to entrepreneurship and invested in transport infrastructure and residential projects. But the world's second-largest economy still lags the 80-90% urbanisation rate in the developed world.翻译:随着国家开放创业精神并投资交通基础设施和住宅项目，大多数中国城市在过去四十年中急剧发展。但世界第二大经济体的城市化率仍落后于发达国家80%至90%的水平。</p>   <p>About 65% of China's 1.4 billion people live in urban areas, compared with 55% in 2013. But only 48% of the population have a city hukou, official data show. That gap has remained steady throughout the period.翻译:中国14亿人口中约有65%居住在城市地区，而2013年这一比例为55%。但官方数据显示，只有48%的人口拥有城市户口。这一差距在此期间一直保持稳定。</p>      <p>While Beijing is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-can-no-longer-extend-pretend-municipal-debt-2023-08-06/">working</a> to address strains in local finances, another set of reforms to encourage more people to settle in cities is not in the pipeline, the advisers said.翻译:顾问们表示，虽然北京正在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-can-no-longer-extend-pretend-municipal-debt-2023-08-06/">努力</a>解决地方财政紧张的问题，但另一套鼓励更多人在城市定居的改革尚未酝酿之中。</p>   <p>In China, rural hukou come with land rights - and, implicitly, the insurance policy of living off the farm if city jobs are unavailable - making many migrant workers from the countryside reluctant to apply for urban permits, especially in a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/part-chinas-economic-miracle-was-mirage-reality-check-is-next-2023-09-03/">slowing economy</a>.翻译:在中国，农村户口伴随着土地权——而且隐含着如果无法获得城市工作就以务农为生的保险政策——使得许多来自农村的农民工不愿申请城市许可证，尤其是在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/part-chinas-economic-miracle-was-mirage-reality-check-is-next-2023-09-03/">经济放缓的情况</a>下。</p>   <p>Local governments can lease land for farming, as well as residential, commercial and industrial development, but there is no private land ownership in China and land rights cannot be traded freely.翻译:地方政府可以租赁土地用于农业以及住宅、商业和工业开发，但中国不存在土地私有制，土地权不能自由交易。</p>   <p>"We must push forward land system reform. We have plenty of land, which has been wasted," the second adviser said, adding however that China's leaders are unwilling to go down that path.翻译:“我们必须推进土地制度改革。我们有大量土地，但都被浪费了，”第二位顾问说，但他补充说，中国领导人不愿意走这条路。</p>   <p>Shao Xiaogai, a 39-year-old store manager in Zhengzhou, prefers to stay registered in her village in the central Henan province. She had tried to get an urban hukou to make it easier to enrol her son in a public school, but a spot opened up for him eventually anyway.翻译:39 岁的郑州商店经理邵小改更愿意留在河南省中部的村庄。她曾试图获得城市户口，以便更容易让儿子进入公立学校就读，但最终还是为他腾出了一个名额。</p>   <p>"I tell my son to study hard because we are outsiders in this city," said Shao. "If he doesn't do well here, his dad and I will become his burden if we stay in the city. In the village, we can grow whatever food we need."翻译:“我告诉儿子要努力学习，因为我们是这个城市的外人，”邵说。 “如果他在这里过得不好，我和他爸爸留在城里就会成为他的负担。在村里，我们可以种植任何我们需要的食物。”</p>   <p>Jia said these hurdles mean further hukou liberalisation will be on a city-by-city basis. The second adviser said the pace of urbanisation will slow in coming years, making rural revitalisation more of a priority for China's leaders.</p>    <h 1="">CONSUMING LESS</h>  <p>Hukou date back to the famines of last century, when Mao Zedong tied food rations to people's birthplaces to prevent starving peasants from flocking to better-fed cities.翻译:户口可以追溯到上个世纪的饥荒，当时毛泽东将粮食配给与人们的出生地挂钩，以防止饥饿的农民涌入食物更好的城市。</p>   <p>In their modern iteration, hukou limit access to public services for many of the almost 300 million rural migrants who leave their families behind to assemble the smartphones, raise the skyscrapers, lay the roads and clean the malls in Chinese cities.翻译:在现代版本中，户口限制了近3亿农民工获得公共服务的机会，他们离开家人在中国城市组装智能手机、建造摩天大楼、铺设道路和打扫商场。</p>   <p>Migrants get smaller reimbursements for medical expenses than those with urban registration and cannot take their employer's contributions to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/rust-belt-province-got-old-before-it-got-rich-much-china-will-2023-02-28/">retirement savings</a> - two-thirds of the pot - with them when they return home.翻译:与城市户口的农民工相比，农民工获得的医疗费用报销要少，而且回国时也不能带走雇主缴纳的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/rust-belt-province-got-old-before-it-got-rich-much-china-will-2023-02-28/">退休储蓄</a>（三分之二）。</p>   <p>As a result, they save more of their income, keeping household consumption - which China wants to make a more <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">prominent driver</a> of economic growth - subdued.翻译:结果，他们将更多收入储蓄起来，从而抑制了家庭消费——中国希望家庭消费成为经济增长的更<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">重要推动力</a>。</p>   <p>Cai Fang, a central bank adviser, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-should-shift-stimulus-consumption-ease-residency-curbs-pboc-adviser-2023-07-10/">estimates</a> migrant workers typically spend 23% less than those with urban hukou, potentially depriving the economy of more than 2 trillion yuan ($281 billion) - or 1.7% of last year's GDP - in domestic consumption annually.翻译:央行顾问蔡昉<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-should-shift-stimulus-consumption-ease-residency-curbs-pboc-adviser-2023-07-10/">估计</a>，农民工的支出通常比城市户口的农民工少 23%，这可能会导致经济每年损失超过 2 万亿元人民币（2810 亿美元）的国内消费，即去年 GDP 的 1.7%。</p>   <p>There's also the imperative of boosting demand for apartments, of which China has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/even-chinas-14-bln-population-cant-fill-all-its-vacant-homes-former-official-2023-09-23/">too many</a>. The property market, which accounts for roughly a quarter of the economy, has been <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/inside-downfall-embattled-property-developer-china-evergrande-2023-08-31/">rattled</a> by private developer defaults.翻译:提高公寓需求也势在必行，而中国的公寓<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/even-chinas-14-bln-population-cant-fill-all-its-vacant-homes-former-official-2023-09-23/">数量太多</a>了。约占经济四分之一的房地产市场因私人开发商违约而<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/inside-downfall-embattled-property-developer-china-evergrande-2023-08-31/">陷入困境</a>。</p>   <p>The market would "substantially improve if migrants could be treated more equally" through improved access to better jobs and benefits and enabling them to buy apartments, said Martin Whyte, professor emeritus of international studies and sociology at Harvard University.</p>    <h 1="">'LOW-END POPULATION'</h>  <p>An uncontrolled influx of migrants into the cities, however, may present risks for China's leaders.翻译:然而，不受控制的农民工涌入城市可能会给中国领导人带来风险。</p>   <p>In 2017, after a fire broke out in migrant workers' living quarters, Beijing authorities launched a campaign to expel people without capital-city hukou, sparking a rare open backlash against the government.翻译:2017年，农民工宿舍发生火灾后，北京当局发起了驱逐无京城户口人员的运动，引发了罕见的公开反对政府的反弹。</p>   <p>Mega-cities such as Beijing, Shanghai, Shenzhen and Guangzhou have "no chance" of opening up in coming years due to "considerations of social stability and harmony", said Jia.翻译:贾表示，出于“社会稳定和谐的考虑”，北京、上海、深圳和广州等大城市“没有机会”在未来几年开放。</p>   <p>"Beijing tried to drive out 'low-end population' at one point, which created chaos," he said, referencing the term that officials in the capital used at the time.翻译:“北京曾一度试图驱逐‘低端人口’，结果造成了混乱，”他说，他指的是当时首都官员使用的这个词。</p>   <p>In Zhengzhou, Yang, the businessman, recalled how life was different before he obtained a city hukou.翻译:在郑州，商人杨回忆起他获得城市户口之前的生活是如何不同的。</p>   <p>He made a living operating an unlicensed mini-mart in a district of rural migrants, often sleeping on a straw mat in a park as he played hide-and-seek with the police.翻译:他在一个农民工聚集区经营一家无牌小超市谋生，经常睡在公园的草席上，与警察玩捉迷藏。</p>   <p>"They would organise big teams of volunteers and officers to knock on doors at night to flush out people without hukou," Yang said.翻译:杨说：“他们会组织志愿者和官员组成的大队，在夜间敲门，驱逐没有户口的人。”</p>   <p>Zhengzhou's government did not respond to Reuters queries.翻译:郑州市政府没有回应路透社的询问。</p>   <p>Once he had the permit, Yang's prospects soared.翻译:获得许可后，杨的前途一片光明。</p>   <p>In addition to expanding his business, he bought a second home - something only hukou holders could have - and his first car, a locally made Changan 50 minivan. He enjoyed a more active social life.翻译:除了扩大业务之外，他还购买了第二套住房（只有户口持有人才能拥有）和他的第一辆车，一辆本地制造的长安 50 小型货车。他享受着更加活跃的社交生活。</p>   <p>"Not many people could afford private vehicles at the time. Pretty girls would ask me to drive them around for some fun," Yang said. "And I did!"翻译:“当时买得起私家车的人不多，漂亮女孩都会叫我开着它们出去玩。”杨说。 “我做到了！”</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1233 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.1233 人民币）</p>    <span>Graphics by Kripa Jayaram; Editing by Marius Zaharia and David Crawshaw翻译:制图：Kripa Jayaram；马吕斯·扎哈里亚和大卫·克劳肖编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 11:22:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6IX4M6SPPRKLLNCRVO4FXMNLYA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-push-loosen-mao-era-residence-rules-runs-into-hurdles-2023-12-07/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Yew Lun Tian, Kevin Yao, Farah Master]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/HUKOU (INSIGHT, PIX, GRAPHIC)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[大豆和锂贸易处于平衡状态，阿根廷米雷面临中国难题]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/24Be1R7EMtGGkQlBmg6WVY1Zboo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3D3QKPOIMRK7DB26YDCIUWPV5Q.jpg" alt="Argentina's President-elect Javier Milei has a China conundrum翻译:阿根廷当选总统哈维尔·米莱面临中国难题" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Parts of a turbine and components sent from China, which will be used in the hydroelectric power complex Jorge Cepernic and Nestor Kirchner, are pictured  in Punta Quilla, Santa&nbsp;Cruz,&nbsp;Argentina October 17, 2023. REUTERS/Horacio Cordoba翻译:照片中，2023 年 10 月 17 日在阿根廷圣克鲁斯蓬塔基拉，从中国运来的涡轮机和部件将用于 Jorge Cepernic 和 Nestor Kirchner 水力发电站。 REUTERS/Horacio Cordoba</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/15KOwfm4JUj3qtL_Li_33j8CFek=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YF4XDKHJF5J3RHNPQEQIBPT3VY.jpg" alt="Argentina's President-elect Javier Milei has a China conundrum翻译:阿根廷当选总统哈维尔·米莱面临中国难题" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Workers load on a truck a part of a turbine sent from China, which will be used in the hydroelectric power complex Jorge Cepernic and Nestor Kirchner, in Punta Quilla, Santa&nbsp;Cruz,&nbsp;Argentina October 17, 2023. REUTERS/Horacio Cordoba翻译:2023 年 10 月 17 日，工人们正在卡车上装载从中国运来的涡轮机的一部分，该涡轮机将用于阿根廷圣克鲁斯蓬塔基拉的 Jorge Cepernic 和 Nestor Kirchner 水力发电站。 REUTERS/Horacio Cordoba</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/3O1MD7MrjOWPd2qLVG5uXrLWRiQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CFOF74QKN5LE7GCUAA3M66F3XU.jpg" alt="Argentina's President-elect Javier Milei has a China conundrum翻译:阿根廷当选总统哈维尔·米莱面临中国难题" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Brine pools used to extract lithium are seen next to a lithium mining camp at the Salar del Rincon salt flat, in Salta, Argentina August 12, 2021. Picture taken August 12, 2021. REUTERS/Agustin Marcarian/File Photo翻译:2021 年 8 月 12 日，阿根廷萨尔塔 Salar del Rincon 盐滩的锂矿营地旁，用于提取锂的盐水池。照片拍摄于 2021 年 8 月 12 日。路透社/Agustin Marcarian/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Yazc9xUVg61O8xwzHE56eISJzsI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7XK2I3QKFBKSJG6CEDVVNUJXTY.jpg" alt="Argentina's President-elect Javier Milei has a China conundrum翻译:阿根廷当选总统哈维尔·米莱面临中国难题" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Labourers of Alpha Lithium work at the Tolillar salt flat, in Salta, Argentina August 13, 2021. Picture taken August 13, 2021. REUTERS/Agustin Marcarian/File Photo翻译:Alpha Lithium 的工人于 2021 年 8 月 13 日在阿根廷萨尔塔的托利拉尔盐滩工作。照片拍摄于 2021 年 8 月 13 日。路透社/Agustin Marcarian/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ZLQFwZ39a3hWjj-LN8wUnA7tj4Q=/1498x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PCTNTVLBIJKITGLRZHY2DDOL4Y.jpg" alt="Argentine President-elect Javier Milei departs meetings at the White House in Washington翻译:阿根廷当选总统哈维尔·米莱离开华盛顿白宫举行的会议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Argentine President-elect Javier Milei departs the Eisenhower Executive Office Building after meeting with Biden administration staff at the White House complex in Washington, U.S., November 28, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 28 日，阿根廷当选总统哈维尔·米雷在美国华盛顿白宫与拜登政府工作人员会面后离开艾森豪威尔行政办公大楼。路透社/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>                     <p>Argentina's President-elect Javier Milei has a China conundrum翻译:阿根廷当选总统哈维尔·米莱面临中国难题.</p>   <p>The libertarian economist insulted communist-run China in a fiery campaign, but takes office on Sunday needing the country's second-largest trade partner more than ever as a recession looms and foreign currency reserves run dry.翻译:这位自由主义经济学家在一场激烈的竞选活动中侮辱了共产主义统治的中国，但在周日上任后，由于经济衰退迫在眉睫且外汇储备枯竭，他比以往任何时候都更需要中国第二大贸易伙伴。</p>   <p>Since he won the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/argentina-readies-vote-likely-presidential-election-thriller-2023-11-19/">Nov. 19 election</a>, Milei's team have taken a more <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/argentinas-milei-thanks-chinese-president-softening-tone-2023-11-23/">diplomatic tone</a>, reflecting complex ties with China, the top buyer of Argentine soybeans and beef, a key investor in its lithium, and the provider of an $18 billion currency swap - effectively, a form of credit provision that has helped Argentina avoid default.翻译:自赢得<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/argentina-readies-vote-likely-presidential-election-thriller-2023-11-19/">11 月 19 日大选</a>以来，米雷的团队采取了更为<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/argentinas-milei-thanks-chinese-president-softening-tone-2023-11-23/">外交的语气</a>，反映出与中国的复杂关系。中国是阿根廷大豆和牛肉的最大买家、锂的主要投资者以及 180 亿美元货币互换的提供者 -有效地，这是一种帮助阿根廷避免违约的信贷提供形式。</p>   <p>Miguel Schiariti, president of the local CICCRA meat industry chamber, is hopeful of a "cordial" relationship, pointing to recent comments by incoming foreign minister Diana Mondino. China buys over three-quarters of Argentina's beef exports.翻译:当地 CICCRA 肉类工业商会会长米格尔·斯基亚里蒂 (Miguel Schiariti) 对即将上任的外交部长戴安娜·蒙迪诺 (Diana Mondino) 最近的评论表示希望建立“亲切”的关系。中国购买了阿根廷四分之三以上的牛肉出口。</p>   <p>Mondino told Reuters in a Dec. 2 interview that the new government would review "secret" <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/argentina-election-puts-china-brazil-ties-spotlight-2023-11-09/">state-to-state deals</a> to ensure they were all above-board, but emphasized Argentina would not cut ties with China, and would look in fact to bolster private trade.翻译:蒙迪诺在 12 月 2 日接受路透社采访时表示，新政府将审查“秘密” <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/argentina-election-puts-china-brazil-ties-spotlight-2023-11-09/">国与国之间的交易</a>，以确保它们都是光明正大的，但强调阿根廷不会切断与中国的关系，并且实际上会加强与中国的关系。私人贸易。</p>   <p>"The private sector is the one that makes the deals," she said, adding that Argentina wanted to "export as much as possible to everyone." The new government will be keen to overturn trade deficits, she said, including with China - around $10 billion last year.翻译:她说：“私营部门是促成交易的部门。”她补充说，阿根廷希望“尽可能多地向所有人出口”。她表示，新政府将热衷于扭转贸易逆差，其中包括对中国的贸易逆差——去年约为 100 亿美元。</p>   <p>"We have a lot of debt... so we need a positive surplus."</p>    <h 1="">'PROJECTS WILL BE REVIEWED'</h>  <p>Not everyone is convinced that things will be so easy, with sensitive mega-projects including hydroelectric and nuclear needing solid state-to-state relations.翻译:并非所有人都相信事情会如此容易，包括水电和核电在内的敏感大型项目需要牢固的国与国关系。</p>   <p>In the southern province of Santa Cruz, Chinese-made turbines are set to arrive early next year for a $5 billion hydropower dam project, which the outgoing Peronist regional governor Alicia Kirchner said could be held up by the change in government.翻译:在南部圣克鲁斯省，中国制造的涡轮机将于明年初运抵一个耗资 50 亿美元的水电大坝项目，即将离任的庇隆主义地区省长艾丽西亚·基什内尔表示，该项目可能会因政府更迭而受阻。</p>   <p>"Those dams are at risk with Milei," Kirchner said in an October interview, citing his public criticism of China during the campaign.翻译:基什内尔在 10 月份的一次采访中引用了他在竞选期间对中国的公开批评，称“米雷的这些水坝面临着风险”。</p>   <p>"(Milei) says we can be an island," Kirchner said. "I don't think the country has a future that way."翻译:“（米莱）说我们可以成为一座岛屿，”基什内尔说。 “我认为这个国家不会有那样的未来。”</p>   <p>Milei's campaign has not spoken specifically about the dams.翻译:米莱的竞选活动没有具体谈论这些水坝。</p>   <p>China is providing financing for around a dozen ongoing infrastructure projects in Argentina, government data show, which range from railways and solar farms to space stations and fertilizer facilities. It also has a dozen mining investments, especially in electric-vehicle battery metal lithium.翻译:政府数据显示，中国正在为阿根廷大约十几个正在进行的基础设施项目提供融资，这些项目包括铁路、太阳能发电厂、空间站和化肥设施。它还拥有十几项矿业投资，特别是在电动汽车电池金属锂方面。</p>   <p>Some projects are already facing big delays or are "paralyzed," said Patricio Giusto, director of the Sino-Argentina observatory based in Buenos Aires, citing poor management, regulatory hurdles and domestic economic issues.翻译:布宜诺斯艾利斯中阿观察站主任帕特里西奥·朱斯托表示，一些项目已经面临严重延误或“瘫痪”，理由是管理不善、监管障碍和国内经济问题。</p>   <p>That could worsen if diplomatic ties are strained, he said. Cross-cancellation clauses in some contracts could allow Beijing to stop loans to projects if another one was canceled, he added.翻译:他说，如果外交关系紧张，情况可能会变得更糟。他补充说，一些合同中的交叉取消条款可能允许北京在另一项合同被取消时停止向项目提供贷款。</p>   <p>"If Milei attempts to cancel any of these public works contracts, China would simply ask for the money back from any number of projects," Giusto said. "That's money Argentina simply doesn't have."翻译:朱斯托说：“如果米莱试图取消任何这些公共工程合同，中国只会要求任何数量的项目退还资金。” “阿根廷根本没有钱。”</p>   <p>Construction of the two Santa Cruz hydropower plants, the biggest Chinese investment yet in Argentina and funded by the China Development Bank, began in 2015 but remains less than half complete, two provincial sources close to the work said.翻译:两名了解工程情况的省级消息人士称，圣克鲁斯水电站的建设于 2015 年开始，是中国在阿根廷迄今为止最大的投资，由国家开发银行资助，但目前尚未完成一半。</p>   <p>Chinese investors would likely be practical, a senior diplomat in Buenos Aires said. "There won't be confrontation with Argentina but projects will be reviewed."翻译:布宜诺斯艾利斯的一位高级外交官表示，中国投资者可能会比较务实。 “不会与阿根廷发生对抗，但项目将受到审查。”</p>   <p>China's embassy in Buenos Aires did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>    <h 1="">'OTHER PROBLEMS TO SOLVE FIRST'</h>  <p>China also gobbles up Argentina's soybeans and other grains, buying over 93% of the country's soy exports so far this year, official data show. It rises to almost 100% for barley and sorghum.翻译:官方数据显示，中国还大量购买阿根廷的大豆和其他谷物，今年迄今购买了该国大豆出口量的93%以上。大麦和高粱的这一比例几乎上升到 100%。</p>   <p>Overall, China accounts for some 10% of Argentine exports, and over a quarter of its imports.翻译:总体而言，中国约占阿根廷出口的 10%，进口的四分之一以上。</p>   <p>"We believe that the foreign ministry will maintain relations and negotiations with China," said Gustavo Idigoras, president of CIARA-CEC, which represents major grains exporters and crushing companies like Bunge and Cargill.翻译:代表邦吉（Bunge）和嘉吉（Cargill）等主要谷物出口商和压榨公司的CIARA-CEC主席古斯塔沃·伊迪戈拉斯（Gustavo Idigoras）表示：“我们相信外交部将与中国保持关系和谈判。”</p>   <p>Meanwhile, China's Gangfeng Lithium <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002460.SZ" target="_blank">(002460.SZ)</a>, Tsingshan Holding Group, and Zijin Mining <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601899.SS" target="_blank">(601899.SS)</a> have major investments in Argentina's lithium sector, the world's no. 4 producer of the "white gold" metal.翻译:与此同时，中国港峰锂业<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002460.SZ" target="_blank">（002460.SZ）</a> 、青山控股集团和紫金矿业<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601899.SS" target="_blank">（601899.SS）</a>在全球第一大锂业领域进行了大量投资。 4 “白金”金属生产商。</p>   <p>In China, experts saw a likely pragmatic relationship.翻译:在中国，专家们看到了可能存在的务实关系。</p>   <p>"Milei will view Argentina's political relationship with China in economic terms. He used to be an economist, after all," said Beijing-based Hu Yukun, a Chinese international relations commentator.翻译:“米雷将从经济角度看待阿根廷与中国的政治关系。毕竟，他曾经是一名经济学家，”北京的中国国际关系评论员胡玉坤表示。</p>   <p>Hu predicted Milei would at most downgrade the relationship, but would, like previous governments, treat China as a crutch for the country's economic woes, flagging the currency swap, which cash-strapped Argentina has used to pay back the International Monetary Fund (IMF).翻译:胡锦涛预测，米莱最多只会降低两国关系的评级，但会像前几届政府一样，将中国视为解决该国经济困境的拐杖，并提出货币互换，而资金短缺的阿根廷曾用该货币互换来偿还国际货币基金组织(IMF)的资金。 。</p>   <p>The swap - of which some $11.5 billion has already been activated - could come into the crosshairs of Milei's government, an Argentine central bank source said.翻译:一位阿根廷央行消息人士称，该互换计划（其中约 115 亿美元已经启动）可能会成为米莱政府的关注焦点。</p>   <p>"It is now an issue for the next administration. The swap was useful to the current government because it avoided defaulting on payments with the IMF," the source said.翻译:“现在这是下一届政府面临的问题。互换对现任政府有用，因为它避免了国际货币基金组织的付款违约，”消息人士称。</p>   <p>Milei's recently appointed economic team has not spoken about the currency swap but has had initial meetings with the IMF that Milei described as "collaborative."翻译:米雷最近任命的经济团队尚未谈论货币互换问题，但与国际货币基金组织进行了初步会议，米雷称其为“合作”。</p>   <p>The swap "could be (impacted) because of what he has said about not having relations with China at the state level," the source said. "But in recent weeks his speech has moderated and he has many other problems to solve first."翻译:消息人士称，此次互换“可能会受到影响，因为他曾说过在州一级与中国没有关系”。 “但最近几周，他的言论有所缓和，他还有许多其他问题需要首先解决。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Lucinda Elliott, Joe Cash, Maximilian Heath and Jorge Otaola; Additional reporting by Jorgelina do Rosario; Editing by Adam Jourdan and Rosalba O'Brien翻译:Lucinda Elliott、Joe Cash、Maximilian Heath 和 Jorge Otaola 报道； Jorgelina do Rosario 的补充报道；亚当·乔丹和罗莎尔巴·奥布莱恩编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">KPPNW7ZU6JJGPL6RIIMQWE43J4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/with-soy-lithium-trade-balance-argentinas-milei-has-china-conundrum-2023-12-07/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Lucinda Elliott, Joe Cash, Maximilian Heath]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ARGENTINA</category>
                
                <category>POLITICS/CHINA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国国家主席习近平将访问越南，寻求加强两国关系]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tKhowAcTk1ZjzKp1NIT68wQI6V8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4RDCS5PVXJKXNFAXZTHO45OGWE.jpg" alt="&quot;Senior Chinese Leader Event&quot; on the sidelines of the APEC summit, in San Francisco翻译:旧金山APEC峰会期间的“中国高级领导人活动”" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>China's President Xi Jinping speaks at the "Senior Chinese Leader Event" held by the National Committee on US-China Relations and the US-China Business Council on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 15, 2023.  REUTERS/Carlos Barria/Pool/File photo翻译:中国国家主席习近平在加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织（APEC）峰会期间，在美中关系全国委员会和美中贸易全国委员会举办的“中国高级领导人活动”上发表讲话美国，2023 年 11 月 15 日。路透社/Carlos Barria/Pool/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's President Xi Jinping will visit Vietnam on Dec. 12-13 to meet top state officials and discuss upgrading the two countries' relations, the Chinese foreign ministry said on Thursday.翻译:中国外交部周四表示，中国国家主席习近平将于12月12日至13日访问越南，会见国家高级官员，讨论升级两国关系。</p>   <p>They will focus on areas of political security, multilateral and maritime issues, and promote further strategic cooperation, spokesperson Wang Wenbin said at a press briefing.翻译:汪文斌在例行记者会上表示，双方将重点关注政治安全、多边、海洋等领域，推动战略合作深入发展。</p>   <p>The Vietnamese communist party confirmed Xi's visit.翻译:越南共产党证实了习近平的访问。</p>   <p>Several Chinese leaders have visited Vietnam leading up to the visit as the two countries seek to fortify ties.翻译:多位中国领导人在访问越南之前访问了越南，两国寻求加强关系。</p>   <p>China is Vietnam's largest trading partner and a vital source of imports for its manufacturing sector.翻译:中国是越南最大的贸易伙伴，也是越南制造业的重要进口来源地。</p>   <p>In October, Xi told Vietnam's second-highest ranking official that both countries must not forget the "original intention" of their traditional friendship.翻译:10月，习近平对越南第二高官员表示，两国不能忘记传统友谊的“初衷”。</p>   <p>China and the United States have been jostling for influence among Southeast Asian nations including Vietnam, which elevated its ties with Washington to a comprehensive strategic partnership, putting its one-time enemy on par with Beijing and Moscow.翻译:中国和美国一直在争夺在包括越南在内的东南亚国家中的影响力，越南将其与华盛顿的关系提升为全面战略伙伴关系，将其曾经的敌人与北京和莫斯科平起平坐。</p>   <p>"Since the beginning of this year, (China and Vietnam) have had frequent high-level interactions, close exchanges in various sectors, and continued deepening of cooperation in various fields," Wang said.翻译:今年以来，中越高层交往频繁，各领域交往密切，各领域合作持续深化。</p>   <p>Deepening cooperation will help to maintenance peace, stability and prosperity in the region, Wang added.翻译:王毅表示，深化合作有利于维护地区和平、稳定、繁荣。</p>    <span>Reporting by Beijing newsroom; Writing by Bernard Orr; Editing by Christopher Cushing翻译:北京新闻编辑室报道；伯纳德·奥尔撰写；克里斯托弗·库欣编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 08:43:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TC4BMD2JTBLR5IUFCA5MHKCGIU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/chinas-president-xi-visit-vietnam-2023-12-07/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>VIETNAM/ (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国出口六个月来首次增长 工厂纾困]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/It2ljFpCO3RdLXXoU-G7XToCGUc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WDRPQRKUU5N6XFYPIZ7VVS7A7I.jpg" alt="Containers and cargo vessels at the Qingdao port翻译:青岛港的集装箱和货船" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An aerial view shows containers and cargo vessels at the Qingdao port in Shandong province, China May 9, 2022. Picture taken with a drone. China Daily via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:2022 年 5 月 9 日，中国山东省青岛港的集装箱和货船鸟瞰图。照片由无人机拍摄。 《中国日报》来自路透社/资料图</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's exports grew for the first time in six months in November, suggesting factories in the world's second-largest economy are attracting buyers through discount pricing to get over a prolonged slump in demand.翻译:11月份，中国的出口出现六个月来的首次增长，这表明世界第二大经济体的工厂正在通过折扣价吸引买家，以克服长期的需求低迷。</p>   <p>Mixed <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-activity-surprisingly-expands-november-caixin-pmi-2023-12-01/">manufacturing data</a> for November has kept alive calls for further policy support to shore up growth but also raised questions about whether predominantly negative sentiment-based surveys have masked improvements in conditions.翻译:11 月份好坏参半的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-activity-surprisingly-expands-november-caixin-pmi-2023-12-01/">制造业数据</a>引发了人们对进一步政策支持以提振增长的呼声，但也引发了人们的疑问：主要基于负面情绪的调查是否掩盖了状况的改善。</p>   <p>Exports grew 0.5% from a year earlier in November, customs data showed on Thursday, compared with a 6.4% fall in October and beating the 1.1% drop expected in a Reuters poll. Imports fell 0.6%, dashing forecasts for a 3.3% increase and swinging from a 3.0% jump last month.翻译:海关周四公布的数据显示，11 月份出口同比增长 0.5%，而 10 月份则下降 6.4%，且超出了路透调查预期的 1.1% 降幅。进口下降 0.6%，远低于上个月增长 3.3% 的预期。</p>   <p>"The improvement in exports is broadly in line with market expectations... sequential growth in China's exports in the past few months has strengthened," said Zhiwei Zhang, chief economist at Pinpoint Asset Management. "There are green shoots in other Asian countries' export data as well in recent months."翻译:品点资产管理公司首席经济学家张志伟表示：“出口的改善基本符合市场预期……过去几个月中国出口的环比增长有所加强。” “近几个月来，其他亚洲国家的出口数据也出现了复苏。”</p>      <p>The Baltic Dry Index, a bellwether gauge of global trade, climbed to a three year high in November, supported by improved demand for industrial commodities, particularly from China.翻译:全球贸易的风向标波罗的海干散货运价指数在 11 月份攀升至三年来的高点，这得益于工业大宗商品需求的改善，尤其是来自中国的需求。</p>   <p>South Korean exports, another gauge of the health of global trade, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/skoreas-chips-exports-rise-first-time-more-than-year-2023-12-01/">rose for a second month</a> in November, buoyed by chip exports, which snapped 15 months of declines.翻译:韩国出口是衡量全球贸易健康状况的另一个指标，在芯片出口的推动下，11 月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/skoreas-chips-exports-rise-first-time-more-than-year-2023-12-01/">连续第二个月增长</a>，芯片出口结束了 15 个月的下降。</p>   <p>Trade with China's major peers also painted a rosy picture, with exports to United States, Japan, South Korea and Taiwan all up on October.</p>    <h 1="">DISCOUNTED EXPORTS</h>  <p>In the short run, however, the pressure on Chinese manufacturers show little sign of easing off completely.翻译:然而，短期来看，中国制造商面临的压力几乎没有完全缓解的迹象。</p>   <p>China's official purchasing managers' index (PMI) last week showed new export orders shrank for a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-factory-activity-contracts-second-month-november-2023-11-30/">ninth consecutive month</a>, while a private sector survey highlighted the struggles of factory owners to attract overseas buyers for a fifth month.翻译:中国官方采购经理人指数（PMI）上周显示新出口订单<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-factory-activity-contracts-second-month-november-2023-11-30/">连续第九个月</a>萎缩，而私营部门调查则凸显工厂主连续第五个月难以吸引海外买家。</p>   <p>"While the level of export volumes hit a fresh high, (they were) supported by exporters reducing prices," noted Zichun Huang, China economist at Capital Economics.翻译:凯投宏观中国经济学家黄子春表示，“虽然出口量创出新高，但受到出口商降价的支撑。”</p>   <p>"We doubt this robustness will persist," Huang cautioned, "as exporters won't be able to continue cutting prices for much longer."翻译:黄警告说：“我们怀疑这种强劲势头能否持续，因为出口商将无法继续降价太长时间。”</p>   <p>Factory gate prices in the official PMI contracted for a second month in November, while input costs expanded for a fifth straight month.翻译:官方 PMI 中的工厂出厂价格 11 月份连续第二个月收缩，而投入成本连续第五个月上涨。</p>   <p>Still, some analysts point to quicker-than-expected growth in the third quarter and a run of mostly upbeat <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/">data from October</a> to argue that recent hard data paints a less gloomy picture of the economic health of the Asian giant than the sentiment-based surveys. The hard data also suggest the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-shaky-economic-recovery-2023-10-25/">support measures</a> trickling out of Beijing since June have had some effect, they say.翻译:尽管如此，一些分析师指出，第三季度的增长速度快于预期，而且<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/">10 月份以来的一系列基本乐观的数据</a>表明，与基于情绪的调查相比，最近的硬数据描绘出的亚洲巨人经济健康状况并不那么悲观。 。他们表示，硬数据还表明，自六月份以来北京陆续推出的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-shaky-economic-recovery-2023-10-25/">支持措施</a>已产生了一些效果。</p>   <p>"The data shows overseas demand is stronger than we thought and domestic demand is weaker than we thought," said Dan Wang, chief economist at Hang Seng Bank China. "The biggest export items are still electrical machinery and cars, so demand in Europe and Russia will have bolstered outbound shipments."</p>    <h 1="">UNEVEN RECOVERY</h>  <p>Analysts say it is too early to tell whether the recent policy support will be enough to shore up domestic demand and how sustainable any uptick in overseas demand is, with property, unemployment and weak household and business confidence threatening a sustainable rebound at home.翻译:分析人士表示，现在判断近期的政策支持是否足以提振国内需求以及海外需求的增长能否持续还为时过早，因为房地产、失业以及疲软的家庭和企业信心威胁着国内经济的可持续反弹。</p>   <p>The International Monetary Fund in November upgraded its <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/imf-upgrades-chinas-2023-2024-gdp-growth-forecasts-2023-11-07/">China growth forecasts</a> for 2023 and 2024 by 0.4% percentage points each, but that came from a lower base. And Moody's on Tuesday slapped a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/moodys-cuts-chinas-credit-outlook-negative-2023-12-05/">downgrade warning</a> on China's A1 credit rating.翻译:国际货币基金组织 (IMF) 11 月将<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/imf-upgrades-chinas-2023-2024-gdp-growth-forecasts-2023-11-07/">中国 2023 年和 2024 年经济增长预测</a>分别上调了 0.4 个百分点，但基数较低。穆迪周二对中国 A1 信用评级发出<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/moodys-cuts-chinas-credit-outlook-negative-2023-12-05/">降级警告</a>。</p>   <p>The Chinese markets seemed to reflect that cautiousness, with the yuan easing against the dollar after the data, while country's blue chip CSI300 stock index fell 0.44% and Hong Kong's Hang's Hang Seng lost 1.46%.翻译:中国市场似乎反映了这种谨慎态度，数据公布后人民币兑美元汇率下跌，而中国蓝筹股沪深300指数下跌0.44%，香港恒生指数下跌1.46%。</p>   <p>China's crude oil imports in November <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-crude-oil-imports-record-first-year-on-year-decline-since-april-2023-12-07/">fell</a> 9.2% year-on-year, the first annual decline since April as high inventory levels and poor manufacturing activity took their toll on demand for products such as diesel. But iron ore imports climbed slightly last month.翻译:11月份中国原油进口量同比<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-crude-oil-imports-record-first-year-on-year-decline-since-april-2023-12-07/">下降</a>9.2%，这是自4月份以来首次出现年度下降，原因是库存水平高企和制造业活动不佳影响了柴油等产品的需求。但上个月铁矿石进口略有攀升。</p>   <p>"While export demand improved, it is unclear if exports can contribute as a growth pillar into next year," Pinpoint Asset Management's Zhang warned.翻译:品点资产管理公司的张警告说：“虽然出口需求有所改善，但目前尚不清楚出口能否成为明年的增长支柱。”</p>   <p>"The European and United States economies are cooling. China still needs to depend on domestic demand as the main driver for growth in 2024."翻译:“欧美经济正在降温，中国2024年仍需依靠内需作为增长主要动力。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Joe Cash
Editing by Shri Navaratnam翻译:乔·卡什 (Joe Cash) 报道 Shri Navaratnam 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 08:40:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">UGCZJXDZZNP4NPUAVR55SFHWBQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-exports-grow-first-time-6-months-imports-unexpectedly-shrink-2023-12-07/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Joe Cash]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/TRADE (WRAPUP 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国电子商务平台Temu吸引美元商店的购物者-数据]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/IvLYVCTfypJEKZ-ucC9mCB4VGjc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HJTVV6OSR5JTRMJ44VT75AV3YI.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of e-commerce platform Temu翻译:电商平台Temu插画图片" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of Temu, an e-commerce platform owned by PDD Holdings, is seen on a mobile phone displayed in front of its website, in this illustration picture taken April 26, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张摄于 2023 年 4 月 26 日的插图图片中，PDD Holdings 旗下的电子商务平台 Temu 的徽标出现在其网站前显示的手机上。REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Temu, the fast-growing Chinese e-commerce platform selling $4 home decor and $10 shirts, is successfully taking on U.S. dollar stores including industry leader Dollar General <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DG.N" target="_blank">(DG.N)</a>, according to the latest market share data.翻译:根据最新的市场份额数据，快速发展的中国电子商务平台 Temu 正在成功与包括行业领导者 Dollar General <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DG.N" target="_blank">(DG.N)</a>在内的美元商店展开竞争，销售 4 美元的家居装饰品和 10 美元的衬衫。</p>   <p>As of last month, Temu accounted for nearly 17% of market share in the United States within the discount stores categories, according to data analytics firm Earnest Analytics. That compares to 8% for the dollar chain Five Below <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FIVE.O" target="_blank">(FIVE.O)</a>, 43% for Dollar General <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DG.N" target="_blank">(DG.N)</a> and 28% for Dollar Tree.翻译:根据数据分析公司 Earnest Analytics 的数据，截至上个月，Temu 占据了美国折扣店类别近 17% 的市场份额。相比之下，美元链五以下<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FIVE.O" target="_blank">(FIVE.O)</a>为 8%，Dollar General <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DG.N" target="_blank">(DG.N)</a>为 43%，Dollar Tree 为 28%。</p>   <p>Temu launched in the United States in September 2022 and quickly became popular through its use of social-media influencers to tout its merchandise as better and more affordable than traditional stores.翻译:Temu 于 2022 年 9 月在美国推出，并通过利用社交媒体影响力宣传其商品比传统商店更好、更实惠而迅速走红。</p>   <p>"Its (Temu) low prices on household goods and consumer staples makes it more of a threat to brick-and-mortar discounters like the dollar stores than other online marketplaces," said Michael Maloof, head of marketing at Earnest Analytics.翻译:Earnest Analytics 营销主管迈克尔·马卢夫 (Michael Maloof) 表示：“Temu 的家居用品和消费品价格低廉，这使得它对一元店等实体折扣店的威胁比其他在线市场更大。”</p>   <p>Temu sells apparel including $12 dresses and $20 sneakers, while also offering similar holiday decor, storage containers and toys as dollar stores. Analysts expect it to generate more than $16 billion in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/pdd-beats-quarterly-revenue-estimates-2023-11-28/">revenue this year</a> as it expands internationally.翻译:Temu 销售的服装包括 12 美元的连衣裙和 20 美元的运动鞋，同时还提供与一元店类似的节日装饰、储物容器和玩具。分析师预计，随着其国际扩张，该公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/pdd-beats-quarterly-revenue-estimates-2023-11-28/">今年的收入</a>将超过 160 亿美元。</p>   <p>"Temu has the advantage of novelty and excitement that is hard to re-create for staid low-end discount retail brands," said Michael Ashley Schulman, chief investment officer at Running Point Capital Advisors.翻译:Running Point Capital Advisors 首席投资官迈克尔·阿什利·舒尔曼 (Michael Ashley Schulman) 表示：“Temu 的优势在于新颖、令人兴奋，而这种优势是古板的低端折扣零售品牌难以复制的。”</p>   <p>Temu, Dollar General, Dollar Tree and Five Below did not respond to requests for comments on the research. The U.S. dollar stores have said previously they do not see an effect from Temu on their sales because of relatively smaller online presences and differing customers.翻译:Temu、Dollar General、Dollar Tree 和 Five Below 没有回应对该研究发表评论的请求。美元商店此前曾表示，由于在线业务规模相对较小且客户不同，他们认为 Temu 不会对其销售产生影响。</p>   <p>While dollar stores have maintained strength among customers buying necessities like food, beverages and items like detergent, they are dealing with a shift in consumer demand and also struggling with operational missteps.翻译:虽然一元店在购买食品、饮料和洗涤剂等必需品的消费者中保持着强劲势头，但它们正在应对消费者需求的转变，并在运营失误中苦苦挣扎。</p>   <p>Dollar General has cut its annual profit forecast three times this year as budget-conscious shoppers have cut spending on higher-margin discretionary goods and shifted to buying more lower-margin consumable goods.翻译:由于精打细算的购物者削减了利润率较高的非必需品支出，转而购买更多利润率较低的消费品，Dollar General 今年已三度下调年度利润预期。</p>   <p>Margins have also fallen at dollar stores because they are marking down merchandise to clear excess inventory and like many retailers are also being hurt by retail theft.翻译:一元店的利润率也下降了，因为它们对商品进行降价以清理多余的库存，而且像许多零售商一样，它们也受到零售盗窃的损害。</p>   <p>Tennessee-based Dollar General has seen the steepest decline in market share compared to competitors, according to Earnest Analytics. It held a 43% market share in November, down from about 57% in January. Dollar Tree's share slid nearly four percentage points from 32% in January to 28% in November.翻译:根据 Earnest Analytics 的数据，与竞争对手相比，田纳西州的 Dollar General 的市场份额下降幅度最大。 11 月份该公司的市场份额为 43%，低于 1 月份的 57% 左右。 Dollar Tree的份额从1月份的32%下降到11月份的28%，下降了近四个百分点。</p>   <p>Temu is benefiting from shopper fatigue with high prices and inflation, said Peter Earle, an economist at the American Institute for Economic Research, a libertarian, free-market think tank. Temu's parent company PDD Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PDD.O" target="_blank">(PDD.O)</a> said <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/pdd-beats-quarterly-revenue-estimates-2023-11-28/">revenue rose</a> by 94% to 68.84 billion yuan ($9.62 billion) in the quarter ended Sept. 30 from a year ago.翻译:美国经济研究所（一家自由主义、自由市场智库）的经济学家彼得·厄尔（Peter Earle）表示，特姆正受益于高物价和通货膨胀带来的购物疲劳。 Temu 的母公司 PDD Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PDD.O" target="_blank">(PDD.O)</a>表示，截至 9 月 30 日的季度<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/pdd-beats-quarterly-revenue-estimates-2023-11-28/">收入较上年同期增长</a>94%，达到 688.4 亿元人民币（合 96.2 亿美元）。</p>   <p>Temu uses a network of China-based manufacturers of cheap personal electronics, clothes and home goods. Factories and merchants on Temu send merchandise directly to Temu shoppers, using a trade exemption that allows shipments under $800 to enter the U.S. duty-free.翻译:Temu 利用中国廉价个人电子产品、服装和家居用品制造商的网络。 Temu 上的工厂和商家使用贸易豁免政策，将商品直接发送给 Temu 购物者，该贸易豁免允许 800 美元以下的货物免税进入美国。</p>   <p>"Temu with their 'shop like a billionaire' slogan has mastered gamification and rewards to make online shopping fun, easy, and cheaper than the dollar stores," Running Point's Schulman said.翻译:Running Point 的舒尔曼表示：“Temu 的口号是‘像亿万富翁一样购物’，他们已经掌握了游戏化和奖励机制，使在线购物变得有趣、轻松，而且比一元店更便宜。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Arriana McLymore in New York City and Granth Vanaik in Bengaluru; Editing by Jamie Freed翻译:纽约市的 Ariana McLymore 和班加罗尔的 Granth Vanaik 的报道；杰米·弗里德编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 23:27:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">KDDVHRQ6NJMJLF6CF7Q2SMPTHQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/chinese-e-commerce-platform-temu-drawing-shoppers-us-dollar-stores-data-2023-12-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Arriana McLymore, Granth Vanaik]]></author>
            
                
                <category>TEMU</category>
                
                <category>GROWTH/DOLLAR GENERAL (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
