<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub-five-red.vercel.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 18:36:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国财政部长耶伦将在亚太经合组织峰会前会见中国国务院副总理]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/PnrwiDL6nD2h27Fr_nO1pl0OXAk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4YZ6HUB2KJP3NHOPLUHJ7N2OLE.jpg" alt="Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen speaks on China at Johns Hopkins in Washington翻译:财政部长珍妮特·耶伦在华盛顿约翰·霍普金斯大学就中国发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen discusses "U.S.-China Economic Relationship" during a forum hosted by the Johns Hopkins University at the Nitze Building in Washington, U.S., April 20, 2023. REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger/File Photo翻译:2023 年 4 月 20 日，美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦在美国华盛顿尼茨大厦由约翰·霍普金斯大学主办的论坛上讨论“美中经济关系”。 REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/NjNqpuireLGpWmf0-t_AkRRFs14=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/N6FQQSPRK5LNTHIWC3KGYCQZ6U.jpg" alt="Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng in Beijing翻译:中国国务院副总理何立峰在北京" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng attends a joint press conference following the 10th China-EU High-Level Economic and Trade Dialogue at the Diaoyutai State Guesthouse in Beijing, China September 25, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo翻译:2023年9月25日，中国国务院副总理何立峰在中国北京钓鱼台国宾馆出席第十次中欧经贸高层对话后举行的联合新闻发布会。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen will meet with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng in San Francisco this week to try to deepen a fledgling economic dialogue between the world's two largest economies ahead of a U.S.-hosted summit of Pacific Rim leaders.翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦本周将在旧金山会见中国国务院副总理何立峰，试图在美国主办的环太平洋地区领导人峰会之前深化世界最大两个经济体之间刚刚起步的经济对话。</p>   <p>The Treasury said on Monday the Nov. 9-10 meetings will also convene the new economic and financial forums launched in October by the Treasury and China's finance ministry and central bank.翻译:美国财政部周一表示，11 月 9 日至 10 日的会议还将召开由美国财政部、中国财政部和央行于 10 月发起的新经济和金融论坛。</p>   <p>Yellen first met with He, China's new economic czar, in July, when she <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/yellen-says-china-us-have-significant-disagreements-that-must-be-communicated-2023-07-09/">visited Beijing</a> to try to stabilize a deteriorating U.S.-China relationship amid growing U.S. restrictions on sensitive technologies.翻译:耶伦于7月份首次会见了中国新任经济沙皇贺建奎，当时她<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/yellen-says-china-us-have-significant-disagreements-that-must-be-communicated-2023-07-09/">访问北京</a>，试图在美国对敏感技术限制日益严格的情况下稳定不断恶化的中美关系。</p>   <p>The San Francisco meetings will take place just before the Biden administration hosts ministers and leaders of Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation countries from Nov. 11-17 -- a gathering during which U.S. President Joe Biden is aiming to meet with Chinese President Xi Jinping.翻译:旧金山会议将在拜登政府于 11 月 11 日至 17 日接待亚太经济合作组织国家部长和领导人之前举行，美国总统乔·拜登计划在这次聚会期间会见中国国家主席习近平。</p>   <p>A senior U.S. Treasury official downplayed the idea that there would be specific "deliverables" from the Yellen-He meetings, saying it was not a "policy trade" situation "where we trade one thing for another."翻译:一位美国财政部高级官员淡化了耶伦与贺会议将产生具体“成果”的想法，称这不是“我们以一物换另一物”的“政策贸易”情况。</p>   <p>But the official said a key aim for Yellen was gaining a better understanding of how the new U.S.-China economic communication line will work, and how to make sure that "it is not vulnerable to shocks," adding that there will be more frequent interactions.翻译:但这位官员表示，耶伦的一个关键目标是更好地了解新的美中经济沟通渠道将如何运作，以及如何确保“它不易受到冲击”，并补充说，双方的互动将会更加频繁。</p>   <p>Yellen also is keen to discuss what steps Chinese officials are contemplating to support their flagging economic growth, and what circumstances might change their policy path.</p>    <h 1="">'NON-MARKET' TOOLS</h>  <p>Amid growing concerns that China will try to dump more manufactured goods on U.S. and global markets, Yellen is expected to warn He against using massive industrial subsidies to state firms and shutting U.S. companies out of domestic markets, the official said.翻译:这位官员表示，由于人们越来越担心中国将试图向美国和全球市场倾销更多制成品，预计耶伦将警告贺建奎不要对国有企业进行大规模工业补贴，并将美国企业拒之门外。</p>   <p>"This week, I will speak to my counterpart about our serious concerns with Beijing's unfair economic practices, including its large-scale use of non-market tools, its barriers to market access, and its coercive actions against U.S. firms in China," Yellen said in an <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2023/11/06/china-relationship-good-american-economy/" target="_blank">opinion piece</a> published by the Washington Post.翻译:耶伦表示：“本周，我将与我的同行谈论我们对北京不公平经济行为的严重关切，包括大规模使用非市场工具、市场准入壁垒以及对在华美国企业采取的强制行动。” 《华盛顿邮报》发表的一篇<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2023/11/06/china-relationship-good-american-economy/" target="_blank">评论文章</a>中说道。</p>   <p>She reiterated that the U.S. was seeking "healthy competition" with China and was not trying to "trigger a "disorderly wholesale private-sector pullback from China with actions to diversify supply chains and protect U.S. national security."翻译:她重申，美国正在寻求与中国的“良性竞争”，而不是试图“通过供应链多元化和保护美国国家安全的行动，引发“私营部门无序大规模撤出中国”。</p>   <p>A brief statement from a Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson said only that He would visit the U.S. from Nov. 8-12 at Yellen's invitation, describing him as China's "lead person for China-U.S. economic and trade affairs." It provided no details of any meetings.</p>    <h 1="">NOT S&amp;ED</h>  <p>The communications so far have helped U.S. officials to explain national security policies to counterparts in Beijing, including on export controls on sensitive technologies that could have military uses and restrictions on outbound U.S. investment to China.翻译:迄今为止的通信已帮助美国官员向北京同行解释国家安全政策，包括对可能用于军事用途的敏感技术的出口管制以及对美国对华投资的限制。</p>   <p>But Yellen said her engagement with He was not meant to reconstitute the broad, Obama-era U.S.-China Strategic and Economic Dialogue, which was widely criticized for its ineffectiveness.翻译:但耶伦表示，她与贺建奎的接触并不是为了重建奥巴马时代广泛的美中战略与经济对话，该对话因其无效而受到广泛批评。</p>   <p>Instead, Yellen said she was "focusing on specific, high-priority economic topics on which we can make tangible progress."翻译:相反，耶伦表示，她“专注于我们可以取得切实进展的具体、高度优先的经济主题”。</p>   <p>Among these are cooperating on global challenges such as tackling climate change, speeding debt relief to poor countries, and reducing illicit financial flows that support terrorism and the illegal drug trade.翻译:其中包括合作应对全球挑战，例如应对气候变化、加快减免穷国债务以及减少支持恐怖主义和非法毒品贸易的非法资金流动。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Lawder; Editing by Simon Cameron-Moore and Deepa Babington翻译:大卫·劳德报道；西蒙·卡梅伦-摩尔和迪帕·巴宾顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 18:11:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CJDERBLMHZOSRPOEZ6FGMK3GJQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-treasurys-yellen-meet-chinese-vice-premier-ahead-apec-summit-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Lawder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/YELLEN (UPDATE 2,PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[伊朗的拉伊西将出席伊斯兰会议组织在利雅得举行的关于加沙危机的会谈 - 网站]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ZClbuipLx5TLnPhn29EU0dnPcvM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WDB2B2ONHRM4LE3HOXWRTBQG24.jpg" alt="Anti-Israel protest in Tehran翻译:德黑兰反以色列抗议活动" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>File photo: Iranian President Ebrahim Raisi speaks during an anti-Israel protest in Tehran, Iran, October 18, 2023. Majid Asgaripour/WANA (West Asia News Agency) via REUTERS/File photo翻译:资料照片：伊朗总统易卜拉欣·莱西 (Ebrahim Raisi) 于 2023 年 10 月 18 日在伊朗德黑兰举行的反以色列抗议活动中发表讲话。Majid Asgaripour/WANA（西亚通讯社）来自 REUTERS/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Iranian President Ebrahim Raisi will travel to Saudi Arabia on Sunday, the Etemadonline news website reported on Monday, the first visit by an Iranian head of state since Tehran and Riyadh ended years of hostility under a China-brokered deal in March.翻译:据Etemadonline新闻网站周一报道，伊朗总统易卜拉欣·莱西将于周日访问沙特阿拉伯，这是自德黑兰和利雅得根据中国斡旋协议结束多年敌对状态以来，伊朗国家元首的首次访问。</p>   <p>"President Raisi will attend the Organisation of Islamic Cooperation' (OIC) summit in Riyadh, where the issue of Palestine will be discussed," the Iranian website reported.翻译:伊朗网站报道说：“莱西总统将出席在利雅得举行的伊斯兰合作组织（OIC）峰会，届时将讨论巴勒斯坦问题。”</p>   <p>World and regional powers have failed to reach any consensus on how to deal with the escalating conflict in the four weeks since fighters from <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/what-is-palestinian-group-hamas-2023-10-30/">Hamas </a>militants stormed southern Israel on Oct. 7, killing some 1,400 Israelis, mainly civilians, and taking more than 240 people <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/palestinians-refuse-accept-partial-tax-transfer-israel-2023-11-06/">hostage</a>.翻译:自<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/what-is-palestinian-group-hamas-2023-10-30/">哈马斯</a>武装分子于 10 月 7 日袭击以色列南部、造成约 1,400 名以色列人（主要是平民）死亡并<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/palestinians-refuse-accept-partial-tax-transfer-israel-2023-11-06/">劫持</a>240 多人为人质以来的四个星期内，世界和地区大国未能就如何应对不断升级的冲突达成任何共识。</p>   <p>Israel has since struck Hamas-controlled Gaza from the air, imposed a siege and launched a ground assault, stirring global alarm over humanitarian conditions in the enclave. At least 10,022 Palestinians, including 4,104 children, have been killed so far in Israeli strikes on Gaza since Oct. 7, the Gaza health ministry said on Monday.翻译:此后，以色列从空中袭击了哈马斯控制的加沙地带，实施了围困，并发动了地面攻击，引起了全球对飞地人道主义状况的警惕。加沙卫生部周一表示，自10月7日以来，以色列对加沙的袭击已造成至少10,022名巴勒斯坦人死亡，其中包括4,104名儿童。</p>   <p>Regional rivals Tehran and Riyadh agreed to resume ties in March under a deal negotiated by China after seven years of hostility, which had threatened stability and security in the Gulf and helped fuel conflicts in the Middle East from Yemen to Syria.翻译:地区竞争对手德黑兰和利雅得同意根据中国在七年敌对之后谈判达成的协议于三月恢复关系，这威胁到了海湾地区的稳定与安全，并助长了从也门到叙利亚的中东冲突。</p>    <span>Reporting by Elwely Elwelly;
Writing by Parisa Hafezi
Editing by Hugh Lawson and Gareth Jones翻译:埃尔韦利 (Elwelly) 报道；埃尔韦利 (Elwelly) 报道；作者：Parisa Hafezi 编辑：Hugh Lawson 和 Gareth Jones</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 16:39:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BJGRMXM6JFMQBKDQ6PFFXXRXJY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/irans-raisi-attend-oic-talks-riyadh-gaza-crisis-website-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ISRAEL</category>
                
                <category>PALESTINIANS/IRAN</category>
                
                <category>SAUDI (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[在预期的峰会之前，民意调查对拜登的解读比对中国习近平的解读更好]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lCQ72Nn45RmL3tG_0Hu_kWDYvNw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VZA4L2TMZ5KV7KRF2CALIQRA3A.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden departs Mass at St. Edmond's Catholic Church in Rehoboth Beach翻译:美国总统乔·拜登离开里霍博斯比奇圣埃德蒙天主教堂的弥撒" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden gives a thumbs-up in response to questions about Israel following Mass at St. Edmond's Catholic Church in Rehoboth Beach, Delaware, U.S., November 4, 2023. REUTERS/Ken Cedeno/File Photo翻译:2023年11月4日，美国特拉华州里霍博斯比奇圣埃德蒙天主教堂举行弥撒后，美国总统乔·拜登在回答有关以色列的问题时竖起大拇指。路透社/肯·塞德诺/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/atW1y53zdUYdycNArASc6RypFQo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3ZWEI6Y3BRPS3GW4WZC2YWEZP4.jpg" alt="BRICS Summit in Johannesburg翻译:金砖国家领导人约翰内斯堡峰会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>President of China Xi Jinping attends the plenary session during the 2023 BRICS Summit at the Sandton Convention Centre in Johannesburg, South Africa on August 23, 2023. GIANLUIGI GUERCIA/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:2023 年 8 月 23 日，中国国家主席习近平出席在南非约翰内斯堡桑顿会议中心举行的 2023 年金砖国家峰会全体会议。 GIANLUIGI GUERCIA/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>Ahead of an expected meeting between U.S. President Joe Biden and China's President Xi Jinping next week, a U.S. think tank says data it has collected from two dozen countries shows the American leader is winning the battle for public opinion.翻译:在美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平下周预计会晤之前，一家美国智库表示，从二十几个国家收集的数据显示，这位美国领导人正在赢得舆论之战。</p>   <p>The Pew Research Center says it surveyed 30,861 adults in 24 countries between Feb. 20 and May 22 about their attitudes to the world's two largest economies and their leadership.翻译:皮尤研究中心表示，它在 2 月 20 日至 5 月 22 日期间对 24 个国家的 30,861 名成年人进行了调查，了解他们对世界最大的两个经济体及其领导力的态度。</p>   <p>"People in 23 countries tend to see U.S. President Joe Biden more positively than Chinese President Xi Jinping," it said in a <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/global/2023/11/06/comparing-views-of-the-u-s-and-china-in-24-countries/" target="_blank">report</a> released on Monday. "A median of 54% have confidence in Biden to do the right thing regarding world affairs, compared with 19% who say the same of Xi."翻译:该组织在周一发布的一份<a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/global/2023/11/06/comparing-views-of-the-u-s-and-china-in-24-countries/" target="_blank">报告</a>中表示，“23个国家的人们对美国总统乔·拜登的看法往往比中国国家主席习近平更积极”。 “中位数为 54% 的人相信拜登会在国际事务上做正确的事情，而对习近平持同样看法的人为 19%。”</p>   <p>Pew said it did not ask people in the United States about their confidence in Biden's handling of world affairs and says it is no longer able to conduct independent surveys in China, so does not survey there.翻译:皮尤表示，它没有询问美国民众对拜登处理国际事务的信心，并表示无法再在中国进行独立调查，因此不会在中国进行调查。</p>   <p>The countries surveyed were the United States, Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Britain, Canada, France, Germany, Greece, Hungary, India, Indonesia, Israel, Italy, Japan, Kenya, Mexico, the Netherlands, Nigeria, Poland, South Africa, South Korea, Spain and Sweden.翻译:接受调查的国家包括美国、阿根廷、澳大利亚、巴西、英国、加拿大、法国、德国、希腊、匈牙利、印度、印度尼西亚、以色列、意大利、日本、肯尼亚、墨西哥、荷兰、尼日利亚、波兰、南非、韩国、西班牙和瑞典。</p>   <p>Pew said its findings showed China was seen unfavorably in North America, Europe, and Asia but more favorably in Africa and Latin America.翻译:皮尤研究中心表示，其调查结果显示，中国在北美、欧洲和亚洲的形象较差，但在非洲和拉丁美洲的形象较好。</p>   <p>The gap in favor of Biden tended to be quite large in high-income contries, but even in most middle-income countries more had confidence in Biden than Xi, with Indonesia and Hungary being notable exceptions. The leaders received nearly identical marks in those countries, Pew said.翻译:在高收入国家，支持拜登的差距往往相当大，但即使在大多数中等收入国家，对拜登的信心也高于对习近平的信心，印度尼西亚和匈牙利是明显的例外。皮尤表示，两位领导人在这些国家获得的分数几乎相同。</p>   <p>"This year, overall views of the United States are much more positive than views of China in most places surveyed," it said.翻译:报告称：“今年，大多数受访地区对美国的总体看法比对中国的看法要积极得多。”</p>   <p>"A median of 59% offer positive evaluations of the U.S., compared with a median of 28% who say the same of China."翻译:“对美国持积极评价的中位数为 59%，而对中国持积极评价的中位数为 28%。”</p>   <p>Pew said that in nearly two decades of its favorability polling, views of the countries have fluctuated alongside views of their leaders, but those of the U.S. under Biden had rebounded dramatically in many of the countries surveyed, while those of China were at their most negative levels.翻译:皮尤研究中心表示，在近二十年的好感度民意调查中，各国的看法随着其领导人的看法而波动，但在许多接受调查的国家中，拜登领导下的美国的好感度大幅反弹，而中国的好感度则处于最负面的时期。水平。</p>   <p>While majorities in most countries saw both the U.S. and China as prone to interfere in the affairs of other countries, the U.S. was almost always more likely to be described that way.翻译:尽管大多数国家的大多数人都认为美国和中国都倾向于干涉其他国家的事务，但美国几乎总是更有可能被这样描述。</p>   <p>However, the U.S. "gets higher marks for contributing to global peace and stability than China," the survey said.翻译:然而，调查称，美国“在对全球和平与稳定的贡献方面获得比中国更高的分数”。</p>   <p>"On balance, views of the U.S. are much more positive than views of China," Pew said.翻译:皮尤表示：“总的来说，美国的看法比中国的看法积极得多。”</p>   <p>Biden and Xi are expected to meet on the sidelines of the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">APEC summit</a> in San Francisco next week, although China has yet to confirm this, and a senior <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/white-house-aims-biden-xi-meeting-san-francisco-november-2023-10-31/">Biden administration official</a> said last week important details had still to be hammered out.翻译:拜登和习近平预计将于下周在旧金山举行的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">亚太经合组织峰会</a>期间会面，尽管中国尚未证实这一点， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/white-house-aims-biden-xi-meeting-san-francisco-november-2023-10-31/">拜登政府一名高级官员</a>上周表示，重要细节仍有待敲定。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Brunnstrom; editing by Jonathan Oatis翻译:大卫·布伦斯特罗姆报道；乔纳森·奥蒂斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 16:03:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ANZJVMDOENL2RGBKJWKUHJN7QM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/poll-makes-better-reading-biden-than-chinas-xi-before-expected-summit-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Brunnstrom]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/SURVEY (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着紧张局势缓和，中国和澳大利亚同意翻开新的一页]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Xi: China, Australia should develop strategic partnership</li>  <li>Both sides should build up mutual trust, Xi says</li>  <li>Albanese: Strong relations 'will be beneficial into the future'</li>  <li>Albanese: Recognise differences but also 'mutual benefit'</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>习近平：中澳要发展战略伙伴关系</li><li>习近平：双方要增进互信</li><li>阿尔巴尼斯：牢固的关系“将有益于未来”</li><li> Albanese：承认差异但也“互惠互利”</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Ekmz-7DesXBcNOQSLUx46KJ3Vh8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GGPNBVIRL5MJRFRGU6S5MBJHYA.jpg" alt="Australia's Albanese retraces historic Beijing walk on visit to mend ties翻译:澳大利亚阿尔巴内斯访华重回历史性的北京徒步之旅，以修复两国关系" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese speaks during the bilateral meeting with Indonesia's President Joko Widodo on the sidelines of the 43rd Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) Summit in Jakarta, Indonesia, 07 September 2023. BAGUS INDAHONO/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞于 2023 年 9 月 7 日在印度尼西亚雅加达举行的第 43 届东南亚国家联盟（东盟）峰会期间与印度尼西亚总统佐科·维多多举行双边会晤。BAGUS INDAHONO/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/FQjrKue3GW6l3X6W6yqHULdwsZ4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4JW3DR2IRVICBNMM6UDIV6R2HI.jpg" alt="Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese meets with China's President Xi Jinping at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内斯在北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese shakes hands with China's President Xi Jinping at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS  翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞于 2023 年 11 月 6 日在中国北京人民大会堂与中国国家主席习近平握手。AAP 图片/Lukas Coch via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/S8RGQ7qV6WfJnR89PdexwT-U_S0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TDZTYFX6U5OQLPNKE4LKERU4IA.jpg" alt="Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese meets with China's President Xi Jinping at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内斯在北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese meets with China's President Xi Jinping at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内斯在北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS 翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞 (Anthony Albanese) 于 2023 年 11 月 6 日在中国北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平。AAP 图片/Lukas Coch via REUTERS 翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞 (Anthony Albanese) 于 2023 年 11 月 6 日在中国北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平。AAP 图片/Lukas Coch via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/dQgM15EWA12fyLiiD8nYejdP4_I=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PRPVDRTVONJ3HKTVNPY5QNVB5A.jpg" alt="Australia’s Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia’s Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛, China, November 6, 2023.  AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS  翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞 (Anthony Albanese) 于 2023 年 11 月 6 日参观中国北京天坛。AAP 图片/Lukas Coch via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/BJvp0NolcJPLPg1C_xJN2LhRMjs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DFQLHIG7BNL6TBM5YVFUZDTQMQ.jpg" alt="Australia’s Foreign Minister Penny Wong and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese attend a press conference after visiting the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤和总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛后出席新闻发布会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia’s Foreign Minister Penny Wong and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese attend a press conference after visiting the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤和总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛后出席新闻发布会, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS  </figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/VKg2-1veHY4AQfmJKxzSqP7DmMo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SFJSUHDLI5MSNFJLONLIEHKT54.jpg" alt="Australia’s Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Foreign Minister Penny Wong visit the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博尼斯和外交部长黄英贤参观北京天坛" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia’s Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Foreign Minister Penny Wong Penny Wong visit the Temple of Heaven in Beijing, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS 翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博尼斯和外交部长黄英贤于 2023 年 11 月 6 日参观中国北京天坛。AAP 图片/Lukas Coch via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/VOb6rBXaVW1DicsQpknPwltFc_g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FPP3E7STCVHSPF2KCLMPXT7QSA.JPG" alt="Australia’s Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞 (Anthony Albanese) 于 2023 年 11 月 6 日参观中国北京天坛。AAP 图片/Lukas Coch via REUTERS" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia’s Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞 (Anthony Albanese) 于 2023 年 11 月 6 日参观中国北京天坛。AAP 图片/Lukas Coch via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>                         <p>President Xi Jinping said on Monday stable ties between China and Australia served each other's interests and both should expand their cooperation, sending a clear signal that Beijing was ready to move on from recent tensions.翻译:习近平主席周一表示，中澳之间稳定的关系符合彼此的利益，双方应扩大合作，发出明确信号，表明北京已准备好摆脱近期的紧张局势。</p>   <p>China and Australia should promote the development of their strategic partnership as they build up mutual understanding and trust, Xi told Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese, the first Australian leader to visit Beijing since 2016, at the Great Hall of the People in the heart of the Chinese capital.翻译:习近平在北京人民大会堂对澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞说，中澳两国要推动战略伙伴关系发展，增进相互了解和信任。他是自2016年以来第一位访问北京的澳大利亚领导人。中国资本。</p>   <p>A strong relationship "will be beneficial into the future," Albanese told Xi in their second face-to-face talks in a year, a meeting that lasted more than an hour.翻译:阿尔巴尼斯在一年内第二次面对面会谈中对习近平表示，牢固的关系“对未来有利”，这次会议持续了一个多小时。</p>   <p>For decades, China and Australia built a relationship on trade, with Beijing becoming Canberra's biggest commercial partner with purchases of Australian food and natural resources.翻译:几十年来，中国和澳大利亚建立了贸易关系，北京通过购买澳大利亚食品和自然资源成为堪培拉最大的商业伙伴。</p>   <p>But ties soured after Australia <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australia-china-rocky-road-back-trade-visits-2023-11-03/">in 2017</a> accused China of meddling in its politics. The following year, Australia banned equipment from Chinese tech giant Huawei Technologies Co (HWT.UL) for its 5G network out of national security fears.翻译:但<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australia-china-rocky-road-back-trade-visits-2023-11-03/">2017年</a>澳大利亚指责中国干涉其政治后，两国关系恶化。次年，出于国家安全担忧，澳大利亚禁止将中国科技巨头华为技术有限公司（HWT.UL）的设备用于其 5G 网络。</p>   <p>An Australian call in 2020 for an international inquiry into the origin of the COVID pandemic, which emerged in the Chinese city of Wuhan in late 2019, infuriated Beijing, which responded with blocks on various Australian imports.翻译:2020 年，澳大利亚呼吁对 2019 年底在中国武汉出现的新冠病毒大流行的起源进行国际调查，此举激怒了北京，北京方面以封锁澳大利亚多种进口产品作为回应。</p>   <p>As relations deteriorated, China warned its students against studying in Australia, citing racist incidents, threatening a multi-billion-dollar education market.翻译:随着关系恶化，中国以种族主义事件为由警告学生不要去澳大利亚学习，这威胁到数十亿美元的教育市场。</p>   <p>Earlier on Monday, Albanese stopped by Beijing's iconic Temple of Heaven and posed for a photograph at the circular Echo Wall where Australia's then prime minister, Gough Whitlam, stood in 1973, a year after the two countries established ties.翻译:周一早些时候，阿尔巴尼斯在北京标志性的天坛停留，并在圆形回音墙前拍照留念，1973 年，即两国建交一年后，时任澳大利亚总理高夫·惠特拉姆 (Gough Whitlam) 曾站过这里。</p>      <p>"In China we often say that when drinking water, we should not forget those who dug the well," Xi said. "The Chinese people will not forget Prime Minister Whitlam for digging the well for us."</p>    <h 1="">'VERY POSITIVE'</h>  <p>Albanese took steps to stabilise relations after he became prime minister in May last year and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-looks-forward-constructive-dialogue-with-china-pm-albanese-2022-11-15/">met Xi</a> on the sidelines of a G20 summit in Indonesia in November.翻译:阿尔巴内斯去年5月就任总理后采取了稳定关系的措施，并于11月在印度尼西亚G20峰会期间<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-looks-forward-constructive-dialogue-with-china-pm-albanese-2022-11-15/">会见了习近平</a>。</p>   <p>China soon began lowering trade barriers, allowing imports of coal in January and ending tariffs on barley in August. Last month, Beijing agreed to review dumping tariffs of 218% on Australian wine.翻译:中国很快开始降低贸易壁垒，一月份允许进口煤炭，八月份取消了大麦关税。上个月，北京同意对澳大利亚葡萄酒征收218%的倾销关税进行复审。</p>   <p>"I noted very much unimpeded trade was in the interest of both countries, was good for Chinese consumers as well as Australian exporters," Albanese told reporters after the meeting. "He certainly agreed that Australian wine is good."翻译:阿尔巴内塞在会后对记者表示：“我指出，畅通无阻的贸易符合两国利益，对中国消费者和澳大利亚出口商都有好处。” “他当然同意澳大利亚葡萄酒很好。”</p>   <p>China's January-September imports from Australia increased 8.1% from a year earlier to $116.9 billion, Chinese customs data show. In 2022, imports plunged 12.7% to $142.1 billion.翻译:中国海关数据显示，1-9月中国从澳大利亚进口同比增长8.1%，达到1169亿美元。 2022年，进口下降12.7%至1421亿美元。</p>   <p>The meeting was "very positive", Albanese said, adding that he had invited Xi to visit Australia.翻译:阿尔巴内斯说，这次会面“非常积极”，并补充说他邀请习近平访问澳大利亚。</p>   <p>"Both of us certainly agreed that we shouldn't be defined by our differences, recognise that they are there, but also recognise the mutual benefit that we have."翻译:“我们双方当然都同意，我们不应该被分歧所定义，认识到分歧的存在，但也认识到我们拥有的共同利益。”</p>   <p>Obstacles remain in their relationship.翻译:他们的关系中仍然存在障碍。</p>   <p>Australian backing of a U.N. ruling rejecting China's territorial claims in the <a href="https://www.un.org/depts/los/clcs_new/submissions_files/mys_12_12_2019/2020_07_23_AUS_NV_UN_001_OLA-2020-00373.pdf" target="_blank">South China Sea</a> has angered Beijing, which has told Canberra the issue is not its concern.翻译:澳大利亚支持联合国拒绝中国在<a href="https://www.un.org/depts/los/clcs_new/submissions_files/mys_12_12_2019/2020_07_23_AUS_NV_UN_001_OLA-2020-00373.pdf" target="_blank">南海的</a>领土主张的裁决激怒了北京，北京已告诉堪培拉这个问题不是它关心的问题。</p>   <p>Australia says the South China Sea is an important passageway for its trade with Japan and South Korea.翻译:澳大利亚表示，南海是其与日本和韩国贸易的重要通道。</p>   <p>Beijing's projection of power among <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/three-pacific-islands-say-their-leaders-will-skip-annual-bloc-meeting-2023-11-06/">Pacific island nations</a> also alarmed Australia, while Canberra's <a href="https://www.defense.gov/News/News-Stories/Article/Article/3407275/us-partnership-with-uk-australia-enhances-security/" target="_blank">security alliance</a> with the United States and Britain in the Indo-Pacific - known as AUKUS - stoked Chinese worries about containment.翻译:北京在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/three-pacific-islands-say-their-leaders-will-skip-annual-bloc-meeting-2023-11-06/">太平洋岛国</a>之间的力量投射也令澳大利亚感到震惊，而堪培拉与美国和英国在印度-太平洋地区的<a href="https://www.defense.gov/News/News-Stories/Article/Article/3407275/us-partnership-with-uk-australia-enhances-security/" target="_blank">安全联盟</a>（称为AUKUS）则引发了中国对遏制的担忧。</p>   <p>"AUKUS didn't come up explicitly. We discussed, though, regional stability," Albanese said, without giving specifics. "I spoke about guardrails and military-to-military cooperation between the United States and China. That's important."翻译:“AUKUS 没有明确提出。不过，我们讨论了地区稳定，”阿尔巴内塞说，但没有透露具体细节。 “我谈到了美中之间的护栏和军事合作。这很重要。”</p>   <p>Albanese also raised the case of Australian writer <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/sons-australian-yang-hengjun-ask-his-release-ahead-pms-visit-china-2023-10-31/">Yang Hengjun</a>, who has been jailed in Beijing for four years on espionage charges.翻译:阿尔巴尼斯还提到了澳大利亚作家<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/sons-australian-yang-hengjun-ask-his-release-ahead-pms-visit-china-2023-10-31/">杨恒均</a>的案件，杨恒均因间谍罪名在北京被判入狱四年。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ryan Woo; additional reporting by Kirsty Needham in Sydney; editing by Robert Birsel and Mark Heinrich翻译:瑞恩·吴 (Ryan Woo) 报道； Kirsty Needham 在悉尼的补充报道；罗伯特·伯塞尔和马克·海因里希编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 15:39:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZMLIPMHVCBJRFMVIRMRE52W2CM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-albanese-retraces-historic-beijing-walk-visit-mend-ties-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ryan Woo]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA/ (UPDATE 2, TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[由于裁员迫在眉睫，英国钢铁公司寻求政府帮助建造新熔炉]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>British Steel wants to shut blast furnaces</li>  <li>Unions warn plan could lead to 2,000 job losses</li>  <li>Company wants two electric arc furnaces</li>  <li>Talks with government are ongoing</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>英国钢铁公司希望关闭高炉</li><li>工会警告计划可能导致 2,000 人失业</li><li>公司需要两台电弧炉</li><li>与政府的谈判正在进行中</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/xw0m3v9axeuLGmY3js9U5HgNDok=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ID5CI2VGCFKPBCIT35VYLKCOCU.jpg" alt="A British Steel works sign is seen in Scunthorpe翻译:斯肯索普看到英国钢铁厂的标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A British Steel works sign is seen in Scunthorpe翻译:斯肯索普看到英国钢铁厂的标志, northern England, Britain, May 21, 2019. REUTERS/Scott Heppell/File Photo翻译:2019 年 5 月 21 日，英国英格兰北部斯肯索普看到英国钢铁厂的标志。路透社/Scott Heppell/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lpKBOUKq45FnT6gA8y0MkdSXwIo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/D3JXJLER2ROKVJ6VUGYLCRYQCQ.jpg" alt="A general view shows the British Steel works in Scunthorpe翻译:英国斯肯索普钢铁厂全景" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A general view shows the British Steel works in Scunthorpe翻译:英国斯肯索普钢铁厂全景, Britain, May 21, 2019. REUTERS/Scott Heppell/File Photo翻译:2019 年 5 月 21 日，英国斯肯索普的英国钢铁厂全景。路透社/Scott Heppell/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>British Steel is in talks with the UK government about funding for a shift to cleaner manufacturing, which would include shutting blast furnaces and probable job losses.翻译:英国钢铁公司正在与英国政府就向清洁制造转型提供资金进行谈判，其中包括关闭高炉和可能的失业。</p>   <p>Owned by China's Jingye Group, Britain's second-biggest steelmaker on Monday outlined a 1.25 billion pound ($1.55 billion) plan to make steel in a less carbon intensive way by installing electric arc furnaces at its sites in Scunthorpe and Teesside, northeast England, replacing ageing blast furnaces.翻译:英国第二大钢铁制造商隶属于中国敬业集团，周一概述了一项耗资 12.5 亿英镑（15.5 亿美元）的计划，通过在英格兰东北部斯肯索普和蒂赛德的工厂安装电弧炉，以减少碳密集度的方式生产钢铁，以取代老化的炉子。高炉。</p>   <p>Unions have warned the shift could lead to between 1,500 and 2,000 job losses, as the new facilities would require fewer workers. The company currently has a workforce of 3,200.翻译:工会警告称，这一转变可能会导致 1,500 至 2,000 人失业，因为新设施需要的工人更少。该公司目前拥有员工 3,200 名。</p>   <p>In a deal in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/britain-provide-621-mln-funding-tata-steel-bbc-2023-09-15/">September</a> aimed at securing the future of Tata Steel, Britain's biggest steelmaker, the government pumped 500 million pounds into the company, which alongside British Steel has complained that high energy costs make it uncompetitive.翻译:在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/britain-provide-621-mln-funding-tata-steel-bbc-2023-09-15/">9月份</a>的一项旨在确保英国最大钢铁制造商塔塔钢铁公司未来的交易中，政府向该公司注入了5亿英镑，该公司与英国钢铁公司一起抱怨高能源成本使其缺乏竞争力。</p>   <p>British Steel wants a similar level of government support.翻译:英国钢铁公司希望获得类似水平的政府支持。</p>   <p>"We remain in talks with the government," British Steel CEO and President Xijun Cao said in a statement, adding its proposals were subject to "appropriate support" from the government.翻译:英国钢铁公司首席执行官兼总裁曹锡军在一份声明中表示，“我们仍在与政府进行谈判”，并补充说其建议将得到政府的“适当支持”。</p>   <p>Britain has offered British Steel a package worth more than 300 million pounds, the government's Business and Trade ministry said.翻译:英国政府商业和贸易部表示，英国已向英国钢铁公司提供了价值超过 3 亿英镑的一揽子计划。</p>   <p>"It is for British Steel to manage commercial decisions for the future of the company, and we cannot comment on ongoing commercial negotiations beyond that," a government spokesperson said.翻译:政府发言人表示：“英国钢铁公司负责管理公司未来的商业决策，我们无法对除此之外正在进行的商业谈判发表评论。”</p>   <p>Under the deal with Tata Steel, the government said 5,000 jobs would be safeguarded, raising the prospect of 3,000 redundancies from a UK workforce of 8,000.翻译:根据与塔塔钢铁公司的协议，政府表示将保护 5,000 个工作岗位，这意味着英国 8,000 名劳动力中可能会裁员 3,000 人。</p>   <p>British Steel said it had started talks with trade unions about its plans and aimed to have the new furnaces operational by late 2025.翻译:英国钢铁公司表示，已开始与工会就其计划进行谈判，目标是在 2025 年底前让新熔炉投入运行。</p>   <p>The Trades Union Congress (TUC) umbrella union group called on the company to halt its plans and get around the table with unions.翻译:工会大会 (TUC) 伞式工会团体呼吁该公司停止其计划并与工会谈判。</p>   <p>"Workers won't stand back and watch as Britain’s steel industry is dismantled in real time," the TUC said in a statement.翻译:英国工会联合会在一份声明中表示：“工人们不会袖手旁观，眼睁睁地看着英国钢铁工业被实时拆除。”</p>   <p>($1 = 0.8070 pounds)翻译:（1 美元 = 0.8070 英镑）</p>    <span>Reporting by Sarah Young
Additional reporting by Kylie MacLellan
Editing by Paul Sandle and Mark Potter翻译:莎拉·杨 (Sarah Young) 报道 凯莉·麦克莱伦 (Kylie MacLellan) 补充报道 保罗·桑德尔 (Paul Sandle) 和马克·波特 (Mark Potter) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 15:24:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZP4DLKQ3NBJ3NJDT4VQOBH3W34</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/british-steel-has-125-bln-stg-decarbonisation-plan-needs-govt-support-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Sarah Young]]></author>
            
                
                <category>BRITAIN</category>
                
                <category>STEEL/ (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：消息人士称，俄罗斯普京将继续执政至 2024 年]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/a_S6MKx028UN8KjP_pwTwxAybHg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/M3WG7SG5O5PPRCCEZNKTDHNCE4.jpg" alt="Russian President Putin marks National Unity Day in Moscow翻译:俄罗斯总统普京在莫斯科庆祝民族团结日" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Russian President Vladimir Putin speaks with members of public associations, youth and volunteer organizations during a flower-laying ceremony at the monument to Kuzma Minin and Dmitry Pozharsky while marking Russia's Day of National Unity in Red Square in central Moscow, Russia November 4, 2023. Sputnik/Mikhail Metzel/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 4 日，俄罗斯莫斯科市中心红场举行俄罗斯民族团结日纪念活动，俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京在库兹马·米宁和德米特里·波扎尔斯基纪念碑献花仪式上与公共协会、青年和志愿者组织成员发表讲话。人造卫星/米哈伊尔·梅策尔/泳池来自路透社/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Vladimir Putin has decided to run in the March presidential election, a move that will keep him in power until least 2030, as the Kremlin chief feels he must steer Russia through the most perilous period in decades, six sources told Reuters.翻译:六名消息人士告诉路透社，弗拉基米尔·普京 (Vladimir Putin) 决定参加 3 月份的总统选举，此举将使他继续掌权至少到 2030 年，因为这位克里姆林宫领导人认为他必须带领俄罗斯度过数十年来最危险的时期。</p>   <p>After defusing an armed mutiny by the leader of the Wagner mercenary group in June, Putin has moved to shore up support among his core base in the security forces, the armed forces and with regional voters outside Moscow, while Wagner has been brought firmly to heel.翻译:在瓦格纳雇佣兵组织领导人六月平息武装叛变后，普京开始加强其安全部队、武装部队和莫斯科以外地区选民的核心基础的支持，而瓦格纳则被坚定地屈服。 。</p>   <p>Russian <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/russia-plans-26-rise-budget-spending-2024-2023-09-22/">defence, weapons and overall budget</a> spending has soared while Putin has made numerous public appearances, including the regions, over recent months.翻译:近几个月来，俄罗斯的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/russia-plans-26-rise-budget-spending-2024-2023-09-22/">国防、武器和总体预算</a>支出猛增，而普京则多次公开露面，包括在这些地区露面。</p>   <p>"The decision has been made - he will run," said one of the sources who has knowledge of the planning.翻译:一位了解该计划的消息人士表示：“决定已经做出——他将参选。”</p>   <p>Another source, also acquainted with the Kremlin's thinking, confirmed that a decision has been made and that Putin's advisers were preparing for his participation. Three other sources said the decision to run in the March 2024 presidential election had been taken.翻译:另一位也了解克里姆林宫想法的消息人士证实，已经做出了决定，普京的顾问正在为他的参与做准备。其他三名消息人士称，参加 2024 年 3 月总统选举的决定已经做出。</p>   <p>The sources spoke to Reuters on condition of anonymity due to the sensitivity of Kremlin politics.翻译:由于克里姆林宫政治的敏感性，消息人士要求匿名。</p>   <p>One of them said a choreographed hint was due to come within a few weeks, confirming a Kommersant<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/putin-may-next-month-hint-he-will-run-russias-2024-election-kommersant-2023-10-03/"> newspaper</a> report last month.翻译:其中一人表示，精心设计的暗示将在几周内发布，这证实了《生意人<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/putin-may-next-month-hint-he-will-run-russias-2024-election-kommersant-2023-10-03/">报》</a>上个月的报道。</p>   <p>While many diplomats, spies and officials have said they expect Putin to stay in power for life, there has until now been now been no specific confirmation of Putin's plans to stand for re-election.翻译:尽管许多外交官、间谍和官员表示，他们预计普京将终身掌权，但到目前为止，还没有具体证实普京竞选连任的计划。</p>   <p>Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said Putin had not yet commented on the issue, adding: "The campaign has not been officially announced yet."</p>    <h 1="">RUSSIA AT WAR</h>  <p>Putin, 71, who was handed the presidency by Boris Yeltsin on the last day of 1999, has already served as president for longer than any other Russian ruler since Josef Stalin, beating even Leonid Brezhnev's 18-year tenure.翻译:现年 71 岁的普京于 1999 年最后一天被鲍里斯·叶利钦 (Boris Yeltsin) 接任，成为自约瑟夫·斯大林 (Josef Stalin) 以来担任总统时间最长的俄罗斯统治者，甚至超过了列昂尼德·勃列日涅夫 (Leonid Brezhnev) 18 年的任期。</p>   <p>Diplomats say there is no serious rival who could threaten Putin's chances at the ballot box, should the incumbent run again. The former KGB spy enjoys <a href="https://www.levada.ru/indikatory/" target="_blank">approval ratings</a> of 80%, can count on the support of the state and the state media, and there is almost no mainstream public opposition to his continued rule.翻译:外交官表示，如果现任总统再次参选，没有任何强有力的竞争对手可以威胁普京的投票机会。这位前克格勃间谍享有80%的<a href="https://www.levada.ru/indikatory/" target="_blank">支持率</a>，可以依靠国家和官方媒体的支持，而且几乎没有主流公众反对他继续统治。</p>   <p>Yet Putin faces the most serious set of challenges any Kremlin chief has faced since Mikhail Gorbachev grappled with the crumbling Soviet Union more than three decades ago.翻译:然而，自三十多年前米哈伊尔·戈尔巴乔夫(Mikhail Gorbachev)与崩溃的苏联作斗争以来，普京面临着克里姆林宫领导人所面临的最严峻的挑战。</p>   <p>The war in Ukraine has triggered the biggest confrontation with the West since the 1962 Cuban Missile Crisis and the resulting Western sanctions have delivered the biggest external shock to the Russian economy in decades.翻译:乌克兰战争引发了自1962年古巴导弹危机以来与西方最严重的对抗，由此引发的西方制裁给俄罗斯经济带来了数十年来最大的外部冲击。</p>   <p>Inflation has accelerated while the rouble has fallen since the war began, and defence spending will account for <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/everything-front-russia-allots-third-2024-spending-defence-2023-10-02/">almost one third of Russia's total budget expenditure</a> in 2024, the government's draft plans show.翻译:政府的计划草案显示，自战争开始以来，通货膨胀加速，而卢布贬值，到2024年，国防支出将占<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/everything-front-russia-allots-third-2024-spending-defence-2023-10-02/">俄罗斯预算总支出的近三分之一</a>。</p>   <p>But the biggest direct threat to Putin's continued rule came in June, when Russia's most powerful mercenary, Yevgeny Prigozhin, led a short-lived mutiny.翻译:但对普京继续统治的最大直接威胁出现在六月，当时俄罗斯最强大的雇佣兵叶夫根尼·普里戈任领导了一场短暂的叛变。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/putin-hand-grenade-fragments-found-bodies-prigozhin-plane-crash-2023-10-05/">Prigozhin was killed</a> in a plane crash two months to the day after the mutiny, and Putin has since used the Defence Ministry and the National Guard to extend his allies' control over the remnants of the Wagner force.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/putin-hand-grenade-fragments-found-bodies-prigozhin-plane-crash-2023-10-05/">兵变发生两个月后的第二天，普里戈任在一次飞机失事中丧生</a>，此后普京利用国防部和国民警卫队扩大其盟友对瓦格纳部队残余的控制。</p>   <p>The West casts Putin as a war criminal and a dictator who has led Russia into an imperial-style land grab that has weakened Russia and forged Ukrainian statehood, while uniting the West and handing NATO a renewed sense of mission.翻译:西方将普京视为战犯和独裁者，他带领俄罗斯进行帝国式的土地掠夺，削弱了俄罗斯并建立了乌克兰国家地位，同时团结了西方并赋予北约新的使命感。</p>   <p>Putin, though, presents the war as part of a much broader struggle with the United States which the Kremlin elite says aims to cleave Russia apart, grab its vast natural resources and then turn to settling scores with China.翻译:不过，普京将这场战争视为与美国更广泛斗争的一部分，克里姆林宫精英称，这场斗争的目的是分裂俄罗斯，攫取其丰富的自然资源，然后转向与中国算账。</p>   <p>"Russia is facing the combined might of the West so major change would not be expedient," one of the sources said.翻译:一位消息人士称：“俄罗斯面临着西方的联合力量，因此重大改变并不合适。”</p>   <p>For some Russians, however, the war has shown the faultlines of post-Soviet Russia.翻译:然而，对于一些俄罗斯人来说，这场战争暴露了后苏联时期俄罗斯的断层。</p>   <p>Jailed Russian opposition politician Alexei Navalny says Putin has led Russia down a strategic dead end towards ruin, building a brittle system of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/jailed-kremlin-foe-navalny-lambasts-putins-stupid-war-ukraine-2022-05-24/">corrupt sycophants</a> that will ultimately bequeath chaos rather than stability.翻译:被监禁的俄罗斯反对派政治家阿列克谢·纳瓦尔尼表示，普京已经将俄罗斯带入了走向毁灭的战略死胡同，建立了一个<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/jailed-kremlin-foe-navalny-lambasts-putins-stupid-war-ukraine-2022-05-24/">由腐败谄媚者</a>组成的脆弱体系，最终将带来混乱而不是稳定。</p>   <p>"Russia is going backwards," <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russia-is-rotting-absurdity-repression-veteran-rights-campaigner-says-2023-07-12/">Oleg Orlov</a>, one of Russia's most respected human rights campaigners, told Reuters in July. "We left Communist totalitarianism but now have returned to a different kind of totalitarianism."翻译:“俄罗斯正在倒退，”俄罗斯最受尊敬的人权活动家之一<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russia-is-rotting-absurdity-repression-veteran-rights-campaigner-says-2023-07-12/">奥列格·奥尔洛夫（Oleg Orlov）</a> 7月份对路透社表示。 “我们离开了共产主义极权主义，但现在又回到了另一种极权主义。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Guy Faulconbridge; Editing by Jon Boyle翻译:盖伊·福尔肯布里奇报道；乔恩·博伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 14:08:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">NH5UP6OUY5MMHNFBG5M2KMZZF4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russias-putin-stay-power-past-2024-sources-say-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Guy Faulconbridge]]></author>
            
                
                <category>RUSSIA</category>
                
                <category>PUTIN/ (UPDATE 1, EXCLUSIVE, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[澳大利亚总理阿尔巴内斯表示与中国沟通很重要]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/EuBKraZQBTo4F9DeYv0y1XtrhCE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YOTL6SMEQFKZHGACEZ3TSSZN7A.jpg" alt="Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese meets with China's President Xi Jinping at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内斯在北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese meets with China's President Xi Jinping at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内斯在北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS 翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞 (Anthony Albanese) 于 2023 年 11 月 6 日在中国北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平。AAP 图片/Lukas Coch via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/mfI92R8j9gHGx_cxNshbSGuhgxo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BWIDIGQHGVIMLGKR77UWEMGVN4.jpg" alt="Australia’s Foreign Minister Penny Wong and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese attend a news conference after visiting the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤和总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛后出席新闻发布会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Australia’s Foreign Minister Penny Wong and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese attend a news conference after visiting the Temple of Heaven in Beijing翻译:澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤和总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观北京天坛后出席新闻发布会, China, November 6, 2023. AAP Image/Lukas Coch via REUTERS  翻译:2023 年 11 月 6 日，澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤和总理安东尼·艾博尼斯参观中国北京天坛后出席新闻发布会。AAP 图片/Lukas Coch via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>               <p>Australia's Prime Minister Anthony Albanese told Chinese President Xi Jinping in Beijing on Monday that Australia has an interest in the continued stable growth of China's economy and its ongoing engagement with the world.翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞周一在北京对中国国家主席习近平表示，中国经济的持续稳定增长及其与世界的持续接触符合澳大利亚的利益。</p>   <p>In opening remarks as the two leaders met at the Great Hall of the People, Albanese said a strong relationship between the two countries was "beneficial into the future".翻译:两国领导人在人民大会堂会面时，阿尔巴尼斯在开幕致辞中表示，两国之间牢固的关系“有利于未来”。</p>   <p>"Australia, along with other countries in the region, has an interest in continued stable growth in the Chinese economy, and its ongoing engagement with the world ," he said, according to an official transcript from the Australian Prime Minister's Office.翻译:根据澳大利亚总理办公室的官方记录，他表示：“澳大利亚与该地区其他国家一样，对中国经济的持续稳定增长及其与世界的持续接触感兴趣。”</p>   <p>Albanese said it was "important that we have communication" where differences arise.翻译:阿尔巴内塞表示，在出现分歧时“保持沟通非常重要”。</p>    <span>Reporting by Kirsty Needham; Editing by Christian Schmollinger翻译:科斯蒂·李约瑟报道；克里斯蒂安·施莫林格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 12:43:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">G3KIRBWVRNPXJDTYY3ZGWKGICU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-pm-albanese-says-important-have-communication-with-china-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA/ALBANESE (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[欧盟布雷顿要求 TikTok 首席执行官“不遗余力”打击虚假信息]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/xepFNLAUSk5atorvki42ObrDC_s=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WEI3DOYNBJPOPFI5HKFTAWPNQ4.jpg" alt="A TikTok logo is displayed on a smartphone in this illustration翻译:在此插图中，智能手机上显示 TikTok 徽标" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A TikTok logo is displayed on a smartphone in this illustration翻译:在此插图中，智能手机上显示 TikTok 徽标 taken January 6, 2020. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration//File Photo翻译:在这张 2020 年 1 月 6 日拍摄的插图中，智能手机上显示了 TikTok 徽标。 REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration//档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/LneUP-ucxWpFPR28eFOWHX7ROOY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/T4SQAZVLZZJXXJ7Z72OK6ZN6IM.jpg" alt="European flags fly outside the European Commission headquarters in Brussels翻译:布鲁塞尔欧盟委员会总部外飘扬着欧洲旗帜" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>European flags fly outside the European Commission headquarters in Brussels翻译:布鲁塞尔欧盟委员会总部外飘扬着欧洲旗帜, Belgium September 20, 2023. REUTERS/Yves Herman/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>TikTok must "spare no effort" to counter the spread of disinformation on the short video sharing app, EU industry chief Thierry Breton told the company's CEO on Monday, as the European Union steps up its efforts to curb the powers of Big Tech.翻译:欧盟行业负责人蒂埃里·布雷顿(Thierry Breton)周一对TikTok首席执行官表示，随着欧盟加大力度遏制大型科技公司的权力，TikTok必须“不遗余力”打击短视频共享应用程序上虚假信息的传播。</p>   <p>Breton last month gave TikTok, owned by China's ByteDance, an Oct. 25 deadline to provide information on its crisis response measures and also ordered the company to provide details by Nov. 8 on how it protects the integrity of elections and minors online on its platform.翻译:布雷顿上个月给中国字节跳动旗下的 TikTok 规定了 10 月 25 日的最后期限，要求其提供有关其危机应对措施的信息，并命令该公司在 11 月 8 日之前提供有关如何在其平台上保护选举和未成年人在线的完整性的详细信息。</p>   <p>The European Commissioner pointed to changes on TikTok's platform in the past months with new features to protect users and investments made in content moderation and trust and safety.翻译:欧盟专员指出，过去几个月 TikTok 平台发生了变化，推出了保护用户的新功能以及在内容审核、信任和安全方面的投资。</p>   <p>"My services and I are now investigating whether this is enough to ensure compliance with the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/big-tech-braces-roll-out-eus-digital-services-act-2023-08-24/">DSA (Digital Services Act)</a>," Breton told Reuters in written comments after a video call with TikTok CEO Shou Zi Chew.翻译:在与 TikTok 首席执行官 Shou Zi Chew 进行视频通话后，布雷顿在书面评论中对路透社表示：“我和我的服务部门现在正在调查这是否足以确保遵守<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/big-tech-braces-roll-out-eus-digital-services-act-2023-08-24/">DSA（数字服务法）</a> 。”</p>   <p>"Because now more than ever, we must spare no effort to protect our citizens – especially children and teenagers – against illegal content and disinformation," he said.翻译:他说：“因为现在我们比以往任何时候都更必须不遗余力地保护我们的公民，特别是儿童和青少年，免受非法内容和虚假信息的侵害。”</p>   <p>TikTok Public Policy Director Caroline Greer said in a post on social media platform X that the company was pleased that Breton recognised its compliance efforts.翻译:TikTok 公共政策总监 Caroline Greer 在社交媒体平台 X 上发帖表示，公司很高兴 Breton 认可其合规努力。</p>   <p>The DSA requires large online platforms to do more to tackle illegal and harmful online content on their platforms. It is one of a slew of recent EU rules aimed at reining in the power of Big Tech.翻译:DSA 要求大型网络平台采取更多措施，打击其平台上的非法和有害网络内容。这是欧盟最近出台的一系列旨在限制大型科技公司权力的规则之一。</p>   <p>Chew is scheduled to meet EU Vice-President for Values and Transparency, Vera Jourova, and EU antitrust head Didier Ryenders in Brussels on Tuesday.翻译:周计划于周二在布鲁塞尔会见欧盟负责价值观和透明度的副主席维拉·朱罗娃（Vera Jourova）和欧盟反垄断负责人迪迪埃·赖恩德斯（Didier Ryenders）。</p>    <span>Reporting by Foo Yun Chee; Editing by Sharon Singleton翻译:符润芝报道；莎朗·辛格尔顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 12:23:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TSVYYLFLKZL4LFJH4SEZMM7IKM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/eus-breton-tells-tiktok-ceo-ramp-up-efforts-against-disinformation-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Foo Yun Chee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>EU</category>
                
                <category>TIKTOK/ (UPDATE 2,PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[墨西哥企业因“近岸外包”曙光而升温]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tIPuW-VF741cNkN-RC3woUfO3P8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XV3YY2VFJRISPLFFHPD5YIKC34.jpg" alt="A building undergoing construction is seen in Mexico City翻译:墨西哥城一座正在建设中的建筑" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A building undergoing construction is seen in Mexico City翻译:墨西哥城一座正在建设中的建筑, Mexico January 30, 2020. REUTERS/Andres Martinez Casares/File Photo翻译:2020 年 1 月 30 日，墨西哥墨西哥城，一座正在施工的建筑。路透社/Andres Martinez Casares/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Mexican businesses, particularly those linked to real estate and construction, are counting on investment from <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/mexico-pitches-tax-breaks-lure-foreign-investment-infrastructure-doubts-persist-2023-10-11/">so-called "nearshoring"</a> to boost profits and economic growth, especially in industrial zones near the U.S. border.翻译:墨西哥企业，特别是与房地产和建筑相关的企业，正在依靠<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/mexico-pitches-tax-breaks-lure-foreign-investment-infrastructure-doubts-persist-2023-10-11/">所谓的“近岸外包”</a>投资来提高利润和经济增长，特别是在美国边境附近的工业区。</p>   <p>Mexico's government expects nearshoring - the trend of locating manufacturing capacity in Mexico, closer to the U.S. market, rather than in Asia - to add up to 1.2 percentage points to growth, which is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/mexico-sees-solid-economic-expansion-price-pressures-persist-2023-10-25/">expected to reach 3.5%</a> this year.翻译:墨西哥政府预计，近岸外包——将制造能力集中在墨西哥、更靠近美国市场而不是亚洲的趋势——将为经济增长带来 1.2 个百分点的增长， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/mexico-sees-solid-economic-expansion-price-pressures-persist-2023-10-25/">预计今年将达到 3.5%</a> 。</p>   <p>Even as analysts warn that <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/mexico-sends-1500-security-forces-southern-region-plagued-by-gangs-2023-09-26/">gang violence</a>, plus <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/mexico-citys-thirst-water-lays-bare-inequalities-changing-climate-2023-04-27/">water and energy supply snags</a> could curb the trend, many local and foreign businesses are looking to capitalize on shifts in production chains, some of which have already begun.翻译:尽管分析人士警告说， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/mexico-sends-1500-security-forces-southern-region-plagued-by-gangs-2023-09-26/">帮派暴力</a>以及<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/mexico-citys-thirst-water-lays-bare-inequalities-changing-climate-2023-04-27/">水和能源供应障碍</a>可能会遏制这一趋势，但许多本地和外国企业正在寻求利用生产链的转变，其中一些已经开始。</p>   <p>"Many companies are already talking about this - about nearshoring and the economic benefits," said Gerardo Copca, an analyst at consultancy MetAnalisis. "And I do think this will take off." It will, however, take time, he cautioned.翻译:咨询公司 MetAnalisis 的分析师赫拉尔多·科普卡 (Gerardo Copca) 表示：“许多公司已经在谈论这个问题，谈论近岸外包和经济效益。” “我确实认为这将会起飞。”不过，他警告说，这需要时间。</p>   <p>Nearshoring was on the lips of many executives during third quarter earnings calls, and in the first six months of 2023, Mexico raked in around $29 billion in foreign direct investment, up 5.6% from 2022. More than half was in the industrial sector.翻译:在第三季度财报电话会议上，许多高管都在谈论近岸外包，2023 年前 6 个月，墨西哥吸引了约 290 亿美元的外国直接投资，比 2022 年增长 5.6%。其中一半以上投资于工业领域。</p>   <p>One notable project - electric vehicle maker Tesla's plans for a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/mexican-president-says-tesla-will-build-major-plant-northern-city-2023-02-28/">reported $5 billion factory</a> in northern Mexico - has been credited with attracting <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinese-suppliers-invest-mexican-state-where-tesla-planning-factory-state-2023-10-18/">$1 billion in Chinese investments</a> to nearby industries.翻译:电动汽车制造商特斯拉计划在墨西哥北部建造一座<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/mexican-president-says-tesla-will-build-major-plant-northern-city-2023-02-28/">价值 50 亿美元的工厂</a>，这一著名项目被认为为附近行业吸引了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinese-suppliers-invest-mexican-state-where-tesla-planning-factory-state-2023-10-18/">10 亿美元的中国投资</a>。</p>   <p>Mexican gross fixed investment is on track to post its strongest annual growth since 1997, leaping 31.5% year-on-year in seasonally adjusted terms in August, the latest data.翻译:最新数据显示，墨西哥固定投资总额有望实现自 1997 年以来最强劲的年度增长，经季节调整后，8 月份同比增长 31.5%。</p>   <p>Mexican real estate investment trust Fibra Uno <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FUNO11.MX" target="_blank">(FUNO11.MX)</a> plans to launch a trust allowing investors to cash in on expected growth of industrial assets.翻译:墨西哥房地产投资信托 Fibra Uno <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FUNO11.MX" target="_blank">(FUNO11.MX)</a>计划推出一项信托，让投资者能够从工业资产的预期增长中获利。</p>   <p>Fibra Uno expects Mexico's nearshoring momentum to continue for the next 15 years, CEO Andre El-Mann said on Oct. 24.</p>    <h 1="">ENERGY WORRIES</h>  <p>Meanwhile, estimated manufacturing property demand for 2023/24 stands at 2.5 million square meters, up nearly 80% from last year, according to industrial parks association AMPIP.翻译:与此同时，根据工业园区协会 AMPIP 的数据，预计 2023/24 年制造业地产需求为 250 万平方米，比去年增长近 80%。</p>   <p>Demand was particularly strong in the auto sector, the electronics industry and among machinery makers, AMPIP said.翻译:AMPIP 表示，汽车行业、电子行业和机械制造商的需求尤其强劲。</p>   <p>Lorenzo Berho, head of construction firm Vesta <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VESTA.MX" target="_blank">(VESTA.MX)</a>, said not only should the north benefit from nearshoring, but also the central carmaking region known as El Bajio, a "very good location" for multinationals, with strong infrastructure in states including Queretaro, Guanajuato and Jalisco.翻译:建筑公司 Vesta <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VESTA.MX" target="_blank">(VESTA.MX)</a>负责人洛伦佐·贝尔霍 (Lorenzo Berho) 表示，不仅北部地区应该受益于近岸外包，而且被称为 El Bajio 的汽车制造中心地区也应该受益，该地区对于跨国公司来说是一个“非常好的位置”，在包括以下州在内的州拥有强大的基础设施克雷塔罗、瓜纳华托和哈利斯科。</p>   <p>"It has a great labor pool. It has good logistics," Berho told an analysts' call last month.翻译:“它拥有大量的劳动力。它有良好的物流，”贝尔霍上个月在分析师电话会议上表示。</p>   <p>Enrique Navarro, finance chief at Banco Regional <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RA.MX" target="_blank">(RA.MX)</a>, observed that relocation activity should fuel "a lot of growth" in northern, western and central Mexico.翻译:Banco Regional <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RA.MX" target="_blank">(RA.MX)</a>财务主管恩里克·纳瓦罗 (Enrique Navarro) 指出，搬迁活动应该会推动墨西哥北部、西部和中部的“大量增长”。</p>   <p>As it seeks to lure manufacturing capacity away from Asia, Mexico can take advantage of its shared border with the United States, the world's largest economy, and multiple trade pacts, including USMCA, which includes Canada.翻译:在寻求从亚洲吸引制造能力时，墨西哥可以利用与世界最大经济体美国的共同边界以及多项贸易协定，包括包括加拿大在内的《美墨加协定》。</p>   <p>Mexico's lower labor costs are also a big draw, as are growing economic tensions between the U.S. and China.翻译:墨西哥较低的劳动力成本也是一个很大的吸引力，美国和中国之间日益紧张的经济关系也是如此。</p>   <p>But challenges remain because President Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador's drive to tighten state control of energy has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/energy-politics-cloud-mexican-bid-join-us-semiconductor-rush-2022-12-14/">fed concerns</a> about a lack of investment in key infrastructure.翻译:但挑战依然存在，因为总统安德烈斯·曼努埃尔·洛佩兹·奥夫拉多尔加强国家对能源控制的努力<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/energy-politics-cloud-mexican-bid-join-us-semiconductor-rush-2022-12-14/">引发了人们对关键基础设施投资缺乏的担忧</a>。</p>   <p>"The investments the country is receiving are already creating bottlenecks due to the instability of electricity transmission, water scarcity and limited industrial space," Swiss bank UBS said in a recent note.翻译:瑞士银行瑞银在最近的一份报告中表示：“由于电力传输不稳定、水资源短缺和工业空间有限，该国正在接受的投资已经造成了瓶颈。”</p>   <p>Still, nearshoring is showing up in the real economy.翻译:尽管如此，近岸外包仍在实体经济中出现。</p>   <p>Cement company GCC <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GCC.MX" target="_blank">(GCC.MX)</a> said between July and September, greater demand for cement was driven by construction of industrial projects in Chihuahua state, which borders Texas.翻译:水泥公司 GCC <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GCC.MX" target="_blank">(GCC.MX)</a>表示，7 月至 9 月期间，与德克萨斯州接壤的奇瓦瓦州工业项目的建设推动了水泥需求的增加。</p>   <p>Total Mexican construction output jumped almost by 46% in August year-on-year, with northern states performing strongly.翻译:墨西哥 8 月份建筑总产出同比增长近 46%，其中北部各州表现强劲。</p>    <span>Reporting by Noe Torres;
Additional reporting by Dave Graham; Editing by David Alire Garcia, Christian Plumb and Josie Kao翻译:诺伊·托雷斯报道；戴夫·格雷厄姆的补充报道；编辑：David Alire Garcia、Christian Plumb 和 Josie Kao</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 12:11:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6BR63JNJPVIVPMVANBRZ34ISCI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/mexican-businesses-warmed-by-glow-nearshoring-dawn-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Noe Torres]]></author>
            
                
                <category>MEXICO</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[欧盟要求阿里巴巴速卖通提供打击非法产品措施的细节]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/FfRoRSVsGfWQ4QnmsEq_y1xiCMc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MP6H46MMKNPKRH2S6WLECHKTOA.jpg" alt="Illustration shows AliExpress logo翻译:插图显示 AliExpress 徽标" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Shopping trolley is seen in front of AliExpress logo in this illustration, July 24, 2022. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张 2022 年 7 月 24 日的插图中，购物车位于全球速卖通标志前。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>The European Commission on Monday ordered Alibaba's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">(9988.HK)</a> AliExpress to provide information on how it tackles illegal products, such as counterfeit goods, sold on its platform by Nov. 27 or face an investigation that could result in fines.翻译:欧盟委员会周一责令阿里巴巴<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">（9988.HK）</a>速卖通在 11 月 27 日之前提供有关如何处理其平台上销售的非法产品（例如假冒商品）的信息，否则将面临可能导致罚款的调查。</p>   <p>The EU executive said it had sent a request for information to AliExpress in line with newly adopted EU rules called the Digital Services Act (DSA), which requires Big Tech to do more to counter illegal and harmful content on their platforms.翻译:欧盟高管表示，已根据欧盟新通过的《数字服务法》(DSA) 规则向全球速卖通发出信息请求，该法案要求大型科技公司采取更多措施打击其平台上的非法和有害内容。</p>   <p>The Commission said it wants to know what measures AliExpress has taken to comply with DSA rules against the dissemination and sale of illegal products online, such as fake medicines.翻译:欧盟委员会表示，它想知道全球速卖通采取了哪些措施来遵守 DSA 规则，打击在线传播和销售假药等非法产品。</p>   <p>It said AliExpress must provide the requested information by Nov. 27 after which the Commission will assess its next steps.翻译:它表示速卖通必须在 11 月 27 日之前提供所要求的信息，之后委员会将评估其下一步行动。</p>   <p>"It (DSA) is also there to ensure removal of illegal or unsafe products sold in the EU via e-commerce platforms, including the growing number of fake and potentially life-threatening medicines and pharmaceuticals sold online," EU industry chief Thierry Breton said in a statement.翻译:欧盟行业负责人蒂埃里·布雷顿 (Thierry Breton) 表示：“DSA 还旨在确保清除通过电子商务平台在欧盟销售的非法或不安全产品，包括网上销售的假冒药品和可能危及生命的药品数量不断增加。”在一份声明中。</p>   <p>Breton has in recent weeks sent similar requests for information to Elon Musk's X platform, Meta Platforms <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/META.O" target="_blank">(META.O)</a> and TikTok, asking what they are doing to fight the spread of disinformation.翻译:最近几周，布雷顿向埃隆·马斯克的 X 平台、Meta Platforms <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/META.O" target="_blank">(META.O)</a>和 TikTok 发出了类似的信息请求，询问他们正在采取哪些措施来打击虚假信息的传播。</p>    <span>Reporting by Foo Yun Chee; Editing by Sharon Singleton翻译:符润芝报道；莎朗·辛格尔顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 11:59:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">IIJKPTSSV5PHBDCXQ2SA3VPA44</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/eu-asks-alibabas-aliexpress-information-illegal-products-sold-its-platform-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Foo Yun Chee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>EU</category>
                
                <category>ALIBABA/ALIEXPRESS (UPDATE 1,PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[习近平主席在北京会见古巴总理马雷罗]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/91XSGYJkWJ0cAIi2FlV1zQxtteM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/I3CQPXP66ZNR3JN72RSZ6EOLIY.jpg" alt="Opening ceremony of the Belt and Road Forum (BRF) in Beijing翻译:一带一路高峰论坛（BRF）在北京开幕" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping speaks at the opening ceremony of the Belt and Road Forum (BRF) to mark the 10th anniversary of the Belt and Road Initiative at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, October 18, 2023. REUTERS/Edgar Su/File Photo/File Photo翻译:2023 年 10 月 18 日，中国国家主席习近平在北京人民大会堂举行的纪念“一带一路”倡议十周年“一带一路”高峰论坛开幕式上发表讲话。 REUTERS/Edgar Su/File照片/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's President Xi Jinping met Cuban Prime Minister Manuel Marrero at Beijing's Great Hall of the People on Monday, Chinese state media reported, a day after the Cuban leader signed cooperation documents with Xi's deputy at a trade fair.翻译:据中国官方媒体报道，中国国家主席习近平周一在北京人民大会堂会见了古巴总理曼努埃尔·马雷罗，此前一天，古巴领导人在一次贸易展览会上与习近平副手签署了合作文件。</p>   <p>Marrero's visit comes as Cuba's economy, which is heavily dependent on food, fuel and other imports, is close to collapse amid a more than 50% decline in its export earnings, which are needed to purchase imports. The Cuban government blames U.S. sanctions and COVID for the economic downturn.翻译:马雷罗此行之际，古巴经济严重依赖食品、燃料和其他进口，由于出口收入下降了 50% 以上，而古巴经济接近崩溃，而出口收入则用于购买进口产品。古巴政府将经济低迷归咎于美国的制裁和新冠疫情。</p>   <p>"China will continue to firmly support the Cuban people, oppose foreign interference and the embargo, and safeguard (Cuba's) national sovereignty and dignity," Xi said, according to state media.翻译:据官方媒体报道，习近平表示：“中方将继续坚定支持古巴人民，反对外国干涉和封锁，维护（古巴）国家主权和尊严。”</p>   <p>Marrero was among foreign dignitaries attending the opening ceremony of the International Import Expo (CIIE) on Sunday in Shanghai, a week-long trade fair where countries and companies often strike deals resulting in the world's second-largest economy buying more of their wares.翻译:马雷罗是周日在上海出席国际进口博览会（CIIE）开幕式的外国政要之一，这是一个为期一周的贸易博览会，各国和企业经常在会上达成交易，导致世界第二大经济体购买更多他们的商品。</p>   <p>Following a meeting between Marrero and China's Premier Li Qiang on the sidelines of the CIIE, Chinese and Cuban officials signed several unspecified cooperation documents, according to a state media report.翻译:据官方媒体报道，马雷罗与中国总理李强在进博会期间会晤后，中国和古巴官员签署了几份未具体说明的合作文件。</p>   <p>"It is hoped that Cuba will continue to make good use of the important platform of the CIIE to bring more of its products to the China market," Xi told Marrero on Monday.翻译:习近平周一对马雷罗表示：“希望古巴继续利用好进博会这一重要平台，将更多古巴产品推向中国市场。”</p>   <p>Cuban officials often laud relations with China as "outstanding" or "historic", and President Miguel Diaz-Canel told China's Xi on the sidelines of a BRICS Summit in Johannesburg翻译:金砖国家领导人约翰内斯堡峰会 in August that ties were at an "all-time high".翻译:古巴官员经常称赞与中国的关系“杰出”或“历史性”，古巴总统米格尔·迪亚斯-卡内尔在八月份约翰内斯堡举行的金砖国家峰会期间对中国习近平表示，两国关系处于“历史最高水平”。</p>   <p>But analysts doubt China can take its relationship with the diplomatically isolated island much further or do anything significant to support it, not least because Cuba lacks the means to pay back any loans China might be willing to extend.翻译:但分析人士怀疑，中国能否进一步深化与这个在外交上孤立的岛屿的关系，或采取任何重大措施来支持它，尤其是因为古巴缺乏偿还中国可能愿意提供的任何贷款的手段。</p>   <p>Still, supporting Cuba could reap significant strategic and diplomatic dividends for China.翻译:尽管如此，支持古巴仍能为中国带来重大的战略和外交红利。</p>   <p>In June, a report claimed China had reached a deal with Cuba to establish an electronic <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-post-spy-facility-cuba-off-southeastern-us-wsj-2023-06-08/">eavesdropping</a> facility on the island, about 100 miles from the U.S. state of Florida. China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-says-allegations-chinese-spying-cuba-are-false-2023-06-12/">denied the report</a> as being false.翻译:6月，一份报告称中国已与古巴达成协议，将在距离美国佛罗里达州约100英里的岛上建立一个电子<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-post-spy-facility-cuba-off-southeastern-us-wsj-2023-06-08/">窃听</a>设施。中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-says-allegations-chinese-spying-cuba-are-false-2023-06-12/">否认该报道</a>不实。</p>    <span>Reporting by Joe Cash; Editing by Robert Birsel and Bernadette Baum翻译:乔·卡什报道；罗伯特·伯塞尔和伯纳黛特·鲍姆编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 11:41:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">VFF6JVOJZBMJFMTVQER5KNXD6Y</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-president-xi-meets-cuban-prime-minister-beijing-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>CUBA/MARRERO (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[欧洲央行调查显示跨国公司计划采取行动尽量减少中国风险]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/H2-gzmZaKH7GRWHL1s6GRqqNXUw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YDDUR5CTYBNORGP6YJ4OXRWI6U.jpg" alt="European Central Bank (ECB) headquarters in Frankfurt翻译:欧洲中央银行 (ECB) 总部位于法兰克福" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view shows the logo of the European Central Bank (ECB) outside its headquarters in Frankfurt, Germany March 16, 2023. REUTERS/Heiko Becker/File Photo翻译:2023 年 3 月 16 日，欧洲中央银行 (ECB) 位于德国法兰克福总部外的标志。REUTERS/Heiko Becker/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>More than 40% of multinational firms surveyed by the European Central Bank expect to move production to politically friendlier countries in the coming years, with risk related to China cited as the main concern, a paper showed on Monday.翻译:周一的一份文件显示，接受欧洲央行调查的跨国公司中，超过 40% 预计未来几年将生产转移到政治上更加友好的国家，其中与中国相关的风险是主要担忧。</p>   <p>Firms have increasingly discussed shifting production sites after the pandemic and Russia's war in Ukraine disrupted value chains, but there has been little empirical evidence of mass relocations.翻译:在大流行和俄罗斯乌克兰战争扰乱价值链之后，企业越来越多地讨论转移生产地点，但几乎没有大规模搬迁的经验证据。</p>   <p>Seeking on-the-ground confirmation, the ECB surveyed 65 very large firms with a global footprint and 49% said they were looking to "near-shore", or bring production closer to the point of sales.翻译:为了寻求实地确认，欧洲央行对 65 家业务遍及全球的大型企业进行了调查，其中 49% 的企业表示，他们正在寻求“近岸”生产，或者使生产更接近销售点。</p>   <p>In total, 42% wanted to "friend-shore" some operations, or move them to more welcoming locations.翻译:总共有 42% 的受访者希望“友好支持”一些业务，或者将其转移到更受欢迎的地点。</p>   <p>"As to those countries which posed – or could pose – a risk to supply chains in their sector more generally, two-thirds of all respondents cited China," the ECB said in an Economic Bulletin article.翻译:欧洲央行在《经济公报》的一篇文章中表示：“对于那些对其行业供应链构成或可能构成风险的国家，三分之二的受访者提到了中国。”</p>   <p>More than half of the firms sourced critical materials from a specific country or small number of countries, and nearly all said that these supplies now faced elevated risk.翻译:超过一半的公司从特定国家或少数国家采购关键材料，几乎所有公司都表示这些供应现在面临更高的风险。</p>   <p>"A large majority of these identified China as that country, or one of those countries, with all of them considering this an elevated risk," the ECB added.翻译:欧洲央行补充说：“其中绝大多数将中国视为该国家或其中之一，他们都认为这是一个较高的风险。”</p>   <p>Near-shoring was already a tendency in recent years but friend-shoring is a new phenomenon as only 11% said they were already pursuing such a strategy in the past five years.翻译:近几年来，近岸外包已成为一种趋势，但友岸外包是一种新现象，只有 11% 的受访者表示，他们在过去五年中已经采取了这种策略。</p>   <p>The European Union is still likely to be a loser in such corporate movements as the number or firms looking to move production out of the bloc remains larger than the number moving it in, and this could have a "significant" impact on employment.翻译:欧盟仍然可能成为此类企业迁移的输家，因为希望将生产转移出欧盟的企业数量仍然多于将其转移到欧盟的企业数量，这可能对就业产生“重大”影响。</p>   <p>The moves could also fuel inflation as close to half of firms said they expected the changes to result in higher prices, the paper added.翻译:该报补充说，这些举措还可能加剧通胀，因为近一半的公司表示，他们预计这些变化将导致价格上涨。</p>    <span>Reporting by Balazs Koranyi; Editing by Andrew Heavens翻译:巴拉兹·科兰尼 (Balazs Koranyi) 报道；安德鲁·天堂编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 11:25:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ES5SZT3TDNIHPPCDHZEHS2YZ3E</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/multinationals-plan-moves-minimise-china-risk-ecb-survey-shows-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ECB</category>
                
                <category>SURVEY/CHINA</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[菲律宾旨在与日本签署“互惠”驻军协议]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Philippines, Japan agree to start talks on military deal</li>  <li>US helping to Philippine "defensive posture" in S. China Sea</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>菲律宾和日本同意启动军事协议谈判</li><li>美国帮助菲律宾在南海采取“防御姿态”</li></ul>     <p>The Philippines hopes to reach an agreement with Japan "at the soonest possible time" on allowing the deployment of military forces on each other's soil, the Philippine defense secretary said on Monday.翻译:菲律宾国防部长周一表示，菲律宾希望“尽快”与日本就允许在对方领土上部署军事力量达成协议。</p>   <p>The two close U.S. allies have agreed to negotiate a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japan-pm-kishida-arrives-philippines-official-visit-2023-11-03/">reciprocal access agreement</a> (RAA) amid growing tensions in the region. Both countries have maritime territorial disputes with an increasingly assertive China.翻译:在该地区紧张局势日益加剧之际，这两个美国亲密盟友已同意就<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japan-pm-kishida-arrives-philippines-official-visit-2023-11-03/">互惠准入协议</a>（RAA）进行谈判。两国都与日益强势的中国存在海洋领土争端。</p>   <p>"We look forward to this reciprocal access agreement between both our countries given the commitment of the Japanese government and the Philippine government to preserve the rules-based international order and international law," Defense Secretary Gilberto Teodoro told a press briefing.翻译:国防部长吉尔伯托·特奥多罗在新闻发布会上表示：“鉴于日本政府和菲律宾政府承诺维护基于规则的国际秩序和国际法，我们期待两国之间达成互惠准入协议。”</p>   <p>Once an agreement is reached, it would have to be submitted to the Philippine Senate and Japanese legislature for ratification, Teodoro said.翻译:特奥多罗表示，一旦达成协议，必须提交菲律宾参议院和日本立法机构批准。</p>   <p>Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida, on a visit to the Philippines on the weekend, said his country, the Philippines and the United States were cooperating to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/japan-pm-kishida-cooperating-with-philippines-us-protect-south-china-sea-2023-11-04/">"to protect the freedom"</a> of the South China Sea.翻译:日本首相岸田文雄周末访问菲律宾时表示，日本、菲律宾和美国正在合作<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/japan-pm-kishida-cooperating-with-philippines-us-protect-south-china-sea-2023-11-04/">“保护南海的自由”</a> 。</p>   <p>Teodoro was speaking on the sidelines of a ceremony at a military base, north of the capital, which is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/philippines-grants-us-greater-access-bases-amid-china-concerns-2023-02-02/">one of nine bases</a> the United States has been given access to under the Enhanced Defense Cooperation Agreement (EDCA).翻译:特奥多罗是在首都北部一个军事基地举行的仪式间隙发表上述讲话的，该基地是美国根据《增强防务合作协议》（EDCA）获得使用权<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/philippines-grants-us-greater-access-bases-amid-china-concerns-2023-02-02/">的九个基地之一</a>。</p>   <p>The United States has said it would allocate $100 million for infrastructure improves at the sites.翻译:美国表示将拨款 1 亿美元用于改善这些地点的基础设施。</p>   <p>"The United States is helping the Philippine government in hardening its defensive posture to include its assertion of its legitimate rights in the West Philippine Sea," Teodoro said, referring to an area where <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/us-airs-concerns-china-about-dangerous-unlawful-south-china-sea-actions-2023-11-03/">tension has been rising</a> between the Philippines and China over an over-lapping territorial claim.翻译:特奥多罗表示：“美国正在帮助菲律宾政府强化防御姿态，包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/us-airs-concerns-china-about-dangerous-unlawful-south-china-sea-actions-2023-11-03/">维护</a>其在西菲律宾海的合法权利。”领土主张。</p>   <p>The Philippines was "not seeking conflict", Teodoro said.翻译:特奥多罗表示，菲律宾“并不寻求冲突”。</p>    <span>Reporting by Mikhail Flores and Karen Lema; Editing by Kanupriya Kapoor翻译:米哈伊尔·弗洛雷斯 (Mikhail Flores) 和凯伦·莱玛 (Karen Lema) 报道；卡努普里亚·卡普尔 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 10:56:24 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">R37A3D63JNJ7LJNMGIITSMJQQE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-hopes-seal-troops-pact-with-japan-soon-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>PHILIPPINES</category>
                
                <category>DEFENCE/ (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[何立峰出任中央金融委员会重要职务]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ujSDkUXlKwmftVaZ8I9Sqe2Sy6Y=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/V6NMNCXEWVK5LCVY7AIVIICF3I.jpg" alt="Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng in Beijing翻译:中国国务院副总理何立峰在北京" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng attends a joint press conference following the 10th China-EU High-Level Economic and Trade Dialogue at the Diaoyutai State Guesthouse in Beijing, China September 25, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo翻译:2023年9月25日，中国国务院副总理何立峰在中国北京钓鱼台国宾馆出席第十次中欧经贸高层对话后举行的联合新闻发布会。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A Chinese vice premier, He Lifeng, has been appointed head of the office of the Central Financial Commission (CFC), which is responsible for running day-to-day affairs of a new regulator tasked with overseeing a vast financial sector.翻译:中国副总理何立峰被任命为中央金融委员会（CFC）办公室主任，负责管理新监管机构的日常事务，该监管机构的任务是监管庞大的金融部门。</p>   <p>He was also appointed as party chief of a separate Central Financial Work Commission (CFWC), which has been set up to strengthen the ideological and political role of the party in China's overall financial system.翻译:他还被任命为中央金融工作委员会（CFWC）党组书记，该委员会的成立是为了加强党在中国整个金融体系中的思想和政治作用。</p>   <p>The appointments, announced by the central bank's Financial News publication, underscore how the ruling Communist Party has taken direct control of supervising the financial sector.翻译:央行的《金融新闻》刊物宣布的这些任命突显了执政的共产党如何直接控制金融业的监管。</p>   <p>The appointments mean He will tackle local government debt and the downturn in the property sector, two crises that threaten financial stability and the long-term growth potential of the world's second-largest economy.翻译:这些任命意味着贺建奎将解决地方政府债务和房地产行业低迷的问题，这两场危机威胁着世界第二大经济体的金融稳定和长期增长潜力。</p>   <p>China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-set-up-new-financial-regulator-major-supervisory-overhaul-2023-03-07/">announced</a> in March it would set up the CFC under a broad restructuring of both party and government entities to tighten the party's supervision of the industry.翻译:中国三月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-set-up-new-financial-regulator-major-supervisory-overhaul-2023-03-07/">宣布，</a>将在党政机构的广泛重组下成立CFC，以加强党对行业的监管。</p>   <p>The head of the CFC has yet to be named.翻译:CFC 主席尚未被任命。</p>   <p>He, regarded as a confidant of President Xi Jinping, has been playing a prominent role in handling financial, economic and trade issues since being named a vice premier in a cabinet reshuffle in March.翻译:他被视为习近平主席的心腹，自3月份内阁改组中被任命为副总理以来，在处理金融、经济和贸易问题上一直发挥着重要作用。</p>   <p>He has also been appointed director of a key ruling Communist Party <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/he-lifeng-chinas-economy-tsar-made-director-key-party-commission-2023-10-30/">economic body</a>, the Central Finance and Economic Affairs Commission, replacing Liu He.翻译:他还被任命为中共主要执政<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/he-lifeng-chinas-economy-tsar-made-director-key-party-commission-2023-10-30/">经济机构</a>中央财经委员会主任，接替刘鹤。</p>   <p>Last week, state media reported that the Communist Party would <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-step-up-financial-supervision-cut-risks-2023-10-31/">step up</a> its leadership of the finance industry and strengthen efforts to reduce local government debt risks, citing a twice-a-decade financial policy meeting that was held on Oct. 30-31.翻译:上周，官方媒体援引10月30日至31日召开的十年两次金融政策会议报道称，中国共产党将<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-step-up-financial-supervision-cut-risks-2023-10-31/">加强</a>对金融业的领导，并加大力度降低地方政府债务风险。</p>   <p>The CFWC would "comprehensively strengthen the party's leadership over financial work" and strive to "promote strong financial supervision", according to a summary of a CFWC meeting last week.翻译:根据上周的 CFWC 会议纪要，CFWC 将“全面加强党对金融工作的领导”，努力“推动强有力的金融监管”。</p>   <p>An economist who studied finance at Xiamen University from 1978 to 1984, He obtained a doctorate in economics in 1998, when he was the party chief of Quanzhou city in Fujian province. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-new-economic-tsar-faces-challenges-emulating-his-predecessor-2023-11-01/"> read more </a>翻译:经济学家，1978年至1984年就读于厦门大学金融系，1998年获经济学博士学位，时任福建省泉州市委书记。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-new-economic-tsar-faces-challenges-emulating-his-predecessor-2023-11-01/">阅读更多</a></p>   <p>He's relationship with Xi dates back four decades. He first worked under Xi in the coastal city of Xiamen and later in the northern municipality of Tianjin.翻译:他与习近平的关系可以追溯到四十年前。他首先在沿海城市厦门在习近平手下工作，后来又到北方直辖市天津工作。</p>   <p>In 2014, He was named vice chairman of the National Development and Reform Commission, the state planning agency, before taking full control in 2017. Since then, He has joined Xi on domestic tours, in diplomatic meetings and at other engagements.翻译:2014年，贺建奎被任命为国家发展和改革委员会副主任，并于2017年全面掌管国家发展和改革委员会。此后，贺建奎与习近平一起进行国内访问、外交会议和其他活动。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ziyi Tang, Kevin Yao and Ryan Woo; Editing by Edwina Gibbs, Robert Birsel翻译:唐子仪、姚凯文和吴瑞安报道；编辑：埃德温娜·吉布斯、罗伯特·伯塞尔</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 10:21:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RJDFNKNE6VKYNAENGVBDSKDVEQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-appoints-he-lifeng-head-office-central-financial-commission-cbank-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>FINANCE/ (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[迪诺拉苏州工厂产量增至三倍，以满足快速增长的亚洲市场]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Italy's Industrie De Nora <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DNR.MI" target="_blank">(DNR.MI)</a> said its plant in Souzhou, in China, would triple its production capacity, in line with the electrode maker's plans to increase manufacturing in the fast-growing Asian market.翻译:意大利迪诺拉工业公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DNR.MI" target="_blank">(DNR.MI)</a>表示，其位于中国苏州的工厂的产能将增加两倍，以符合该电极制造商在快速增长的亚洲市场增加产量的计划。</p>   <p>The project is part of De Nora's plan to expand in Asia, where the group is facing increasing demand, and be able to face request for technologies used to produce green hydrogen, the group said in a statement on Monday.翻译:该集团在周一的一份声明中表示，该项目是迪诺拉在亚洲扩张计划的一部分，该集团在亚洲面临不断增长的需求，并能够满足对用于生产绿色氢的技术的要求。</p>   <p>The Souzhou site, 70 km (43.5 miles) from Shanghai, was opened in 2005 and is De Nora's main site in China, serving Asian and Chinese clients as well as high-tech business partners.翻译:苏州工厂距离上海 70 公里（43.5 英里），于 2005 年开业，是迪诺拉在中国的主要工厂，为亚洲和中国客户以及高科技业务合作伙伴提供服务。</p>   <p>In particular, De Nora aims to strengthen its positioning in the maintenance services of chlor-alkali plants in China, which represent 45% of the global market, in the high-growth sector of electrodes for the production of the copper foil, used both in the manufacture of lithium batteries for electric cars and as a raw material for printed circuit boards.翻译:特别是，迪诺拉旨在加强其在中国氯碱工厂维护服务中的地位，该工厂占全球市场的 45%，在铜箔生产电极的高增长领域，铜箔用于生产铜箔。电动汽车锂电池的制造以及印刷电路板的原材料。</p>    <span>Reporting by Giulia Segreti, Editing by Louise Heavens翻译:Giulia Segreti 报道，Louise Heavens 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 10:20:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZILKNNFE65KHLP52QSLXQTIUUQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/de-noras-souzhou-plant-production-triple-fast-growing-asian-market-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>INDUSTRIE DENORA</category>
                
                <category>PRODUCTION/CHINA</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[蒙古中部暴风雪致8人死亡1人失踪-新华网]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Blizzards sweeping through central Mongolia since last Friday have killed eight and left one missing, China's official Xinhua news agency reported on Monday, citing Mongolian emergency management authorities.翻译:中国官方新华社周一援引蒙古应急管理部门的话说，自上周五以来席卷蒙古中部的暴风雪已造成八人死亡，一人失踪。</p>   <p>Rescuers have been searching for 46 people after blizzards hit multiple Mongolian provinces, Xinhua said, adding 37 of those missing have been found.翻译:新华社称，暴风雪袭击蒙古多个省份后，救援人员一直在寻找46人，其中37人已找到。</p>   <p>The hardest-hit areas in central Mongolia were blanketed by snow up to 34 cm (13.4 inches) thick, Xinhua said, citing Mongolia's National Agency for Meteorology and Environmental Monitoring.翻译:新华社援引蒙古国家气象和环境监测局的消息称，蒙古中部受灾最严重的地区被厚达34厘米（13.4英寸）的积雪覆盖。</p>   <p>Blizzards are expected to continue in the coming week in most parts of Mongolia, including the capital Ulaanbaatar, the news agency said, as local herdsmen, construction workers and drivers were urged to take extra precautions against possible disasters.翻译:该通讯社称，预计暴风雪将在未来一周继续出现在包括首都乌兰巴托在内的蒙古大部分地区，当地牧民、建筑工人和司机被敦促采取额外的预防措施，以防可能发生的灾害。</p>    <span>Reporting by Beijing Newsroom; Editing by Christian Schmollinger翻译:北京新闻编辑室报道；克里斯蒂安·施莫林格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 09:56:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">J5GCXA5JRNOMVOHFPC6BWZ4C2M</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/blizzards-kill-8-leave-1-missing-central-mongolia-xinhua-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ASIA</category>
                
                <category>WEATHER/MONGOLIA</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国表示将努力恢复巴勒斯坦领土的和平]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/kxAnhmGrixlweKkU1vxpVpYPpVU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5JN6OPXNTFJBHGZ7DWXMEN4ZMU.jpg" alt="A view of military action at a location given as Gaza, amid the conflict between Israel and the Palestinian Islamist group Hamas翻译:在以色列和巴勒斯坦伊斯兰组织哈马斯之间的冲突中，对加沙地带采取军事行动的看法" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view of military action at a location given as Gaza, amid the conflict between Israel and the Palestinian Islamist group Hamas翻译:在以色列和巴勒斯坦伊斯兰组织哈马斯之间的冲突中，对加沙地带采取军事行动的看法, in this screengrab obtained from a handout video released on November 6, 2023. Israel Defense Forces/Handout via REUTERS    </figcaption></figure>       <p>China will do its utmost to restore peace in the Palestinian territories as it takes over the presidency of the U.N. Security Council (UNSC), its foreign ministry said on Monday, as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/pressure-israel-over-civilians-steps-up-ceasefire-calls-rebuffed-2023-11-06/">tensions intensify</a> in the Middle East.翻译:中国外交部周一表示，随着中东<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/pressure-israel-over-civilians-steps-up-ceasefire-calls-rebuffed-2023-11-06/">紧张局势加剧</a>，中国将在接任联合国安理会主席国期间尽最大努力恢复巴勒斯坦领土的和平。</p>   <p>"China will do its utmost to encourage the Security Council to fulfil its responsibilities, play its role, build consensus and take responsible and meaningful actions as soon as possible to ease the current crisis and safeguard the safety of civilians in order to restore peace," ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin told a regular news conference.翻译:中方将全力推动安理会履行职责，发挥作用，凝聚共识，尽快采取负责任、有意义的行动，缓解当前危机，维护平民安全，恢复和平。外交部发言人汪文斌在例行新闻发布会上表示。</p>   <p>China's statement comes as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israels-netanyahu-says-no-gaza-ceasefire-until-hostages-returned-2023-11-05/">Israel</a> ratchets up its military offensive against the Palestinian Islamist group Hamas.翻译:中国发表声明之际， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israels-netanyahu-says-no-gaza-ceasefire-until-hostages-returned-2023-11-05/">以色列</a>加大了对巴勒斯坦伊斯兰组织哈马斯的军事攻势。</p>   <p>China took over the rotating presidency of the UNSC last week.翻译:中国上周接任联合国安理会轮值主席。</p>   <p>The conflict in the Middle East tops the Security Council's agenda in November, said Zhang Jun, China's permanent representative to the UN, according to state media.翻译:据官方媒体报道，中国常驻联合国代表张军表示，中东冲突是 11 月份安理会议程的首要议题。</p>   <p>"It is imperative to promote a cease-fire and halt the fighting, prevent further civilian casualties, prevent a larger-scale humanitarian disaster and prevent the conflict from spilling over," Zhang was quoted as saying, the China Daily reported.翻译:据《中国日报》报道，张军说：“当务之急是推动停火止战，防止更多平民伤亡，防止发生更大规模的人道主义灾难，防止冲突蔓延。”</p>   <p>China's special envoy to the Middle East, Zhai Jun, has just wrapped a tour of the region.翻译:中国中东问题特使翟隽刚刚结束对该地区的访问。</p>   <p>Zhai, who met leaders of several countries over the crisis, pinned the cause of the Israel-Gaza crisis on the lack of guarantees for Palestinian rights.翻译:翟在此次危机中会见了多国领导人，他将以色列和加沙危机的原因归咎于巴勒斯坦权利缺乏保障。</p>   <p>The presidency of the UNSC rotates among the 15 member states of the council monthly. China last held it in August 2022.翻译:联合国安理会主席每月由安理会 15 个成员国轮流担任。中国上次举办是在2022年8月。</p>    <span>Reporting by Beijing newsroom; Writing by Bernard Orr; Editing by Christian Schmollinger翻译:北京新闻编辑室报道；伯纳德·奥尔撰写；克里斯蒂安·施莫林格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 08:22:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">K37RSVM5CBMHDJ5HWYBKRCLAFY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/china-says-will-work-restore-peace-palestinian-territories-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ISRAEL</category>
                
                <category>PALESTINIAN/CHINA (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[亚洲足球周]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Talking points from the week in Asian football:</p>    <h 1="">LATE GOALS SEE POHANG STEELERS CLAIM KOREAN FA CUP TITLE</h>  <p>Pohang Steelers twice came from behind to hand Jeonbuk Motors a 4-2 defeat and lift the Korean FA Cup on Saturday.翻译:周六，浦项制铁队两次后来居上，以4-2击败全北汽车队，捧起韩国足协杯冠军。</p>   <p>Song Min-kyu struck from close range to give Jeonbuk a 16th minute lead but Han Chen-hee levelled for Kim Gi-dong's side a minute before the interval.翻译:第16分钟，宋旻奎近距离射门，为全北队取得领先，但韩振熙在中场休息前一分钟为金基东队扳平比分。</p>   <p>Gustavo's penalty five minutes after the restart put Jeonbuk back in front but goals from Zeca, Kim Jong-woo and Hong Yun-sang in the final 16 minutes earned Pohang their fifth FA Cup triumph and a place in next year's Asian Champions League.</p>    <h 1="">AVISPA FUKUOKA DOWN URAWA RED DIAMONDS TO WIN J.LEAGUE CUP</h>  <p>Avispa Fukuoka claimed the first trophy in their history on Saturday with a 2-1 win over Urawa Red Diamonds to lift the J.League Cup at National Stadium in Tokyo.翻译:周六，福冈黄蜂队在东京国家体育场以 2-1 战胜浦和红钻队，捧起 J 联赛杯，夺得队史首座奖杯。</p>   <p>A crowd of 61,683 turned out to see Avispa take a fifth-minute lead as Hiroyuki Mae scored from close range following Kazuya Konno's low centre from the right.翻译:全场 61,683 名观众观看了 Avispa 在第 5 分钟取得领先，Hiroyuki Mae 在 Kazuya Konno 右路低射后近距离射门得分。</p>   <p>Daiki Miya doubled his side's advantage four minutes into first-half injury time and, though Takahiro Akimoto scored with 23 minutes remainIng when he controlled Hiroki Sakai's cross-field ball on his chest, Fukuoka held on.</p>    <h 1="">ADELAIDE UNITED PEG BACK VICTORY TO KEEP A-LEAGUE'S TOP SPOT</h>  <p>Melbourne Victory and Adelaide United remain level at the top of the A-League standings after the pair shared a 1-1 draw on Saturday in a game that saw each team finish with 10 players.翻译:墨尔本胜利队和阿德莱德联队在周六的比赛中以 1-1 战平，双方均以 10 名球员结束比赛，两队在 A 联赛积分榜上保持并列榜首。</p>   <p>Both clubs have seven points, with Adelaide at the top of the table after three rounds thanks to a better goal difference. Wellington Phoenix and Macarthur FC also have seven points.翻译:两家具乐部均积7分，阿德莱德队三轮过后凭借净胜球优势暂居积分榜榜首。惠灵顿凤凰队和麦克阿瑟足球俱乐部也积7分。</p>   <p>Bruno Fornaroli put Victory in front after 28 minutes but Hiroshi Ibusuki levelled 14 minutes into the second half. Both sides were then handed red cards, with Victory's Roderick Miranda and Adelaide's Nestory Irankunda sent off.</p>    <h 1="">MITROVIC STRIKES AGAIN AS AL-HILAL STAY UNBEATEN IN SAUDI</h>  <p>Al-Hilal maintained their unbeaten start to the Saudi Pro League season with a 2-0 win over Al Fateh on Friday that keeps Jorge Jesus' side four points clear of Riyadh rivals Al-Nassr.翻译:周五，阿尔希拉尔队以 2-0 战胜阿尔法塔赫，保持了沙特职业联赛赛季不败的开局，豪尔赫热苏斯的球队领先利雅得对手阿尔纳斯尔队 4 分。</p>   <p>Aleksandar Mitrovic scored his ninth goal of the campaign from the penalty spot in the fifth minute and Salem Al Dawsari secured the points in the third minute of injury time as Al-Hilal won for the 10th time in 12 games.翻译:亚历山大·米特罗维奇在第 5 分钟通过点球打进了本赛季的第 9 个进球，塞勒姆·阿尔·道萨里在伤停补时第 3 分钟进球，帮助阿尔希拉尔在 12 场比赛中第 10 次获胜。</p>   <p>Cristiano Ronaldo remains the league's top scorer after hitting his 12th of the season to put Al-Nassr ahead in their 2-0 win over Al-Khaleej, with former Manchester City defender Aymeric Laporte also on target as his side remained in second.</p>    <h 1="">AL DAWSARI, KERR CLAIM AFC PLAYER OF THE YEAR AWARDS</h>  <p>Saudi Arabia's Salem Al-Dawsari has been named the Asian Football Confederation's Player of the Year with Chelsea and Australia forward Sam Kerr taking the women's title at the regional body's awards ceremony in Doha on Tuesday.翻译:沙特阿拉伯的塞勒姆·道萨里被评为亚洲足球联合会年度最佳球员，切尔西和澳大利亚前锋萨姆·科尔周二在多哈举行的亚洲足球联合会颁奖典礼上荣获女子冠军。</p>   <p>Hajime Moriyasu was named men's coach of the year after taking Japan to the last 16 of the World Cup in Qatar last year, while Shui Qingxia was presented with the women's award having guided China to the Women's Asian Cup in India.翻译:去年带领日本队进入卡塔尔世界杯16强的守康肇被评为年度最佳男教练，而水青霞则带领中国队在印度女足亚洲杯上获得了年度最佳教练奖。</p>   <p>The awards were being held for the first time in four years following disruption caused to the game across the continent by the COVID-19 pandemic.翻译:在新冠肺炎 (COVID-19) 大流行对整个非洲大陆的比赛造成干扰后，该奖项是四年来首次举办。</p>    <span>Reporting by Michael Church; Editing by Christopher Cushing翻译:迈克尔·丘奇报道；克里斯托弗·库欣编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 06:40:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5LCXISU3JBIXFGEZ4IXUF3WY7Q</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sports/soccer/week-asian-football-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Michael Church]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SOCCER</category>
                
                <category>ASIA/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[菲律宾称日本、韩国和印度愿意为铁路项目提供资金]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Japan, South Korea and India have offered to finance three Philippine railway projects worth nearly $5 billion, the country's transport chief said on Monday, after Manila dropped China as a funding source last year.翻译:菲律宾交通运输部长周一表示，在马尼拉去年放弃中国作为资金来源后，日本、韩国和印度已提出为菲律宾三个价值近 50 亿美元的铁路项目提供融资。</p>   <p>Transportation Secretary Jaime Bautista said the Philippine government could tap the three countries for possible official development assistance (ODA). He said the government may also fund a portion of the rail projects or seek private sector investments.翻译:交通部长海梅·包蒂斯塔表示，菲律宾政府可以向这三个国家寻求官方发展援助（ODA）。他表示，政府还可能为部分铁路项目提供资金或寻求私营部门投资。</p>   <p>"We're exploring these. We cannot give any details yet," Bautista told a media forum.翻译:“我们正在探索这些。我们还不能提供任何细节，”包蒂斯塔在媒体论坛上说。</p>   <p>The rail projects are the Subic-Clark Railway Project, the Philippine National Railways South Long-Haul Project and the Davao-Digos segment of the Mindanao Railway Project, collectively worth $4.95 billion.翻译:这些铁路项目包括苏比克-克拉克铁路项目、菲律宾国家铁路南长途项目和棉兰老岛铁路项目达沃-迪戈斯段，总价值49.5亿美元。</p>   <p>President Ferdinand Marcos Jr had ordered officials last year to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-marcos-wants-renegotiate-loans-49-bln-china-backed-rail-projects-2022-07-16/">renegotiate</a> loan agreements with China, which were considered "withdrawn" after the Chinese government failed to act on the funding request.翻译:小费迪南德·马科斯总统去年曾命令官员与中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-marcos-wants-renegotiate-loans-49-bln-china-backed-rail-projects-2022-07-16/">重新谈判</a>贷款协议，由于中国政府未能对资金请求采取行动，这些协议被视为“撤回”。</p>   <p>But Bautista said the government had to look for other financing options since there was no progress on the loan negotiations with China on the rail projects, which began in 2018 during the term of former President Rodrigo Duterte.翻译:但包蒂斯塔表示，政府必须寻找其他融资选择，因为与中国就铁路项目进行的贷款谈判没有取得任何进展，该谈判于2018年前总统罗德里戈·杜特尔特(Rodrigo Duterte)任期内开始。</p>   <p>Duterte pursued warmer ties with Beijing and set aside territorial disputes in exchange for billions of dollars in aid when he was president. Marcos replaced him in June last year.翻译:杜特尔特在担任总统期间寻求与北京建立更温暖的关系，并搁置领土争端，以换取数十亿美元的援助。马科斯于去年六月接替了他。</p>   <p>From more than 1,100 km (680 miles) before World War II, the Philippines had only 77 km of operational railway as of 2016, well behind other urban centres across Asia, government data shows. Marcos has promised to modernise the country's railway system.翻译:政府数据显示，从二战前的 1,100 多公里（680 英里）到 2016 年，菲律宾的运营铁路里程仅为 77 公里，远远落后于亚洲其他城市中心。马科斯承诺实现该国铁路系统的现代化。</p>   <p>Construction of the Philippines' first subway train, funded by loans from Japan, is underway in the capital region.翻译:由日本贷款资助的菲律宾第一列地铁列车正在首都地区建设。</p>   <p>($1 = 55.8000 Philippine pesos)翻译:（1 美元 = 55.8000 菲律宾比索）</p>    <span>Reporting by Mikhail Flores and Karen Lema; Editing by Raju Gopalakrishnan翻译:米哈伊尔·弗洛雷斯 (Mikhail Flores) 和凯伦·莱玛 (Karen Lema) 报道；编辑：拉朱·戈帕拉克里希南</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 06:05:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">VVIG2L3AFZL5BGRLALS45R5J6Y</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-says-japan-skorea-india-offer-fund-railway-projects-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>PHILIPPINES</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/RAILWAYS</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早盘竞价：降息前景推动股市上涨]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/GpyTwhxMw2aY9lCG5oOg1Zdm7fc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/G7YLSNFQWFLYZCGWB44USEOXDU.jpg" alt="A currency dealer works at a dealing room of a bank in Seoul翻译:一名货币交易商在首尔一家银行的交易室工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A currency dealer works at a dealing room of a bank in Seoul翻译:一名货币交易商在首尔一家银行的交易室工作, South Korea, August 25, 2015.    REUTERS/Kim Hong-Ji/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>A look at the day ahead in European and global markets from Wayne Cole.翻译:韦恩·科尔 (Wayne Cole) 对欧洲和全球市场未来一天的展望。</p>   <p>It's been an upbeat start to the week in Asia as markets cast aside concerns about rate hikes, and go straight to pricing in early cuts. All the major equity indices are well into the green with South Korea <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.KS11" target="_blank">(.KS11)</a> surging 4%, helped by the re-imposition of a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/skorea-ban-all-stock-short-selling-through-june-2024-2023-11-05/">short-selling ban</a>.翻译:亚洲本周开局乐观，市场抛开了对加息的担忧，直接消化了提前降息的预期。所有主要股指均大幅上涨，其中韩国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.KS11" target="_blank">(.KS11)</a>在重新实施<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/skorea-ban-all-stock-short-selling-through-june-2024-2023-11-05/">卖空禁令</a>的帮助下飙升 4%。</p>   <p>U.S. equity futures and Treasuries have steadied after last week's big gains, with everyone waiting to see if yields can extend their bull rally or sellers re-emerge once more. The omens would seem to be positive given how benign the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/traders-see-fading-chances-of-fed-rate-hike-bet-earlier-rate-cut-2023-11-03/">payrolls</a> report was on almost every measure.翻译:美国股指期货和国债在上周大幅上涨后已趋于稳定，所有人都在观望收益率是否能够延续牛市涨势，或者卖家是否再次出现。考虑到<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/traders-see-fading-chances-of-fed-rate-hike-bet-earlier-rate-cut-2023-11-03/">非农就业</a>报告几乎在所有指标上都表现良好，这些预兆似乎是积极的。</p>   <p>Perhaps just as important was the strength of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/productivity-adds-anesthetic-powells-pain-free-disinflation-2023-11-03/">productivity</a> that suggests unemployment does not need to rise as much as in the past to keep inflation restrained. Analysts already note that unemployment has climbed to 3.9%, from a trough of 3.4%, and similar-sized increases in the past have sometimes preceded recessions.翻译:也许同样重要的是<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/productivity-adds-anesthetic-powells-pain-free-disinflation-2023-11-03/">生产力</a>的强劲，这表明失业率不需要像过去那样上升来抑制通胀。分析师已经指出，失业率已从 3.4% 的低谷攀升至 3.9%，过去类似规模的增长有时会先于经济衰退。</p>   <p>Markets are clearly more confident inflation will continue to slow and that means central banks will have to ease just to stop policy becoming more restrictive in real terms. Fed fund futures imply around an 85% chance the Federal Reserve is done, and an 80% chance it will start cutting in June.翻译:市场显然对通胀将继续放缓更有信心，这意味着央行将不得不放松货币政策，以阻止政策实际上变得更加严格。联邦基金期货暗示美联储完成降息的可能性约为 85%，而 6 月份开始降息的可能性为 80%。</p>   <p>Futures imply an 80% probability the ECB will begin easing as soon as April, and the first BoE rate cut is almost fully priced for August.翻译:期货暗示欧洲央行最早将于 4 月份开始宽松的可能性为 80%，而英国央行 8 月份的首次降息几乎已完全定价。</p>   <p>Going the other way is the Bank of Japan, albeit at a sedentary pace. BOJ chief <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/bojs-ueda-sees-progress-hitting-price-goal-not-enough-end-easy-policy-2023-11-06/">Ueda</a> on Monday indicated they were creeping closer to their inflation target, but it was still too soon to abandon super-easy policy altogether.翻译:走另一条路的是日本央行，尽管步伐缓慢。日本<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/bojs-ueda-sees-progress-hitting-price-goal-not-enough-end-easy-policy-2023-11-06/">央行</a>行长上田周一表示，他们正逐渐接近通胀目标，但现在完全放弃超级宽松政策还为时过早。</p>   <p>An outlier here is the Reserve Bank of Australia (RBA) which might well resume hiking on Tuesday after four months of steady policy outcomes. Analysts are almost <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/rba-deliver-25-bp-interest-rate-hike-nov-7-2023-11-03/">all-in</a> for a rise to 4.35%, but the market implies it could be a coin toss, setting the stage for some fireworks whatever happens.翻译:这里的一个例外是澳大利亚储备银行（RBA），在四个月稳定的政策结果之后，它很可能在周二恢复加息。分析师几乎<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/rba-deliver-25-bp-interest-rate-hike-nov-7-2023-11-03/">全押上</a>涨至 4.35%，但市场暗示这可能只是抛硬币，无论发生什么，都会为一些烟火奠定基础。</p>   <p>Note that at least nine Fed speakers are out this week to generate headlines, including two appearances by Chair Jerome Powell - the second of which on Thursday includes a Q&amp;A session. There are also plenty of ECB speakers on the card, including President Christine Lagarde on Friday.翻译:请注意，本周至少有九位美联储发言人将成为头条新闻，其中包括主席杰罗姆·鲍威尔的两次露面——周四的第二次露面包括问答环节。会议上还有很多欧洲央行发言人，包括周五的行长克里斯蒂娜·拉加德。</p>   <p>As for the dollar, the payrolls report has stirred talk that the days of U.S. economic exceptionalism are numbered and the currency could be entering a downtrend. Bears will note the Atlanta Fed's usually reliable GDPNow measure is signalling a sharp Q4 slowdown to just 1.2% annualised.翻译:至于美元，非农就业报告引发了人们的议论，认为美国经济例外论的日子已经屈指可数，美元可能进入下行趋势。看空者会注意到，亚特兰大联储通常可靠的 GDPNow 指标预示着第四季度经济增速将大幅放缓至年化增长率仅为 1.2%。</p>   <p>That is not to say Europe is faring any better, many analysts look for the EU to enter recession this quarter. But expectations were already so low that it's the dollar that has all the downside in the disappointment stakes.翻译:这并不是说欧洲的情况有所好转，许多分析师预计欧盟本季度将陷入衰退。但预期已经如此之低，以至于美元在令人失望的风险中承担了所有的下行风险。</p>   <p>Key developments that could influence markets on Monday:翻译:可能影响周一市场的主要事态发展：</p>   <p>- Data on German industrial orders, PMIs from across Europe翻译:- 德国工业订单数据、欧洲各地采购经理人指数 (PMI)</p>   <p>- Virtual Q&amp;A with Bank of England Chief Economist Huw Pill翻译:- 与英格兰银行首席经济学家 Huw Pill 的虚拟问答</p>   <p>- Federal Reserve Board Governor Lisa Cook speaks翻译:- 美联储理事丽莎·库克讲话</p>    <span>By Wayne Cole. Editing by Sam Holmes翻译:作者：韦恩·科尔。山姆·霍姆斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 05:34:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4DLNCS4AF5ISXLH75WJL3A55R4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/global-markets-view-europe-2023-11-06/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Wayne Cole]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>EUROPE</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
