<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 19:27:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[法国外交部：法国计划在2024年初与乌克兰达成安全协议]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/_JAqHenP5DWtHw_602efgpk0Grs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KXM4EPQAOVKGJJEVCE7A3SMTSE.jpg" alt="European Political Community Summit in Granada翻译:格拉纳达欧洲政治共同体峰会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelenskiy and French President Emmanuel Macron pose for a picture during a meeting on the sidelines of the European Political Community Summit in Granada翻译:格拉纳达欧洲政治共同体峰会, Spain October 5, 2023. Ukrainian Presidential Press Service/Handout via REUTERS /File Photo翻译:乌克兰总统弗拉基米尔·泽伦斯基和法国总统伊曼纽尔·马克龙于 2023 年 10 月 5 日在西班牙格拉纳达举行的欧洲政治共同体峰会期间举行会议期间合影留念。乌克兰总统新闻服务/路透社提供的讲义/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>France intends to complete a bilateral security guarantee accord with Ukraine by the start 2024, its foreign ministry spokesperson said on Wednesday.翻译:法国外交部发言人周三表示，法国打算在 2024 年初与乌克兰完成双边安全保障协议。</p>   <p>G7 countries in June unveiled an international framework for the long-term security of Ukraine to boost its finances and defences against Russia with a view to deterring Moscow from future aggression, officials said.翻译:官员们表示，七国集团国家六月公布了乌克兰长期安全国际框架，以加强其财政和针对俄罗斯的防御，以阻止莫斯科未来的侵略。</p>   <p>Unable to join NATO while the war with Russia continues - given that NATO's Article 5, stipulating that an attack on one member is an attack on all, could push it into war with Russia - Ukraine has lobbied for long-term security commitments from its main backers.翻译:由于无法在与俄罗斯的战争持续期间加入北约 - 鉴于北约第 5 条规定，对一个成员国的攻击就是对所有成员国的攻击，这可能会将其推向与俄罗斯的战争 - 乌克兰已游说其主要成员国做出长期安全承诺支持者。</p>   <p>Countries, including France, have been negotiating bilaterally since June, but there has been scant detail on what countries are willing to do and with the war entering its second year there are question marks about how committed Kyiv's allies may be.翻译:包括法国在内的各国自六月以来一直在进行双边谈判，但关于各国愿意做什么的细节很少，而且随着战争进入第二年，基辅盟友的承诺程度也存在疑问。</p>   <p>"On the security guarantees and the work we have been doing with our Ukrainians partners ... we are working towards a conclusion of this accord with the Ukrainian authorities by the end of the year, start of next year," Anne-Claire Legendre told reporters at a weekly news briefing.翻译:安妮-克莱尔·勒让德告诉记者：“关于安全保障以及我们与乌克兰合作伙伴所做的工作……我们正在努力在今年年底明年初之前与乌克兰当局达成这项协议。”记者在每周新闻发布会上。</p>   <p>A diplomatic source said early 2024 was more likely.翻译:一位外交消息人士称，2024 年初的可能性更大。</p>   <p>The accord would outline the framework for long-term humanitarian aid, support for reconstruction and military assistance, she said.翻译:她说，该协议将概述长期人道主义援助、重建支持和军事援助的框架。</p>   <p>A second diplomatic source said the accord would not provide detailed financial figures or commitments as such with the French government not wanting to have the text going to parliament for approval.翻译:另一位外交消息人士称，该协议不会提供详细的财务数据或承诺，因为法国政府不希望将文本提交议会批准。</p>   <p>"I think that the Ukrainians are in a logic where they want to see what the Americans offer them for benchmarking for others," the source said.翻译:消息人士称：“我认为乌克兰人的逻辑是，他们希望看到美国人向他们提供什么，以作为其他国家的基准。”</p>   <p>"Our proposal to them doesn't contain figures. It's more our objectives. We describe the type of action we are ready to take in terms of military support, economic support, etc."翻译:“我们向他们提出的建议不包含数字。更多的是我们的目标。我们描述了我们准备在军事支持、经济支持等方面采取的行动类型。”</p>    <span>Reporting by John Irish
Editing by Alexandra Hudson翻译:约翰·爱尔兰报道 亚历山德拉·哈德森编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 17:39:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">PVT33LZZLRO6JATDTODS3C5WQY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/france-aiming-complete-security-accord-with-ukraine-by-start-2024-foreign-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[John Irish]]></author>
            
                
                <category>UKRAINE</category>
                
                <category>FRANCE/ (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“我们哪儿也不去”：巴拿马渔船如何让第一量子屈服]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/4yP5MyQKti3lIg8a4_YxSYBeteM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WY7VPPCQEZKG3OL5KHFQDK77TU.jpg" alt="People react after Panama's top court ruled the mining contract with Canadian miner First Quantum to operate a copper mine in the country as unconstitutional, in Panama City翻译:巴拿马最高法院裁定与加拿大矿业公司 First Quantum 在该国巴拿马城经营铜矿的采矿合同违宪后，人们做出了反应" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People react after Panama's top court ruled unconstitutional a mining contract with Canadian miner First Quantum to operate a copper mine in the country, following weeks of protests against the deal, in Panama City, Panama, November 28, 2023. REUTERS/Aris Martinez翻译:2023 年 11 月 28 日，巴拿马巴拿马城，巴拿马最高法院裁定与加拿大矿业公司 First Quantum 签订的在该国经营铜矿的采矿合同违宪，此前针对该交易的抗议活动持续数周，人们做出了反应。 REUTERS/Aris Martinez</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lfGvkhSPPQUXJ4srAO4Gao4tzxI=/800x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/UFBZS7HRVVPWBCAV7COH4W2BTA.jpg" alt="View of the Cobre Panama mine, of Canadian First Quantum Minerals, in Donoso, Panama, December 6, 2022. REUTERS/Aris Martínez翻译:2022 年 12 月 6 日，加拿大第一量子矿物公司位于巴拿马多诺索的 Cobre巴拿马矿场景观。REUTERS/Aris Martínez" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>View of the Cobre Panama mine, of Canadian First Quantum Minerals, in Donoso, Panama, December 6, 2022. REUTERS/Aris Martínez翻译:2022 年 12 月 6 日，加拿大第一量子矿物公司位于巴拿马多诺索的 Cobre巴拿马矿场景观。REUTERS/Aris Martínez</figcaption></figure>               <p>For more than a month, a group of 16 fishing boats has been blocking a key port in Panama, choking off coal and essential supplies destined for <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/what-happens-next-after-panamas-top-court-strikes-down-first-quantum-contract-2023-11-28/">First Quantum Minerals</a>' <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FM.TO" target="_blank">(FM.TO)</a> giant copper mine there, eventually forcing it to halt operations at the company's biggest revenue source.翻译:一个多月以来，由 16 艘渔船组成的一群渔船一直封锁巴拿马的一个重要港口，切断运往<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/what-happens-next-after-panamas-top-court-strikes-down-first-quantum-contract-2023-11-28/">第一量子矿业</a><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FM.TO" target="_blank">(FM.TO)</a>巨型铜矿的煤炭和必需品供应，最终迫使该公司停止在巴拿马的运营。公司最大的收入来源。</p>   <p>The fishing flotilla has provided a fresh jolt of marine backing to the thousands of Panamanians who have been marching daily to demand the annulment of the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/panama-congress-signs-off-contract-with-canadas-first-quantum-2023-10-20/">Canadian miner's contract</a>, arguing its presence violates Panama's sovereignty and threatens its environment.翻译:渔船队为成千上万的巴拿马人提供了新的海上支持，他们每天都上街游行，要求废除<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/panama-congress-signs-off-contract-with-canadas-first-quantum-2023-10-20/">加拿大矿工的合同</a>，认为其存在侵犯了巴拿马的主权并威胁其环境。</p>   <p>The fishermen are angry that the company has appropriated resources, land and water, and worry about the mine's environmental consequences. Cobre Panama has said it is committed to growing more new forest than is impacted by its mine.翻译:渔民对公司侵占资源、土地和水感到愤怒，并担心该矿的环境后果。巴拿马铜矿表示，该公司致力于种植比其矿山影响更多的新森林。</p>   <p>Panama's top court on Tuesday declared First Quantum's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/top-panama-court-rules-first-quantum-mining-contract-unconstitutional-2023-11-28/">contract unconstitutional</a> and its president announced an orderly <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/top-panama-court-rules-first-quantum-mining-contract-unconstitutional-2023-11-28/">shutdown</a> of the mine, but the vigils on land and sea are set to continue as protesters insist that authorities take concrete steps to close the site.翻译:巴拿马最高法院周二宣布第一量子公司的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/top-panama-court-rules-first-quantum-mining-contract-unconstitutional-2023-11-28/">合同违宪</a>，总统宣布有序<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/top-panama-court-rules-first-quantum-mining-contract-unconstitutional-2023-11-28/">关闭</a>该矿，但陆地和海上的守夜活动将继续，因为抗议者坚持要求当局采取具体措施关闭该矿场。</p>   <p>"We aren't going anywhere," Sabino Ayarza, a representative of the protesting fishermen, told Reuters on Tuesday from his boat.翻译:抗议渔民代表萨比诺·阿亚尔扎 (Sabino Ayarza) 周二在船上对路透社表示：“我们哪儿也不去。”</p>   <p>A complete shuttering of the mine, which accounts for about 1% of global copper output and 5% of Panama's GDP, would signal a David vs. Goliath victory for Panamanian protesters.翻译:该矿的铜产量约占全球铜产量的 1%，占巴拿马 GDP 的 5%，完全关闭该矿将标志着巴拿马抗议者以弱胜强的胜利。</p>   <p>Their grassroots movement, nearly unheard of in business-friendly Panama, has wiped C$11 billion ($7.4 billion) off First Quantum's market value and raised global copper prices on <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/dwindling-copper-supply-panama-peru-could-wipe-out-global-surplus-2024-2023-11-28/">supply worries</a>. Copper is a crucial metal in electrification as the world moves to reduce reliance on fossil fuels.翻译:他们的草根运动在商业友好的巴拿马几乎闻所未闻，已使第一量子的市值蒸发了 110 亿加元（74 亿美元），并因<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/dwindling-copper-supply-panama-peru-could-wipe-out-global-surplus-2024-2023-11-28/">供应担忧</a>而推高了全球铜价。随着世界努力减少对化石燃料的依赖，铜是电气化中的关键金属。</p>   <p>The protesters' victory in Panama is emblematic of the outsized and sometimes unexpected influence local communities are having on mining companies worldwide. In Portugal, for instance, Europe's biggest producer of lithium, some <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/europes-mining-quest-faces-hurdle-angry-locals-2023-09-13/">local activists</a> are determined to halt mine developments. Canada's First Nation groups <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/land-use-biodiversity/canada-first-nations-protest-ontarios-ring-fire-mining-plans-2023-07-20/">have also mounted fierce opposition</a> against mining on their lands.翻译:巴拿马抗议者的胜利象征着当地社区对全球矿业公司产生的巨大影响，有时甚至是意想不到的影响。例如，在欧洲最大的锂生产国葡萄牙，一些<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/europes-mining-quest-faces-hurdle-angry-locals-2023-09-13/">当地活动人士</a>决心停止矿山开发。加拿大原住民团体<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/land-use-biodiversity/canada-first-nations-protest-ontarios-ring-fire-mining-plans-2023-07-20/">也强烈反对</a>在他们的土地上采矿。</p>   <p>Those hoping to halt the mine's operations have seen false dawns before. Panama's top court struck down First Quantum's previous contract in 2017, but the company was allowed to mine while a new contract was approved. So protesters aren't taking any chances this time.翻译:那些希望停止该矿运营的人以前也曾看到过虚假的曙光。巴拿马最高法院于 2017 年驳回了 First Quantum 之前的合同，但该公司获准开采，同时新合同获得批准。所以抗议者这次不会再冒险了。</p>   <p>"If this goes on for a year, we will stay a year, there is no end-date," Ayarza said.翻译:阿亚尔扎说：“如果这种情况持续一年，我们就会停留一年，没有结束日期。”</p>   <p>Cobre Panama accounted for about 46% of First Quantum's overall revenue in the third quarter, according to company data. The company was "reasonably confident" last week in ships carrying supplies reaching the port soon, but failed to circumvent the fishermen's blockade, said a person familiar with the mine's developments who asked not to be named.翻译:根据公司数据，Cobre巴拿马公司第三季度的收入约占First Quantum总收入的46%。一位不愿透露姓名的熟悉该矿动态的人士表示，该公司上周对运载物资的船只很快抵达港口“相当有信心”，但未能绕过渔民的封锁。</p>   <p>First Quantum, said it would respect the court's ruling and on Tuesday announced the mine has suspended commercial production due to the blockades.</p>    <h 1="">SURPLUS THREATENED</h>  <p>A Scotiabank report forecasts Cobre Panama's copper output in 2024 to represent about 1.6% of global supply and warned an indefinite shutdown increases risks of First Quantum potentially defaulting by the third quarter of 2024, and threaten its liquidity by early 2025.翻译:丰业银行的一份报告预测，2024 年 Cobre巴拿马的铜产量将占全球供应量的 1.6% 左右，并警告无限期关闭将增加 First Quantum 在 2024 年第三季度可能违约的风险，并在 2025 年初威胁到其流动性。</p>   <p>First Quantum did not immediately reply to a request for comment on the question about possible default.翻译:第一量子没有立即回复就可能违约问题发表评论的请求。</p>   <p>Together with dwindling supply from Peru, the world's No. 2 copper producer after Chile, the Panama shutdown threatens to wipe out what had been seen as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/dwindling-copper-supply-panama-peru-could-wipe-out-global-surplus-2024-2023-11-28/">global surplus</a> in 2024, according to Macquarie.翻译:麦格理表示，加上继智利之后的全球第二大铜生产国秘鲁的供应减少，巴拿马的停产可能会消除 2024 年的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/dwindling-copper-supply-panama-peru-could-wipe-out-global-surplus-2024-2023-11-28/">全球供应过剩</a>。</p>   <p>In Chile, the copper outlook for 2023 went from 5.9% growth in May to 1% in July, as state-owned miner Codelco, the world's largest producer, lowered production amid operational difficulties, though it is expected to recover in 2024.翻译:在智利，由于全球最大生产商Codelco因运营困难而降低产量，2023年铜增长前景从5月的5.9%下调至7月的1%，但预计将于2024年恢复。</p>   <p>The fishermen have added muscle to a movement which blocked roads, causing daily losses of more than $90 million to businesses, according to experts, and food shortages nationwide. Protesters also hurled rocks at a bus transporting workers to the mine on one occasion, injuring eight <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/panama-protesters-attack-workers-canadas-first-quantum-mine-union-2023-11-26/">workers</a>.翻译:据专家称，渔民们助长了封锁道路的行动，每天给企业造成超过 9000 万美元的损失，并造成全国范围内的粮食短缺。抗议者还曾向一辆运送工人前往矿井的巴士投掷石块，造成八名<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/panama-protesters-attack-workers-canadas-first-quantum-mine-union-2023-11-26/">工人</a>受伤。</p>   <p>The court verdict leaves three possible outcomes: Panama could close the mine indefinitely, nationalize it, or agree to settle its differences in international arbitration by negotiating a constitutionally correct contract with First Quantum alongside a new joint-venture partner.翻译:法院的判决留下了三种可能的结果：巴拿马可以无限期关闭该矿，将其国有化，或者同意通过与第一量子以及新的合资伙伴谈判一份符合宪法的合同来解决国际仲裁中的分歧。</p>   <p>"We believe it may be time for FM to consider bringing in a major mining partner to share the future risk of operating in Panama," Scotiabank said in a note on Tuesday.翻译:丰业银行周二在一份报告中表示：“我们认为，FM 可能是时候考虑引入主要矿业合作伙伴来分担未来在巴拿马运营的风险了。”</p>   <p>However, protesters are pushing firmly towards <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/panama-econ-minister-backs-contract-with-first-quantum-despite-protests-2023-10-27/">a ban on all kinds of mining</a> despite warnings of economic consequences.翻译:然而，尽管有经济后果的警告，抗议者仍在坚决推动<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/panama-econ-minister-backs-contract-with-first-quantum-despite-protests-2023-10-27/">禁止各种采矿活动</a>。</p>   <p>The protesting fishermen have been posting their bank account details on social media for people to donate food and fuel. Ayarza did not detail how much they have received, but said he was confident they can outlast the mining giant.翻译:抗议的渔民一直在社交媒体上发布他们的银行账户详细信息，以便人们捐赠食物和燃料。阿亚尔扎没有详细说明他们收到了多少资金，但表示他有信心他们能够比这家矿业巨头更长久。</p>   <p>"We know our sea. We know the area in which we are waging war," said Ayarza. "We use ropes to make them back down and, well, threaten them so they have to go back."翻译:“我们了解我们的海洋。我们了解我们正在发动战争的地区，”阿亚尔扎说。 “我们用绳子让他们后退，然后威胁他们，让他们不得不回去。”</p>   <p>($1 = 1.3579 Canadian dollars)翻译:（1 美元 = 1.3579 加元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Valentine Hilaire in Mexico City and Divya Rajagopal in Toronto; Additional reporting by Fabian Cambero in Santiago;
Editing by Christian Plumb, Denny Thomas and Nick Zieminski翻译:墨西哥城的 Valentine Hilaire 和多伦多的 Divya Rajagopal 的报道； Fabian Cambero 在圣地亚哥的补充报道；编辑：克里斯蒂安·普拉姆 (Christian Plumb)、丹尼·托马斯 (Denny Thomas) 和尼克·齐明斯基 (Nick Zieminski)</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 17:30:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F4FOW6LJA5KM5HGTXSZZCLBKUA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/we-arent-going-anywhere-how-panama-fishing-boats-brought-first-quantum-its-knees-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Valentine Hilaire, Divya Rajagopal]]></author>
            
                
                <category>PANAMA</category>
                
                <category>FIRST QUANTUM/PROTESTS (FOCUS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shein IPO 引发有关供应链中涉嫌强迫劳动的新问题]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Q8b-K6TaMCqpY-8bLJ01meRQ35M=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/O2FMBEKGANO6LPZJNYZSVKRYOY.jpg" alt="Shein Holiday Pop-Up Shop In Forever 21 at Times Square翻译:Shein Holiday 快闪店位于时代广场 Forever 21" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People shop at the Shein Holiday pop-up shop inside of Times Square's Forever 21 in New York City, U.S., November 10, 2023.REUTERS/David 'Dee' Delgado/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 10 日，人们在美国纽约时代广场 Forever 21 内的 Shein Holiday 快闪店购物。REUTERS/David &#39;Dee&#39; Delgado/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0ZEBwrUF5l53uGohNippDToQ-Vg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4MRVJDJEGROX7OJQQJ36O7FTXU.jpg" alt="A Shein logo is pictured at the company's office in the central business district of Singapore翻译:Shein 标志位于该公司位于新加坡中央商务区的办公室" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Shein logo is pictured at the company's office in the central business district of Singapore翻译:Shein 标志位于该公司位于新加坡中央商务区的办公室, October 18, 2022. REUTERS/Chen Lin/File Photo翻译:2022 年 10 月 18 日，Shein 标志在该公司位于新加坡中央商务区的办公室拍摄。路透社/Chen Lin/档案照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>As China-founded e-commerce behemoth Shein moves to list in New York, U.S. lawmakers are again calling on it to prove that forced labor is not used to make its $5 t-shirts and $10 sweaters.翻译:随着中国创立的电子商务巨头 Shein 在纽约上市，美国立法者再次呼吁该公司证明其 5 美元的 T 恤和 10 美元的毛衣的生产过程中没有使用强迫劳动。</p>   <p>Shein <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinese-fast-fashion-shein-files-us-ipo-wsj-2023-11-27/">confidentially filed</a> for an initial public offering on Monday and could launch sales of its shares some time in 2024. The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/how-chinas-shein-became-fast-fashion-giant-2023-11-28/">Singapore-based company</a> has not determined the size of the deal or the valuation at IPO. Bloomberg earlier this month reported that it targeted up to $90 billion in the float.翻译:Shein 周一<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinese-fast-fashion-shein-files-us-ipo-wsj-2023-11-27/">秘密申请</a>首次公开募股，并可能在 2024 年某个时候出售其股票。这家<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/how-chinas-shein-became-fast-fashion-giant-2023-11-28/">总部位于新加坡的公司</a>尚未确定交易规模或 IPO 估值。彭博社本月早些时候报道称，其发行目标为 900 亿美元。</p>   <p>Founded in 2012, Shein has been <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/shein-talks-with-banks-exchanges-about-us-ipo-sources-2023-07-04/">eyeing a U.S. IPO</a> for at least three years but has been deterred by headwinds that included tensions between Beijing and Washington.翻译:Shein 成立于 2012 年，至少三年来一直<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/shein-talks-with-banks-exchanges-about-us-ipo-sources-2023-07-04/">考虑在美国首次公开募股</a>，但因北京和华盛顿之间的紧张局势等不利因素而止步。</p>   <p>The online fast-fashion retailer, which manufactures most of its merchandise in China, faces criticism that Uyghur forced labor is used to make its low-priced apparel and home goods.翻译:这家在线快时尚零售商的大部分商品在中国生产，该公司面临着使用维吾尔族强迫劳动来生产其低价服装和家居用品的批评。</p>   <p>Critics are concerned that Shein may use contract manufacturers in China's Xinjiang region, where advocates and governments have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/us-committee-demands-reasons-lack-xinjiang-sanctions-2023-09-19/">accused China</a> of interning Uyghurs and other largely Muslim minority groups. Beijing denies any abuses.翻译:批评者担心，谢因可能会使用中国新疆地区的合同制造商，那里的倡导者和政府<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/us-committee-demands-reasons-lack-xinjiang-sanctions-2023-09-19/">指责中国</a>拘禁维吾尔人和其他以穆斯林为主的少数民族群体。北京否认有任何侵权行为。</p>   <p>Convincing regulators that its supply chain is clean will likely be a major regulatory hurdle as Shein works to convince the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission that its shares should be traded publicly.翻译:让监管机构相信其供应链是干净的可能会成为主要的监管障碍，因为 Shein 正在努力说服美国证券交易委员会其股票应该公开交易。</p>   <p>“If the fast-fashion giant Shein wants to go public in the U.S., they should have to prove to American consumers that their products are not sourced from forced labor,” Democratic Representative Jennifer Wexton said in a statement on Tuesday.翻译:“如果快时尚巨头 Shein 想要在美国上市，他们应该向美国消费者证明他们的产品并非来自强迫劳动，”民主党众议员詹妮弗·韦克斯顿 (Jennifer Wexton) 在周二的一份声明中表示。</p>   <p>The congresswoman earlier this year led a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/us-lawmakers-push-sec-order-audit-shein-ipo-over-uyghur-forced-labor-fears-2023-05-01/">bipartisan call</a> for the SEC to halt Shein’s IPO until it verifies that the company does not use forced labor within its supply chain.翻译:今年早些时候，这位女议员领导<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/us-lawmakers-push-sec-order-audit-shein-ipo-over-uyghur-forced-labor-fears-2023-05-01/">两党</a>呼吁美国证券交易委员会停止 Shein 的首次公开募股，直到核实该公司在其供应链中不使用强迫劳动。</p>   <p>A separate group of Republican attorneys general from 16 U.S. states has also asked the SEC to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/society-equity/us-states-ask-sec-check-if-shein-complies-with-forced-labor-rules-2023-08-28/">audit the company</a>, and Shein has been investigated by two separate congressional committees over its sourcing and use of a trade loophole that allows most of its products to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/key-trade-loophole-keeps-cheap-chinese-products-flowing-us-2023-08-04/">enter the United States duty free</a>.翻译:来自美国 16 个州的共和党总检察长组成的独立小组也要求美国证券交易委员会<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/society-equity/us-states-ask-sec-check-if-shein-complies-with-forced-labor-rules-2023-08-28/">对该公司进行审计</a>，Shein 已受到两个独立的国会委员会的调查，原因是该公司的采购和利用了允许其大部分产品<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/key-trade-loophole-keeps-cheap-chinese-products-flowing-us-2023-08-04/">进入美国的</a>贸易漏洞。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/key-trade-loophole-keeps-cheap-chinese-products-flowing-us-2023-08-04/">各国免税</a>。</p>   <p>A spokesperson for Shein in a statement on Tuesday said the company has a zero-tolerance policy for forced labor and was "eager to engage and continue to be transparent with all stakeholders, including Representative Wexton and her staff."翻译:Shein 的发言人在周二的一份声明中表示，该公司对强迫劳动采取零容忍政策，并“渴望与所有利益相关者接触并继续保持透明，包括代表韦克斯顿及其员工。”</p>   <p>Shein has previously told Reuters it has no contract manufacturers in Xinjiang.翻译:Shein 此前曾告诉路透社，该公司在新疆没有合同制造商。</p>   <p>A spokesperson for the SEC said the agency does not comment on any individual entity’s filings.翻译:美国证券交易委员会发言人表示，该机构不会对任何个别实体的备案文件发表评论。</p>   <p>Megan Penick, a public securities lawyer at Michelman &amp; Robinson, said it is unlikely to see a "direct block" from the SEC, but the agency could make the process difficult for Shein by making "the disclosure requirements so detailed, and, perhaps extreme, that it makes it seem ... trying to go public cannot be achieved."翻译:米歇尔曼·罗宾逊律师事务所 (Michelman &amp; Robinson) 的公共证券律师梅根·佩尼克 (Megan Penick) 表示，不太可能看到 SEC 的“直接阻止”，但该机构可能会通过“披露要求如此详细，甚至可能是极端”，从而使 Shein 的流程变得困难。 ，这看起来……试图上市是不可能实现的。”</p>   <p>"There may be issues with the forced labor allegations and the IP (intellectual property) issues that may make it hard for (Shein) to be able to answer the questions to the satisfaction of the SEC," Penick said.</p>    <h 1="">LOBBYING CAPITOL HILL</h>  <p>Public disclosures show that Shein has spent $1.28 million on Capitol Hill lobbying this year as it prepares to go public.翻译:公开披露的信息显示，Shein 今年在准备上市时已花费 128 万美元用于国会山游说。</p>   <p>The company has also met privately with lawmakers, including some of its biggest critics, in an effort to shift its reputation in Washington, according to several congressional aides.翻译:据几位国会助手称，该公司还与立法者私下会面，其中包括一些最大的批评者，以努力改变其在华盛顿的声誉。</p>   <p>One source familiar with the matter said that representatives for Shein emphasized the retailer’s efforts to diversify its supply chain from China to other countries, including India.翻译:一位知情人士表示，Shein 的代表强调了该零售商努力将其供应链从中国转向包括印度在内的其他国家。</p>   <p>Shein also touted its efforts to bring more China-made goods to the United States <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/shein-shifts-shipping-strategy-bring-china-made-goods-closer-us-shoppers-2023-09-22/">in bulk on traditional container ships</a>, which requires paying tariffs on those items.翻译:Shein还宣传其努力<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/shein-shifts-shipping-strategy-bring-china-made-goods-closer-us-shoppers-2023-09-22/">通过传统集装箱船</a>将更多中国制造的商品批量运往美国，这需要对这些商品缴纳关税。</p>   <p>“Shein is fundamentally a Chinese company and investors should approach Chinese offerings with extreme caution. Its attempt to go public should prompt a closer look at its business practices, especially its links to slave labor and its evasion of U.S. customs laws," Republican Sen. Marco Rubio told Reuters.翻译:“Shein 从根本上来说是一家中国公司，投资者应极其谨慎地对待中国产品。它的上市尝试应该促使人们更仔细地审视其商业行为，特别是其与奴役劳工的联系以及其逃避美国海关法的行为，”共和党参议员马可·卢比奥告诉路透社。</p>   <p>"I will closely monitor Shein's disclosures in the lead-up to its IPO,” added Rubio, who in June criticized the retailer’s lobbying efforts in a letter distributed to other senators.翻译:卢比奥补充道：“我将在 Shein 首次公开募股前夕密切关注 Shein 的披露情况。”6 月份，卢比奥在发给其他参议员的一封信中批评了该零售商的游说努力。</p>   <p>Republican Representative Chris Smith, chairman of the Congressional-Executive Commission on China, has also criticized Shein's lobbying efforts.翻译:国会及行政部门中国委员会主席、共和党众议员克里斯·史密斯也批评了谢因的游说努力。</p>   <p>“Any investor in this company should be wary of the material risks involved in Shein’s business model ... particularly as Congress is demanding an end to forced labor and closure of import subsidies for Chinese companies,” Smith said.</p>    <h 1="">INCREASED SCRUTINY</h>  <p>In its most recent social impact report, Shein highlighted its partnership with Oritain, a company also used by the U.S. government to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/us-customs-finds-garments-made-with-banned-chinese-cotton-documents-2023-09-01/">test cotton </a>for links to China’s Xinjiang region.翻译:Shein 在其最新的社会影响报告中强调了其与 Oritain 的合作关系，该公司也被美国政府用来<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/us-customs-finds-garments-made-with-banned-chinese-cotton-documents-2023-09-01/">测试棉花</a>与中国新疆地区的联系。</p>   <p>Oritain CEO Grant Cochrane on Tuesday that the testing company conducted 2,762 tests of Shein yarn, fabric and finished products between August 2022 and November 2023 and that 1.7% tested positive for cotton from unapproved regions. The average prevalence of cotton from unapproved regions among brands that work with Oritain was 6% in 2023, according to the company.翻译:Oritain首席执行官格兰特·科克伦(Grant Cochrane)周二表示，该测试公司在2022年8月至2023年11月期间对Shein纱线、织物和成品进行了2,762次测试，其中1.7%的棉花测试结果呈阳性，这些棉花来自未经批准的地区。据该公司称，到 2023 年，与 Oritain 合作的品牌中来自未经批准地区的棉花的平均流行率为 6%。</p>   <p>Critics, however, say that the testing does not adequately screen the millions of garments exported globally by Shein every year.翻译:然而批评者表示，测试并没有充分筛查 Shein 每年向全球出口的数百万件服装。</p>   <p>Penick said that the SEC's handling of Shein's IPO will be crucial for other e-commerce players including ByteDance's TikTok and PDD Group's Temu, which may consider going public in the U.S. in the future.翻译:佩尼克表示，SEC 对 Shein IPO 的处理对于字节跳动旗下 TikTok 和拼多多集团旗下 Temu 等其他电商企业至关重要，这些企业未来可能会考虑在美国上市。</p>   <p>Shein's IPO is "going to be raising issues (for the SEC) that may later be applied across the board to all China-based or China-related companies that are going public," Penick said.翻译:佩尼克表示，Shein 的首次公开募股“将（向美国证券交易委员会）提出问题，这些问题随后可能会全面适用于所有即将上市的中国或与中国相关的公司”。</p>    <span>Reporting by Katherine Masters and Arriana Mclymore; Additional reporting by Michael Martina; Editing by Marguerita Choy and Mark Porter翻译:凯瑟琳·马斯特斯和阿里安娜·麦克利莫尔的报道；迈克尔·玛蒂娜 (Michael Martina) 的补充报道；玛格丽塔·蔡和马克·波特编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 15:03:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CBHAFJU6ZBKW7KOMWE6QWZQDKI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/sheins-ipo-raises-fresh-questions-alleged-forced-labor-its-supply-chain-2023-11-28/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Katherine Masters, Arriana McLymore]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SHEIN</category>
                
                <category>IPO/ (UPDATE 1, ANALYSIS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国习近平访问金融中心上海]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/cygCsR_sJeJjS90x2pK3wTh-j0A=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/RNSBSQIK7BIUJBB4A6CFU27YCU.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden hosts the Leaders Retreat at the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit in San Francisco翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在旧金山主持亚太经合组织（APEC）峰会领导人务虚会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping attends the Leaders Retreat at the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 17, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:中国国家主席习近平出席 2023 年 11 月 17 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会领导人务虚会。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>       <p>China President Xi Jinping visited Shanghai, where he went to several venues and learned about the city's efforts to strengthen its competitiveness as an international financial centre, Xinhua news agency reported on Wednesday.翻译:据新华社周三报道，中国国家主席习近平访问上海，参观了上海多个场馆，了解上海为增强国际金融中心竞争力所做的努力。</p>   <p>Xi made the trip on Tuesday and Wednesday and he inspected the Shanghai Futures Exchange, an exhibition on Shanghai's sci-tech innovations and a government-subsidized rental housing community, the report said.翻译:报道称，习近平周二和周三出访，考察了上海期货交易所、上海科技创新展览和政府补贴租赁住房社区。</p>   <p>He was seen with other government leaders, including Cai Qi, the head of the powerful Secretariat of the Communist Party of China Central Committee that oversees day-to-day affairs of the CPC.翻译:人们看到他与其他政府领导人在一起，其中包括负责中共日常事务的中共中央书记处书记蔡奇。</p>   <p>Vice Premier He Lifeng, Shanghai's Communist party secretary Chen Jining and Mayor Gong Zheng also accompanied his visit.翻译:国务院副总理何立峰、上海市委书记陈吉宁、市长龚正陪同考察。</p>   <p>A video posted by state television showed Xi inspecting a humanoid robot and a section of an exhibition showcasing China's integrated circuits technology, an industry that he has been pushing for more mondernisation and self-sufficiency.翻译:国家电视台发布的一段视频显示，习近平正在检查一个人形机器人以及展示中国集成电路技术的展览的一部分，他一直在推动这个行业更加现代化和自给自足。</p>   <p>He could also be seen touring an affordable housing compound in Shanghai's Minhang district. The Chinese government has in recent months pledged more support in boosting affordable housing as high home prices in major cities like Shanghai shut out many buyers.翻译:人们还看到他参观了上海闵行区的一个经济适用房小区。由于上海等主要城市的高房价将许多购房者拒之门外，中国政府近几个月承诺加大经济适用房支持力度。</p>   <p>It was his first visit to the city since November 2020 and comes a year after historic street protests against China's zero-COVID policy broke out in Shanghai.翻译:这是他自 2020 年 11 月以来首次访问这座城市，一年前，上海爆发了针对中国零新冠政策的历史性街头抗议活动。</p>   <p>The visit also coincides with the 10th anniversary of the establishment of the Shanghai Free-Trade Zone (FTZ), a testing ground for economic reforms that has struggled to live up to its initial promise of free-flowing currency and easier international trade.翻译:此次访问也恰逢上海自由贸易区（FTZ）成立十周年。上海自由贸易区是经济改革的试验场，一直在努力兑现其最初承诺的货币自由流动和国际贸易便利化的承诺。</p>   <p>Shanghai is home to China's largest foreign business community, hosting firms such as Tesla <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a>, Disney <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DIS.N" target="_blank">(DIS.N)</a> and L'Oreal, but its economy and global reputation was badly hit by a two-month-long COVID-induced lockdown last year.翻译:上海是中国最大的外国商业社区的所在地，拥有特斯拉<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a> 、迪士尼<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DIS.N" target="_blank">(DIS.N)</a>和欧莱雅等公司，但其经济和全球声誉受到了长达两个月的新冠疫情的严重打击。去年引发的封锁。</p>   <p>Xi's visit also comes as confidence among foreign businesses and private investors in the Chinese economy remains subdued, hurt by the country's past COVID policies and a years-long regulatory crackdown on sectors from technology to property that the government began easing this year.翻译:习近平此次访问之际，外国企业和私人投资者对中国经济的信心仍然低迷，原因是中国过去的新冠疫情政策以及政府今年开始放松的对技术和房地产等行业长达数年的监管打压。</p>   <p>Overtures by Chinese Premier Li Qiang, a close Xi confidant, to both foreign firms and local entrepreneurs over the past year where he has declared the country open for business has been greeted with scepticism in light of a broader anti-espionage law, and moves such as raids on consultancies, as well as a lack of policies to boost confidence.翻译:过去一年里，习近平的亲密密友、中国总理李强向外国公司和当地企业家提出的建议，他宣布中国开放商业，但鉴于更广泛的反间谍法，他受到了质疑，并采取了诸如此类的举措。对咨询机构的突击搜查，以及缺乏提振信心的政策。</p>    <span>Reporting by Brenda Goh, Bernard Orr, Ella Cao and Ethan Wang; Editing by Mark Potter, Louise Heavens, Chizu Nomiyama and Mark Porter翻译:Brenda Goh、Bernard Orr、Ella Cao 和 Ethan Wang 报道；编辑：Mark Potter、Louise Heavens、Chizu Nomiyama 和 Mark Porter</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 14:36:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">H6Z6C44SSFL7TOAHI2SW7COA44</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-xi-visits-financial-hub-shanghai-first-trip-three-years-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>XI/SHANGHAI (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[克里表示，中美将在 COP28 峰会上合作]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/qRIBDJ8ijLiEaVBO3_DK3u-aoMU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TTAOMPAQDJNQTJL63PZ4S45L54.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry attends the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 16, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:美国总统气候问题特使约翰·克里出席 2023 年 11 月 16 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria</figcaption></figure>       <p>The United States will work with China to make the United Nations climate negotiations that begin in the United Arab Emirates this week a success, Washington's climate envoy said on Wednesday.翻译:华盛顿气候特使周三表示，美国将与中国合作，使本周在阿拉伯联合酋长国开始的联合国气候谈判取得成功。</p>   <p>Cooperation between the U.S. and China, the world's two biggest emitters of greenhouse gases, is seen as crucial to securing consensus at the Nov. 30 - Dec. 12 summit, known as COP28.翻译:美国和中国这两个世界上最大的温室气体排放国之间的合作被认为对于在 11 月 30 日至 12 月 12 日举行的 COP28 峰会上达成共识至关重要。</p>   <p>"We have decided to actually work together to get a successful COP, to get a successful global stocktake," Kerry said of his meeting with his Chinese counterpart this month.翻译:克里在谈到本月与中国外长的会面时表示：“我们决定切实合作，以召开一次成功的缔约方会议，并成功进行全球盘点。”</p>   <p>The global stocktake is an assessment taking place at the climate talks on how far off countries are from limiting global heating to 1.5 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels.翻译:全球盘点是在气候谈判中进行的一项评估，旨在评估各国距离将全球升温限制在工业化前水平以上 1.5 摄氏度以内还有多远。</p>   <p>Kerry and Chinese climate envoy Xie Zhenhua met in California where the sides agreed to the revival of a bilateral climate working group that Beijing had suspended last year.翻译:克里和中国气候特使解振华在加州会面，双方同意恢复北京去年暂停的双边气候工作组。</p>   <p>The U.S. and China agreed to back a new global renewables target and work together on methane and plastic pollution, though differences remain on fossil fuels, among other issues.翻译:美国和中国同意支持新的全球可再生能源目标，并就甲烷和塑料污染问题开展合作，尽管在化石燃料等问题上仍存在分歧。</p>   <p>"We intend to work hard to see if there's further collaboration that could advance the cause for all of us," Kerry said. "Without China and the United States aggressively moving forward to reduce emissions, we don't win this battle."翻译:克里说：“我们打算努力看看是否有进一步的合作可以推动我们所有人的事业。” “如果中国和美国不积极推进减排，我们就无法赢得这场战斗。”</p>   <p>The talks in the UAE, a major oil producer, are a critical opportunity for governments to accelerate action on climate change. However, they remain split over the use of fossil fuels, the burning of which is the main cause of climate change.翻译:在主要石油生产国阿联酋举行的会谈是各国政府加快应对气候变化行动的重要机会。然而，他们在化石燃料的使用问题上仍然存在分歧，化石燃料的燃烧是气候变化的主要原因。</p>   <p>Kerry, in a call with reporters, urged major producers of fossil fuels to support language that would commit them to phasing out the use of "unabated" fossil fuels - a reference to fuels burned without emissions-capturing technology.翻译:克里在与记者的通话中敦促主要化石燃料生产商支持承诺逐步淘汰使用“有增无减”化石燃料的措辞——指的是在没有排放捕获技术的情况下燃烧的燃料。</p>   <p>"They need to immediately step up and be part of the solution, not the most significant part of the problem," he said without identifying any particular producer.翻译:“他们需要立即挺身而出，成为解决方案的一部分，而不是成为问题最重要的部分，”他说，但没有透露具体的生产商。</p>   <p>In April the Group of Seven industrialised nations, which includes the United States, agreed to speed up the "phase-out of unabated fossil fuels" in what appeared to be a possible breakthrough over their use.翻译:今年四月，包括美国在内的七国集团同意加快“逐步淘汰化石燃料”，这似乎是化石燃料使用方面的一个可能的突破。</p>   <p>Negotiators have turned to new terminologies in search of a compromise after divisions over the future of fossil fuels failed to lead to a deal on a phase-down at last year's summit.翻译:去年峰会上，由于对化石燃料未来的分歧未能达成逐步削减协议，谈判代表们转向新术语寻求妥协。</p>   <p>"We hope we can send a very strong signal that the nations of the world are committed to work together to transition away from fossil fuel emissions in the next three decades. Period. It's critical," Kerry said.翻译:“我们希望我们能够发出一个非常强烈的信号，即世界各国致力于共同努力，在未来三十年内摆脱化石燃料排放。就这样。这很关键，”克里说。</p>    <span>Reporting by Alexander Cornwell
Editing by Mark Potter and Gareth Jones翻译:亚历山大·康威尔 (Alexander Cornwell) 报道 马克·波特 (Mark Potter) 和加雷斯·琼斯 (Gareth Jones) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 14:35:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5JI426VP3ZP6THTMUXUGSHO4RM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/us-climate-envoy-urges-wider-support-phasing-out-unabated-fossil-fuels-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Alexander Cornwell]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CLIMATE</category>
                
                <category>UN/USA</category>
                
                <category>EMIRATES (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[一年过去了，中国的新冠抗议者陷入希望与冷漠之间]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ya8E6-xzvLZoGFWuRsqoysz-LgM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FBCJJPC765JF3JCO2KTTKAL4NY.jpg" alt="People hold white sheets of paper in protest over COVID-19 restrictions in mainland China, in Hong Kong翻译:人们举着白纸抗议中国大陆和香港的 COVID-19 限制" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People hold white sheets of paper in protest over coronavirus disease (COVID-19) restrictions in mainland China, during a commemoration of the victims of a fire in Urumqi, in Hong Kong, China November 28, 2022. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu/File Photo翻译:2022 年 11 月 28 日，在中国香港乌鲁木齐火灾遇难者纪念活动中，人们手举白纸抗议中国大陆对冠状病毒 (COVID-19) 的限制。 REUTERS/Tyrone Siu/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>One year after "white paper" protests flared across China against stringent COVID restrictions, Yicheng Huang fears this rare show of public dissent may eventually be forgotten by the Chinese public amid state censorship.翻译:一年前，中国各地爆发针对严格的新冠限制措施的“白皮书”抗议活动，黄义成担心，这种罕见的公开异议表现可能最终会在国家审查制度下被中国公众遗忘。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shanghai-hit-by-covid-protests-anger-spreads-across-china-2022-11-27/">wave of civil disobedience</a> which erupted on Nov 25 last year was unprecedented in President Xi Jinping's decade in power, which has seen a widespread crackdown on civil society.翻译:去年11月25日爆发的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shanghai-hit-by-covid-protests-anger-spreads-across-china-2022-11-27/">公民抗命浪潮</a>在习近平主席执政十年中是前所未有的，公民社会受到了广泛的打压。</p>   <p>While the protests against the zero-COVID policy were quickly suppressed by police, they <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/how-chinas-new-no2-hastened-end-xis-zero-covid-policy-2023-03-03/">helped hasten</a> the end of three years of some of the world's strictest pandemic curbs.翻译:虽然针对零新冠政策的抗议活动很快被警方镇压，但它们<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/how-chinas-new-no2-hastened-end-xis-zero-covid-policy-2023-03-03/">帮助加速了</a>世界上一些最严格的流行病遏制措施的三年结束。</p>   <p>"Many protesters experienced being part of a civic collective for the first time," said Huang, who fled to Germany in March after <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/protester-breaks-silence-chinas-crackdown-covid-demonstrators-2023-04-19/">narrowly avoiding detention</a> during protests in Shanghai. "For Chinese people, this is like first love."翻译:“许多抗议者第一次体验到成为公民集体的一部分，”黄说。他在上海的抗议活动中<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/protester-breaks-silence-chinas-crackdown-covid-demonstrators-2023-04-19/">险些被拘留，</a>并于三月份逃往德国。 “对于中国人来说，这就像初恋。”</p>   <p>Six participants based in China and overseas told Reuters they felt a mixture of hope and ambivalence towards the demonstrations, which they said helped to end COVID restrictions but failed to achieve lasting political change.翻译:来自中国和海外的六名参与者告诉路透社，他们对示威活动感到既希望又矛盾，他们说示威有助于结束新冠病毒限制，但未能实现持久的政治变革。</p>   <p>Many spoke on condition of anonymity for fear of state retribution, after last year's widespread <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-police-out-numbers-prevent-more-covid-protests-2022-11-29/">police crackdown</a>. Reuters was unable to confirm the total number of protesters detained last year, although some were since <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-covid-protesters-released-after-four-months-detention-sources-2023-04-20/">released</a>.翻译:在去年<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-police-out-numbers-prevent-more-covid-protests-2022-11-29/">警方的广泛镇压</a>之后，由于担心国家报复，许多人都要求匿名。路透社无法确认去年被拘留的抗议者总数，尽管一些人后来被<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-covid-protesters-released-after-four-months-detention-sources-2023-04-20/">释放</a>。</p>   <p>This year, on the weekend anniversary of the protests, there were no demonstrations in Beijing and Shanghai. There was also a heavy police presence at protest sites. Cities with large Chinese communities overseas, including New York, London and Washington DC, staged commemorative events.翻译:今年，在抗议活动周年纪念日的周末，北京和上海没有发生示威活动。抗议现场也有大量警察驻守。纽约、伦敦、华盛顿等海外华人社区较多的城市都举办了纪念活动。</p>   <p>Huang said many of his Shanghai friends walked past the main protest site to mark the anniversary, but did little else. "It's turned into a forbidden memory, like June 4th," he said, referring to the widely censored 1989 crackdown on student protesters in Tiananmen Square.翻译:黄说，他的许多上海朋友都走过主要抗议地点来纪念周年纪念日，但没有做其他事情。 “它已经变成了一种禁忌的记忆，就像 6 月 4 日一样，”他说，指的是 1989 年天安门广场上受到广泛审查的镇压学生抗议活动。</p>   <p>During last year's Beijing protests, some demonstrators also called for press freedom, democracy and human rights.翻译:在去年的北京抗议活动中，一些示威者还呼吁新闻自由、民主和人权。</p>   <p>Some of the protesters that Reuters spoke to, as well as observers, said the events helped raise awareness of how much political power Chinese people actually wielded.翻译:路透社采访的一些抗议者以及观察人士表示，这些事件有助于提高人们对中国人民实际掌握的政治权力的认识。</p>   <p>An Italy-based Chinese artist and blogger known as "Teacher Li", whose Twitter account became a viral <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/painter-who-shared-chinas-covid-protests-with-world-2022-12-14/">conduit</a> for protest information, told Reuters the protests "brought Chinese people's civic awareness to a new stage, and more people realised they need to stand up to protect their rights."翻译:一位被称为“李老师”的意大利华人艺术家和博主，其推特账户成为抗议信息的病毒传播<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/painter-who-shared-chinas-covid-protests-with-world-2022-12-14/">渠道</a>，他告诉路透社，抗议活动“将中国人民的公民意识提升到了一个新的阶段，更多的人意识到他们需要站起来”以保护他们的权利。”</p>   <p>The protests also preceded small-scale acts of subversion this year, including politically charged costumes during <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/halloween-revellers-throng-shanghai-some-wearing-costumes-seen-protest-china-2023-11-01/">Halloween</a> celebrations in Shanghai and widespread <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-former-premier-li-keqiang-has-died-state-media-2023-10-27/">mourning</a> over the death of former Chinese Premier Li Keqiang, who was sidelined by Xi.翻译:这些抗议活动还发生在今年的小规模颠覆活动之前，包括上海<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/halloween-revellers-throng-shanghai-some-wearing-costumes-seen-protest-china-2023-11-01/">万圣节</a>庆祝活动期间穿着带有政治色彩的服装，以及对被习近平排除在外的中国前总理李克强去世的广泛<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-former-premier-li-keqiang-has-died-state-media-2023-10-27/">哀悼</a>。</p>   <p>"I never thought that the protests would resonate so widely with people in China, where there's a high degree of monitoring," said a 30-year-old Guangzhou-based demonstrator.翻译:一名 30 岁的广州示威者表示：“我没想到抗议活动会引起如此广泛的共鸣，因为中国的监控程度很高。”</p>   <p>"I finally realised I'm not alone," she said. "This made me feel less pessimistic about China's future political situation, although I'm still pretty pessimistic!"翻译:“我终于意识到我并不孤单，”她说。 “这让我对中国未来的政治形势不那么悲观了，尽管我还是相当悲观！”</p>   <p>Other China-based participants were more ambivalent, saying they would not publicly commemorate the protests or discuss them among friends due to security concerns and a general unwillingness to revisit memories of the pandemic.翻译:其他中国参与者的态度则更为矛盾，他们表示，出于安全考虑以及普遍不愿重温这场大流行病的记忆，他们不会公开纪念这些抗议活动，也不会在朋友之间讨论这些抗议活动。</p>   <p>One of them, a 28-year-old Beijing tech firm employee, said she and a friend were warned by police not to take part in any activities over the weekend, even though they had not been contracted by the authorities before.翻译:其中一名 28 岁的北京科技公司员工表示，她和一名朋友被警方警告不要在周末参加任何活动，尽管她们之前并未与当局签订合同。</p>   <p>These warnings, and the reality of life in China, may dampen hopes for wider social change, she added.翻译:她补充说，这些警告以及中国的现实生活可能会削弱人们对更广泛的社会变革的希望。</p>   <p>"Even if some young first-time protesters did have a political awakening, this was probably soon overtaken by mundane concerns like the bad economy, property market and high unemployment," she said.翻译:她说：“即使一些年轻的首次抗议者确实有了政治觉醒，但这种觉醒可能很快就会被经济不景气、房地产市场和高失业率等世俗担忧所取代。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Laurie Chen in Beijing and Jessie Pang in Hong Kong; Additional reporting by Casey Hall, Nicoco Chan and Brenda Goh in Shanghai, and Yew Lun Tian in Beijing; editing by Miral Fahmy翻译:Laurie Chen 在北京和 Jessie Pang 在香港的报道； Casey Hall、Nicoco Chan 和 Brenda Goh 在上海以及 Yew Lun Tian 在北京的补充报道；米拉尔·法赫米 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 12:10:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Z4VU5GWWGRNDDAKTPWPSL7MGAU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/one-year-chinas-covid-protesters-caught-between-hope-apathy-2023-11-28/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Laurie Chen, Jessie Pang]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>CORONAVIRUS/PROTESTS (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[第三季离港居民提取退休金按年增1.7%]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/wg0SmxpT3CybR-FIA8CBy5ySYvA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ROV2TAOP7RPC3CNMAYFZWWVHVM.jpg" alt="General view of the city of Hong Kong is seen through a window of the Observation Wheel翻译:透过摩天轮的窗户可以看到香港城市的全景" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>General view of the city of Hong Kong is seen through a window of the Observation Wheel翻译:透过摩天轮的窗户可以看到香港城市的全景, Hong Kong, China September 5, 2019. REUTERS/Amr Abdallah Dalsh/File Photo翻译:2019年9月5日，透过中国香港观景轮的窗户可以看到香港城市的全景。路透社/Amr Abdallah Dalsh/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Residents leaving Hong Kong for good withdrew a total of HK$2.213 billion ($283.72 million) from their Mandatory Provident Fund (MPF) pension accounts in the third quarter of 2023, up 1.7% from a year earlier, government data showed.翻译:政府数据显示，2023年第三季度，永久离开香港的居民从强制性公积金(MPF)养老金账户中提取的资金总额为22.13亿港元(合2.8372亿美元)，同比增长1.7%。</p>   <p>A total of 8,700 claims were made in the July-September quarter, compared with the 8,600 claims taking out HK$2.177 billion during the same period in 2022, data from the Mandatory Provident Fund Schemes Authority (MPFA) showed on Wednesday.翻译:强制性公积金计划管理局（积金局）周三公布的数据显示，7月至9月季度共提出8,700宗申索，而2022年同期为8,600宗，涉及金额达21.77亿港元。</p>   <p>The number of claims was higher than the 7,300 for the April-June quarter and 6,700 claims in January-March that saw withdrawals of a respective HK$1.787 billion and HK$1.573 billion.翻译:索偿人数较四月至六月季度的 7,300 宗及一月至三月的 6,700 宗为高，提取金额分别为 17.87 亿港元及 15.73 亿港元。</p>   <p>Curbs to control the spread of COVID-19 were among the reasons for people leaving Hong Kong, which tracked China's strict zero-COVID-19 policy closely but began easing restrictions in August last year.翻译:控制 COVID-19 传播的限制措施是人们离开香港的原因之一，香港密切关注中国严格的零 COVID-19 政策，但从去年 8 月开始放松限制。</p>   <p>The MPF is a compulsory retirement scheme for Hong Kong residents, with employees and their employers required to make contributions.翻译:强积金是香港居民的强制性退休计划，雇员及其雇主均须缴款。</p>   <p>Border checkpoints were reopened fully in February while all pandemic curbs were lifted from March 1 and authorities have been trying to restore business confidence and lure investors after more than three years of severe COVID-19 measures.翻译:边境检查站于 2 月全面重新开放，而所有大流行限制措施从 3 月 1 日起取消，当局在实施了三年多的严格的 COVID-19 措施后一直在努力恢复商业信心并吸引投资者。</p>   <p>The city's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/hong-kongs-population-climbs-75-million-near-2019-level-2023-08-15/">population increased</a> by 152,000, or 2.1%, from the middle of last year, to 7,498,100 in June this year, marking the first significant uptick since a downward trend began in 2020 due to stringent COVID-19 measures.翻译:今年 6 月，该市<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/hong-kongs-population-climbs-75-million-near-2019-level-2023-08-15/">人口比去年年中增加了</a>152,000 人，即 2.1%，达到 7,498,100 人，这是自 2020 年因严格的 COVID-19 措施而开始下降趋势以来的首次显着上升。</p>   <p>The Mandatory Provident Fund Schemes Authority said multiple claims for pension withdrawals are sometimes made by a single person as a scheme member may have more than one account.翻译:强制性公积金计划管理局表示，由于一名计划成员可能拥有多个账户，有时一人会提出多次提取退休金的申请。</p>   <p>In the third quarter of 2023, the total number of claims - spanning all reasons including retirement - was 68,500, an increase of 18.9% from the previous quarter's 57,600 claims.翻译:2023 年第三季度，涵盖包括退休在内的所有原因的索赔总数为 68,500 起，比上一季度的 57,600 起索赔增加了 18.9%。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.7999 Hong Kong dollars)翻译:(1 美元 = 7.7999 港元)</p>    <span>Reporting by Donny Kwok; Editing by Bernadette Baum翻译:郭敦尼报道；伯纳黛特·鲍姆编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:16:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Z2P4OBDMD5JPVEONSXOVXYJEOI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pension-withdrawals-by-residents-leaving-hong-kong-q3-up-17-year-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HONGKONG</category>
                
                <category>PENSIONS/OUTFLOWS (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[具有里程碑意义的香港国家安全案预计将在3至4个月内判决 - 法官]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/E4zxYUNfo3AAFMiLfKH7MXjMWJY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SWJHBNZIGBNPZBRLDTM37QRCUM.jpg" alt="Owen Chow Ka-shing arrives at West Kowloon Magistrates' Courts building to take part in a hearing, in Hong Kong翻译:周嘉诚抵达香港西九龙裁判法院大楼参加听证会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Owen Chow Ka-shing, one of the 47 pro-democracy activists charged with conspiracy to commit subversion under the national security law, arrives at West Kowloon Magistrates' Courts building, in Hong Kong, China November 29, 2021. REUTERS/Lam Yik/File photo翻译:2021 年 11 月 29 日，被指控串谋颠覆国家安全法的 47 名民主活动人士之一周嘉诚抵达中国香港西九龙裁判法院大楼。 REUTERS/Lam Yik/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A landmark national security trial for 16 Hong Kong democracy activists entered its final stretch on Wednesday, with a verdict expected in early 2024, over two years after they were charged with conspiracy to commit subversion.翻译:对 16 名香港民主活动人士进行的具有里程碑意义的国家安全审判于周三进入最后阶段，预计将于 2024 年初作出判决，距离他们被指控串谋颠覆已有两年多。</p>   <p>On the first day of closing submissions, one of the national security judges, Andrew Chan, said a verdict would "tentatively" come in three to four months, with 10 days set aside for closing submissions.翻译:在结案陈词的第一天，国家安全法官之一安德鲁·陈 (Andrew Chan) 表示，判决将“暂定”在三到四个月内做出，其中有 10 天的时间用于结案陈词。</p>   <p>This is the first official indication of a potential end point for the legal proceedings, which have already stretched over 100 days in court since the trial began on Feb. 6.翻译:这是该法律诉讼程序可能结束的首次正式迹象，自 2 月 6 日审判开始以来，该诉讼程序已经在法庭上持续了 100 多天。</p>   <p>The legal saga began with police raids on more than 50 of the city's leading democrats in early 2021 under a sweeping China-imposed national security law. Some Western governments, including the United States, have criticised the law as a tool of repression.翻译:这场法律传奇始于 2021 年初，根据中国实施的一项全面的国家安全法，警方突袭了该市 50 多名民主党领袖。包括美国在内的一些西方政府批评该法律是镇压工具。</p>   <p>Beijing says the national security law brought stability to the city after months long pro-democracy protests in 2019.翻译:北京表示，在 2019 年持续数月的民主抗议活动之后，国家安全法给这座城市带来了稳定。</p>   <p>The court case could see many leading democrats jailed for life.翻译:该法庭案件可能导致许多民主党领袖被判终身监禁。</p>   <p>Throughout the trial, government prosecutors have accused the democrats of hatching a conspiracy to cause a constitutional crisis and to subvert the authorities by unlawful means.翻译:在整个审判过程中，政府检察官指控民主党策划阴谋引发宪法危机，并以非法手段颠覆当局。</p>   <p>The prosecutors alleged that after organising a primary election aimed at maximising the democratic opposition's chances of a majority in the legislature, the democrats would then seek to "indiscriminately veto" government budgets to push the government to respond to the demands of democratic protesters.翻译:检察官声称，在组织旨在最大限度地提高民主反对派在立法机构获得多数席位的机会的初选后，民主党将寻求“不加区别地否决”政府预算，以迫使政府回应民主抗议者的要求。</p>   <p>The aim was to subvert state power, or force Hong Kong's leader to resign, the prosecutors said.翻译:检察官表示，其目的是颠覆国家政权，或迫使香港领导人辞职。</p>   <p>During the closing submission, prosecutor Jonathan Man argued that it was quite clear that acts of subversion had taken place, even without actual violence.翻译:在结案陈词中，检察官乔纳森·曼 (Jonathan Man) 辩称，即使没有实际的暴力，也很明显发生了颠覆行为。</p>   <p>"Nowadays physical violence would not be necessary," to carry out subversion, Man told the court, saying such acts were often carried out through digital means including social media.翻译:曼告诉法庭，“如今，身体暴力不再是必要的”，以进行颠覆，并表示此类行为通常是通过包括社交媒体在内的数字手段进行的。</p>   <p>"Communication with the public is much easier, (it's) easy to manipulate those means in order to endanger national security," he added.翻译:他补充说：“与公众的沟通更加容易，很容易操纵这些手段来危害国家安全。”</p>   <p>Some defence lawyers argued, however, in their closing submissions that the right to veto a budget is allowed for under the city's mini constitution, the Basic Law.翻译:然而，一些辩护律师在结案陈词中辩称，香港的小宪法《基本法》允许否决预算的权利。</p>   <p>Most of the democrats have been detained for more than 1,000 days since Feb. 28, 2021, on national security grounds, and were subjected to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/hongkong-security-bail/">marathon bail hearings</a>. The case has been repeatedly delayed as prosecutors requested more time to prepare. Only 13 of the original 47 democrats were granted bail.翻译:自2021年2月28日以来，大多数民主党人以国家安全为由被拘留超过1000天，并接受了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/hongkong-security-bail/">马拉松式的保释听证会</a>。由于检察官要求更多时间准备，此案一再被推迟。最初的 47 名民主党人中只有 13 人获准保释。</p>   <p>Thirty-one of the 47 charged have pleaded guilty - which could qualify them for reduced sentences. Only 16 are not pleading guilty, including former journalist Gwyneth Ho; activists Owen Chow and Gordon Ng; and ex-democratic lawmakers Leung Kwok-hung, Lam Cheuk-ting and Helena Wong.翻译:47 名被指控的人中有 31 人已认罪，这可能使他们有资格获得减刑。只有 16 人没有认罪，其中包括前记者 Gwyneth Ho；活动家 Owen Chow 和 Gordon Ng；以及前民主派议员梁国雄、林卓婷和黄海伦。</p>   <p>Those who have pleaded guilty include former law professor Benny Tai and activist Joshua Wong, who will be sentenced after the trial. Four who pleaded guilty have become prosecution witnesses.翻译:已认罪的人包括前法学教授戴耀廷和活动人士黄之锋，他们将在审判后被判刑。四名认罪者已成为控方证人。</p>    <span>Editing by Gerry Doyle and Raju Gopalakrishnan翻译:编辑：Gerry Doyle 和 Raju Gopalakrishnan</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 09:43:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CYYTZNHFQVN5PKY4KP5OEYVCAI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/landmark-hong-kong-national-security-case-verdict-expected-3-4-months-judge-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jessie Pang, James Pomfret]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HONGKONG</category>
                
                <category>SECURITY/ (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[政策措施出台后，中国新房价格今年将攀升]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li></li>  <li>New home prices will likely rise in 2024</li>  <li>Property sales, investment seen continuing to slide next year</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li></li><li> 2024年新房价格可能上涨</li><li>明年房地产销售和投资预计将继续下滑</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/48pA01IRfufQdwGR2BydNsAmlKc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/R3GENPWFXZN7RGKWQ6AN3GK3ZM.jpg" alt="A woman rides a scooter past residential buildings at an Evergrande residential complex in Beijing翻译:一名女子骑着摩托车经过北京恒大住宅小区的居民楼" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A woman rides a scooter past residential buildings at an Evergrande residential complex in Beijing翻译:一名女子骑着摩托车经过北京恒大住宅小区的居民楼, China September 27, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo翻译:2023 年 9 月 27 日，一名女子骑着摩托车经过中国北京恒大住宅区的住宅楼。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Prices of new homes in China are now expected to climb 3% this year after a slew of policy measures to support the country's beleaguered property market, up from earlier expectations for prices to be flat, a Reuters poll showed.翻译:路透调查显示，在采取一系列政策措施支持中国陷入困境的房地产市场后，中国新房价格预计今年将上涨 3%，高于此前价格持平的预期。</p>   <p>But the poll of 11 economists, conducted Nov. 20-28, also showed expectations for 1% growth in new home prices in 2024 were little changed from an August poll. Economists said more measures from authorities are needed.翻译:但 11 月 20 日至 28 日对 11 名经济学家进行的民意调查也显示，对 2024 年新房价格增长 1% 的预期与 8 月的民意调查相比几乎没有变化。经济学家表示，当局需要采取更多措施。</p>   <p>Defaults on debt payments by many developers in China's cash-squeezed and highly indebted property sector have sparked fears of a broader financial crisis, weighed on consumer confidence and hindered economic growth.翻译:中国现金紧张且负债累累的房地产行业许多开发商拖欠债务，引发了人们对更广泛的金融危机的担忧，打压了消费者信心并阻碍了经济增长。</p>   <p>Authorities, particularly those in major cities, have embarked on a string of steps to bolster demand, including allowing smaller down payments, easing curbs on home buying such as the number of homes that can be bought, lowering borrowing costs and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-vows-support-property-sector-tackle-local-debt-2023-11-17/">encouraging the extension of loans</a>.翻译:当局，特别是大城市的当局，已采取一系列措施来提振需求，包括允许减少首付、放宽对购房的限制（例如可购买的房屋数量）、降低借贷成本以及<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-vows-support-property-sector-tackle-local-debt-2023-11-17/">鼓励延长贷款期限</a>。</p>   <p>But most analysts believe these actions must be complemented by <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-needs-pull-multiple-levers-property-turnaround-say-analysts-2023-11-17/">stronger fiscal and monetary action</a>.翻译:但大多数分析师认为，这些行动必须辅之以<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-needs-pull-multiple-levers-property-turnaround-say-analysts-2023-11-17/">更强有力的财政和货币行动</a>。</p>   <p>"There is still room for easing property policies in major cities in 2024 ... The market in first and second tier cities will continue to outperform third and fourth cities next year, " said Huang Yu, an analyst at real estate research firm China Index Academy.翻译:房地产研究公司中国指数分析师黄宇表示，“2024年主要城市房地产政策仍有宽松空间……明年一二线城市市场将继续跑赢三四线城市”学院。</p>   <p>Estimates for home unit sales for 2023 were revised down to an 8% slide compared with predictions of a 5% drop in August, the poll also showed. Economists also expect declines next year, predicting a 5% fall.翻译:民意调查还显示，与 8 月份预测的下降 5% 相比，2023 年房屋销售预期下调至 8%。经济学家还预计明年将出现下降，预计下降 5%。</p>   <p>"The key reason is that homebuyer confidence has not yet been fully rebuilt," said Wang Xingping, a senior analyst at Fitch Bohua.翻译:惠誉博华高级分析师王兴平表示：“关键原因是购房者信心尚未完全重建。”</p>   <p>According to the poll, property investment is expected to slump 10% in 2023 and then 8.4% in 2024.翻译:调查显示，预计 2023 年房地产投资将下降 10%，2024 年将下降 8.4%。</p>   <p>Regulators are drafting a list of 50 property <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-puts-country-garden-draft-list-builders-support-bloomberg-news-2023-11-22/">developers</a> eligible for a range of financing support, including Country Garden <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">(2007.HK)</a> and state-backed China Vanke <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/000002.SZ" target="_blank">(000002.SZ)</a>, Bloomberg reported last week.翻译:据彭博社上周报道，监管机构正在起草一份有资格获得一系列融资支持的 50 家房地产<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-puts-country-garden-draft-list-builders-support-bloomberg-news-2023-11-22/">开发商</a>名单，其中包括碧桂园<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">(2007.HK)</a>和国家支持的万科<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/000002.SZ" target="_blank">(000002.SZ)</a> 。</p>   <p>(For other stories from the Reuters quarterly housing market polls)翻译:（有关路透社季度房地产市场民意调查的其他报道）</p>    <span>Reporting by Liangping Gao and Ryan Woo; Editing by翻译:高亮平、吴瑞安报道；编辑者</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 09:13:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">IPXEJT322ZOGDPIRVSOQGRGPTQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-new-home-prices-now-seen-climbing-this-year-after-policy-steps-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Liangping Gao, Ryan Woo]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHNA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/ (POLL, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国最高外交官王毅将于周四访问越南 - 消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/8FaNuojFWh1xX5WXkMpRgTxOkeI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/45GFL7FAMRKDRPPRQQBJECYP7A.jpg" alt="Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi attends a press conference in Beijing翻译:中国外交部长王毅在北京出席记者会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi attends a press conference on the white paper on "A Global Community of Shared Future: China's Proposals and Actions", in Beijing, China September 26, 2023. REUTERS/Shubing Wang/File photo翻译:2023年9月26日，中国外交部长王毅在中国北京出席《构建人类命运共同体：中国的主张与行动》白皮书记者会。路透社/王书兵/资料图</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's top diplomat Wang Yi will visit Vietnam from Thursday, two Vietnamese sources with knowledge of trip said on Wednesday.翻译:两名越南消息人士周三表示，中国最高外交官王毅将从周四开始访问越南。</p>   <p>"He is expected to attend a Vietnam-China inter-government meeting in Hanoi on Friday," one of the sources said.翻译:一位消息人士称：“预计他将于周五出席在河内举行的越南-中国政府间会议。”</p>   <p>Vietnam's and China's foreign ministries did not immediately respond to a requests for comment.翻译:越南和中国外交部没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>China has had traditionally strong ties with Vietnam since diplomatic relations were established in 1950, despite a brief war in 1979.翻译:自 1950 年建交以来，中国与越南传统上一直保持着牢固的关系，尽管 1979 年发生了短暂的战争。</p>   <p>China is Vietnam's largest trading partner and a vital source of imports for its manufacturing sector.翻译:中国是越南最大的贸易伙伴，也是越南制造业的重要进口来源地。</p>   <p>China's Commerce Minister Wang Wentao on Monday during a visit to Vietnam pledged to further open the Chinese market to Vietnamese agricultural products as the two countries seek to deepen trade ties, according to Vietnam's Ministry of Industry and Trade.翻译:据越南工贸部称，中国商务部部长王文涛周一在访问越南期间承诺，随着两国寻求深化贸易关系，将进一步向越南农产品开放中国市场。</p>   <p>Reuters last month reported that Vietnamese and Chinese officials were preparing for a possible trip by Chinese President Xi Jinping to Hanoi. At the time, plans were for the trip to take place at the end of October or in early November. Three Hanoi-based diplomats subsequently said the visit was likely to be postponed to December.翻译:路透社上个月报道称，越南和中国官员正在为中国国家主席习近平可能访问河内做准备。当时计划在十月底或十一月初进行这次旅行。三名驻河内外交官随后表示，此次访问可能会推迟到 12 月。</p>   <p>Bilateral trade between Vietnam and China rose 5.5% last year to $175.5 billion, with shipments from China to Vietnam accounting for 67%, according to the ministry.翻译:据越南商务部称，去年越南和中国的双边贸易增长了5.5%，达到1755亿美元，其中中国对越南的出口额占67%。</p>    <span>Reporting by Hanoi bureau, additional reporting by Ryan Woo in Beijing; Editing by Kanupriya Kapoor翻译:河内分社报道，北京吴瑞安补充报道；卡努普里亚·卡普尔 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 05:02:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">P2GB2Q5GHNJQFDB5LSO5C2BZ7Q</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/chinas-top-diplomat-wang-yi-visit-vietnam-thursday-sources-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>VIETNAM</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国11月份工厂活动可能连续第二个月收缩]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ThZdlkaNrqi9xkIsprX5Fx04L5w=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MXX5ZK4ZHFIZXDB32HX222DIAQ.jpg" alt="Leapmotor's EV production line in Jinhua翻译:零跑汽车金华电动车生产线" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Robotic arms assemble cars in the production line for Leapmotor's electric vehicles at a factory in Jinhua, Zhejiang province, China, April 26, 2023. China Daily via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:2023 年 4 月 26 日，中国浙江省金华市一家工厂，机械臂在零跑电动汽车生产线上组装汽车。《中国日报》来自路透社/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's manufacturing activity likely contracted for a second consecutive month in November, a Reuters poll showed on Wednesday, keeping alive calls for further stimulus measures as factory owners struggle for orders both at home and abroad.翻译:路透社周三的一项民意调查显示，中国11月份制造业活动可能连续第二个月萎缩，在工厂主努力争取国内外订单之际，要求采取进一步刺激措施的呼声依然高涨。</p>   <p>While the official purchasing managers' index (PMI) is expected to have improved to 49.7 in November from last month's unexpected drop to 49.5, the median forecast of 31 economists in a Reuters poll has the index staying below the 50-point level demarcating contraction from expansion.翻译:虽然官方采购经理人指数 (PMI) 预计 11 月将从上个月意外下降的 49.5 改善至 49.7，但路透调查中 31 名经济学家的预测中值显示，该指数仍低于 50 点的水平，标志着经济萎缩。扩张。</p>   <p>Economists appear in agreement that the economy is still largely struggling for traction despite some signs of green shoots in mixed October data, with all respondents returning readings between 49.0 and 50.2 and the vast majority predicting a small contraction of between 49.6 and 49.8.翻译:经济学家们似乎一致认为，尽管 10 月份混合数据出现了一些复苏迹象，但经济在很大程度上仍难以获得牵引力，所有受访者的读数都在 49.0 至 50.2 之间，绝大多数人预测将出现小幅收缩，在 49.6 至 49.8 之间。</p>   <p>The world's second-largest economy has been unable to mount a strong post-COVID recovery this year as a deep crisis in the property market, local government debt risks, slow global growth and geopolitical tensions dented momentum.翻译:由于房地产市场的深度危机、地方政府债务风险、全球经济增长缓慢和地缘政治紧张局势削弱了经济增长势头，全球第二大经济体今年未能在疫情后实现强劲复苏。</p>   <p>A flurry of policy support measures has had only a modest effect, raising pressure on authorities to roll out more stimulus.翻译:一系列政策支持措施收效甚微，加大了当局推出更多刺激措施的压力。</p>   <p>Profit growth at China's industrial firms <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-industrial-profits-fall-78-jan-oct-2023-11-27/">shrank</a> back to the low single digits last month, following an 11.9% increase in September and a 17.2% gain in August, which analysts attributed to volatile input costs. Both new export and import orders shrank in October.翻译:继9月份增长11.9%和8月份增长17.2%之后，中国工业企业利润增速上个月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-industrial-profits-fall-78-jan-oct-2023-11-27/">回落</a>至低个位数，分析师将其归因于投入成本波动。 10月份新出口和进口订单均出现萎缩。</p>   <p>The sputtering recovery has prompted many analysts to warn that China may begin <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">flirting</a> with Japan-style stagnation later this decade unless policymakers take steps to reorientate the economy towards household consumption and market-allocation of resources.翻译:缓慢的复苏促使许多分析师警告称，除非政策制定者采取措施将经济重新定位为家庭消费和资源市场配置，否则中国可能会在本十年晚些时候开始<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">陷入</a>日本式的停滞。</p>   <p>China's central bank governor <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">said</a> on Tuesday he was "confident that China will enjoy healthy and sustainable growth in 2024 and beyond," but urged structural reforms to reduce reliance on infrastructure and property for growth.翻译:中国央行行长周二<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">表示，</a>他“相信中国将在2024年及以后实现健康、可持续的增长”，但敦促进行结构性改革，减少增长对基础设施和房地产的依赖。</p>   <p>Policy advisers say the government will need to implement further stimulus should it wish to sustain an annual economic growth target of 'around 5%' next year, which would match this year's goal.翻译:政策顾问表示，如果政府希望明年维持“5%左右”的年度经济增长目标（这将与今年的目标相匹配），那么政府将需要实施进一步的刺激措施。</p>   <p>The official PMI will be released on Thursday. The private Caixin factory survey will be issued on Friday, and analysts expect its reading to edge up to 49.8 from 49.5 in October.翻译:官方采购经理人指数将于周四发布。私营财新工厂调查将于周五发布，分析师预计其读数将从 10 月份的 49.5 升至 49.8。</p>    <span>Reporting by Joe Cash; Polling by Susobhan Sarkar and Devayani Sathyan in Bangalore; Editing by Kim Coghill翻译:乔·卡什报道； Susobhan Sarkar 和 Devayani Sathyan 在班加罗尔进行的民意调查；编辑：金·科吉尔</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 04:41:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">J67PW3Q2FBMNNKVGN7I3Z2JMQQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-nov-factory-activity-likely-contracted-second-month-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Joe Cash]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/PMI (UPDATE 1, POLL)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[负债累累的中国地方政府争相发行210亿美元专项债券救助小银行]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/WDwjuJTfojue9CkpS7a75cuxrlQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KFAJWWAST5N7RK5QWKER2ZVTLU.jpg" alt="Chinese national flag flutters at the headquarters of a commercial bank on a financial street near the headquarters of the People's Bank of China, China's central bank, in central Beijing翻译:位于北京市中心中国人民银行总部附近的金融街上，中国国旗在一家商业银行总部飘扬" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Chinese national flag flutters at the headquarters of a commercial bank on a financial street near the headquarters of the People's Bank of China, China's central bank, in central Beijing翻译:位于北京市中心中国人民银行总部附近的金融街上，中国国旗在一家商业银行总部飘扬 November 24, 2014. REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Local governments in China have sold record amounts of so-called special bonds this year to inject capital into struggling smaller banks, as authorities seek to contain spillover risks from a deepening property crisis and a sputtering economy.翻译:中国地方政府今年发行了创纪录数量的所谓特别债券，为陷入困境的小型银行注入资金，当局试图遏制房地产危机加深和经济不景气带来的溢出风险。</p>   <p>Special-purpose bonds are a form of off-budget debt financing used by local governments in China, with the proceeds raised typically earmarked for specific policy goals, such as spending on infrastructure projects.翻译:特殊用途债券是中国地方政府使用的一种预算外债务融资形式，筹集的资金通常专门用于特定的政策目标，例如基础设施项目支出。</p>   <p>Local governments plan to use the proceeds of the latest bond sales to purchase equity or convertible bonds from smaller banks, most of them state-owned, effectively recapitalising them, according to the deal prospectuses.翻译:交易招股说明书显示，地方政府计划利用最新发债所得的资金，从规模较小的银行（其中大多数是国有银行）购买股权或可转换债券，从而有效地对这些银行进行资本重组。</p>   <p>The governments have raised 152.3 billion yuan ($21.05 billion) via such bonds so far in 2023 to replenish the capital of small and medium-sized banks, according to data from the official China Electronic Local Government Bond Market Access.翻译:根据中国电子地方政府债券市场准入的官方数据，2023年迄今为止，政府已通过此类债券筹集了1523亿元人民币（210.5亿美元），以补充中小型银行的资本。</p>   <p>But total funds raised so far are modest compared to the banks' needs, analysts say.翻译:但分析师表示，与银行的需求相比，迄今为止筹集的资金总额并不多。</p>   <p>China's small, regional banks would need to address a capital shortfall of an estimated 2.2 trillion yuan based on a scenario where up to 20% of regional lenders face capital inadequacy, according to an October report by S&amp;P Global Ratings.翻译:标准普尔全球评级公司 10 月份的一份报告显示，如果高达 20% 的地区性银行面临资本不足的情况，中国小型地区性银行将需要解决估计 2.2 万亿元人民币的资本短缺问题。</p>   <p>Highlighting Beijing's push to avoid a financial crisis like the one in 2008, the value of special-purpose bonds issued this year is already more than double the 63 billion yuan issued in 2022, and is the highest on record since such instruments were introduced in 2020 to help smaller lenders impacted by the COVID-19 pandemic.翻译:今年发行的特殊用途债券的价值已经是2022年发行的630亿元人民币的两倍多，并且是自2020年推出此类工具以来的最高记录，突显了北京为避免2008年那样的金融危机所做的努力帮助受 COVID-19 大流行影响的小型贷方。</p>   <p>The trend highlights how more and more of the country's smaller banks are being propped up with government support, amid a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/">deepening crisis</a> in the property market, which accounts for about a quarter of the economy.翻译:这一趋势突显出，在占经济约四分之一的房地产市场<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/">危机日益加深</a>之际，越来越多的中国小型银行得到了政府的支持。</p>   <p>Authorities have been ramping up measures to support real estate, including relaxing home purchase restrictions and lowering borrowing costs, although these have failed to shore up a meaningful recovery.翻译:当局一直在加大支持房地产的措施，包括放宽购房限制和降低借贷成本，尽管这些措施未能支撑有意义的复苏。</p>   <p>The People's Bank of China (PBOC) and the National Financial Regulatory Administration (NFRA) did not respond to Reuters request for comment.</p>    <h 1="">DEEPER IN DEBT</h>  <p>The intensified efforts to support smaller banks also come amid growing worries about the impact of ballooning local government debt on the economy.翻译:在加大力度支持小型银行之际，人们越来越担心地方政府债务不断膨胀对经济的影响。</p>   <p>Local government debt reached 92 trillion yuan ($12.6 trillion), or 76% of China's economic output in 2022, up from 62.2% in 2019, according to the latest data from the International Monetary Fund.翻译:根据国际货币基金组织的最新数据，到2022年，地方政府债务将达到92万亿元人民币（12.6万亿美元），占中国经济产出的76%，高于2019年的62.2%。</p>   <p>While policymakers are highly concerned over rising debt levels, Beijing has little option but to support smaller banks to contain spillover risks, analysts said.翻译:分析师表示，尽管政策制定者高度关注债务水平上升，但北京别无选择，只能支持规模较小的银行遏制溢出风险。</p>   <p>"It is important to avoid any failures of even the smallest institutions, as a single failure could generate knock-on effects and spread financial contagion to other financial institutions," said Gavekal Dragonomics researcher Zhang Xiaoxi.翻译:龙洲经讯研究员张晓曦表示：“即使是最小的机构，也要避免出现任何倒闭，因为单一的倒闭可能会产生连锁反应，并将金融危机蔓延到其他金融机构。”</p>   <p>It was not immediately clear if the central authorities had given any guidance to the local governments on recapitalising smaller banks, and who were the buyers of these special-purpose bonds.翻译:目前尚不清楚中央是否已就小型银行资本重组向地方政府提供任何指导，以及这些特殊用途债券的买家是谁。</p>   <p>Some provinces are accelerating plans to reform and defuse risks at local, high-risk small and medium-sized banks and to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">replenish capital</a> via multiple channels, central bank governor Pan Gongsheng said in Beijing earlier this month.</p>    <h 1="">CONTAGION RISK</h>  <p>Local governments and banks are fundamental to China's economy, with Beijing tasking provincial and city officials with meeting ambitious growth targets.翻译:地方政府和银行对中国经济至关重要，北京向省市官员下达了实现雄心勃勃的增长目标的任务。</p>   <p>But after years of over-investment in infrastructure, plummeting returns from land sales, and soaring COVID costs, economists say debt-laden municipalities now represent a major risk to the world's second-largest economy.翻译:但经济学家表示，经过多年的基础设施过度投资、土地销售回报大幅下降以及新冠疫情成本飙升，负债累累的城市现在对世界第二大经济体构成了重大风险。</p>   <p>The issuance of fresh debt by the local governments to recapitalise banks, coming at a time when their own liabilities are growing rapidly, could make the financial balancing act for municipalities even more precarious.翻译:地方政府在自身负债迅速增长之际发行新债以对银行进行资本重组，可能会使市政当局的财务平衡行为变得更加不稳定。</p>   <p>On top of $21 billion raised so far this year, the Henan provincial government last week announced a plan to issue 28.2 billion yuan worth of special purpose bonds to recapitalise 26 local banks, according to the government website.</p>    <h 1="">WEAK LINKS</h>  <p>Smaller regional banks are the weak links in China's $61 trillion financial sector, due to their industrial, sectoral and geographical concentration, opaque governance, and lack of stringent regulatory oversight.翻译:由于行业、部门和地域集中、治理不透明以及缺乏严格的监管，小型区域性银行是中国 61 万亿美元金融部门的薄弱环节。</p>   <p>As of end-September, China's rural commercial banks reported a 3.18% non-performing loan ratio with city commercial banks at 1.91%, data from the NFRA showed, higher than the average of 1.61% in the banking sector.翻译:NFRA数据显示，截至9月底，中国农村商业银行不良贷款率为3.18%，城市商业银行不良贷款率为1.91%，高于银行业1.61%的平均水平。</p>   <p>Many analysts believe the real amount of soured loans is far higher.翻译:许多分析师认为，不良贷款的实际数量要高得多。</p>   <p>Smaller Chinese banks face greater challenges in raising funds to replenish their balance sheets compared with their large peers, because of their lower creditworthiness, limited operating scope and risk profiles.翻译:与大型银行相比，规模较小的中国银行在筹集资金补充资产负债表方面面临更大的挑战，因为它们的信用度较低，经营范围和风险状况有限。</p>   <p>Among the top issuers of the special bonds this year are debt-laden provincial governments in Liaoning, Yunnan and the government in Inner Mongolia region, which aim to use the proceeds to recapitalise local banks.翻译:今年特别债券的最大发行者是负债累累的辽宁省、云南省政府和内蒙古地区政府，它们的目的是利用所得资金对当地银行进行资本重组。</p>   <p>Regional banks operating primarily in weaker regions heavily exposed to indebted local government financing vehicles bear higher credit risks than their peers in wealthy regions, S&amp;P analysts said in last month's research note.翻译:标准普尔分析师在上个月的研究报告中表示，主要在实力较弱地区运营、地方政府融资工具负债累累的地区性银行比富裕地区的同行承担更高的信贷风险。</p>   <p>"Local governments are a likely the first line of defense whenever regional banks become stressed," they said. "Nevertheless, we expect local-government support to strained lenders will be selective."翻译:他们表示：“每当地区性银行面临压力时，地方政府可能是第一道防线。” “尽管如此，我们预计地方政府对紧张的贷方的支持将是有选择性的。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Ziyi Tang and Ryan Woo; Editing by Sumeet Chatterjee and Kim Coghill翻译:唐子仪和吴瑞安报道；编辑：Sumeet Chatterjee 和 Kim Coghill</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 01:58:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">LE35VK4SHVM3XL6PFWDU2NUNDU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/debt-laden-chinas-local-governments-scramble-rescue-small-banks-with-21-bln-2023-11-28/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ziyi Tang, Ryan Woo]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>LOCALGOVERNMENT/BANKS (ANALYSIS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国恒大集团对母公司提起法律诉讼]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/x1Un4BLp4DPSUue4O3jzAcJENxA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/N6SYACE4HVNN7JLTSD4D725HUE.jpg" alt="The company logo is seen on the headquarters of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen翻译:中国恒大集团深圳总部的公司标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The company logo is seen on the headquarters of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen翻译:中国恒大集团深圳总部的公司标志, Guangdong province, China September 26, 2021. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2021年9月26日，该公司标志出现在中国广东省深圳的中国恒大集团总部。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Evergrande Property Services Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">(6666.HK)</a> said on Tuesday one of its units had commenced legal proceedings against Hengda Real Estate Group Company and embattled developer China Evergrande <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a>, among others.翻译:恒大物业服务集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">（6666.HK）</a>周二表示，其旗下之一已对恒大地产集团公司和陷入困境的开发商中国恒大<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）</a>等公司提起法律诉讼。</p>   <p>The unit, Jinbi Property Management Company, has commenced the proceedings for the recovery of about 2 billion yuan ($279.60 million) deposit certificate pledge guarantees.翻译:该单位金碧物业管理公司已启动追回约20亿元人民币（2.796亿美元）存单质押担保的程序。</p>   <p>The proceedings are related to the enforcement of Evergrande Property Services' deposit pledge of about 13.4 billion yuan.翻译:该诉讼涉及恒大物业约134亿元存款质押的执行。</p>   <p>Jinbi Property has also commenced legal proceedings against Shenzhen Qihang Metals Materials Company, Guizhou Guangjuyuan Real Estate Development and Hengda Real Estate Group Guiyang Property.翻译:金碧置业还对深圳市启航金属材料公司、贵州广聚源房地产开发有限公司和恒大地产集团贵阳置业提起法律诉讼。</p>   <p>In February, parent Evergrande had <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/china-evergrande-says-directors-fell-below-standards-property-unit-probe-2023-02-15/">said</a> it was in talks with Evergrande Property Services to repay the funds.翻译:今年2月，母公司恒大集团曾<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/china-evergrande-says-directors-fell-below-standards-property-unit-probe-2023-02-15/">表示</a>，正在与恒大物业洽谈偿还资金事宜。</p>   <p>In <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-ceo-cfo-step-down-after-probe-into-property-services-unit-2022-07-22/">July 2022</a>, Evergrande's chief executive and its finance head resigned after a preliminary probe found their involvement in diverting loans secured by Evergrande Property Services.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-ceo-cfo-step-down-after-probe-into-property-services-unit-2022-07-22/">2022年7月</a>，恒大首席执行官和财务负责人因涉嫌挪用恒大物业担保贷款而辞职。</p>   <p>Evergrande was investigating how deposits worth 13.4 billion yuan belonging to Evergrande Property Services were used as collateral for pledge guarantees and seized by banks.翻译:恒大正在调查恒大物业的134亿元存款如何被用作质押担保的抵押品，并被银行扣押。</p>   <p>Evergrande Property Services has received a notice from the Guangzhou Intermediate People's Court of Guangdong Province formally accepting the filing of the case, it said on Tuesday.翻译:恒大物业周二表示，已收到广东省广州市中级人民法院正式立案的通知。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1532 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.1532 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Echha Jain in Bengaluru; Editing by Devika Syamnath翻译:Echha Jain 班加罗尔报道；编辑：德维卡·萨姆纳特</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 13:07:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">JIINBKCETFJFXLK3K5BKG42UHY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-evergrande-unit-commences-legal-proceedings-against-parent-2023-11-28/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/DEBT</category>
                
                <category>CHINA EVERGRANDE (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国在供应链博览会上反击西方的去风险策略]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>China warns protectionism, geopolitical tensions threaten supply chains</li>  <li>China says wants closer supply chain ties with all</li>  <li>US, EU greenfield investment into China dropped $100 billion between 2018-2022 - study</li>  <li>US, EU 'de-risking' strategies overplay risk level - analysts</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>中国警告保护主义、地缘政治紧张局势威胁供应链</li><li>中国表示希望与所有国家建立更紧密的供应链联系</li><li>研究显示，2018年至2022年间，美国和欧盟对华绿地投资减少1000亿美元</li><li>分析师称美国和欧盟的“去风险”策略夸大了风险水平</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/azs25QB5WbLNhWYewZCFlH9HE4Y=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/A3DE7EUX7BOHDI63EQQMGXJQRU.jpg" alt="Chinese Premier Li Qiang speaks at the China International Supply Chain Expo in Beijing翻译:北京中国国际供应链博览会翻译:中国国务院总理李强在北京中国国际供应链博览会上发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Premier Li Qiang speaks at the opening ceremony of the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing, China November 28, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo翻译:中国国务院总理李强于 2023 年 11 月 28 日在中国北京举行的首届中国国际供应链博览会 (CISCE) 开幕式上发表讲话。 REUTERS/Florence Lo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/RZIrHgi9cZGBL1nhXNUf3e8NV_8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2G3HNXLWMRI4TMMYHXOVLY4TKE.jpg" alt="Chinese Premier Li Qiang speaks at the China International Supply Chain Expo in Beijing翻译:北京中国国际供应链博览会翻译:中国国务院总理李强在北京中国国际供应链博览会上发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Premier Li Qiang speaks at the opening ceremony of the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing, China November 28, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo翻译:中国国务院总理李强于 2023 年 11 月 28 日在中国北京举行的首届中国国际供应链博览会 (CISCE) 开幕式上发表讲话。 REUTERS/Florence Lo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/fKLLra-cumnbkK1hmadsY8KUJmQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YBYI5KXWYBKU7HUIMM5I37MLAY.jpg" alt="China International Supply Chain Expo in Beijing翻译:北京中国国际供应链博览会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A staff member cleans a display showing the locations of battery maker CATL's production bases, at the CATL booth during the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing, China November 28, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo翻译:2023 年 11 月 28 日，在中国北京举行的首届中国国际供应链博览会 (CISCE) 期间，一名工作人员在宁德时代展位上清理显示电池制造商宁德时代生产基地位置的显示屏。路透社/Florence Lo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/QiG9rscvMx9R6SmtszIN6Dj3bP0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/H2ABVETE7RPRRDE5TC6VEXXXVY.jpg" alt="Chinese Premier Li Qiang speaks at the China International Supply Chain Expo in Beijing翻译:北京中国国际供应链博览会翻译:中国国务院总理李强在北京中国国际供应链博览会上发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Premier Li Qiang delivers the keynote speech at the opening ceremony of the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing, China November 28, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo翻译:2023年11月28日，中国国务院总理李强在中国北京首届中国国际供应链博览会（CISCE）开幕式上发表主旨演讲。 REUTERS/Florence Lo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/bEjLDo6JmmQfZ-LRLUyphOU62ms=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NDLJ5AJ3DFI33AX3PGRQKPJILM.jpg" alt="Chinese Premier Li Qiang speaks at the China International Supply Chain Expo in Beijing翻译:北京中国国际供应链博览会翻译:中国国务院总理李强在北京中国国际供应链博览会上发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Premier Li Qiang applauds during his keynote speech at the opening ceremony of the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing, China November 28, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo翻译:中国总理李强于 2023 年 11 月 28 日在中国北京举行的首届中国国际供应链博览会 (CISCE) 开幕式上发表主旨演讲并表示赞赏。 REUTERS/Florence Lo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/-oJxget0HJBkLCJk1aY7zj2D_0g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/STQU4DO6MZLMPP5OMO4K7U5NNM.jpg" alt="Chinese Premier Li Qiang speaks at the China International Supply Chain Expo in Beijing翻译:北京中国国际供应链博览会翻译:中国国务院总理李强在北京中国国际供应链博览会上发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Premier Li Qiang speaks at the opening ceremony of the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE) in Beijing, China November 28, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo翻译:中国国务院总理李强于 2023 年 11 月 28 日在中国北京举行的首届中国国际供应链博览会 (CISCE) 开幕式上发表讲话。 REUTERS/Florence Lo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/MN77JWejFhzfsTgUXNIPSDhYNXw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BXAZGJ4XWJMDLOHAHXZKOZSLUY.jpg" alt="ASEAN Summit in Jakarta翻译:东盟峰会在雅加达举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>China's Premier Li Qiang speaks during the 26th ASEAN-China Summit at the 43rd ASEAN Summit in Jakarta翻译:东盟峰会在雅加达举行, Indonesia, on September 6, 2023. Yasuyoshi Chiba/Pool via REUTERS/File photo翻译:中国国务院总理李强于 2023 年 9 月 6 日在印度尼西亚雅加达举行的第 43 届东盟峰会上，在第 26 次东盟-中国峰会上发表讲话。Yasuyoshi Chiba/Pool via REUTERS/资料照片</figcaption></figure>                         <p>China opposes protectionism and wants to strengthen supply chains with all countries, Premier Li Qiang said on Tuesday, as a growing number of nations voice concern at how much their supply chains depend on the world's second largest economy.翻译:中国总理李强周二表示，中国反对保护主义，希望加强与所有国家的供应链，越来越多的国家对其供应链对世界第二大经济体的依赖程度表示担忧。</p>   <p>Li's comments comes amid calls over the past year from the United States and the European Union to reduce their dependence on China in certain sectors and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/eus-borrell-warns-china-de-risking-may-speed-up-if-imbalances-persist-2023-10-13/">"de-risk" their supply chains</a>, as well as efforts to cut off Chinese enterprises from some advanced semiconductors.翻译:李克强发表上述言论之际，美国和欧盟在过去一年中呼吁减少在某些领域对中国的依赖并<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/eus-borrell-warns-china-de-risking-may-speed-up-if-imbalances-persist-2023-10-13/">“降低供应链风险”</a> ，并努力切断中国企业对某些先进半导体的供应。</p>   <p>"We are willing to build closer production and industrial supply chain partnerships with all countries," Li told the first China International Supply Chain Expo (CISCE), adding that the international community needs to be "more wary of the challenges and risks brought about by protectionism and uncontrolled globalisation."翻译:李克强在首届中国国际供应链博览会上表示：“我们愿意与各国建立更紧密的生产和产业供应链伙伴关系。”他补充说，国际社会需要“更加警惕供应链带来的挑战和风险”。保护主义和不受控制的全球化。”</p>   <p>Recent geopolitical tensions, from Russia's war in Ukraine to concerns over a future Chinese invasion of Taiwan, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/mood-swing-global-producers-us-hunt-china-alternatives-2023-10-23/">have led a growing number of foreign businesses</a> to opt against expanding their supply chains in China, instead directing investment to countries including India, Mexico and Vietnam that enjoy better ties with the United States, a strategy known as China-plus-one.翻译:最近的地缘政治紧张局势，从俄罗斯在乌克兰的战争，到对中国未来入侵台湾的担忧， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/mood-swing-global-producers-us-hunt-china-alternatives-2023-10-23/">导致越来越多的外国企业</a>选择不扩大在中国的供应链，而是将投资转向印度、墨西哥和越南等享有便利条件的国家。与美国建立更好的关系，这一战略被称为“中国加一”。</p>   <p>The expo, organised by the state-run China Council for the Promotion of International Trade (CCPIT), is Beijing's latest bid to increase foreign investment in China, which has dropped to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-first-deficit-foreign-investment-signals-wests-de-risking-pressure-2023-11-06/">historic lows</a>.翻译:此次进博会由国营的中国国际贸易促进委员会（CCPIT）主办，是北京为增加对华外国投资而采取的最新举措，目前中国的外国投资已降至<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-first-deficit-foreign-investment-signals-wests-de-risking-pressure-2023-11-06/">历史低点</a>。</p>   <p>The value of announced U.S. and European greenfield investment into China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/western-firms-shift-investment-china-india-worries-mount-2023-09-13/">dropped</a> to less than $20 billion last year, from a peak of $120 billion in 2018, according to Rhodium Group, while investment into India shot up by some $65 billion or 400% between 2021 and 2022.翻译:根据荣鼎集团的数据，美国和欧洲宣布的对华绿地投资额从 2018 年 1200 亿美元的峰值<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/western-firms-shift-investment-china-india-worries-mount-2023-09-13/">降至</a>去年的不足 200 亿美元，而对印度的投资在 2021 年至 2021 年期间猛增约 650 亿美元，即 400%。 2022 年。</p>   <p>Despite this decrease, China remains an attractive option: a survey conducted by HSBC bank at the China International Import Expo (CIIE) earlier this month showed 45% of firms expect to expand their supply chain in China over the next year.翻译:尽管下降，中国仍然是一个有吸引力的选择：汇丰银行本月早些时候在中国国际进口博览会（CIIE）上进行的一项调查显示，45%的企业预计明年将扩大在中国的供应链。</p>   <p>"I think there is a lot of hyperbole around this. And I'm not sure whether the (de-risking) measures the EU or U.S. are considering match the scale of the risk," said Dan Marks, research fellow for energy security at the Royal United Services think tank.翻译:“我认为这有很多夸张的成分。而且我不确定欧盟或美国正在考虑的（去风险）措施是否与风险的规模相匹配，”能源安全研究员丹·马克斯说。皇家联合军种智囊团。</p>   <p>An apparent improvement in U.S.-Sino ties, after Chinese President Xi Jinping recently met U.S. President Joe Biden and participated in the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Summit, should also help reinforce China's position as a key manufacturing hub.翻译:在中国国家主席习近平最近会见美国总统乔·拜登并参加亚太经合组织（APEC）峰会之后，中美关系明显改善，也应有助于巩固中国作为主要制造业中心的地位。</p>   <p>Zhang Shaogang, a CCPIT official who was part of the Chinese delegation at the APEC summit, said last week that 20% of the foreign firms exhibiting at the supply chain expo were U.S.-based, and included Amazon <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AMZN.O" target="_blank">(AMZN.O)</a>, Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a>, Tesla <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a>, and Intel <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/INTC.O" target="_blank">(INTC.O)</a>.翻译:参加APEC峰会的中国代表团成员、中国贸促会官员张绍刚上周表示，参加供应链博览会的外国企业中有20%是美国企业，其中包括亚马逊<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AMZN.O" target="_blank">(AMZN.O)</a> 、苹果(Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">)等。 AAPL.O）</a> 、特斯拉<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">（TSLA.O）</a>和英特尔<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/INTC.O" target="_blank">（INTC.O）</a> 。</p>   <p>"We wholeheartedly hope U.S. businesses can...while actively realising their own development, also positively promote the healthy, stable, and long-term development of U.S.-China relations," Zhang said.翻译:我们衷心希望美国企业在积极实现自身发展的同时，也积极推动美中关系健康稳定长期发展。</p>    <span>Reporting by Eduardo Baptista and Joe Cash; Editing by Jamie Freed and Miral Fahmy翻译:爱德华多·巴普蒂斯塔和乔·卡什的报道；编辑：杰米·弗里德和米拉尔·法赫米</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 09:50:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3UCUFMNBOBP43IVVYFK2UFVSP4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-says-against-supply-chain-decoupling-wants-closer-ties-with-all-2023-11-28/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Eduardo Baptista, Joe Cash]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>SUPPLY CHAIN/ (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国习近平敦促在“外部风险”下加强海外法治]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Y5GVEli1ppNCqNTPQgz9FG3Lppc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/C4YQ6CE3TJNJ7A2ZSRNYHS3UQM.jpg" alt="New Politburo Standing Committee members in Beijing翻译:新一届中央政治局常委在北京" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping meets the media following the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, China October 23, 2022. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File photo翻译:2022年10月23日，中国国家主席习近平在中国北京人民大会堂举行中国共产党第二十次全国代表大会后会见媒体。路透社/Tingshu Wang/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>President Xi Jinping has called for stronger rule of law related to foreign affairs given "external risks and challenges" as China opens up to the outside world, state media reported on Tuesday.翻译:据官方媒体周二报道，鉴于中国对外开放的“外部风险和挑战”，国家主席习近平呼吁加强与外交相关的法治。</p>   <p>Xi, speaking during a study session of the Communist's Party's powerful political bureau, said that to protect its overseas citizens and interests, it was necessary to deepen international cooperation on law enforcement, strengthen consular protection and assistance, and build strong rule of law.翻译:习近平在中共政治局学习时表示，保护海外公民和利益，必须深化国际执法合作，加强领事保护和协助，建设坚强法治。</p>   <p>China's private companies have run into legal challenges abroad in recent years, from <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/china-leads-world-counterfeit-pirated-products-us-report-2023-01-31/">U.S. accusations</a> on counterfeit and pirated goods sold on online platforms owned by Tencent Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0700.HK" target="_blank">(0700.HK)</a> and Alibaba Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">(9988.HK)</a>, to steps to ban the TikTok video app, owned by Chinese tech firm ByteDance, in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/nepal-govt-decides-ban-chinas-tiktok-ani-2023-11-13/">Nepal</a>.翻译:近年来，中国私营企业在海外遭遇法律挑战，从<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/china-leads-world-counterfeit-pirated-products-us-report-2023-01-31/">美国指控</a>腾讯控股<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0700.HK" target="_blank">（0700.HK）</a>和阿里巴巴集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">（9988.HK）</a>旗下在线平台销售假冒盗版商品，到禁止 TikTok 视频的措施应用程序，由中国科技公司字节跳动在 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/nepal-govt-decides-ban-chinas-tiktok-ani-2023-11-13/">尼泊尔</a>拥有。</p>   <p>Xi said in the Monday speech it was necessary to raise compliance awareness and guide the public and enterprises to abide by laws, regulations and customs in the process of "going global".翻译:习近平在周一的讲话中表示，要提高合规意识，引导公众和企业在“走出去”过程中遵守法律法规和习俗。</p>   <p>To facilitate economic and trade exchanges, authorities say Chinese law firms have set up 180 overseas offices in 35 countries and regions, an increase of nearly 50% since 2018.翻译:为便利经贸往来，有关部门表示，中国律师事务所已在35个国家和地区设立了180个海外办事处，自2018年以来增长了近50%。</p>   <p>China needs to actively develop foreign-related legal services and cultivate world-class arbitration institutions and law firms, Xi said.翻译:习近平指出，我国要积极发展涉外法律服务，培育世界一流仲裁机构和律师事务所。</p>   <p>But authorities in some Western countries, including the U.S., Canada, Britain and the Netherlands, have accused China of illegally setting up "overseas police service centres" to monitor its overseas citizens, accusations that Beijing vehemently denies.翻译:但包括美国、加拿大、英国和荷兰在内的一些西方国家当局指责中国非法设立“海外警察服务中心”来监视其海外公民，北京方面强烈否认这一指控。</p>   <p>China says such centres are meant to help its citizens renew expired driving licences, and are run by Chinese volunteers, not law enforcement officers.翻译:中国表示，这些中心旨在帮助其公民更新过期的驾驶执照，并且由中国志愿者而非执法人员运营。</p>   <p>The call to better protect citizens abroad coincides with recent outbreaks of conflict in countries such as Ukraine and Sudan that have led to China organising evacuations of its people.翻译:在呼吁更好地保护海外公民的同时，乌克兰和苏丹等国最近爆发了冲突，导致中国组织了人员撤离。</p>   <p>China has organised almost 20 evacuations and dealt with more than 500,000 cases of consular protection involving millions of its people over the past decade, according to the foreign ministry.翻译:据外交部称，过去十年来，中国组织了近20次撤侨行动，处理了超过50万起领事保护案件，涉及数百万人。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ryan Woo; editing by Robert Birsel翻译:瑞恩·吴 (Ryan Woo) 报道；罗伯特·伯塞尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 08:01:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">NWOEIKV4FNK3NIZRD3H7TDW2VA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/chinas-xi-urges-stronger-rule-law-overseas-amid-external-risks-2023-11-28/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>XI/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[放缓的中国仍引领大宗商品竞争]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/MZM2E8mkFQqTQJ0yartBZkprBIg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/Q2IWEWSWUJMDHGLGR4V2CPL6OY.jpg" alt="Workers are seen at a production line of copper foils used for lithium batteries, at a Tongling Nonferrous Metals Group plant翻译:铜陵有色金属集团工厂的锂电池铜箔生产线上，工人们在工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Workers are seen at a production line of copper foils used for lithium batteries, at a Tongling Nonferrous Metals Group plant翻译:铜陵有色金属集团工厂的锂电池铜箔生产线上，工人们在工作 in Tongling, Anhui province, China November 30, 2018. Picture taken November 30, 2018. REUTERS/Stringer</figcaption></figure>       <p>President Xi Jinping is trying to wean China off its property-based, debt-fuelled <a href="https://www.reuters.com/breakingviews/chinas-growth-is-buried-under-great-wall-debt-2023-09-13/">economic model</a>. The transformation will cool growth in the world’s second-largest economy after years of rapid development. Investors are worried but risk ignoring the structural changes underpinning the country's continuing voracious appetite for raw materials.翻译:中国国家主席习近平正试图让中国摆脱以房地产为基础、债务驱动的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/breakingviews/chinas-growth-is-buried-under-great-wall-debt-2023-09-13/">经济模式</a>。这一转型将给这个世界第二大经济体在经历了多年的快速发展后的增长降温。投资者感到担忧，但有可能忽视支撑该国对原材料持续旺盛需求的结构性变化。</p>      <p>Take the $300 billion copper market. China imports over 60% of the metal’s globally traded volume. "When it comes to copper, the thinking usually goes that copper equals property, property equals China," said one commodities trader. "And because China property is down, copper must be down too."翻译:以价值 3000 亿美元的铜市场为例。中国进口的金属占全球金属交易量的60%以上。 “谈到铜，人们通常认为铜等于财产，财产等于中国，”一位大宗商品交易员表示。 “由于中国房地产价格下跌，铜价也必然下跌。”</p>   <p>True, the country's vast real estate sector, which powers a quarter of GDP and some 40 other sectors from construction to home appliances, is still finding a bottom. New construction starts by area have shrunk by another 23% in the year to October from an already battered 2022. Coupled with Beijing's geopolitical fissures with the West, ranging from a technology race with Washington to its cosiness with Moscow and its position on Taiwan, investors are having cold feet about a broad set of Chinese assets. China recorded its <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-first-deficit-foreign-investment-signals-wests-de-risking-pressure-2023-11-06/">first-ever</a> quarterly deficit in foreign direct investment – $11.8 billion between July and September.翻译:诚然，中国庞大的房地产行业仍在探底，该行业为国内生产总值的四分之一以及从建筑到家电等约 40 个其他行业提供动力。与已经遭受重创的 2022 年相比，截至 10 月的一年内新开工面积又减少了 23%。再加上北京与西方的地缘政治裂痕，从与华盛顿的技术竞赛到与莫斯科的友好关系以及对台湾的立场，投资者对广泛的中国资产表现出临阵退缩的态度。 7月至9月，中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-first-deficit-foreign-investment-signals-wests-de-risking-pressure-2023-11-06/">首次</a>出现季度外国直接投资赤字——118亿美元。</p>   <p>But two nuanced trends complicate the picture. First, as much as Xi frets about housing bubbles, he is still keen to prevent social unrest, given that ordinary Chinese store 70% of their wealth in property. That's why he wants to ensure distressed developers like China Evergrande <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a> finish building the apartments that they have pre-sold to mortgage payers. By October, China still had about 8.2 billion square metres under construction – roughly 80 million typical three-bedroom homes. Copper tends to be used in a building’s late stages, so the potential demand loss arising from the property crisis is likely to be less severe than for iron ore, which is used more prominently at the start of construction.翻译:但两个微妙的趋势使情况变得复杂。首先，尽管习近平对房地产泡沫感到担忧，但他仍然热衷于防止社会动荡，因为普通中国人将其 70% 的财富储存在房地产中。这就是为什么他希望确保中国恒大<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）</a>等陷入困境的开发商完成预售给抵押贷款付款人的公寓的建设。截至10月，中国仍有约82亿平方米的在建面积——约8000万套典型的三居室住宅。铜往往在建筑的后期使用，因此房地产危机造成的潜在需求损失可能没有铁矿石那么严重，铁矿石在施工初期使用更为突出。</p>   <p>Second, Xi's mission to shift the country's economic drivers from real estate to green and high-tech industries is accelerating. When China’s top leaders set priorities at the Communist Party’s twice-a-decade finance <a href="https://nam02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fenglish.www.gov.cn%2Fnews%2F202310%2F31%2Fcontent_WS6541ab70c6d0868f4e8e0daa.html&amp;data=05%7C01%7CThomas.Shum%40thomsonreuters.com%7C903680ec6197411f55b708dbeb437f4e%7C62ccb8646a1a4b5d8e1c397dec1a8258%7C0%7C0%7C638362447374537958%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=Q%2FfBPoIoigXM9YIRLhQEaP4axJh0uQ%2FJyUVwYoh3XJ8%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank">conference</a> on Oct. 31, they explicitly asked that more financial resources go into these investments. That means state-owned banks will probably be guided to lend more to electric cars, wind and solar energy, artificial intelligence and advanced chips. Those industries need copper and other metals.翻译:其次，习近平将国家经济驱动力从房地产转向绿色和高科技产业的使命正在加速推进。当中国最高领导人在 10 月 31 日召开的中国共产党十年两次的金融<a href="https://nam02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fenglish.www.gov.cn%2Fnews%2F202310%2F31%2Fcontent_WS6541ab70c6d0868f4e8e0daa.html&amp;data=05%7C01%7CThomas.Shum%40thomsonreuters.com%7C903680ec6197411f55b708dbeb437f4e%7C62ccb8646a1a4b5d8e1c397dec1a8258%7C0%7C0%7C638362447374537958%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=Q%2FfBPoIoigXM9YIRLhQEaP4axJh0uQ%2FJyUVwYoh3XJ8%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank">会议</a>上确定优先事项时，他们明确要求将更多的财政资源投入到这些投资中。这意味着国有银行可能会被引导向电动汽车、风能和太阳能、人工智能和先进芯片提供更多贷款。这些行业需要铜和其他金属。</p>   <p>Thus, while the share of China's “new economy” remains small versus the old growth engines, its rise is also creating new demand for commodities. Copper, for one, is essential in making electric motors and batteries, as well as in power grids, and other efforts to boost renewable energy. In wind energy, for example, China added more generation capacity in the past two years than over the previous seven and will grow its grid-connected wind power at a 10-year compound annual growth rate of 11% to 2.38 terawatts at the end of 2032, according to Wood Mackenzie.翻译:因此，虽然与旧的增长引擎相比，中国“新经济”的份额仍然较小，但其崛起也创造了对大宗商品的新需求。例如，铜对于制造电动机和电池、电网以及其他促进可再生能源的努力至关重要。以风能为例，中国过去两年新增发电量超过前七年，并网风电将以11%的年复合增长率增长，到年底将达到2.38太瓦。根据伍德·麦肯齐的说法，2032 年。</p>   <p>That’s why China's copper demand will still rise by 4 million metric tons from the 2020 level to around 18 million tons per year in 2030, according to estimates by commodity trading group Trafigura. That compares to an increase of 5 million tons in annual demand from 2010 to 2020. And China's copper demand has grown by 8% this year, faster than the 5% Xi is targeting for overall GDP growth. Copper prices followed the boom and gloom surrounding China's pandemic reopening this year, yet they did much better than the collapse threatened by the property downturn. The most traded copper contract on the Shanghai Futures Exchange (SHFE) still rose about 4% this year to $9,367 a ton, while three-month copper contracts on the London Metal Exchange are about 3% higher. Chinese producers are having a blast: shares in Shanghai-listed Zijin Mining <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601899.SS" target="_blank">(601899.SS)</a> have gained almost 20% this year.翻译:因此，据大宗商品贸易集团托克估计，到2030年，中国的铜需求仍将比2020年的水平增加400万吨，达到每年1800万吨左右。相比之下，从2010年到2020年，年需求量增加了500万吨。今年中国的铜需求增长了8%，高于习近平设定的GDP总体增长5%的目标。铜价跟随今年中国疫情重新爆发的繁荣和低迷，但其表现比房地产低迷威胁的崩溃要好得多。上海期货交易所 (SHFE) 交易量最大的铜合约今年仍上涨约 4%，至每吨 9,367 美元，而伦敦金属交易所的三个月期铜合约上涨约 3%。中国生产商正大放异彩：在上海上市的紫金矿业<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601899.SS" target="_blank">(601899.SS)</a>股价今年已上涨近 20%。</p>   <p>It’s similar for aluminium, which is prominent in property construction but also in EV components, such as those that enclose and protect the battery pack, and infrastructure like charging stations. China's annual aluminium demand rose by 18 million tons from 2010 to 2020 and is forecast to grow by another 13 million tons to over 50 million tons a year in 2030, per Trafigura. Aluminium prices on the SHFE have risen by more than 1% this year, outperforming global prices on the London Metal Exchange, which have slumped by more than 8%, per ING analysts.翻译:铝的情况与此类似，铝在房地产建筑中占据着重要地位，但在电动汽车组件中也很常见，例如封装和保护电池组的组件以及充电站等基础设施。托克表示，从2010年到2020年，中国的铝需求量每年增加1800万吨，预计到2030年将再增加1300万吨，达到5000万吨以上。 ING 分析师表示，今年上海期货交易所的铝价上涨了 1% 以上，跑赢了伦敦金属交易所的全球铝价，而伦敦金属交易所的铝价已下跌了 8% 以上。</p>   <p>Together, these factors are acting as a floor for Chinese growth. This month, the International Monetary Fund upgraded China's GDP growth for 2023 and 2024. It now expects the country’s output to expand by 4.6% in 2024 from a 4.2% estimate in October. The People’s Republic contributed 35% of world GDP growth in 2019; it would still account for 27% of that in 2024, even if it expands by a sub-par 4%, according to Breakingviews calculations based on IMF and World Bank data. That's partly because other regions, like the United States, are expected to slow.翻译:这些因素共同构成了中国经济增长的基础。本月，国际货币基金组织上调了中国2023年和2024年的GDP增速。目前预计中国2024年的产出将从10月份的4.2%增长4.6%。 2019年，中华人民共和国对世界GDP增长的贡献率为35%；根据 Breakingviews 基于国际货币基金组织和世界银行数据的计算，到 2024 年，即使增幅低于 4%，它仍将占其中的 27%。部分原因是美国等其他地区的经济增长预计会放缓。</p>      <p>To be sure, the phasing out of real estate would hit some commodities more than others. For example, China's steel-reliant construction sector may grow at around just 2.5% a year over the next 10 years, per Oxford Economics analysts, which should concern iron ore exporters like Australia. But even then, the blow to prices might be far from extreme. China accounts for nearly 70% of global demand for iron ore so when its housing market slumped in 2015, prices plunged to an all-time low of around $40 per ton. This year, though, they still averaged above $110 per ton, according to HSBC analysts, and are now around the highest in six months. That’s partly due to hopes Beijing will spend money to stimulate the economy, and partly because new demand for steel used in electric vehicles, wind farms, and other infrastructure helped soften the blow.翻译:可以肯定的是，房地产的逐步退出对某些大宗商品的打击会比其他大宗商品更大。例如，根据牛津经济研究院分析师的说法，中国依赖钢铁的建筑行业未来 10 年的年增长率可能仅为 2.5% 左右，这应该引起澳大利亚等铁矿石出口国的担忧。但即便如此，对价格的打击可能还远非极端。中国占全球铁矿石需求的近70%，因此当2015年中国房地产市场低迷时，铁矿石价格跌至每吨40美元左右的历史低点。不过，据汇丰银行分析师称，今年的平均价格仍高于每吨 110 美元，目前约为六个月来的最高水平。部分原因是希望北京方面花钱刺激经济，部分原因是电动汽车、风电场和其他基础设施对钢材的新需求有助于缓解冲击。</p>   <p>As China transitions to a new economic model, its appetite for green technologies should continue to benefit Latin American countries like Chile – a top copper producer – and Indonesia, which produces more niche metals such as nickel, as well as African countries like the Democratic Republic of Congo, which dominates cobalt mining.翻译:随着中国向新的经济模式转型，其对绿色技术的需求应会继续惠及拉美国家，如最大的铜生产国智利和生产镍等更多利基金属的印度尼西亚，以及民主共和国等非洲国家刚果，主导钴矿开采。</p>   <p>As the Chinese idiom goes, a skinnier camel would still be bigger than a horse. From a commodities perspective, investors who are too focused on China’s loss of economic weight risk overlooking the fact that it remains too big to ignore.翻译:中国有句成语，“骆驼瘦了，马还大”。从大宗商品的角度来看，过于关注中国经济失重风险的投资者忽视了中国经济规模仍然大得不容忽视的事实。</p>   <p>Follow <a href="https://twitter.com/ywchen1" target="_blank">@ywchen1</a> on X翻译:在 X 上关注<a href="https://twitter.com/ywchen1" target="_blank">@ywchen1</a></p>    <span>Editing by Francesco Guerrera, Katrina Hamlin and Thomas Shum翻译:编辑：Francesco Guerrera、Katrina Hamlin 和 Thomas Shum</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 05:20:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2GN3L6RW4JK2ZMCLQ7L5Z2UOLE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/breakingviews/slowing-china-still-leads-race-commodities-2023-11-28/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Yawen Chen]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>COMMODITIES/BREAKINGVIEWS</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[西方的去风险化举措开始损害中国的前景]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>China records first quarterly foreign direct investment deficit</li>  <li>Execs worry about China slowdown, geopolitics, regulations</li>  <li>Trend could weigh on yuan, chip away at growth potential-analyst</li>  <li>China-focused buyout fundraising has ground to a halt-data</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>中国首次出现季度外国直接投资赤字</li><li>高管担心中国经济放缓、地缘政治和监管</li><li>分析师称，趋势可能会对人民币造成压力，削弱增长潜力</li><li>以中国为重点的收购融资已陷入停滞数据</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/iVn0qPKOnIwYRfKi26Ld66AZPW8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VMPOMVUG7NMAFHSYKLS5QVDNCU.jpg" alt="A man walks in the Central Business District on a rainy day, in Beijing翻译:雨天，一名男子在北京中央商务区散步" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A man walks in the Central Business District on a rainy day, in Beijing翻译:雨天，一名男子在北京中央商务区散步, China, July 12, 2023. REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2023 年 7 月 12 日，中国北京，雨天，一名男子在中央商务区行走。路透社/Thomas Peter/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S. furniture company head Jordan England thinks his firm's Chinese suppliers are among the best in the game, but geopolitics and a slowing economy have pushed him to source more products from Southeast Asia, Eastern Europe and Mexico.翻译:美国家具公司负责人乔丹·英格兰认为，他的公司的中国供应商是业内最好的供应商之一，但地缘政治和经济放缓迫使他从东南亚、东欧和墨西哥采购更多产品。</p>   <p>"I'm looking to move away from it (China)," said England, CEO and co-founder of Florida-based Industry West.翻译:总部位于佛罗里达州的 Industry West 的首席执行官兼联合创始人 England 表示：“我正在寻求离开（中国）。”</p>   <p>"It was always 'China plus one,'" he said, referring to the diversification strategy many businesses began implementing after Washington imposed trade tariffs on Beijing in 2018 to ensure they were not wholly dependent on Chinese suppliers.翻译:“总是‘中国加一’，”他说，指的是2018年华盛顿对北京征收贸易关税后，许多企业开始实施多元化战略，以确保它们不完全依赖中国供应商。</p>   <p>Now "it's like 'plus-10' and then China," he added, with the latter down to providing half of Industry West's products and being trimmed more.翻译:现在“就像‘+10’，然后是中国，”他补充道，后者减少到提供工业西部一半的产品，并进行了更多削减。</p>   <p>Foreign investors have been sour on China for most of this year, but data released over the past month has provided clear evidence of the negative impact de-risking strategies are having on the world's second-largest economy.翻译:今年大部分时间里，外国投资者一直对中国感到不满，但过去一个月发布的数据清楚地证明了去风险策略对世界第二大经济体产生的负面影响。</p>   <p>Activity surveys showed manufacturing <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-factory-activity-unexpectedly-contracted-october-2023-10-31/">unexpectedly contracted</a> in October, while exports accelerated their <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-imports-unexpectedly-grow-oct-exports-extend-declines-2023-11-07/">decline</a>. China recorded its first-ever quarterly deficit in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-first-deficit-foreign-investment-signals-wests-de-risking-pressure-2023-11-06/">foreign direct investment</a> in July-September, suggesting capital outflow pressure.翻译:活动调查显示，10 月份制造业<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-factory-activity-unexpectedly-contracted-october-2023-10-31/">意外收缩</a>，而出口则加速<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-imports-unexpectedly-grow-oct-exports-extend-declines-2023-11-07/">下滑</a>。中国7-9月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-first-deficit-foreign-investment-signals-wests-de-risking-pressure-2023-11-06/">外国直接投资</a>首次出现季度逆差，显示资本外流压力。</p>      <p>Nicholas Lardy, senior researcher at the Peterson Institute for International Economics, said in a note the new data imply that foreign firms are not only declining to reinvest earnings, but are selling existing investments and repatriating funds.翻译:彼得森国际经济研究所高级研究员尼古拉斯·拉迪在一份报告中表示，新数据表明外国公司不仅拒绝将收益再投资，而且正在出售现有投资并将资金汇回国内。</p>   <p>This trend could further weaken the yuan and clip China's economic growth potential, he added.翻译:他补充说，这种趋势可能会进一步削弱人民币并削弱中国的经济增长潜力。</p>   <p>"In recent years, the scale, proportion and growth rate of foreign investment absorbed by China have all remained at a relatively high level," He Yadong, a Chinese commerce ministry spokesperson, said in response to a question from Reuters.</p>    <h 1="">LONG-TERM PROSPECTS</h>  <p>Businesses have longstanding worries about geopolitics, tightening regulations and a more favourable playing field for state-owned companies. But for the first time in the four decades since China opened up to foreign investments, executives are now also concerned about long-term <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">growth prospects</a>.翻译:企业界长期以来对地缘政治、监管收紧以及国有企业更有利的竞争环境感到担忧。但自中国向外国投资开放四十年来，高管们首次对长期<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">增长前景</a>表示担忧。</p>   <p>A survey released last week by The Conference Board, a think tank, showed more than two-thirds of the CEOs who responded said China's demand has not returned to pre-COVID levels, with 40% expecting a decrease in capital investments in the country over the next six months and a similar proportion expecting to cut jobs.翻译:智库世界大型企业联合会上周发布的一项调查显示，超过三分之二的受访首席执行官表示，中国的需求尚未恢复到新冠疫情爆发前的水平，其中 40% 的受访者预计中国的资本投资将在未来六个月，预计裁员的比例类似。</p>   <p>China is outwardly confident about growth despite a global economic slowdown, with policy advisers <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-govt-advisers-call-steady-growth-target-2024-more-stimulus-2023-11-22/">favouring a target</a> of about a 5% expansion of gross domestic product in 2024 and the country aiming to double the economy's size by 2035.翻译:尽管全球经济放缓，但中国表面上对增长充满信心，政策顾问<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-govt-advisers-call-steady-growth-target-2024-more-stimulus-2023-11-22/">支持2024年国内生产总值增长约5%的目标</a>，并计划到2035年将经济规模扩大一倍。</p>   <p>But England said he is concerned about how his Chinese suppliers that also produce for the domestic market will cope with the country's severe property market <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">downturn</a>.翻译:但英格兰表示，他担心同样为国内市场生产的中国供应商将如何应对该国严重的房地产市场<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">低迷</a>。</p>   <p>"I'm worried about these factories going from 500 workers to 200, to 100," he said.</p>    <h 1="">OPEN FOR BUSINESS?</h>  <p>Premier Li Qiang's overtures declaring China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-economy-improves-march-will-consolidate-recovery-says-premier-li-2023-03-30/">open for business</a> to foreign investors after the pandemic have been greeted with scepticism in some Western boardrooms in light of a broader <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/us-warns-new-chinese-counterespionage-law-puts-companies-risk-2023-06-30/">anti-espionage law</a>, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/raids-exit-bans-us-companies-face-growing-hurdles-china-2023-08-29/">raids</a> on consultancies and due diligence firms and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-exit-bans-multiply-political-control-tightens-under-xi-2023-05-02/">exit bans</a>, trade bodies say.翻译:贸易机构表示，鉴于更广泛的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/us-warns-new-chinese-counterespionage-law-puts-companies-risk-2023-06-30/">反间谍法</a>、对咨询公司和尽职调查公司的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/raids-exit-bans-us-companies-face-growing-hurdles-china-2023-08-29/">突击检查</a>以及<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-exit-bans-multiply-political-control-tightens-under-xi-2023-05-02/">出境禁令</a>，疫情后李强总理宣布中国向外国投资者<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-economy-improves-march-will-consolidate-recovery-says-premier-li-2023-03-30/">开放的提议</a>遭到了一些西方董事会的怀疑。</p>   <p>Li is expected to make a similar call on Tuesday at the country's inaugural China International Supply Chain Expo, which it is expected to use to tout its supply chain advantages.翻译:预计李克强将于周二在中国首届中国国际供应链博览会上发表类似的讲话，预计中国将利用该博览会宣传其供应链优势。</p>   <p>"Foreign business executives here are eager to continue in China," AmCham President Michael Hart said. "But boards back in the U.S. are wary."翻译:“这里的外国企业高管渴望继续在中国发展，”美国商会主席迈克尔·哈特说。 “但美国的董事会对此持谨慎态度。”</p>   <p>European firms have raised <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/with-manufacturing-loans-rising-can-china-avoid-new-supply-glut-2023-11-12/">fair competition concerns</a> about state-directed lending to Chinese manufacturers, while Noah Fraser, managing director of the Canada China Business Council, said "bad blood" remains over the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/huawei-cfo-meng-appear-court-expected-reach-agreement-with-us-source-2021-09-24/">detention</a> of two Canadians from 2018 to 2021.翻译:欧洲公司对国家向中国制造商提供的贷款提出了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/with-manufacturing-loans-rising-can-china-avoid-new-supply-glut-2023-11-12/">公平竞争担忧</a>，而加中贸易理事会董事总经理诺亚·弗雷泽(Noah Fraser)表示，2018年至2021年两名加拿大人<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/huawei-cfo-meng-appear-court-expected-reach-agreement-with-us-source-2021-09-24/">被拘留</a>的问题仍然存在“不和”。</p>      <p>In private equity, while Asia-focused funds have allocated capital to China, data from Preqin shows that as of Nov. 24, no China-focused buyout fund had been raised in 2023 in any currency, compared with $210 million in 2022 and $13.2 billion in 2019, before the pandemic.翻译:在私募股权领域，虽然专注于亚洲的基金已向中国配置资金，但Preqin的数据显示，截至11月24日，2023年没有以任何货币筹集专注于中国的收购基金，而2022年为2.1亿美元，2022年为132亿美元。 2019年，疫情爆发之前。</p>   <p>Primavera Capital founder Fred Hu cites mounting macroeconomic uncertainty, a "murky capital market outlook," and lingering concerns over past <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/education-bitcoin-chinas-season-regulatory-crackdown-2021-07-27/">regulatory crackdowns</a> on high-growth industries such as technology and education.翻译:春华资本创始人胡祖六表示，宏观经济不确定性不断增加、“资本市场前景黯淡”，以及对过去对科技和教育等高增长行业的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/education-bitcoin-chinas-season-regulatory-crackdown-2021-07-27/">监管打压</a>的持续担忧。</p>   <p>"Tech firms and other private enterprises must be able to tap public markets for financing and liquidity, so the current market conditions in China do considerable harm to the real economy," said Hu, adding China-focused private equity firms were diverting capital to Southeast Asia, Australia and Europe.翻译:胡说：“科技公司和其他私营企业必须能够利用公共市场进行融资和流动性，因此中国目前的市场状况对实体经济造成了相当大的损害。”他补充说，专注于中国的私募股权公司正在将资金转移到东南部亚洲、澳大利亚和欧洲。</p>   <p>Despite the challenges, foreign investment flows are not unidirectional. Many firms, especially in the retail sector, still target China's giant market. McDonald's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MCD.N" target="_blank">(MCD.N)</a> said last week it had struck a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/mcdonalds-acquire-carlyles-stake-china-unit-2023-11-20/">deal</a> to boost its stake in its China business.翻译:尽管面临挑战，外国投资流动并不是单向的。许多公司，尤其是零售行业的公司，仍然瞄准中国这个巨大的市场。麦当劳<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MCD.N" target="_blank">(MCD.N)</a>上周表示，已达成一项<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/mcdonalds-acquire-carlyles-stake-china-unit-2023-11-20/">协议</a>，以增持其在中国业务的股份。</p>   <p>An executive at a European hotel chain, who spoke on condition of anonymity due to the topic's sensitivity, said his firm was happy to reinvest profits in China for now.翻译:一位欧洲连锁酒店的高管表示，他的公司目前很乐意将利润再投资到中国。由于该话题的敏感性，该高管要求匿名。</p>   <p>"We know what's going on politically and yes, economically," he said, adding the latest data "was nothing to be proud of."翻译:他说：“我们知道政治上正在发生什么，是的，经济上也发生了什么事。”他补充说，最新数据“没有什么值得骄傲的”。</p>   <p>"It's slow, but only warrants taking a 'wait and see approach.'"翻译:“虽然速度很慢，但只能采取‘观望态度’。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Joe Cash and Ellen Zhang in Beijing and Kane Wu in Hong Kong; Additional reporting by Eduardo Baptista and Don Durfee in Beijing; Graphics by Kripa Jayaram; Writing by Marius Zaharia; Editing by Jamie Freed翻译:Joe Cash 和 Ellen 张在北京以及 Kane Wu 在香港的报道； Eduardo Baptista 和 Don Durfee 在北京的补充报道；制图：Kripa Jayaram；马吕斯·扎哈里亚 (Marius Zaharia) 撰写；杰米·弗里德编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 01:53:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">EHI4T4T2CRIFNCLJEUOYCI56QE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/wests-de-risking-starts-bite-chinas-prospects-2023-11-27/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Joe Cash, Ellen Zhang, Kane Wu]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/INVESTMENT (ANALYSIS, GRAPHICS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[马来西亚MH370客机失踪中国家属向法庭寻求赔偿]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/SXqT1WzEXU70Bv6HTstNMMeTuIY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OLN5XZYHNBKVNJDAKI7K37SO34.jpg" alt="Family members of passengers on Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 that went missing in 2014, in Beijing翻译:2014 年在北京失踪的马来西亚航空 MH370 航班乘客家属" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A man surnamed Fu, who lost his brother, reacts as he speaks to the media following a court hearing on compensation for those who lost their loved ones on the Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 that went missing in 2014, in Beijing, China November 27, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo翻译:2023 年 11 月 27 日，中国北京，一名失去兄弟的付姓男子在就 2014 年马航 MH370 航班失踪人员赔偿问题举行法庭听证会后向媒体发表讲话. 路透社/Florence Lo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/a2YoMjlkL4OXLzFTdXQ7EnQ0RLs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JHBQ4WYDCZMBXI6UPYE62VGFEE.jpg" alt="Family members of passengers on Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 that went missing in 2014, in Beijing翻译:2014 年在北京失踪的马来西亚航空 MH370 航班乘客家属" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Hu Xiufang, 72, who lost her son, daughter-in-law and granddaughter, holds a sign as she speaks to the media following a court hearing on compensation for those who lost their loved ones on the Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 that went missing in 2014, in Beijing, China November 27, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo翻译:72 岁的胡秀芳失去了儿子、儿媳和孙女，她在法庭听证会上举着牌子接受媒体采访，该听证会涉及马航 MH370 航班失踪人员的赔偿事宜。 2014 年，2023 年 11 月 27 日在中国北京。REUTERS/Florence Lo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/WhxKQLVoJ4kEQsWfR_-VtT3lqpA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6MEFMDOVK5LCPKDGJJC2BIVAEU.jpg" alt="Family members of passengers on Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 that went missing in 2014, in Beijing翻译:2014 年在北京失踪的马来西亚航空 MH370 航班乘客家属" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Family members walk past police officers before court hearings on compensation for those who lost their loved ones on the Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 that went missing in 2014, near the People's Court of Chaoyang district in Beijing, China November 27, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo翻译:2023 年 11 月 27 日，中国北京朝阳区人民法院附近，在为 2014 年马航 MH370 航班失踪人员提供赔偿的法庭听证会上，家属走过警察。 REUTERS/Florence Lo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/3moq9M8NOmXYFc0FAPlDugTOJAA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CK35ZCLRENK5HO5MLSH7X7BZNA.jpg" alt="Family members of passengers on Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 that went missing in 2014, in Beijing翻译:2014 年在北京失踪的马来西亚航空 MH370 航班乘客家属" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Family members hold signs as they speak to the media following a court hearing on compensation for those who lost their loved ones on the Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 that went missing in 2014, in Beijing, China November 27, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo翻译:2023 年 11 月 27 日，中国北京，在关于赔偿 2014 年马航 MH370 航班失踪人员家属赔偿问题的法庭听证会后，家属举着标语向媒体发表讲话。 REUTERS/Florence Lo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Cf2TeydA3Q56ziJN4Gng5c9Kyh0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KO2HHIVC7VPZ3K2HLGFTFIZHOE.jpg" alt="Victim's family member wipes her tears during the sixth annual remembrance event for the missing Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 in Putrajaya翻译:受害者家属在布城举行的马航 MH370 航班失踪第六届年度纪念活动中擦眼泪" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Victim's family member wipes her tears during the sixth annual remembrance event for the missing Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 in Putrajaya翻译:受害者家属在布城举行的马航 MH370 航班失踪第六届年度纪念活动中擦眼泪, Malaysia, March 7, 2020. REUTERS/Lim Huey Teng翻译:2020 年 3 月 7 日，在马来西亚普特拉贾亚举行的马来西亚航空 MH370 航班失踪第六次年度纪念活动中，受害者家属擦眼泪。 REUTERS/Lim Huey Teng</figcaption></figure>                     <p>A Beijing court on Monday began compensation hearings for the Chinese relatives of passengers on board Malaysia Airlines flight MH370, which mysteriously disappeared over the Indian Ocean almost a decade ago, the plaintiffs said.翻译:原告称，北京一家法院周一开始为马来西亚航空公司 MH370 航班乘客的中国亲属举行赔偿听证会，该航班近十年前在印度洋神秘失踪。</p>   <p>Over 150 Chinese passengers were on the flight which vanished en route from Kuala Lumpur to Beijing on March 8, 2014. Malaysian investigators did not rule out the possibility that the aircraft had been deliberately taken off course, and debris confirmed or believed to be from the aircraft has washed up along the coast of Africa and on islands in the Indian Ocean.翻译:2014 年 3 月 8 日，这架航班在从吉隆坡飞往北京的途中失踪，机上载有 150 多名中国乘客。马来西亚调查人员不排除飞机被故意偏离航线的可能性，残骸已确认或相信来自飞机。飞机被冲到非洲海岸和印度洋岛屿上。</p>   <p>Relatives of these passengers said they were demanding compensation from Malaysia Airlines, Boeing, aircraft engine maker Rolls-Royce and Allianz insurance group among others.翻译:这些乘客的亲属表示，他们要求马来西亚航空、波音公司、飞机发动机制造商劳斯莱斯和安联保险集团等提供赔偿。</p>   <p>The court did not release any details on the case, but state media said more than 40 relatives were seeking between 10 million and 80 million yuan ($1.4 million and $11.2 million) each in compensation.翻译:法院没有公布该案的任何细节，但官方媒体称，40 多名亲属正在寻求每人 1000 万至 8000 万元人民币（140 万美元至 1120 万美元）的赔偿。</p>   <p>Malaysia Airlines, Rolls-Royce, Allianz and Boeing did not immediately respond to requests for comment.翻译:马来西亚航空、劳斯莱斯、安联和波音没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Holding up signs saying "resume the search" and "re-establish an international investigation team", Jiang Hui, a spokesperson for the bereaved families, said Malaysia Airlines left them with no choice but to go to court to seek answers.翻译:遇难者家属发言人江辉举着“恢复搜寻”和“重新成立国际调查组”的牌子，表示马航让他们别无选择，只能上法庭寻求答案。</p>   <p>"'We are not responsible anymore' is their attitude," said Jiang, whose mother was on board.翻译:“‘我们不再负责’是他们的态度，”蒋的母亲在船上。</p>   <p>There was a heavy police presence outside Chaoyang District People's Court in Beijing before the hearing, with reporters cordoned off and unable to interact with the family members.翻译:开庭前，北京朝阳区人民法院外戒备森严，记者被封锁，无法与家属互动。</p>   <p>Some of the relatives, who spoke to reporters after the hearing, said they wanted the resumption of search efforts and for Malaysia Airlines to directly communicate with them as well as to provide them with psychological counselling.翻译:一些在听证会后接受记者采访的亲属表示，他们希望恢复搜寻工作，并希望马航能够直接与他们沟通，并为他们提供心理咨询。</p>   <p>Many said these demands were more important than the monetary compensation.翻译:许多人表示，这些要求比金钱补偿更重要。</p>   <p>"My mother died last year and she brought up my son. Until the very end I hid from her what really happened to him," said Beijing resident Bao Lanfang, 71, who lost her son and daughter-in-law on board. She said her husband had recently died after suffering from severe depression because of the incident.翻译:“我的母亲去年去世了，她抚养了我的儿子。直到最后我才向她隐瞒了他的真实情况，”71岁的北京居民鲍兰芳说，她在船上失去了儿子和儿媳。她说，她的丈夫因这起事件而患上严重抑郁症，最近去世了。</p>   <p>In March, another group of relatives <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/nine-years-families-urge-new-search-missing-malaysia-plane-mh370-2023-03-05/">urged</a> the Malaysian government to allow U.S. seabed exploration firm Ocean Infinity to mount a new search for the missing plane.翻译:今年三月，另一群亲属<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/nine-years-families-urge-new-search-missing-malaysia-plane-mh370-2023-03-05/">敦促</a>马来西亚政府允许美国海底勘探公司 Ocean Infinity 对失踪飞机进行新的搜索。</p>    <span>Reporting by Laurie Chen; editing by Miral Fahmy翻译:陈劳瑞报道；米拉尔·法赫米 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 21:17:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Q2BQ5TYECJJVHCLSHMVXVNRGRQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/chinese-families-missing-malaysia-mh370-plane-seek-compensation-court-2023-11-27/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Laurie Chen]]></author>
            
                
                <category>MALAYSIA AIRLINES</category>
                
                <category>MH370/ (PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国央行承诺支持内需]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/AQ1mTGyGkgwf9cQi1R7rzspzSGk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/Y6RFL5TNYFLRBNUGFPHDEQ3N3I.jpg" alt="A worker walks across a construction site in the Central Business District, ahead of the opening of the National People's Congress (NPC) in Beijing翻译:北京全国人民代表大会开幕前，一名工人走过中央商务区的建筑工地" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A worker walks across a construction site in the Central Business District, ahead of the opening of the National People's Congress (NPC) in Beijing翻译:北京全国人民代表大会开幕前，一名工人走过中央商务区的建筑工地, China, February 28, 2023. REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2023 年 2 月 28 日，中国北京，全国人民代表大会开幕前，一名工人走过中央商务区的一个建筑工地。路透社/Thomas Peter/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's central bank on Monday said it would fend off systemic risks to the economy and use forceful and targeted monetary policy to better support domestic demand.翻译:中国央行周一表示，将防范经济系统性风险，运用强有力、有针对性的货币政策更好地支持内需。</p>   <p>In its quarterly policy implementation report, the bank laid out the general direction of financial policy and said it would use a variety of monetary tools at its disposal to ensure sufficient liquidity.翻译:在季度政策执行报告中，央行明确了金融政策的总体方向，并表示将运用多种货币工具，确保流动性充足。</p>   <p>"Prudent monetary policy should be precise and forceful, with greater emphasis on cross-cyclical and countercyclical adjustments, enriching the monetary policy toolbox," the bank said.翻译:央行表示，稳健的货币政策要精准有力，更加注重跨周期和逆周期调节，丰富货币政策工具箱。</p>   <p>The bank added it would "further unblock the monetary policy transmission mechanism", enhance the stability of financial support for the real economy and keep prices "reasonably stable".翻译:该行补充称，将“进一步畅通货币政策传导机制”，增强金融支持实体经济的稳定性，保持物价“合理稳定”。</p>   <p>China's economy is gaining momentum, but it faces challenges such as an imbalanced global economic recovery and an unstable foundation for domestic economic recovery, the central bank said.翻译:央行表示，中国经济发展势头良好，但也面临全球经济复苏不平衡、国内经济复苏基础不稳定等挑战。</p>   <p>Beijing has launched a slew of policy measures this year, seeking to shore up a feeble post-pandemic recovery amid a persistent property sector downturn, local government debt risks, slow global growth and geopolitical tensions.翻译:北京今年推出了一系列政策措施，在房地产行业持续低迷、地方政府债务风险、全球经济增长放缓和地缘政治紧张局势的背景下，寻求支撑疫情后微弱的复苏。</p>   <p>The bank said it would guide financial institutions to resolve local debt risks and noted there was urgency for faster economic transformation.翻译:该行表示将引导金融机构化解地方债务风险，并指出加快经济转型的紧迫性。</p>   <p>"Supply and demand dynamics in the property market have greatly changed," the central bank said.翻译:央行表示，“房地产市场供需格局发生较大变化。”</p>   <p>The bank said it would keep the yuan -- which has come under pressure on the foreign exchange market this year -- "basically stable" and strive to foster a sound monetary and financial environment.翻译:央行表示，今年在外汇市场面临压力的情况下，将保持人民币汇率“基本稳定”，努力营造良好的货币金融环境。</p>   <p>It reiterated that it expects to achieve around <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-govt-advisers-call-steady-growth-target-2024-more-stimulus-2023-11-22/">5% growth</a> this year.翻译:它重申，预计今年将实现<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-govt-advisers-call-steady-growth-target-2024-more-stimulus-2023-11-22/">5%左右的增长</a>。</p>    <span>Reporting by Liangping Gao, Kevin Yao, Ella Cao, Ethan Wang and Bernard Orr; Editing by Toby Chopra and Christina Fincher翻译:高亮平、姚凯文、曹艾拉、王伊森和伯纳德·奥尔报道；托比·乔普拉和克里斯蒂娜·芬奇编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 17:56:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">J6QZAFRN25L7PDSQ5LJVO2M7YU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-central-bank-pledges-support-domestic-demand-2023-11-27/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/ (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国表示重视MH370事件的后续行动]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/a2YoMjlkL4OXLzFTdXQ7EnQ0RLs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JHBQ4WYDCZMBXI6UPYE62VGFEE.jpg" alt="Family members of passengers on Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 that went missing in 2014, in Beijing翻译:2014 年在北京失踪的马来西亚航空 MH370 航班乘客家属" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Hu Xiufang, 72, who lost her son, daughter-in-law and granddaughter, holds a sign as she speaks to the media following a court hearing on compensation for those who lost their loved ones on the Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 that went missing in 2014, in Beijing, China November 27, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo翻译:72 岁的胡秀芳失去了儿子、儿媳和孙女，她在法庭听证会上举着牌子接受媒体采访，该听证会涉及马航 MH370 航班失踪人员的赔偿事宜。 2014 年，2023 年 11 月 27 日在中国北京。REUTERS/Florence Lo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China values the follow-up to the incident of MH370, a Malaysia Airlines flight that went missing nearly 10 years ago, and hopes all sides maintain close communication and properly handle this issue, the foreign ministry said on Monday.翻译:外交部周一表示，中方重视近十年前马航MH370航班失踪事件的后续进展，希望各方保持密切沟通，妥善处理这一问题。</p>   <p>Spokesperson Wang Wenbin made the comments after a media report of a Chinese court holding the first hearing of a liability lawsuit filed by relatives of passengers on MH370.翻译:发言人汪文斌是在媒体报道中国法院就马航MH370乘客亲属提起的责任诉讼举行首次听证会后发表上述言论的。</p>    <span>Reporting by Beijing newsroom; Editing by Tom Hogue翻译:北京新闻编辑室报道；汤姆·霍格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 16:09:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5W36RPAFIJN7VLPKANVHT26EXY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-says-it-values-follow-up-mh370-incident-2023-11-27/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>MALAYSIA/MH370 (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
