<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 01:37:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[习近平在河内进行国事访问第二天会见越南领导人]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/qSMvKz5CPf0HNfGVSz03oHxIsrE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2PZI3DCAHJMZFLACQP62LRP4DI.jpg" alt="&quot;Senior Chinese Leader Event&quot; on the sidelines of the APEC summit, in San Francisco翻译:旧金山APEC峰会期间的“中国高级领导人活动”" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>China's President Xi Jinping speaks at the "Senior Chinese Leader Event" held by the National Committee on US-China Relations and the US-China Business Council on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 15, 2023.  REUTERS/Carlos Barria/Pool/File Photo翻译:中国国家主席习近平在加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织（APEC）峰会期间，在美中关系全国委员会和美中贸易全国委员会举办的“中国高级领导人活动”上发表讲话美国，2023 年 11 月 15 日。REUTERS/Carlos Barria/Pool/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's President Xi Jinping will meet Vietnamese leaders on Wednesday on the second day of a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/chinas-xi-visits-vietnam-after-biden-seeks-boost-ties-2023-12-12/">state visit to Hanoi</a>, during which dozens of deals have been announced, including on diplomatic ties, railways and telecommunications.翻译:中国国家主席习近平将于周三<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/chinas-xi-visits-vietnam-after-biden-seeks-boost-ties-2023-12-12/">在河内进行国事访问</a>的第二天会见越南领导人，访问期间宣布了数十项协议，包括外交关系、铁路和电信方面的协议。</p>   <p>His first trip to Vietnam in six years came after the visit of U.S. President Joe Biden in September, in a sign of the increasing importance of the Southeast Asian manufacturing hub amid trade tensions between the two global powers.翻译:他六年来首次访问越南是在美国总统乔·拜登九月访问越南之后，这表明在两个全球大国之间的贸易紧张局势中，东南亚制造业中心的重要性日益增加。</p>   <p>On Wednesday Xi will pay tribute to the mausoleum of the founding leader of Communist Vietnam, Ho Chi Minh. He will then meet the chairman of Vietnam's parliament, Vuong Dinh Hue, Prime Minister Pham Minh Chinh and President Vo Van Thuong, according to a schedule from Vietnam's foreign ministry.翻译:周三，习近平将瞻仰越南共产党开国领袖胡志明的陵墓。根据越南外交部的日程安排，他随后将会见越南国会主席王廷惠、总理范明正和国家主席武文上。</p>   <p>During the day, a China-Vietnam joint statement on diplomatic relations is expected to be formally signed after its text was shown to reporters on Tuesday.翻译:当天，中越外交关系联合声明文本周二向记者展示后预计将正式签署。</p>   <p>Xi will meet students before departing in the afternoon from the Vietnamese capital, whose central roads had been festooned with China's and Vietnam's red flags for his visit.翻译:习近平将于下午离开越南首都之前会见学生，为了此次访问，首都的中央道路上挂满了中国和越南的红旗。</p>    <span>Reporting by Francesco Guarascio; Editing by Gerry Doyle翻译:弗朗西斯科·瓜拉西奥报道；格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 01:06:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Q63QMMHR6RLODDLA66J6ZQ5BUY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/chinas-xi-meets-vietnam-leaders-second-day-state-visit-hanoi-2023-12-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>VIETNAM</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国本周将迎来严寒天气]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/vzQLuEzuEtwy14wvdyn8_KX2b6M=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JJBHRTRS65L3LJLXEP3IMNMA3I.jpg" alt="Snowy day in Beijing翻译:北京下雪天" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People stand near Qianmen Street on a snowy day in Beijing, China December 11, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年12月11日，中国北京，下雪天，人们站在前门大街附近。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/EN6wuZMNGA1drl1Ovvo-EV2wF9k=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/QF3EO3EREVIVLATEROU3SHSX4E.jpg" alt="Snowy day in Beijing翻译:北京下雪天" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A general view of the city on a snowy day in Beijing, China December 11, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023 年 12 月 11 日，中国北京雪天的城市景观。REUTERS/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>               <p>Chinese authorities warned from Tuesday most of the country faced heavy snowfall, blizzards and plunging temperatures this week in what could be one of the coldest December snaps in China in decades.翻译:中国当局从周二开始警告，本周中国大部分地区将面临大雪、暴风雪和气温骤降，这可能是中国几十年来最冷的12月天气之一。</p>   <p>Beijing is expected to be hit by temperatures as low as minus 18 degrees Celsius (minus 0.4 degrees Fahrenheit) this weekend compared to around minus 8 C on average in mid-December. Even Shanghai in the south could be buffeted by weather as frigid as minus 4 C on Saturday through Sunday, unusual for this time of the year.翻译:预计本周末北京气温将低至-18摄氏度（-0.4华氏度），而12月中旬的平均气温约为-8摄氏度。即使是南方的上海，周六至周日也可能遭遇零下 4 摄氏度的寒冷天气，这在一年中的这个时候并不常见。</p>   <p>Having issued its second highest alert for blizzards, Beijing shut all schools from Wednesday and moved learning online, while firms were encouraged to offer employees flexibility for work and staggered commutes.翻译:北京发布了第二高的暴风雪警报后，从周三开始关闭所有学校，并将学习转移到网上，同时鼓励企业为员工提供灵活的工作和错峰通勤。</p>   <p>In a safety caution message, the capital warned of avoiding snow hazard areas and asked residents to reduce travel and closely monitor as well as remove snow from the top of long-span buildings and facilities.翻译:在安全警示信息中，首都警告避开雪灾区域，并要求居民减少出行，密切监测并清除大跨度建筑和设施顶部的积雪。</p>   <p>Heavy snow is expected to hit Beijing's Capital Airport between Wednesday morning and early Friday.翻译:预计周三上午至周五早些时候，北京首都机场将出现大雪。</p>   <p>Parts of north, northwest and south China, as well as parts of the Inner Mongolia region, Guizhou province and even regions south of the Yangtze River, could see temperatures slide by more than 14 degrees C, the National Meteorological Center (NMC) cautioned.翻译:国家气象中心警告，华北、西北、华南部分地区以及内蒙古地区、贵州省乃至长江以南地区的部分地区气温可能下降14℃以上。</p>   <p>It has called on local governments to take precautions against the cold weather, advised the public to keep warm, and urged measures to be taken to protect tropical crops and aquatic produce.翻译:它呼吁地方政府做好防寒措施，建议公众注意保暖，并敦促采取措施保护热带作物和水产品。</p>   <p>Until Friday, the NMC forecast large-scale rain and snowfall in central and eastern regions of the country, bringing as much as 30 mm (1.2 inches) of precipitation in snowstorms in parts of Shaanxi, Henan and Shandong.翻译:直到周五，国家气象局预计该国中部和东部地区将出现大范围降雨和降雪，陕西、河南和山东部分地区将出现高达30毫米（1.2英寸）的暴风雪降水量。</p>   <p>Many rivers in Heilongjiang, a vast northeastern province that shares a border with Russia, have already frozen over.翻译:黑龙江是一个与俄罗斯接壤的东北大省，许多河流已经结冰。</p>   <p>Also on Tuesday, the China Meteorological Administration activated a Level-II emergency response - its second-highest emergency response level - for the cold wave and blizzards.翻译:同样在周二，中国气象局针对寒潮和暴风雪启动了二级应急响应，这是其第二高应急响应级别。</p>   <p>In Beijing, more than 6,000 people have been put on call for any road emergency rescues and 2,200 sets of snow-removal equipment and machinery are on standby for deployment.翻译:北京目前已投入道路应急救援6000余人，2200台套除雪设备机械待命部署。</p>   <p>Additionally, 32,000 tonnes of snow-thawing agent is ready for use on icy roads and motorways.翻译:此外，还有 32,000 吨融雪剂可供在结冰的道路和高速公路上使用。</p>   <p>The city authorities also encouraged voluntary participation in snow clearing and ice shoveling operations even as 73,000 people have been placed on duty, and required indoor heating be ramped up in all districts.翻译:尽管已派出7.3万人值班，市政府还鼓励自愿参与除雪和铲冰作业，并要求各地区加强室内供暖。</p>   <p>The Chinese capital last saw such cold weather on Jan. 7, 2021, when the temperature fell to minus 19.6 C.翻译:中国首都上次出现如此寒冷的天气是在2021年1月7日，当时气温降至-19.6℃。</p>   <p>The cold snap in Beijing this week, compared with the autumn-like conditions a week ago, reflects the sharp oscillations in temperatures recently. In October, Beijing experienced <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/beijing-logs-second-warmest-october-summer-like-autumn-2023-11-01/">one of its warmest Octobers</a> in decades in a year of weather extremes.翻译:与一周前的秋意相比，本周北京的寒流反映出近期气温的剧烈波动。十月，北京经历了几十年来<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/beijing-logs-second-warmest-october-summer-like-autumn-2023-11-01/">最温暖的十月之一，这</a>是一年中极端天气的一年。</p>   <p>Beijing's all-time low temperature was minus 27.4 C, set on Feb. 22, 1966.翻译:1966年2月22日，北京的历史最低气温为-27.4℃。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ryan Woo and Liz Lee; Editing by Frances Kerry and Sonali Paul翻译:Ryan Woo 和 Liz Lee 的报道；编辑：弗朗西斯·克里和索纳利·保罗</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:57:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6ZTHTLSRDFM47JNN5V5VCBQ55A</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-braces-blistering-cold-this-week-2023-12-12/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ryan Woo, Liz Lee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ASIA</category>
                
                <category>WEATHER/CHINA (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国委员会提出2024年对抗中国的立法“蓝图”]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Jf9K-SnRm8-WxXxl5EaxVJlJQxc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/Y25ZATSQ5JO7PFTGOR5VYOMQAU.jpg" alt="House Select Committee on the Strategic Competition Between the United States and the Chinese Communist Party holds a meeting on the wargames simulation &quot;Taiwan Tabletop Exercise (TTX),&quot; on Capitol Hill in Washington翻译:众议院美国与中国共产党战略竞争特别委员会在华盛顿国会山举行模拟兵棋“台湾桌面演习（TTX）”会议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Committee chairman U.S. Rep. Mike Gallagher (R-WI) and U.S. Rep. Raja Krishnamoorthi (D-IL) talk over procedures with their members during a House Select Committee on the Strategic Competition Between the United States and the Chinese Communist Party meeting on "Taiwan Tabletop Exercise (TTX)," a war games simulation, on Capitol Hill in Washington, U.S., April 19, 2023. REUTERS/Amanda Andrade Rhoades/ File Photo翻译:委员会主席美国众议员迈克·加拉格尔（R-WI）和美国众议员拉贾·克里希纳莫蒂（Raja Krishnamoorthi）（民主党-伊利诺伊州）在众议院美国与中国共产党战略竞争特别委员会会议上与其成员讨论了程序“台湾桌面演习（TTX），一种战争游戏模拟，2023 年 4 月 19 日在美国华盛顿国会山举行。路透社/Amanda Andrade Rhoades/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A U.S. congressional committee issued an extensive list of bipartisan recommendations on Tuesday to reset America's economic ties with China, setting out legislative goals for 2024 that it said would prevent the U.S. from becoming the "economic vassal" of its chief geopolitical rival.翻译:美国国会一个委员会周二发布了一份内容广泛的两党建议清单，旨在重启美国与中国的经济关系，并制定了2024年的立法目标，称这些目标将防止美国成为其主要地缘政治对手的“经济附庸”。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://selectcommitteeontheccp.house.gov/sites/evo-subsites/selectcommitteeontheccp.house.gov/files/evo-media-document/reset-prevent-build-scc-report.pdf" target="_blank">proposals</a> drew on a year of hearings and investigations by the House of Representatives' select committee on China, and range from what would be dramatic shifts in U.S. regulatory approaches, including adding restrictions on outbound investment to China, to more technical legal revisions, such as reducing a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/legalindustry/proposed-legislation-could-alter-e-commerce-purchases-low-value-items-shift-2023-07-13/">threshold for duty-free shipments</a> from China into the U.S.翻译:这些<a href="https://selectcommitteeontheccp.house.gov/sites/evo-subsites/selectcommitteeontheccp.house.gov/files/evo-media-document/reset-prevent-build-scc-report.pdf" target="_blank">提案</a>借鉴了众议院中国问题特别委员会一年来的听证会和调查，内容包括美国监管方式的巨大转变，包括增加对中国境外投资的限制，以及更具技术性的法律修订，例如降低从中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/legalindustry/proposed-legislation-could-alter-e-commerce-purchases-low-value-items-shift-2023-07-13/">免税运送到美国的门槛</a></p>   <p>Implementing the measures would "require hard trade-offs and will not be without cost," the committee, led by Republican chair Mike Gallagher and Democratic ranking member Raja Krishnamoorthi, said in a report.翻译:由共和党主席迈克·加拉格尔和民主党资深成员拉贾·克里希纳莫蒂领导的委员会在一份报告中表示，实施这些措施将“需要艰难的权衡，并且不会没有代价”。</p>   <p>"The United States now has a choice: accept Beijing's vision of America as its economic vassal or stand up for our security, values, and prosperity," the committee said.翻译:该委员会表示：“美国现在有一个选择：要么接受北京将美国视为其经济附庸的愿景，要么捍卫我们的安全、价值观和繁荣。”</p>   <p>Gallagher and Krishnamoorthi told reporters on a call that the November meeting between President Joe Biden and Chinese leader Xi Jinping in San Francisco, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">intended to smooth rocky relations</a>, did little to change their 150 recommendations.翻译:加拉格尔和克里希纳莫蒂在电话中告诉记者，美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平11月在旧金山举行的会晤<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">旨在缓和不稳定的关系</a>，但并没有改变他们提出的150项建议。</p>   <p>Among them: forcing a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/congress-will-not-take-up-tiktok-legislation-before-end-year-senator-2023-12-07/">ban or Chinese divestment of social media platform TikTok</a>, directing the Commerce Department to impose import duties on legacy Chinese semiconductors, requiring the Federal Reserve to stress-test U.S. banks' ability to withstand a potential loss of market access to China, and restricting U.S. federal agencies from buying Chinese-made drones.翻译:其中：强制禁止<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/congress-will-not-take-up-tiktok-legislation-before-end-year-senator-2023-12-07/">中国社交媒体平台TikTok或撤资</a>、指示商务部对中国传统半导体征收进口关税、要求美联储对美国银行承受可能失去中国市场准入的能力进行压力测试，并限制美国联邦机构购买中国制造的无人机。</p>   <p>"I think this is really a blueprint for some bipartisan legislation that we're hoping to move in the next year," Krishnamoorthi said.翻译:克里希纳莫蒂说：“我认为这确实是一些两党立法的蓝图，我们希望明年能够推动这些立法。”</p>   <p>The committee was set up earlier this year in an effort to convince Americans why they should care about competing with China, and has promoted the selective decoupling of the U.S. and Chinese economies.翻译:该委员会于今年早些时候成立，旨在说服美国人为什么应该关心与中国的竞争，并推动了美国和中国经济的选择性脱钩。</p>   <p>Gallagher said Republicans were having a "robust discussion" on how to move forward with legislation restricting U.S. outbound investment to China, a version of which was dropped from an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/key-provisions-us-congress-massive-defense-bill-2023-12-07/">annual defense authorization bill</a>. He added that he was hopeful those discussions would lead to "responsible legislative activity" in the first quarter of 2024.翻译:加拉格尔表示，共和党人正在就如何推进限制美国对华对外投资的立法进行“热烈讨论”，该法案的一个版本已从<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/key-provisions-us-congress-massive-defense-bill-2023-12-07/">年度国防授权法案</a>中删除。他补充说，他希望这些讨论能够在 2024 年第一季度带来“负责任的立法活动”。</p>   <p>"Even those major asset managers or bankers with whom we've engaged that are skeptical of any restrictions on investment in China, even in military and critical technological areas, I think would welcome the predictability that legislating the issue would provide," Gallagher said.翻译:加拉格尔表示：“即使是那些与我们接触过的主要资产管理公司或银行家，他们对对中国的投资限制持怀疑态度，即使是在军事和关键技术领域，但我认为，他们也会欢迎立法这一问题所提供的可预测性。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Michael Martina; Editing by Alex Richardson翻译:迈克尔·玛蒂娜报道；亚历克斯·理查森编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 22:10:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5CEQDV5KTROI7CGZ4IERGBEFMQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-committee-offers-2024-legislative-blueprint-countering-china-2023-12-12/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Michael Martina]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/CONGRESS</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国与北京就安排军事沟通事宜进行接触-五角大楼]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/dfgE9YxhnvE_TIEZAqlg5BHqOtg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/UCYT5M353RL3LF3VEQXEZTX3Q4.jpg" alt="The flags of the United States and China fly in Boston翻译:美国和中国国旗在波士顿飘扬" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The flags of the United States and China fly from a lamppost in the Chinatown neighborhood of Boston, Massachusetts, U.S., November 1, 2021.   REUTERS/Brian Snyder/ File Photo翻译:2021年11月1日，美国和中国国旗从美国马萨诸塞州波士顿唐人街附近的灯柱上飘扬。路透社/布莱恩·斯奈德/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The United States has been coordinating with Beijing to arrange military-to-military talks, the Pentagon said on Tuesday, though it did not have any announcements on any talks.翻译:五角大楼周二表示，美国一直在与北京协调安排军事会谈，但没有就任何会谈发表任何声明。</p>   <p>U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese leader Xi Jinping agreed last month at a closely watched California summit to resume such contacts, which were severed after then-House of Representatives Speaker Nancy Pelosi visited self-ruled Taiwan in August 2022. China claims sovereignty over democratically governed Taiwan.翻译:美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平上个月在一场备受关注的加州峰会上同意恢复这种接触，这种接触在时任众议院议长南希·佩洛西于 2022 年 8 月访问自治的台湾后被中断。中国声称对民主治理的台湾拥有主权台湾。</p>   <p>"We have been working closely with our defense attache office and our policy team has been in active coordination with Beijing in order to arrange communication," Pentagon spokesperson Major General Patrick Ryder told a press conference.翻译:五角大楼发言人帕特里克·莱德少将在新闻发布会上表示：“我们一直在与我们的武官办公室密切合作，我们的政策团队一直在与北京积极协调，以安排沟通。”</p>   <p>"But again nothing to announce at this time," he added, in terms of any specific engagements.翻译:“但目前没有什么可宣布的，”他补充说，就任何具体合作而言。</p>   <p>White House national security adviser Jake Sullivan said at a Wall Street Journal event on Tuesday that he believed progress on military-to-military communication was on track since the Biden-Xi summit only took place a few weeks ago.翻译:白宫国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文周二在《华尔街日报》的一次活动中表示，他相信自从几周前才举行拜登与习近平峰会以来，军方沟通方面的进展正在步入正轨。</p>   <p>"I actually don't think of it as a delay. I think this is just the normal implementation of a summit outcome and it's continuing as both sides expected it would so I see no issue there," Sullivan said.翻译:沙利文说：“我实际上并不认为这是一种拖延。我认为这只是峰会成果的正常实施，并且按照双方的预期继续进行，所以我认为这没有问题。”</p>   <p>"We believe that the real question is not: 'Will it get started? We're confident in that. The real question is: Can it be sustained through any ups and downs that may come in the future," Sullivan added.翻译:“我们认为真正的问题不是：‘它会开始吗？我们对此充满信心。真正的问题是：它能否在未来可能出现的任何起起落落中持续下去，’”沙利文补充道。</p>   <p>The Biden administration has said that it wants communications throughout the two countries' militaries, including both senior leaders and commanders in specific geographic areas.翻译:拜登政府表示，希望两国军队能够进行沟通，包括特定地理区域的高级领导人和指挥官。</p>   <p>Relations between the two countries grew frosty after Biden ordered the shooting down in February of a suspected Chinese spy balloon that flew over the United States.翻译:拜登二月份下令击落飞越美国上空的疑似中国间谍气球后，两国关系变得冷淡。</p>   <p>But top Biden administration officials have since visited Beijing and met with their counterparts to rebuild communications and trust.翻译:但拜登政府高级官员此后访问了北京，并与同行会面，以重建沟通和信任。</p>    <span>Reporting by Idrees Ali and Phil Stewart; Additional reporting by Andrea Shalal and Doina Chiacu; editing by Jonathan Oatis and Sandra Maler翻译:Idrees Ali 和 Phil Stewart 报道； Andrea Shalal 和 Doina Chiacu 的补充报道；乔纳森·奥蒂斯和桑德拉·马勒编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 21:40:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">P6V2HV7VQNLQVBB3BR2XF73KWI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us-touch-with-beijing-about-arranging-military-communication-pentagon-2023-12-12/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/MILITARY (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国因乌克兰战争对俄罗斯实施全面制裁]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Hj_XPpkjPjkcbLSWJWwDmy4fjO0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MTK5IL5SURLMROZGPE6TCS5OL4.jpg" alt="Aftermath of a Russian missile strike in Kyiv翻译:俄罗斯导弹袭击基辅后的后果" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A local resident stands next to a crater at a site of a Russian missile strike, amid Russia's attack on Ukraine, in Kyiv, Ukraine December 11, 2023. REUTERS/Valentyn Ogirenko/File Photo翻译:2023 年 12 月 11 日，在乌克兰基辅，一名当地居民站在俄罗斯导弹袭击地点的弹坑旁边。路透社/Valentyn Ogirenko/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The United States on Tuesday imposed sanctions on hundreds of people and entities, including in China, Turkey and the United Arab Emirates, as it targets Russia's sanctions evasion, future energy capabilities, banks and its metals and mining sector.翻译:美国周二对包括中国、土耳其和阿拉伯联合酋长国在内的数百人和实体实施制裁，目标是俄罗斯逃避制裁、未来能源能力、银行及其金属和采矿业。</p>   <p>The U.S. Treasury and State departments targeted more than 250 individuals and entities in Washington's latest action attempting to crack down on Russia and its evasion of sanctions imposed by the U.S. and its allies over the war in Ukraine.翻译:在华盛顿试图打击俄罗斯及其逃避美国及其盟国因乌克兰战争而实施的制裁的最新行动中，美国财政部和国务院针对了超过250名个人和实体。</p>   <p>"We will continue to use the tools at our disposal to promote accountability for Russia’s crimes in Ukraine and those who finance and support Russia’s war machine," U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken said in a statement.翻译:美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯在一份声明中表示：“我们将继续利用我们掌握的工具，追究俄罗斯在乌克兰所犯下的罪行以及那些资助和支持俄罗斯战争机器的人的责任。”</p>   <p>The Treasury said it imposed sanctions on a network of four entities and nine people based in China, Russia, Hong Kong and Pakistan over the facilitation and procurement of Chinese-manufactured weapons and technologies to Russia.翻译:美国财政部表示，由于为俄罗斯提供便利和采购中国制造的武器和技术，对位于中国、俄罗斯、香港和巴基斯坦的四个实体和九人网络实施了制裁。</p>   <p>It said the network sought to circumvent U.S. sanctions and Chinese controls on the export of military-related materials.翻译:据称，该网络试图规避美国的制裁和中国对军事相关材料出口的控制。</p>   <p>It also targeted Turkey, United Arab Emirates and China-based companies over the shipment of technology, equipment and inputs, including ball or roller bearings, aircraft parts and X-ray systems.翻译:它还针对土耳其、阿拉伯联合酋长国和中国公司运送技术、设备和投入，包括滚珠或滚柱轴承、飞机零部件和 X 射线系统。</p>   <p>The China-based firms targeted included commercial satellite imagery companies that Treasury said provided high-resolution observation imagery to Russian mercenary firm Wagner.翻译:被攻击的中国公司包括商业卫星图像公司，财政部称这些公司向俄罗斯雇佣军公司瓦格纳提供高分辨率观测图像。</p>   <p>The State Department also targeted Chinese entities in an action against a network it said was involved in procuring microelectronic components for Russian state conglomerate Rostec, which itself is under U.S. sanctions.翻译:美国国务院还针对中国实体采取了行动，打击一个据称参与为俄罗斯国有企业 Rostec 采购微电子元件的网络，而该企业本身也受到美国的制裁。</p>   <p>It said the microelectronics were being used to develop electronic warfare systems. Companies in Russia, Turkey and Hong Kong were also targeted as part of action against the network.翻译:据称，微电子技术正被用于开发电子战系统。俄罗斯、土耳其和香港的公司也成为针对该网络的行动的目标。</p>   <p>Washington has stepped up diplomatic pressure on countries and private companies globally to ensure enforcement of the sanctions it, the European Union and other Western nations have imposed on Moscow over its invasion of Ukraine.翻译:华盛顿加大了对全球各国和私营企业的外交压力，以确保其、欧盟和其他西方国家因莫斯科入侵乌克兰而对其实施的制裁得到执行。</p>   <p>Russia's embassy in Washington did not immediately respond to requests for comment. Russia dismisses Western sanctions as illegal, and says they will not impede the development of its economy.翻译:俄罗斯驻华盛顿大使馆没有立即回应置评请求。俄罗斯认为西方制裁是非法的，并表示这些制裁不会阻碍其经济发展。</p>   <p>Liu Pengyu, spokesperson for the Chinese embassy in Washington, said China regulates military and dual-use exports responsibly and opposes the United States' use of sanctions, which he called "unilateral" and "illegal."翻译:中国驻华盛顿大使馆发言人刘鹏宇表示，中国负责任地监管军用和军民两用出口，反对美国采取制裁措施，他称这种制裁是“单边”和“非法”的。</p>   <p>"(W)e firmly oppose the U.S. side sanctioning relevant companies under groundless pretext," Liu said in an emailed response to questions about Tuesday's sanctions.翻译:“我们坚决反对美方以毫无根据的借口制裁相关企业，”刘在回应有关周二制裁的问题的电子邮件中表示。</p>   <p>UAE's embassy did not immediately respond to a request for comment. Its foreign ministry did not immediately reply to a request outside usual working hours.翻译:阿联酋大使馆没有立即回应置评请求。其外交部没有在正常工作时间之外立即回复请求。</p>   <p>A Turkish official, speaking on condition of anonymity, told Reuters that while Turkey only imposed sanctions endorsed by the United Nations Security Council and opposed unilateral measures, Ankara took measures to minimize any circumvention of sanctions.翻译:一位不愿透露姓名的土耳其官员告诉路透社，虽然土耳其只实施了联合国安理会认可的制裁，并反对单方面措施，但安卡拉采取了措施，尽量减少任何规避制裁的行为。</p>   <p>"Strict monitoring and prevention of efforts to skirt sanctions through Turkey is an integral part of our non-abidance policy," the official said, and added the Turkish financial and commercial sector dealt primarily with Western markets.翻译:这位官员表示：“严格监控和防止通过土耳其规避制裁的行为是我们不遵守政策的一个组成部分。”他补充说，土耳其金融和商业部门主要与西方市场打交道。</p>   <p>"Inevitably, there are evasion attempts by obscure and insignificant entities that are uneducated about or indifferent to sanctions," the person said. "Such entities will unavoidably incur the consequences of unilateral restrictive measures."翻译:这位人士表示：“不可避免的是，一些不知名且无关紧要的实体会试图逃避制裁，这些实体对制裁缺乏了解或漠不关心。” “此类实体将不可避免地遭受单方面限制措施的后果。”</p>   <p>Turkish authorities are taking regulatory actions if the circumventions amount to a pattern breaching Turkey's policy, the official told Reuters.</p>    <h 1="">FUTURE ENERGY</h>  <p>The U.S. targeted three companies developing the Ust-Luga liquefied natural gas (LNG) terminal, a facility at a Baltic seaport in northwest Russia to be operated by Gazprom and RusGazDobycha.翻译:美国瞄准了三家开发乌斯季卢加液化天然气（LNG）终端的公司，该终端位于俄罗斯西北部波罗的海港口，由俄罗斯天然气工业股份公司（Gazprom）和俄罗斯天然气工业股份公司（RusGazDobycha）运营。</p>   <p>The yet-to-be-built complex is part of Gazprom's strategy to shift focus to processing and is poised to become Russia's largest gas processing plant, and one of the world's largest in terms of production volumes.翻译:这座尚未建成的综合设施是俄罗斯天然气工业股份公司将重点转向加工战略的一部分，有望成为俄罗斯最大的天然气加工厂，也是世界上产量最大的天然气加工厂之一。</p>   <p>The sanctions were put on Russian-based companies Limited Liability Company Northern Technologies, Joint Stock Company Kazan Compressor Machinery Plant, and Limited Liability Company Gazprom Linde Engineering.翻译:制裁对象为俄罗斯有限责任公司北方技术公司、股份公司喀山压缩机机械厂和有限责任公司俄罗斯天然气工业股份公司林德工程公司。</p>   <p>Washington is seeking to interfere with Russia's future energy production and fuel export capacity.翻译:华盛顿正在寻求干预俄罗斯未来的能源生产和燃料出口能力。</p>   <p>The move came a little over a month after Washington put sanctions on an entity developing <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-imposes-sweeping-new-sanctions-targeting-russia-over-war-ukraine-2023-11-02/">another LNG project</a>, Arctic-2 LNG in Siberia.翻译:一个月多前，华盛顿对开发<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-imposes-sweeping-new-sanctions-targeting-russia-over-war-ukraine-2023-11-02/">另一个液化天然气项目</a>（位于西伯利亚的 Arctic-2 液化天然气）的实体实施制裁。</p>   <p>It was not immediately clear how Russia's future LNG exports would be affected. The U.S. is the world's largest LNG exporter.翻译:目前尚不清楚俄罗斯未来的液化天然气出口将如何受到影响。美国是全球最大的液化天然气出口国。</p>   <p>German company Linde <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LIN.DE" target="_blank">(LIN.DE)</a> stopped work at Ust-Luga in 2022 due to Western sanctions. This year Russia has been talking with China to involve Chinese companies in construction of the plant.翻译:由于西方制裁，德国林德公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LIN.DE" target="_blank">(LIN.DE)</a>于 2022 年停止了 Ust-Luga 的工作。今年，俄罗斯一直在与中国谈判，让中国公司参与该工厂的建设。</p>   <p>Gazprom did not immediately reply to a request for comment.翻译:俄罗斯天然气工业股份公司没有立即回复置评请求。</p>   <p>The State Department also targeted Russian businessman Vladislav Sviblov and Highland Gold Mining Ltd, a UK-registered company owned and controlled by him that it said is Russia’s seventh-largest gold producer, as well as other companies connected to Sviblov following action Britain took in November.翻译:英国去年 11 月采取行动后，美国国务院还针对俄罗斯商人弗拉迪斯拉夫·斯维布洛夫 (Vladislav Sviblov) 和他拥有并控制的一家在英国注册的公司高地黄金矿业有限公司 (Highland Gold Mining Ltd) 以及与斯维布洛夫有关联的其他公司（据说是俄罗斯第七大黄金生产商）。 。</p>   <p>A representative for Sviblov declined to comment.翻译:斯维布洛夫的代表拒绝发表评论。</p>   <p>The State Department also designated three shipping companies and three Russian-flagged commercial vessels it said have been used to transfer munitions between North Korea and Russia.翻译:美国国务院还指定了三家航运公司和三艘悬挂俄罗斯国旗的商船，据称这些商船曾被用来在朝鲜和俄罗斯之间转运弹药。</p>   <p>North Korea's mission to the United Nations in New York did not immediately reply to a request for comment.翻译:朝鲜驻纽约联合国代表团没有立即回复置评请求。</p>   <p>Washington also targeted four Russian financial institutions - including <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-sanctions-expobank-proposed-buyer-hsbcs-russian-business-2023-12-12/">Expobank</a>, the proposed buyer of HSBC's Russian business - and dozens of Russia-based entities involved in the import, production, modification and sale of defense-related and industrial technology, including drones.翻译:华盛顿还针对四家俄罗斯金融机构（包括汇丰银行俄罗斯业务的拟议买家<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-sanctions-expobank-proposed-buyer-hsbcs-russian-business-2023-12-12/">Expobank</a> ）以及数十家涉及国防相关技术和工业技术（包括无人机）进口、生产、改造和销售的俄罗斯实体。</p>   <p>The State Department also listed former telecoms CEO Ivan Tavrin and a network of companies he runs. It said Tavrin "has become one of Russia’s biggest wartime dealmakers since the beginning of Russia’s illegal war against Ukraine."翻译:美国国务院还列出了前电信首席执行官伊万·塔夫林 (Ivan Tavrin) 和他经营的公司网络。报告称，塔夫林“自俄罗斯对乌克兰发动非法战争以来，已成为俄罗斯最大的战时交易撮合者之一”。</p>   <p>A representative for Kismet, owned by Tavrin, did not immediately respond to a request for comment on the sanctions. New Towers, one of the companies in Tavrin's empire, declined to comment.翻译:塔夫林旗下 Kismet 的一名代表没有立即回应就制裁发表评论的请求。塔夫林帝国的公司之一新塔拒绝置评。</p>    <span>Reporting by Daphne Psaledakis, Simon Lewis, Timothy Gardner, Michael Martina, Susan Heavey and Doina Chiacu in Washington, Vladimir Soldatkin in Moscow, Alexander Marrow in London, Maha El Dahan in Dubai, and Tuvan Gumrukcu in Ankara; Editing by Daniel Wallis翻译:华盛顿的 Daphne Psaledakis、Simon Lewis、Timothy Gardner、Michael Martina、Susan Heavey 和 Doina Chiacu、莫斯科的 Vladimir Soldatkin、伦敦的 Alexander Marrow、迪拜的 Maha El Dahan 和安卡拉的 Tuvan Gumrukcu 进行报道；丹尼尔·沃利斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 19:06:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">YMAGX4JLHFOQHJQMQQ7IBKQV5U</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-issues-sweeping-sanctions-targeting-russia-over-ukraine-war-2023-12-12/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Daphne Psaledakis, Simon Lewis, Timothy Gardner]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>RUSSIA/SANCTIONS (UPDATE 4, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[保乐力加 (Pernod Ricard) 瞄准中国市场，推出本土生产的威士忌]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/MNhllhTgt0yQEgFCtdNrYBBOC5M=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5QHGXKS4ANNR3K4LLN7TAUUQVM.jpg" alt="Alexandre Ricard, Pernod Ricard Chairman and CEO, speaks during an interview with CNBC on the floor at the NYSE in New York翻译:保乐力加 (Pernod Ricard) 董事长兼首席执行官亚历山大·里卡德 (Alexandre Ricard) 在纽约证券交易所接受 CNBC 采访时发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Alexandre Ricard, Pernod Ricard Chairman and CEO, speaks during an interview with CNBC on the floor at the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) in New York, U.S., September 5, 2019. REUTERS/Brendan McDermid/File Photo翻译:保乐力加董事长兼首席执行官亚历山大·里卡德 (Alexandre Ricard) 于 2019 年 9 月 5 日在美国纽约纽约证券交易所 (NYSE) 接受 CNBC 采访。 REUTERS/Brendan McDermid/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>French spirits maker Pernod Ricard <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PERP.PA" target="_blank">(PERP.PA)</a> launched The Chuan pure malt whisky in China on Tuesday, the first product released by its local distillery in southwestern Sichuan province.翻译:法国烈酒制造商保乐力加 (Pernod Ricard <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PERP.PA" target="_blank">) (PERP.PA)</a>周二在中国推出了“川”纯麦芽威士忌，这是该公司在四川省西南部的当地酿酒厂推出的首款产品。</p>   <p>Pernod Ricard's Chinese-made malt whisky will be distributed throughout the country from Wednesday, priced from 888 yuan ($123.74).翻译:保乐力加 (Pernod Ricard) 的中国产麦芽威士忌将从周三开始在全国销售，售价 888 元（123.74 美元）起。</p>   <p>According to Pernod Ricard CEO Alexandre Ricard, the Chinese market is currently "soft, from a contextual point of view" but prevailing macro-economic headwinds are not enough to change the fundamentals of a growing middle class and room to grow for international-style spirits.翻译:保乐力加首席执行官亚历山大·里卡德 (Alexandre Ricard) 表示，中国市场目前“从背景角度来看较为疲软”，但当前的宏观经济逆风不足以改变中产阶级不断壮大的基本面和国际烈酒的增长空间。</p>   <p>"Chinese consumers are really developing a taste for diverse profiles of spirits, in particular whiskies," he said. "We believe the potential is quite significant for the next decade or so."翻译:“中国消费者确实正在培养对各种烈酒的口味，特别是威士忌，”他说。 “我们相信未来十年左右的潜力是相当巨大的。”</p>   <p>Pernod is not the only global spirits player increasing its whisky production in China. The company's main rival, Diageo, will also open this month a $75 million single malt distillery in the country, under construction since 2021.翻译:保乐力加并不是唯一一家在中国增加威士忌产量的全球烈酒公司。该公司的主要竞争对手帝亚吉欧 (Diageo) 也将于本月在该国开设一家耗资 7500 万美元的单一麦芽酿酒厂，该酿酒厂自 2021 年开始建设。</p>   <p>There are 30-50 whiskey distilleries in China, Ricard said, with most still under construction.翻译:Ricard说，中国有30-50家威士忌酿酒厂，其中大多数仍在建设中。</p>   <p>Pernod is on a mission to overtake Diageo as the world's top spirits maker, and massive emerging international spirits markets like China are key battlegrounds in that fight. China is the world's largest spirits market, but it is currently almost entirely dominated by local alcohol baijiu.翻译:保乐力加的使命是超越帝亚吉欧，成为世界顶级烈酒制造商，而中国等庞大的新兴国际烈酒市场是这场斗争的关键战场。中国是世界上最大的烈酒市场，但目前几乎完全由本土白酒主导。</p>   <p>International spirits make up 3% of total alcoholic beverages market in China, which is three and a half times the size of the United States, Diageo executives said at a recent capital markets day, casting China as a key opportunity.翻译:帝亚吉欧高管在最近的资本市场日表示，国际烈酒占中国酒精饮料市场总量的 3%，是美国市场规模的三倍半，并将中国视为一个关键机遇。</p>   <p>"It's huge ... and we haven't even begun to make inroads into it," John O'Keeffe, President of Asia Pacific, Global Travel and India at Diageo told investors.翻译:帝亚吉欧亚太区、全球旅游和印度区总裁约翰·奥基夫 (John O&#39;Keeffe) 告诉投资者：“这是一个巨大的......但我们甚至还没有开始涉足这一领域。”</p>   <p>Whiskey is a rapidly-growing category, with China's total market value reaching $2.3 billion in 2022, according to market research provider Euromonitor International, with estimates it will grow to $6.7 billion by 2027.翻译:威士忌是一个快速增长的品类，根据市场研究提供商 Euromonitor International 的数据，2022 年中国的总市场价值将达到 23 亿美元，预计到 2027 年将增长到 67 亿美元。</p>   <p>That represents more than 20% annual growth for the next few years, compared to an approximate 4% growth-rate worldwide.翻译:这意味着未来几年的年增长率将超过 20%，而全球增长率约为 4%。</p>   <p>According to Allison Malmsten, public research director at Daxue Consulting, China's baijiu drinkers are aging and production is falling, making room for other spirits.翻译:大学咨询公司公共研究总监艾莉森·马尔姆斯顿表示，中国的白酒饮用者正在老龄化，产量正在下降，为其他烈酒腾出了空间。</p>   <p>"Around half of China's whiskey drinkers are Gen-Z, nearly 90% are men, they are generally educated and high-class," Malmsten said, adding that whiskey bars popping up in Chinese cities are "crowded with young people."翻译:“中国大约一半的威士忌饮用者是 Z 世代，近 90% 是男性，他们普遍受过教育，而且阶层较高，”马尔姆斯顿说，并补充说，中国城市中涌现的威士忌酒吧“挤满了年轻人”。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1762 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.1762 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Casey Hall
Editing by Tomasz Janowski翻译:凯西·霍尔报道 托马斯·雅诺夫斯基编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 16:33:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FJ6APQ2CBNKB5GNQ44TXIFQ7QY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/pernod-ricard-takes-aim-chinese-market-with-locally-made-whisky-2023-12-12/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Casey Hall, Emma Rumney]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PERNOD RICARD/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[巴基斯坦针对安全部队的重大袭击]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/QjlSztPZx5IbmlIbi4jc-VMOFl8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KUHKXVPHKNMORHQGVYS376XWHI.jpg" alt="Security officers and paramilitary soldiers survey the site, after five suicide bombers tried to drive a vehicle laden with ammunition and explosives into a military facility in Quetta翻译:五名自杀式炸弹袭击者试图驾驶一辆满载弹药和爆炸物的车辆冲入奎达的一处军事设施后，安全官员和准军事士兵正在调查现场" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Security officers and paramilitary soldiers survey the site, after five suicide bombers tried to drive a vehicle laden with ammunition and explosives into a military facility in Quetta翻译:五名自杀式炸弹袭击者试图驾驶一辆满载弹药和爆炸物的车辆冲入奎达的一处军事设施后，安全官员和准军事士兵正在调查现场, Pakistan May 17, 2018. REUTERS/Naseer Ahmed/File Photo翻译:2018 年 5 月 17 日，巴基斯坦奎达，五名自杀式炸弹袭击者试图驾驶一辆满载弹药和爆炸物的车辆进入一处军事设施，安全官员和准军事士兵正在调查现场。 REUTERS/Naseer Ahmed/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A six-man suicide squad <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/militant-attack-kills-four-security-officials-northwest-pakistan-official-2023-12-12/">drove</a> an explosive-laden truck into a military camp in northwest Pakistan on Tuesday, killing at least 23 soldiers, in the latest attack on security forces in the South Asian nation.翻译:周二，一支由六人组成的自杀小队<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/militant-attack-kills-four-security-officials-northwest-pakistan-official-2023-12-12/">驾驶</a>一辆满载炸药的卡车冲入巴基斯坦西北部的一个军营，造成至少 23 名士兵死亡，这是对这个南亚国家安全部队的最新袭击。</p>   <p>Here are some other incidents of violence over recent years that have targeted security forces in the country.</p>    <h 1="">AUGUST, 2023</h>  <p>Militants <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/militants-attack-pakistani-military-convoy-escorting-chinese-nationals-2023-08-13/">attacked</a> a Pakistani military convoy near the strategic southwestern port of Gwadar in the country's mineral-rich province of Balochistan while it was escorting a delegation of Chinese nationals to a construction project.翻译:武装分子在该国矿产资源丰富的俾路支省西南战略港口瓜达尔附近<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/militants-attack-pakistani-military-convoy-escorting-chinese-nationals-2023-08-13/">袭击了</a>一支巴基斯坦军事车队，当时该车队正在护送一个中国公民代表团前往一个建设项目。</p>   <p>A separatist group, the Balochistan Liberation Army (BLA), claimed the attack and said it had inflicted multiple casualties, but Pakistani officials said no harm had been caused to any military personnel or civilians.</p>    <h 1="">JULY 2023</h>  <p>Suspected Islamist militants <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/militants-attack-pakistan-military-base-killing-four-soldiers-army-2023-07-12/">stormed</a> into an army base in Balochistan's Zhob district, armed with guns, hand grenades, and rockets, in an attack that caused the deaths of nine soldiers.翻译:疑似伊斯兰武装分子携带枪支、手榴弹和火箭<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/militants-attack-pakistan-military-base-killing-four-soldiers-army-2023-07-12/">冲进</a>俾路支省佐布地区的一个军事基地，袭击造成 9 名士兵死亡。</p>   <p>Newly founded jihadist group Tehreek-e-Jihad Pakistan (TJP) claimed responsibility for the assault.</p>    <h 1="">APRIL, 2023</h>  <p>A suicide bomber on a motorcycle <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/pakistan-militant-attack-kills-three-troops-officials-say-2023-04-28/">blew</a> himself up, killing three soldiers, as militants attacked a temporary military camp in northwest Pakistan.翻译:当武装分子<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/pakistan-militant-attack-kills-three-troops-officials-say-2023-04-28/">袭击</a>巴基斯坦西北部的一个临时军营时，一名骑摩托车的自杀式炸弹袭击者引爆了身上的炸弹，造成三名士兵死亡。</p>   <p>The attack, for which no group claimed responsibility, occurred in the district of Lakki Marwat, near a rugged tribal area bordering Afghanistan which has long been home to Islamist militants.</p>    <h 1="">MARCH, 2023</h>  <p>A suicide bomber <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/suicide-bombing-southwest-pakistan-kills-nine-policemen-2023-03-06/">rammed</a> a motorcycle into a police truck in Sibbi, a city some 160 km (100 miles) east of Quetta, provincial capital of Balochistan, killing nine policemen and injuring 15 more.翻译:俾路支省首府奎达以东约 160 公里（100 英里）处的锡比市，一名自杀式炸弹袭击者用一辆摩托车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/suicide-bombing-southwest-pakistan-kills-nine-policemen-2023-03-06/">撞上</a>一辆警车，造成 9 名警察死亡，另有 15 人受伤。</p>   <p>The Islamic State later claimed responsibility for the attack.</p>    <h 1="">FEBRUARY, 2022</h>  <p>Insurgents armed with bombs and guns attacked two Pakistani military bases in Balochistan, killing seven soldiers in an attack for which the BLA group claimed responsibility.翻译:武装分子携带炸弹和枪支袭击了俾路支省的两个巴基斯坦军事基地，造成 7 名士兵死亡，BLA 组织声称对此次袭击负责。</p>   <p>China has been investing in the region and the attack came hours before Pakistan's then-Prime Minister Imran Khan arrived in Beijing for the opening of the Winter Olympics, where he was due to meet Chinese President Xi Jinping and other leaders.</p>    <h 1="">JANUARY, 2022</h>  <p>An insurgency attack on a Pakistani army post near Gwadar port killed 10 soldiers. The BLF claimed responsibility for the attack.翻译:瓜达尔港附近的巴基斯坦军队哨所遭到叛乱分子袭击，造成 10 名士兵死亡。 BLF 声称对此次袭击负责。</p>    <span>Reporting by Kanjyik Ghosh
Editing by Gareth Jones翻译:坎吉克·戈什 (Kanjyik Ghosh) 报道 加雷斯·琼斯 (Gareth Jones) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 15:47:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">OULVNQTEVRJBBE2TWT6QLCJKGY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/major-attacks-pakistan-targeting-security-forces-2023-12-12/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>PAKISTAN</category>
                
                <category>MILITANTS/ATTACK</category>
                
                <category>TIMELINE (FACTBOX, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[越南加强对华关系，继美国升级“竹子外交”后]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Xi embarked on first Vietnam trip in six years</li>  <li>China, Vietnam committed to "shared future"</li>  <li>Sign deals on railways, telecoms, but not on rare earths</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>习近平六年来首次越南之行</li><li>中越致力于“命运共同体”</li><li>签署铁路、电信协议，但不签署稀土协议</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/iMDJmcXa-MQOMQaTLOCEIyUUooI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SEXAYE6SWVIYPPB67R6L7EOP7A.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>China's President Xi Jinping attends the Leaders Retreat at the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 17, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 17 日，中国国家主席习近平出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会领导人非正式会议。路透社/Carlos Barria/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Communist-ruled China and Vietnam, at odds over claims in the South China Sea, agreed on Tuesday to boost ties and build a community with a "shared future", three months after Hanoi upgraded its formal relations with the United States.翻译:在河内升级与美国的正式关系三个月后，共产党统治的中国和越南在南海主权问题上存在分歧，两国同意加强关系并建立“命运共同体”。</p>   <p>On Chinese President Xi Jinping's first visit to Hanoi in six years, the two countries announced 37 deals, including on diplomatic ties, railways and telecommunications.翻译:在中国国家主席习近平六年来首次访问河内之际，两国宣布了 37 项协议，包括外交关系、铁路和电信等领域。</p>   <p>As China and the United States vie for influence in the strategic nation, the agreements mark an achievement of Vietnam's "Bamboo diplomacy", although analysts and diplomats said the improvement in relations could be more symbolic than real.翻译:随着中国和美国争夺在这个战略国家的影响力，这些协议标志着越南“竹子外交”的成就，尽管分析人士和外交官表示，关系的改善可能更具象征意义，而不是实际意义。</p>   <p>Vietnam agreed to "support the initiative of building a community of shared future for human kind", according to a joint statement shown to reporters on Tuesday, after sources said China had been pushing for it. The joint statement is expected to be formally signed on Wednesday.翻译:周二向记者展示的一份联合声明显示，越南同意“支持构建人类命运共同体的倡议”，此前消息人士称，中国一直在推动这一倡议。联合声明预计将于周三正式签署。</p>   <p>The countries' diplomats had debated the "shared future" phrase for months, following Hanoi's initial reluctance to use it, say officials and diplomats.翻译:官员和外交官表示，在河内最初不愿使用“共同未来”这个词之后，两国外交官已经争论了几个月。</p>   <p>The Chinese term literally means "common destiny", but its translation in English and Vietnamese is "common future", which may be seen as less demanding.翻译:中文的字面意思是“共同的命运”，但其英语和越南语的翻译是“共同的未来”，可能会被认为要求不那么高。</p>   <p>"One declaration, many translations," said a diplomat based in the Vietnamese capital, commenting on the interpretation of the term.翻译:“一份声明，多种翻译，”一位驻越南首都的外交官在评论该术语的解释时说道。</p>   <p>In diplomatic ties, the upgrade is symbolic, Le Hong Hiep, a specialist in Vietnamese strategic and political issues at Singapore's Iseas–Yusof Ishak Institute, said.翻译:新加坡尤索夫伊萨研究所研究越南战略和政治问题的专家黎洪协表示，在外交关系中，升级具有象征意义。</p>   <p>"Vietnam's mistrust of China runs deep, and from the Vietnamese people's viewpoint, there is little to no 'shared destiny' between the two countries, as long as China continues to claim most of the South China Sea," he said.翻译:他说：“越南对中国的不信任根深蒂固，从越南人民的角度来看，只要中国继续对南海大部分地区拥有主权，两国之间就几乎没有‘共同命运’。”</p>   <p>Despite close <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/chinas-investments-vietnam-boom-xi-visits-hanoi-us-spending-down-2023-12-08/">economic</a> ties, the neighbours have been at odds over boundaries in the South China Sea and have a millennia-long history of conflict.翻译:尽管<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/chinas-investments-vietnam-boom-xi-visits-hanoi-us-spending-down-2023-12-08/">经济</a>关系密切，但两国在南海边界问题上一直存在分歧，冲突历史已有数千年。</p>   <p>In a sign of possible de-escalation, however, they signed two cooperation agreements for joint patrols in the Tonkin Gulf in the South China Sea and to establish a hotline to handle fisheries incidents, according to one of the agreements.</p>    <h 1="">RAILWAYS, DIGITAL SILK ROAD</h>  <p>Apart from taking ties to a level Beijing may consider above those with the United States, the upgraded status came with the announcement of 36 cooperation deals, according to a list of documents seen by Reuters, and the joint statement on diplomatic ties.翻译:根据路透社看到的文件清单和外交关系联合声明，除了将双边关系提升到北京可能考虑的高于与美国的水平之外，升级的地位还伴随着宣布的 36 项合作协议。</p>   <p>That was short of 45 initially proposed, according to one Vietnamese official, and missed agreements on critical minerals and rare earths on which Xi had urged more cooperation in an opinion piece published on Tuesday in a Vietnamese state newspaper.翻译:一名越南官员称，这一数字比最初提议的 45 项要少，而且未能就关键矿产和稀土达成一致，而习近平在周二在越南官方报纸上发表的一篇评论文章中敦促加强合作。</p>   <p>Deals included two memoranda of understanding on cross-border rail development, including one mentioning developing aid.翻译:交易包括两份关于跨境铁路发展的谅解备忘录，其中一份提到发展援助。</p>   <p>Top officials in both countries had urged a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-vietnam-consider-rail-link-through-rare-earths-heartland-2023-12-01/">boost</a> to a rail link between the southern Chinese city of Kunming and the northern Vietnamese port of Haiphong, which crosses regions in Vietnam rich in rare earths.翻译:两国高级官员都敦促<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-vietnam-consider-rail-link-through-rare-earths-heartland-2023-12-01/">加强</a>中国南部城市昆明和越南北部港口海防之间的铁路连接，该铁路穿越越南富含稀土的地区。</p>   <p>China's ambassador to Vietnam Xiong Bo said earlier this week Beijing was ready to offer <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/xi-visits-china-offers-rail-grants-vietnam-pushes-digital-silk-road-2023-12-11/">grants</a> to develop rail connections, though the volume and terms of possible loans are unclear.翻译:中国驻越南大使熊波本周早些时候表示，北京准备提供<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/xi-visits-china-offers-rail-grants-vietnam-pushes-digital-silk-road-2023-12-11/">赠款</a>以发展铁路连接，但可能提供的贷款数量和条款尚不清楚。</p>   <p>Boosting transport links would allow Vietnam to export more to China, especially farm products, while Beijing wants to further integrate the country's north with its southern supply chain networks, where Chinese firms are moving some operations.翻译:加强运输联系将使越南能够向中国出口更多产品，特别是农产品，而北京方面希望进一步整合该国北部与南部的供应链网络，中国公司正在将一些业务转移到那里。</p>   <p>Stronger rail networks would speed the import of components from China for assembly in Vietnam, effectively expanding China's Belt and Road Initiative (BRI).翻译:更强大的铁路网络将加快从中国进口零部件并在越南组装的速度，从而有效扩大中国的“一带一路”倡议（BRI）。</p>   <p>So far the Hanoi metro is Vietnam's only project to have received BRI loans and it has not been labelled as part of the initiative, as the country's leaders often grapple with widespread anti-Chinese sentiment.翻译:到目前为止，河内地铁是越南唯一获得“一带一路”贷款的项目，但由于该国领导人经常应对广泛的反华情绪，该项目并未被视为该倡议的一部分。</p>   <p>The two countries agreed to jointly promote the "two corridors, one belt" initiative, which is the Vietnamese term for infrastructure projects supported by China.翻译:两国同意共同推进“两廊一带”倡议，这是越南对中国支持的基础设施项目的称呼。</p>   <p>Xi's visit is also expected to boost plans on what is known as the Digital Silk Road, and the two countries signed several deals to cooperate on telecommunications and the digital economy.翻译:预计习近平的访问还将推动数字丝绸之路的计划，两国签署了多项电信和数字经济合作协议。</p>   <p>The content of the agreements is not known but officials had said the increased telecoms cooperation could include digital infrastructure such as 5G networks and undersea optical fibre cables.翻译:这些协议的内容尚不清楚，但官员们表示，增加的电信合作可能包括 5G 网络和海底光缆等数字基础设施。</p>    <span>Reporting by Francesco Guarascio @fraguarascio; Additional reporting by Khanh Vu and Phuong Nguyen in Hanoi; Editing by Lincoln Feast, Clarence Fernandez and Barbara Lewis翻译:Francesco Guarascio@fraguarascio 报道； Khanh Vu 和 Phuong Nguyen 在河内的补充报道；林肯·费斯特 (Lincoln Feast)、克拉伦斯·费尔南德斯 (Clarence Fernandez) 和芭芭拉·刘易斯 (Barbara Lewis) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 15:24:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">LSLGPY73SRI65FLKSXFTKWSMGI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/chinas-xi-visits-vietnam-after-biden-seeks-boost-ties-2023-12-12/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Francesco Guarascio, Khanh Vu, Phuong Nguyen]]></author>
            
                
                <category>VIETNAM</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (UPDATE 8, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[11 月份全球电动汽车销量创下新纪录 - Rho Motion]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/iPAgn7gqvPYkDofRVl_elJgxAVM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4UASRBS7UFI2VG4ABUDJEUV53A.jpg" alt="A charging handle recharges a Volkswagen ID.4 electric vehicle parked at an EV charging station in Baltimore翻译:充电手柄正在为停在巴尔的摩电动汽车充电站的大众 ID.4 电动汽车充电" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A charging handle recharges a Volkswagen ID.4 electric vehicle (EV) parked at an EV charging station inside a parking garage owned by the City of Baltimore, in Baltimore, Maryland, U.S., March 23, 2023. REUTERS/Bing Guan/File Photo翻译:2023 年 3 月 23 日，美国马里兰州巴尔的摩市巴尔的摩市拥有的停车场内的电动汽车充电站内，充电手柄正在为一辆大众 ID.4 电动汽车 (EV) 充电。 REUTERS/Bingguan/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Global sales of battery electric vehicles (BEV) and plug-in hybrids (PHEV) rose 20% versus a year ago as strong growth in North America and China offset lower sales in Europe, according to market research firm Rho Motion.翻译:市场研究公司 Rho Motion 的数据显示，由于北美和中国的强劲增长抵消了欧洲销量的下降，纯电动汽车 (BEV) 和插电式混合动力汽车 (PHEV) 的全球销量同比增长 20%。</p>   <p>Sales of BEVs and PHEVs hit a fresh monthly record of 1.4 million units, up from 1.1 million in November 2022.翻译:BEV 和 PHEV 的销量创下 140 万辆的新月度纪录，高于 2022 年 11 月的 110 万辆。</p>   <p>"Sales have continued to rise despite a lot of negative sentiment in the market and we're expecting sales to remain strong in December," data manager Charles Lester told Reuters.翻译:数据经理查尔斯·莱斯特 (Charles Lester) 告诉路透社：“尽管市场存在很多负面情绪，但销售额仍在继续增长，我们预计 12 月份的销售额将保持强劲。”</p>   <p>After years of accelerating growth, some automakers fear that electric car sales in Europe and elsewhere could be heading for <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/electric-car-demand-set-stall-europes-valley-death-2023-11-13/">slowing demand</a> as drivers wait for better, cheaper models that are two to three years down the road.翻译:经过多年的加速增长，一些汽车制造商担心，欧洲和其他地区的电动汽车销售可能会导致<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/electric-car-demand-set-stall-europes-valley-death-2023-11-13/">需求放缓</a>，因为司机们正在等待两到三年后更好、更便宜的车型。</p>   <p>Globally, BEVs made up 70% of sales and PHEVs made up the remaining 30% in November, Rho Motion said.翻译:Rho Motion 表示，从全球来看，11 月份纯电动汽车占销量的 70%，插电式混合动力汽车占剩余的 30%。</p>   <p>China posted a 25% increase in sales and were up 43% in the United States and Canada, while Europe saw sales drop 3% versus the same month in 2022.翻译:中国的销售额增长了 25%，美国和加拿大的销售额增长了 43%，而欧洲的销售额与 2022 年同月相比下降了 3%。</p>   <p>The drop in Europe reflects a strong end of the year in 2022 as Germans bought electric cars before a reduction in government subsidies kicked in, Rho Motion said.翻译:Rho Motion 表示，欧洲的下降反映了 2022 年年底的强劲表现，因为德国人在政府补贴减少之前购买了电动汽车。</p>   <p>Lester said that as Germany is reducing its BEV subsidies and France is narrowing its own subsidies - to favour European-made electric cars over Chinese ones - sales in Europe should remain strong because automakers will still need to meet emissions targets heading into 2025.翻译:莱斯特表示，随着德国正在减少纯电动汽车补贴，法国也在缩小自己的补贴范围——以青睐欧洲制造的电动汽车而不是中国制造的电动汽车——欧洲的销售应该会保持强劲，因为汽车制造商在 2025 年之前仍需要实现排放目标。</p>   <p>He added that France's targeted subsidies are "going to have a bigger impact" on vehicles like Renault's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RENA.PA" target="_blank">(RENA.PA)</a> Dacia Spring, which is made in China for the European market than on China's BYD <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002594.SZ" target="_blank">(002594.SZ)</a>, because BYD cars "are only just starting to be sold" in France.翻译:他补充说，法国的定向补贴对雷诺<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RENA.PA" target="_blank">（RENA.PA）</a> Dacia Spring等在中国为欧洲市场制造的汽车“将产生比对中国比亚迪<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002594.SZ" target="_blank">（002594.SZ）</a>更大的影响”，因为比亚迪汽车“才刚刚开始在法国销售”。</p>    <span>Reporting By Nick Carey; Editing by Sharon Singleton翻译:尼克·凯里报道；莎朗·辛格尔顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 14:11:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">HNMQOVXKFNOP3J3F7HZAYCYVNA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/global-ev-sales-hit-new-record-november-rho-motion-2023-12-12/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Nick Carey]]></author>
            
                
                <category>AUTOS</category>
                
                <category>ELECTRIC/GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>SALES</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[芬兰警告俄罗斯与中国、伊朗和朝鲜的联系构成威胁]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Russia's increasing cooperation with China, Iran, North Korea and its other global allies is a serious, long-term threat to European countries, Finland's Defence Minister Antti Hakkanen said on Tuesday.翻译:芬兰国防部长安蒂·哈卡宁周二表示，俄罗斯与中国、伊朗、朝鲜及其其他全球盟友日益加强的合作对欧洲国家构成了严重的长期威胁。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/finland-says-it-has-informed-russia-about-its-baltic-sea-gas-pipe-probe-2023-11-08/">Finland</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/estonia-says-chinese-ship-is-main-focus-probe-into-cables-damage-2023-11-10/">Estonia</a> are investigating the destruction in October of the Balticconnector gas pipeline and telecom cables on the Baltic seabed and have named a Hong Kong registered container vessel as their main suspect for the damage.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/finland-says-it-has-informed-russia-about-its-baltic-sea-gas-pipe-probe-2023-11-08/">芬兰</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/estonia-says-chinese-ship-is-main-focus-probe-into-cables-damage-2023-11-10/">爱沙尼亚</a>正在调查 10 月份波罗的海海底的 Balticconnector 天然气管道和电信电缆遭到破坏的事件，并已将一艘香港注册的集装箱船列为此次破坏的主要嫌疑人。</p>   <p>"While these issues are not public, what Russia does at the moment together with China, Iran, North Korea and its other allies, also from the global south, constitutes a very serious prospect in the long term," Hakkanen said in a speech.翻译:哈卡宁在一次演讲中表示：“虽然这些问题并未公开，但俄罗斯目前与中国、伊朗、朝鲜及其其他来自南半球的盟友所做的事情，从长远来看构成了一个非常严峻的前景。”</p>   <p>As the NATO military alliance's newest member, which shares a 1,340-km (830-mile) border with Russia, Finland and its intelligence services are monitoring Russia's action globally, Hakkanen said.翻译:哈卡宁说，作为北约军事联盟的最新成员，芬兰与俄罗斯有着 1,340 公里（830 英里）的边界，其情报部门正在监视俄罗斯在全球的行动。</p>   <p>He called Russia's new cooperation with its global allies "a weather system of security policy that is unfortunately troublesome".翻译:他称俄罗斯与其全球盟友的新合作是“不幸的是，这是一个麻烦的安全政策天气系统”。</p>    <span>Reporting by Anne Kauranen; editing by Barbara Lewis翻译:安妮·考拉宁报道；芭芭拉·刘易斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 11:16:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">53U5UOM6C5JDLLZVWISMN4FDF4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russian-links-with-china-iran-north-korea-threat-warns-finland-2023-12-12/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>NATO</category>
                
                <category>FINLAND/RUSSIA</category>
                
                <category>ALLIES (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[北京智库称儿童是中国最好的投资]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/w1DQv7TqPzOXR2_WQXim27Og3yA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CMMAYLUGSVMIBMADGYTL372WFA.jpg" alt="People pick up children from a school in Beijing翻译:人们从北京一所学校接孩子" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People pick up children from a school in Beijing翻译:人们从北京一所学校接孩子, China, April 6, 2021. Picture taken April 6, 2021.   REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2021年4月6日，人们从中国北京的一所学校接孩子。照片摄于2021年4月6日。路透社/Thomas Peter/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/gHnIF_fCYiw5GPE4b0IlMKEossU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WITTEVZR55MCTBUMGWABOJE5M4.jpg" alt="A little girl sits with her dad in a park in Shanghai翻译:一个小女孩和她爸爸坐在上海的一个公园里" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A little girl sits with her dad in a park in Shanghai翻译:一个小女孩和她爸爸坐在上海的一个公园里, China, April 2, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2023 年 4 月 2 日，一个小女孩和她的父亲坐在中国上海的一个公园里。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>Children are the most worthy investment for China's economy to help stimulate consumption and expand domestic demand a Beijing policy institute said, after the country posted its first <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-population-shrinks-first-time-since-1961-2023-01-17/">population drop</a> in more than six decades last year.翻译:北京政策研究所表示，在中国去年出现六十多年来<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-population-shrinks-first-time-since-1961-2023-01-17/">人口首次下降</a>后，儿童是中国经济最有价值的投资，有助于刺激消费和扩大内需。</p>   <p>China, the world's second-largest economy, has struggled to mount a strong post-pandemic recovery and any decline in its future workforce and consumer demand could have a profound impact on its economy.翻译:作为世界第二大经济体，中国一直在努力实现疫情后的强劲复苏，未来劳动力和消费者需求的任何下降都可能对其经济产生深远影响。</p>   <p>"In the current Chinese economy, children are the best investment. Infrastructure investment is becoming saturated, manufacturing has overcapacity ... but investment in the number of children is not enough," said the policy paper by the Yuwa Population Research institute published on Tuesday.翻译:友和人口研究所周二发布的政策文件称，“当前中国经济中，孩子是最好的投资。基础设施投资趋于饱和，制造业产能过剩……但对孩子数量的投资还不够。” 。</p>   <p>The paper urged authorities to "urgently" reverse a rapid decline in the number of newborns.翻译:该报敦促当局“紧急”扭转新生儿数量迅速下降的趋势。</p>   <p>China's advantage will shrink in the future as the young population shrinks rapidly, while economic measures such as cutting interest rates, activating the capital market and optimising real estate regulation have not helped to bolster economic growth and the recovery remains weak, it said.翻译:报告称，未来中国的优势将缩小，因为年轻人口迅速萎缩，而降息、激活资本市场、优化房地产调控等经济措施对提振经济增长无助益，复苏依然疲软。</p>   <p>In order to boost the economy, the Yuwa report recommended that maternity subsidies be distributed at a national level rather than by local governments and targeted measures be implemented to reduce the large cost of childbearing and rearing.翻译:为了提振经济，友和报告建议生育补贴应由国家层面而不是地方政府来分配，并采取有针对性的措施，降低生育和抚养的巨额成本。</p>   <p>Local governments have announced a series of measures to help lower childcare costs in recent years but many policies翻译:近年来，地方政府出台了一系列降低托儿费用的措施，但不少政策</p>   <p>have not been implemented or remain on paper due to insufficient funding and lack of motivation by local governments, it said翻译:报告称，由于资金不足和地方政府缺乏动力，尚未落实或停留在纸面上。</p>   <p>"Nowadays people are unwilling to get married and have children ... Because the cost of childbearing is too high, the difficulty for women to balance family and work, the average fertility willingness of Chinese people is almost the lowest in the world."翻译:“现在人们不愿意结婚生子……因为生育成本太高，女性难以平衡家庭和工作，中国人的平均生育意愿几乎是全世界最低的。”</p>   <p>Current subsidies are still insufficient, lower than most European countries it said.翻译:目前的补贴仍然不足，低于大多数欧洲国家的水平。</p>   <p>China reported a drop of roughly 850,000 people for a population of 1.41175 billion in 2022, marking the first decline since 1961, the last year of China's Great Famine.翻译:中国报告称，2022年人口将达到14.1175亿，减少约85万人，这是自1961年（中国大饥荒的最后一年）以来的首次下降。</p>    <span>Reporting by Farah Master and the Biejing newsroom; Editing by Michael Perry翻译:Farah Master和北京新闻编辑室报道；迈克尔·佩里编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 04:01:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">G2VEYNZEPRLLTGWSGD3FPCJ4TU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/children-are-best-investment-china-says-beijing-think-tank-2023-12-12/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ASIA</category>
                
                <category>POPULATION/CHINA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024年中国落后市场的投资者将采取防御策略]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/9ernWcDXMc7emYYkHmxRujZKFpE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XI2WTBS6D5JJZDGOL2ILBLDPNA.jpg" alt="An electronic board shows Shanghai and Shenzhen stock indices at the Lujiazui financial district in Shanghai翻译:上海陆家嘴金融区的电子板显示上海和深圳股票指数" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An electronic board shows Shanghai and Shenzhen stock indices at the Lujiazui financial district in Shanghai翻译:上海陆家嘴金融区的电子板显示上海和深圳股票指数, China, March 17, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Investors in Chinese stocks next year will be seeking out businesses with global reach or other insulation from an economic downturn, after three straight years of China underperforming world markets.翻译:在中国连续三年落后于世界市场之后，明年中国股票的投资者将寻找具有全球影响力或其他免受经济衰退影响的企业。</p>   <p>Companies in defensive sectors such as health, medical innovation and exporters in the electric vehicles supply chain and advanced manufacturing, as well as multinationals such as e-commerce firm PDD Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PDD.O" target="_blank">(PDD.O)</a>, will top the list.翻译:健康、医疗创新等防御性行业的公司以及电动汽车供应链和先进制造业的出口商，以及电子商务公司 PDD Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PDD.O" target="_blank">(PDD.O)</a>等跨国公司将名列榜首。</p>   <p>That's despite sell-side analysts turning bullish on China's broader market for next year, with Morgan Stanley and Goldman Sachs forecasting Chinese equities to outperform the S&amp;P 500.翻译:尽管卖方分析师转而看好明年中国更广泛的市场，摩根士丹利和高盛预测中国股市将跑赢标准普尔 500 指数。</p>   <p>"Since economic recovery is slower than expected, we lowered exposures which are sensitive to macro cycles," said Wang Qing, chairman at Shanghai Chongyang Investment Management.翻译:上海重阳投资管理有限公司董事长王庆表示，“由于经济复苏慢于预期，我们降低了对宏观周期敏感的风险敞口。”</p>   <p>Chongyang is instead buying defensive high-dividend stocks, medical innovators with global competitiveness, and advanced manufacturing backed by Beijing, Wang said, declining to list any investments by name.翻译:王表示，重阳转而购买防御性高股息股票、具有全球竞争力的医疗创新公司以及北京支持的先进制造业，但他拒绝透露任何投资的名称。</p>   <p>This follows China's blue chip CSI300 index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI300" target="_blank">(.CSI300)</a> sinking to five-year lows and losing 12% over 2023 against a 15% gain for global stocks <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIWD00000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIWD00000PUS)</a> as the Chinese economy struggled with a property crunch and a slow recovery from COVID-19.翻译:在此之前，中国蓝筹股沪深 300 指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI300" target="_blank">(.CSI300)</a>跌至五年低点，并在 2023 年下跌 12%，而全球股市<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIWD00000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIWD00000PUS)</a>则上涨 15%，原因是中国经济因房地产紧缩和从新冠疫情中缓慢复苏而苦苦挣扎。 -19。</p>   <p>Hong Kong's Hang Seng <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a> fared even worse, sliding more than 18% to trade on a forward price-to-earnings ratio below six, against 21 for the S&amp;P 500 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a>.翻译:香港恒生指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a>的表现更糟，下跌超过 18%，远期市盈率低于 6，而标准普尔 500 指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a>则为 21。</p>   <p>Performance over the last 10 months crushed the optimism that infused the beginning of the year, with four straight months of foreign outflows in the second half of the year totalling a net 138 billion yuan ($19 billion) withdrawn from Chinese equities via the Stock Connect scheme.翻译:过去 10 个月的表现粉碎了年初的乐观情绪，下半年外资连续四个月通过沪港通计划从中国股市净撤资达 1,380 亿元人民币（合 190 亿美元） 。</p>   <p>"Investors (have) struggled to think what the next growth driver for China will be," said Caroline Yu Maurer, head of China and specialised Asia strategies at HSBC Asset Management.翻译:汇丰资产管理公司中国及亚洲专业策略主管卡罗琳·于毛雷尔(Caroline Yu Maurer)表示：“投资者一直在努力思考中国的下一个增长动力是什么。”</p>   <p>Goldman analysts target 4,200 for the CSI300 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI300" target="_blank">(.CSI300)</a> by the end of 2024, up 23% from Monday's close at 3,419. Morgan Stanley forecasts the blue chip index at 3,850 at the end of next year and the Hang Seng <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a> - which finished Monday at 16,201 - at 18,500, up 14%.翻译:高盛分析师的目标是到 2024 年底沪深 300 指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI300" target="_blank">(.CSI300) 达到</a>4,200 点，较周一收盘价 3,419 点上涨 23%。摩根士丹利预计蓝筹股指数到明年年底将达到 3,850 点，而恒生指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a>周一收于 16,201 点，预计将上涨 14% 至 18,500 点。</p>   <p>In contrast, Goldman sees the S&amp;P 500 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a> up less than 2% from current levels to 4,700 by the end of next year. Morgan Stanley sees it falling to 4,500.</p>    <h 1="">EXPORTERS AND MULTINATIONALS</h>  <p>Real estate is casting the longest shadow. The sector that once accounted for a quarter of China's economy is reeling from a series of developer failures and a crisis of confidence that fund managers want to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/words-only-go-so-far-investors-want-property-fixed-before-buying-china-2023-07-31/">see resolved</a> before they commit capital.翻译:房地产业的阴影最为深远。这个曾经占中国经济四分之一的行业正因一系列开发商倒闭和信心危机而陷入困境，基金经理希望在投入资金之前<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/words-only-go-so-far-investors-want-property-fixed-before-buying-china-2023-07-31/">解决这些问题</a>。</p>   <p>Moody's slapped a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/moodys-cuts-chinas-credit-outlook-negative-2023-12-05/">downgrade warning</a> on China's credit rating last week, in part due to the property malaise. Shares of Country Garden <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">(2007.HK)</a>, once China's biggest private property developer and now battling to service its debt, are down 73% this year.翻译:穆迪上周对中国信用评级发出<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/moodys-cuts-chinas-credit-outlook-negative-2023-12-05/">下调警告</a>，部分原因是房地产市场低迷。碧桂园<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">（2007.HK）</a>曾经是中国最大的私营房地产开发商，目前正在努力偿还债务，今年其股价已下跌 73%。</p>   <p>The Hang Seng index of mainland developers <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSMPI" target="_blank">(.HSMPI)</a> is down 44%.翻译:内地开发商恒生指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSMPI" target="_blank">(.HSMPI)</a>下跌 44%。</p>   <p>With the property shock ricocheting through the economy and dampened consumption, Morgan Stanley estimates the number of MSCI China companies missing analyst earnings expectations in the third quarter was the most since 2018.翻译:随着房地产冲击波及经济并抑制消费，摩根士丹利估计第三季度未达到分析师盈利预期的 MSCI 中国公司数量为 2018 年以来最多。</p>   <p>New York hedge fund Indus Capital Partners is among several investors turning away from exposure to China's domestic demand.翻译:纽约对冲基金 Indus Capital Partners 是几家放弃投资中国内需的投资者之一。</p>   <p>We see value in "some exporters and multinationals, and cheap (state-owned enterprises) aligned with and otherwise not of great concern to the government," said Indus partner John Pinkel, without naming specific companies.翻译:Indus 合伙人约翰·平克尔 (John Pinkel) 表示，我们看到了“一些出口商和跨国公司以及与政府结盟的廉价企业（国有企业）的价值”，但他没有透露具体公司的名称。</p>   <p>The stock of PDD, which owns U.S.-based shopping app Temu, for example, is up 75%. Discount retailer Miniso <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9896.HK" target="_blank">(9896.HK)</a> also has a global footprint and its shares are up 80% this year.翻译:例如，拥有美国购物应用 Temu 的拼多多 (PDD) 的股价上涨了 75%。折扣零售商名创优品<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9896.HK" target="_blank">（9896.HK）</a>的足迹也遍布全球，今年其股价上涨了80%。</p>   <p>Global asset manager <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/invesco-overweight-china-likes-some-hong-kong-reits-2023-11-10/">Invesco</a> is overweight on Chinese assets in its Asian portfolios, and strategist David Chao highlighted the attractiveness of global expansion, citing the success of Japanese companies abroad while growth slowed at home.翻译:全球资产管理公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/invesco-overweight-china-likes-some-hong-kong-reits-2023-11-10/">景顺(Invesco)</a>在其亚洲投资组合中增持了中国资产，策略师赵大伟(David Chao)强调了全球扩张的吸引力，理由是日本公司在海外取得了成功，而国内增长却放缓了。</p>   <p>To be sure, there are bargain hunters.翻译:可以肯定的是，有一些讨价还价的人。</p>   <p>Wenli Zheng, a portfolio manager at T. Rowe Price, says shipmakers have record orderbooks and the timing is ideal to buy good but perceived economically sensitive companies that are trading cheaply, such as Kanzhun <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2076.HK" target="_blank">(2076.HK)</a>, a recruiter, or mall operator China Resources Mixc Lifestyle <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/1209.HK" target="_blank">(1209.HK)</a>.翻译:T. Rowe Price的投资组合经理郑文丽表示，造船商的订单量创历史新高，现在是买入价格便宜但被认为对经济敏感的优质公司的理想时机，例如招聘公司或购物中心运营商看准<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2076.HK" target="_blank">（2076.HK）</a>华润万象生活<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/1209.HK" target="_blank">（1209.HK）</a> 。</p>   <p>Jefferies said it has turned "tactically positive" on China given an appreciating yuan and cheap valuations, and LSEG data shows <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinese-firms-set-best-earnings-growth-seven-years-2024-2023-11-28/">sellside analysts</a> think Chinese firms will see their strongest earnings expansion in seven years in 2024.翻译:杰富瑞 (Jefferies) 表示，鉴于人民币升值和估值低廉，该公司已对中国采取“策略上的积极态度”，伦敦证交所 (LSEG) 数据显示， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinese-firms-set-best-earnings-growth-seven-years-2024-2023-11-28/">卖方分析师</a>认为，中国企业将在 2024 年实现七年来最强劲的盈利扩张。</p>   <p>Yet BofA Securities' November survey of 265 Asia fund managers found a majority are either waiting for improvement or looking elsewhere, suggesting no rush to add to their exposure to China.翻译:然而，美国银行证券公司 11 月份对 265 名亚洲基金经理的调查发现，大多数人要么等待改善，要么寻找其他地方，这表明他们并不急于增加在中国的投资。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1872 yuan)翻译:(1 美元 = 7.1872 元)</p>    <span>Reporting by Summer Zhen; Additional reporting by Samuel Shen in Shanghai; Editing by Tom Westbrook and Tom Hogue翻译:夏震报道； Samuel Shen 在上海的补充报道；汤姆·威斯布鲁克和汤姆·霍格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 03:11:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">IEIYMIGWQNMEVOS26T3T62FTS4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/investors-chinas-lagging-markets-play-defence-2024-2023-12-12/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Summer Zhen]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/OUTLOOK (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
