<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 22:30:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[澳门业务复苏 永利度假村第三季度盈利好于预期]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/CL5SMTHg_AE2s7UCAcDeATAWsqI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ETFYV2AQLFNHFJRQPLEGLNCFCU.jpg" alt="Wynn Resorts Ltd property in Las Vegas翻译:Wynn Resorts Ltd 在拉斯维加斯的房产" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An exterior view Wynn hotel-casino in Las Vegas, Nevada, U.S., February 7, 2018.   REUTERS/Steve Marcus/File Photo翻译:2018 年 2 月 7 日，美国内华达州拉斯维加斯永利赌场酒店外景。路透社/史蒂夫·马库斯/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Casino operator Wynn Resorts <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/WYNN.O" target="_blank">(WYNN.O)</a> beat third-quarter profit estimates on Thursday, as strength in gaming, luxury retail and hotel bookings drove steady demand at its Macau properties.翻译:赌场运营商永利度假村<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/WYNN.O" target="_blank">(WYNN.O)</a>周四第三季度利润超出预期，原因是博彩、奢侈品零售和酒店预订的强劲推动了其澳门酒店的稳定需求。</p>   <p>The post-pandemic travel rebound in Macau has been a tailwind for casino operators such as Wynn Resorts.翻译:澳门疫情后旅游业的反弹对永利度假村等赌场运营商来说是一个顺风车。</p>   <p>The results come ahead of the Nov. 10 strike deadline from Las Vegas hospitality workers over a new labor contract.翻译:该结果是在 11 月 10 日拉斯维加斯酒店业工人就新劳动合同进行罢工的最后期限之前公布的。</p>   <p>The unions representing hospitality workers in Las Vegas have been negotiating for about seven months for higher wages, stronger protections against new technology that may threaten jobs, a reduction in steep quotas for housekeepers and improved safety for workers.翻译:代表拉斯维加斯酒店业工人的工会已经就提高工资、加强对可能威胁就业的新技术的保护、减少管家的大幅配额以及提高工人安全等问题进行了大约七个月的谈判。</p>   <p>While competitors <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/mgm-resorts-reaches-labor-deal-with-las-vegas-unions-averts-strike-2023-11-09/">MGM Resorts International</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MGM.N" target="_blank">(MGM.N)</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/culinary-union-reaches-labor-deal-with-caesars-las-vegas-2023-11-08/">Caesars Entertainment</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/CZR.O" target="_blank">(CZR.O)</a> have reached a tentative deal with the unions, Wynn Resorts has yet to yield an agreement.翻译:虽然竞争对手<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/mgm-resorts-reaches-labor-deal-with-las-vegas-unions-averts-strike-2023-11-09/">米高梅国际度假村</a><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MGM.N" target="_blank">(MGM.N)</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/culinary-union-reaches-labor-deal-with-caesars-las-vegas-2023-11-08/">凯撒娱乐</a><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/CZR.O" target="_blank">(CZR.O)</a>已与工会达成初步协议，但永利度假村尚未达成协议。</p>   <p>It previously said it has negotiations scheduled with the unions on Thursday.翻译:该公司此前表示已计划于周四与工会进行谈判。</p>   <p>Shares of the company fell 4.7% in trading after the bell.翻译:盘后交易中，该公司股价下跌 4.7%。</p>   <p>The company posted adjusted profit of 99 cents per share in the third quarter, compared with analysts' average estimate of 75 cents per share, according to LSEG data.翻译:根据 LSEG 数据，该公司第三季度调整后利润为每股 99 美分，而分析师平均预期为每股 75 美分。</p>   <p>Its total revenue was $1.67 billion during the period, while analysts expected $1.59 billion.翻译:其期内总营收为 16.7 亿美元，而分析师预期为 15.9 亿美元。</p>    <span>Reporting by Anandita Mehrotra and Aishwarya Jain in Bengaluru; Editing by Shilpi Majumdar翻译:Anandita Mehrotra 和 Aishwarya Jain 在班加罗尔的报道；希尔皮·马宗达尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 22:06:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">WVIHABPOQVILTOQX4DO32KFJNM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/wynn-resorts-posts-better-than-expected-q3-profit-macau-business-recovery-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>WYNN RESORTS</category>
                
                <category>RESULTS/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[针对中国工商银行的勒索软件攻击扰乱了国债市场交易]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/-H8rgHIF0Z3r-2YqMnYRluFplH4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4TDXCPGCFVIONOBSA7IY45TYRA.jpg" alt="Industrial and Commercial Bank of China Ltd (ICBC)'s logo is seen at its branch in Beijing翻译:中国工商银行（ICBC）北京分行的标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Industrial and Commercial Bank of China Ltd (ICBC)'s logo is seen at its branch in Beijing翻译:中国工商银行（ICBC）北京分行的标志, China, March 30, 2016. REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/File Photo翻译:2016 年 3 月 30 日，中国工商银行 (ICBC) 在中国北京分行的标志。路透社/Kim Kyung-Hoon/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A ransomware attack on Industrial and Commercial Bank of China (ICBC) disrupted some trades in the U.S. Treasury market on Thursday, the Treasury Department said, although the impact on the market was unclear.翻译:美国财政部表示，周四针对中国工商银行（ICBC）的勒索软件攻击扰乱了美国国债市场的部分交易，但对市场的影响尚不清楚。</p>   <p>In ransomware attacks, hackers encrypt an organization's systems and demand ransom payments in exchange for unlocking them. It was not immediately clear who was behind the attack.翻译:在勒索软件攻击中，黑客会对组织的系统进行加密，并要求支付赎金以换取解锁系统。目前尚不清楚谁是此次袭击的幕后黑手。</p>   <p>While <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/white-house-share-ransomware-data-with-allies-source-2023-10-30/">ransomware attacks</a> have been soaring across a range of sectors in recent years, they have rarely disrupted a major financial market. Thursday's incident is likely to raise questions over market participants' cyber security controls and potentially draw regulatory scrutiny.翻译:尽管近年来<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/white-house-share-ransomware-data-with-allies-source-2023-10-30/">勒索软件攻击</a>在多个领域激增，但很少扰乱主要金融市场。周四的事件可能会引发对市场参与者网络安全控制的质疑，并可能引起监管机构的审查。</p>   <p>The Financial Times reported earlier on Thursday that the U.S. Securities Industry and Financial Markets Association (SIFMA) told members that ICBC <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601398.SS" target="_blank">(601398.SS)</a> had been hit by ransomware that disrupted the U.S. Treasury market by preventing it from settling trades on behalf of other market players.翻译:英国《金融时报》周四早些时候报道称，美国证券业和金融市场协会（SIFMA）告诉会员，中国工商银行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601398.SS" target="_blank">（601398.SS）</a>遭到勒索软件攻击，勒索软件阻止其代表其他市场结算交易，扰乱了美国国债市场玩家。</p>   <p>"We are aware of the cybersecurity issue and are in regular contact with key financial sector participants, in addition to federal regulators. We continue to monitor the situation," a Treasury spokesperson said in a response to a question about the FT report.翻译:“我们意识到了网络安全问题，除了联邦监管机构之外，我们还与主要金融部门参与者保持定期联系。我们将继续关注事态发展，”财政部发言人在回答有关《金融时报》报告的问题时表示。</p>   <p>ICBC, China's largest commercial lender by assets, was beginning to restore services as of Thursday afternoon, the newspaper said, citing people briefed on the ransomware attack, which paralyses computer systems unless a payment is made.翻译:该报援引了解勒索软件攻击情况的人士称，中国工商银行是中国资产规模最大的商业银行，从周四下午开始恢复服务，勒索软件攻击会导致计算机系统瘫痪，除非付款。</p>   <p>The Treasury market appeared to be functioning normally on Thursday, according to LSEG data.翻译:根据伦敦证券交易所数据，周四国债市场似乎运行正常。</p>   <p>"In general, the event had a limited impact on the market," said Scott Skrym, executive vice president for fixed income and repo at broker-dealer Curvature Securities.翻译:经纪交易商 Curvature Securities 负责固定收益和回购的执行副总裁 Scott Skrym 表示：“总的来说，该事件对市场的影响有限。”</p>   <p>SIFMA declined to comment. ICBC was not immediately available to comment.翻译:SIFMA拒绝发表评论。记者未能立即联系到中国工商银行置评。</p>   <p>According to the data platform Statista, globally organizations detected 493.33 million ransomware attack attempts last year. Cyber criminal group Lockbit was the most prolific ransomware operator throughout 2022, according to the Financial Services Information Sharing and Analysis Center.翻译:根据数据平台 Statista 的数据，去年全球组织检测到 4.9333 亿次勒索软件攻击尝试。根据金融服务信息共享和分析中心的数据，网络犯罪组织 Lockbit 是 2022 年最多产的勒索软件运营商。</p>    <span>Reporting by Urvi Dugar in Bengaluru and Pete Schroder in Washington; Additional reporting by Zeba Siddiqui and Gertrude Chavez; Editing by Michelle Price, Lisa Shumaker and Diane Craft翻译:Urvi Dugar 在班加罗尔和 Pete Schroder 在华盛顿的报道； Zeba Siddiqui 和 Gertrude Chavez 的补充报道；编辑：Michelle Price、Lisa Shumaker 和 Diane Craft</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 22:02:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">VBXWF64MS5LINE3N466YFWUWHY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-largest-bank-icbc-hit-by-ransomware-software-ft-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Pete Schroeder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ICBC</category>
                
                <category>HACK/ (UPDATE 4, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[共和党人要求拜登在芬太尼和囚犯问题上挑战中国习近平]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/_hxVq59HIHjP5-Kp9Xnkxt7NJ_g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SPITPHHJCFKX7LFBV2AZZKDTYA.jpg" alt="The flags of the United States and China fly in Boston翻译:美国和中国国旗在波士顿飘扬" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The flags of the United States and China fly from a lamppost in the Chinatown neighborhood of Boston, Massachusetts, U.S., November 1, 2021.   REUTERS/Brian Snyder/File Photo翻译:2021年11月1日，美国马萨诸塞州波士顿唐人街附近的灯柱上飘扬着中美两国国旗。路透社/布莱恩·斯奈德/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Republicans in the U.S. Congress urged President Joe Biden to make demands of China's leader Xi Jinping over detained Americans and other issues when they meet next week in San Francisco, arguing that Washington's push to engage Beijing had "negligible benefit."翻译:美国国会共和党人敦促总统乔·拜登下周在旧金山举行会议时就被拘留的美国人和其他问题向中国领导人习近平提出要求，他们认为华盛顿推动与北京接触的“好处微乎其微”。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-set-steal-apec-spotlight-with-talks-steady-ties-2023-11-08/">Biden-Xi meeting</a> around events at the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum will follow a series of largely unreciprocated U.S. cabinet-level visits to China, as the U.S. seeks to recover from a diplomatic crisis over its downing of a suspected Chinese spy balloon flying over the United States in February.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-set-steal-apec-spotlight-with-talks-steady-ties-2023-11-08/">拜登和习近平围绕亚太经合组织（APEC）论坛上的活动举行会晤，</a>此前美国对中国进行了一系列基本上未得到回应的内阁级访问，美国正寻求从击落一名疑似中国人引发的外交危机中恢复过来。二月份，间谍气球飞越美国上空。</p>   <p>Republicans and Democrats in Congress have offered sometimes different approaches for countering China's growing economic and military might despite bipartisan consensus on the need to do so.翻译:尽管两党都认为有必要这样做，但国会中的共和党人和民主党人有时会提出不同的方法来对抗中国日益增长的经济和军事实力。</p>   <p>The 13 Republicans on the House of Representative's bipartisan select committee on China, led by chairman Mike Gallagher, credited the Biden administration in a letter made public on Thursday for strengthened semiconductor export controls and restrictions on outbound investment toward China.翻译:由主席迈克·加拉格尔 (Mike Gallagher) 领导的众议院两党中国特别委员会的 13 名共和党人在周四公开的一封信中称赞拜登政府加强了半导体出口管制和对中国对外投资的限制。</p>   <p>But they asked Biden to present Xi with a list of 10 demands to improve relations, much like Beijing did to U.S. officials in 2021.翻译:但他们要求拜登向习近平提出一份改善关系的10项要求清单，就像北京在2021年对美国官员所做的那样。</p>   <p>Their demands included that China release all Americans the U.S. considers wrongfully detained, take measures over the flow of chemicals used in the opioid fentanyl, cease unsafe intercepts of U.S. ships and aircraft in international waters, and stop the harassment of Philippines ships around a disputed shoal in the South China Sea.翻译:他们的要求包括，中国释放美国认为错误拘留的所有美国人，对阿片类芬太尼所用化学品的流动采取措施，停止在国际水域不安全拦截美国船只和飞机，并停止骚扰有争议浅滩附近的菲律宾船只。在南中国海。</p>   <p>The lawmakers said they shared Biden's desire to deter a conflict, but that the president's engagement push had come at an "unacceptable cost" to competitive or defensive actions that have been "delayed, scuttled, or otherwise dropped."翻译:议员们表示，他们和拜登一样希望阻止冲突，但总统的接触推动付出了“不可接受的代价”，而竞争性或防御性行动却“被推迟、破坏或以其他方式放弃”。</p>   <p>"So far, these very real tradeoffs have led to negligible benefit," they said.翻译:“到目前为止，这些非常现实的权衡带来的好处可以忽略不计，”他们说。</p>   <p>Meanwhile, the letter said Beijing had taken no steps to stop military provocations in the South China Sea or toward the democratically governed island of Taiwan, which China claims as its own.翻译:与此同时，信中称，北京没有采取任何措施阻止在南海或对民主治理的台湾岛的军事挑衅，中国声称台湾拥有主权。</p>   <p>The U.S. also had taken few recent actions toward China specifically regarding human rights issues, the lawmakers wrote, adding that for nearly two years the U.S. had not imposed sanctions on Chinese officials over the erosion of Hong Kong's autonomy or for allegations of rights abuses in China's Xinjiang region and had not expanded trade restrictions under the Treasury Department's Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List.翻译:议员们写道，美国最近也没有针对中国采取一些专门针对人权问题的行动，并补充说，近两年来，美国没有因香港自治受到侵蚀或中国侵犯人权的指控而对中国官员实施制裁。新疆地区，并没有扩大财政部中国军工综合体公司名单下的贸易限制。</p>   <p>"It is clear that competitive actions have been sacrificed to advance aimless, zombie-like engagement," they said.翻译:他们表示：“很明显，为了促进漫无目的、僵尸般的参与，竞争性行动被牺牲了。”</p>   <p>The White House did not respond immediately to a request for comment on the letter.翻译:白宫没有立即回应对这封信发表评论的请求。</p>   <p>China denies allegations by Western governments that it abuses human rights.翻译:中国否认西方政府对其侵犯人权的指控。</p>   <p>Families of Americans the U.S. government has classified as wrongfully detained in China, including Texas-based businessman Mark Swidan, Chinese-American Kai Li and pastor David Lin, have also repeatedly urged the government to prioritize the release of their loved ones in talks with Chinese officials.翻译:被美国政府列为在中国被错误拘留的美国人的家属，包括德克萨斯州商人马克·斯维丹（Mark Swidan）、美籍华人李凯（Kai Li）和牧师大卫·林（David Lin），也一再敦促政府在与中国人的谈判中优先释放他们的亲人官员。</p>   <p>China says such cases are handled according to law.翻译:中方表示，此类案件将依法处理。</p>    <span>Reporting by Michael Martina and Patricia Zengerle; editing by Grant McCool翻译:迈克尔·马丁纳和帕特里夏·曾格勒报道；格兰特·麦库尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 21:50:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TRPMO74CDZK7NFONY3A5ABXXP4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/republicans-demand-biden-challenge-chinas-xi-fentanyl-prisoners-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Michael Martina]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CONGRESS</category>
                
                <category>CHINA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国的 Zeekr 揭示了更大的损失以及北京对美国 IPO 文件的影响]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/isBe0IBRFwA4eM42jPY81Jc1rVY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CV7TH7NCVBPTTMD7I3TU5YBIJE.jpg" alt="People walk past a booth of Zeekr, Chinese automaker Geely's premium electric vehicle (EV) brand, at a shopping mall in Beijing翻译:在北京的一家购物中心，人们走过中国汽车制造商吉利旗下的高端电动汽车 (EV) 品牌 Zeekr 的展位" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk past a booth of Zeekr, Chinese automaker Geely's premium electric vehicle (EV) brand, at a shopping mall in Beijing翻译:在北京的一家购物中心，人们走过中国汽车制造商吉利旗下的高端电动汽车 (EV) 品牌 Zeekr 的展位, China November 3, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 3 日，在中国北京的一家购物中心，人们走过中国汽车制造商吉利旗下的高端电动汽车 (EV) 品牌 Zeekr 的展位。路透社/Tingshu Wang/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's Zeekr Intelligent revealed wider losses for the first half of the year on Thursday and cautioned Beijing could influence its business, as the premium electric car brand made its paperwork public for a stock market listing in New York.翻译:中国的 Zeekr 智能公司周四公布了今年上半年更大的亏损，并警告称，随着这家高端电动汽车品牌公开其在纽约股市上市的文件，北京方面可能会影响其业务。</p>   <p>Zeekr, owned by Chinese automaker Geely Auto <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0175.HK" target="_blank">(0175.HK)</a>, had confidentially filed for its initial public offering (IPO) in December last year.翻译:中国汽车制造商吉利汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0175.HK" target="_blank">（0175.HK）</a>旗下的Zeekr于去年12月秘密申请首次公开募股（IPO）。</p>   <p>"The Chinese government exerts substantial influence over the conduct of our business and may intervene with or influence our operations as the government deems appropriate to further regulatory, political and societal goals," Zeekr said in its prospectus.翻译:Zeekr 在招股说明书中表示：“中国政府对我们的业务行为施加重大影响，并可能在政府认为适当的情况下干预或影响我们的运营，以进一步实现监管、政治和社会目标。”</p>   <p>The filing confirms a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-ev-maker-zeekr-start-investor-tour-ahead-1-bln-us-ipo-sources-2023-08-23/">report</a> from Reuters earlier on Thursday, which said Zeekr was looking to make its IPO prospectus public this week.翻译:该文件证实了路透社周四早些时候的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-ev-maker-zeekr-start-investor-tour-ahead-1-bln-us-ipo-sources-2023-08-23/">报道</a>，该报道称 Zeekr 计划在本周公开其 IPO 招股说明书。</p>   <p>The company was aiming to raise more than $1 billion, Reuters previously <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-ev-maker-zeekr-start-investor-tour-ahead-1-bln-us-ipo-sources-2023-08-23/">reported</a>, but is unlikely to breach the billion-dollar mark, according to one of the sources.翻译:据路透社此前<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-ev-maker-zeekr-start-investor-tour-ahead-1-bln-us-ipo-sources-2023-08-23/">报道</a>，该公司的目标是筹集超过 10 亿美元，但据一位消息人士透露，不太可能突破 10 亿美元大关。</p>   <p>In February, Zeekr was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/geelys-ev-brand-zeekr-raises-750-mln-fresh-funding-round-2023-02-12/">valued</a> at $13 billion after a $750 million funding round from investors including Amnon Shashua, CEO and founder of autonomous driving technology company Mobileye Global <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MBLY.O" target="_blank">(MBLY.O)</a>, and the Guangzhou city municipal government's investment arm Yuexiu Industrial Fund.翻译:今年 2 月，在自动驾驶技术公司 Mobileye Global <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MBLY.O" target="_blank">(MBLY.O)</a>首席执行官兼创始人 Amnon Shashua 和广州市政府投资部门越秀产业基金等投资者的 7.5 亿美元融资后，Zeekr <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/geelys-ev-brand-zeekr-raises-750-mln-fresh-funding-round-2023-02-12/">估值</a>达到 130 亿美元。</p>   <p>For the six months ended June 30, Zeekr reported a net loss of 3.87 billion Chinese yuan ($531.34 million), compared with 3.09 billion Chinese yuan a year earlier.翻译:截至 6 月 30 日的六个月，Zeekr 报告净亏损 38.7 亿元人民币（5.3134 亿美元），而去年同期为 30.9 亿元人民币。</p>   <p>Net revenue, however, more than doubled to 21.27 billion Chinese yuan in the same period.翻译:然而，同期净收入增长了一倍多，达到 212.7 亿元人民币。</p>   <p>The company's current portfolio primarily includes three vehicle models. It plans to launch its first premium sedan model "targeting tech-savvy adults and families" this month.</p>    <h 1="">IPO TO TEST FALLOUT OF SINO-U.S. TENSIONS</h>  <p>The listing could mark the first major float in the U.S. by a Chinese company in two years, after the infamous delisting of ride-hailing giant Didi Global from the New York Stock Exchange.翻译:此次上市可能标志着两年来中国公司在美国首次大规模上市，此前网约车巨头滴滴出行从纽约证券交易所退市。</p>   <p>Didi had <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/majority-shareholders-vote-favor-delisting-didi-new-york-2022-05-23/">angered</a> Chinese regulators by pushing ahead with its $4.4 billion New York listing despite being asked to put it on hold.翻译:滴滴出行尽管被要求暂停，但仍推进其价值 44 亿美元的纽约上市，此举<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/majority-shareholders-vote-favor-delisting-didi-new-york-2022-05-23/">激怒了</a>中国监管机构。</p>   <p>The episode, together with a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/us-pcaob-says-is-able-inspect-firms-china-first-time-2022-12-15/">longstanding</a> audit dispute between China and the U.S., stalled Chinese companies from seeking U.S. listings. Only six mainland China-based companies launched U.S. IPOs in 2022.翻译:这一事件，加上中美之间<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/us-pcaob-says-is-able-inspect-firms-china-first-time-2022-12-15/">长期存在的</a>审计纠纷，阻碍了中国企业寻求美国上市。 2022 年，只有六家中国大陆公司在美国进行 IPO。</p>   <p>Since then, however, Beijing has softened its stance towards companies looking to list internationally, unveiling a set of rules earlier this year to revive such listings, after the U.S. accounting watchdog and China solved the audit dispute in December 2022.翻译:然而，自那以后，北京方面对寻求国际上市的公司的立场软化了，在美国会计监管机构和中国于 2022 年 12 月解决审计纠纷后，北京方面于今年早些时候公布了一套规则，以恢复此类上市。</p>   <p>But simmering tensions between two of the world's biggest economies over trade, intellectual property and the future of Taiwan continue to spill over into the corporate sphere.翻译:但世界上最大的两个经济体之间在贸易、知识产权和台湾未来方面不断升温的紧张关系继续蔓延到企业领域。</p>   <p>In August, Intel <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/INTC.O" target="_blank">(INTC.O)</a> had to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/intel-walk-away-54-bln-acquisition-tower-semiconductor-sources-2023-08-16/">scrap</a> its $5.4 billion deal to buy Israeli contract chipmaker Tower Semiconductor <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSEM.TA" target="_blank">(TSEM.TA)</a> after their merger agreement expired without regulatory approval from China.翻译:8 月，英特尔<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/INTC.O" target="_blank">(INTC.O)</a>不得不<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/intel-walk-away-54-bln-acquisition-tower-semiconductor-sources-2023-08-16/">取消</a>其以 54 亿美元收购以色列合约芯片制造商 Tower Semiconductor <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSEM.TA" target="_blank">(TSEM.TA)</a>的交易，因为双方的合并协议未经中国监管部门批准就到期。</p>   <p>A similar delay had also led to DuPont De Nemours <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DD.N" target="_blank">(DD.N)</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/dupont-end-52-bln-acquisition-rogers-clearance-hurdles-2022-11-01/">ending</a> its $5.2 billion deal to buy electronics materials maker Rogers Corp <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ROG.N" target="_blank">(ROG.N)</a> last year.翻译:类似的延迟还导致杜邦德内穆尔公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DD.N" target="_blank">(DD.N)</a>去年<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/dupont-end-52-bln-acquisition-rogers-clearance-hurdles-2022-11-01/">终止了</a>以 52 亿美元收购电子材料制造商罗杰斯公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ROG.N" target="_blank">(ROG.N)</a>的交易。</p>   <p>Zeekr will list its shares on the New York Stock Exchange under the ticker symbol "ZK".翻译:Zeekr 将在纽约证券交易所上市，股票代码为“ZK”。</p>   <p>Goldman Sachs and Morgan Stanley are the lead underwriters for the IPO.翻译:高盛和摩根士丹利是此次IPO的主承销商。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2835 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2835 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Niket Nishant and Manya Saini in Bengaluru, Additional reporting by Jaiveer Shekhawat and Mehnaz Yasmin; Editing by Krishna Chandra Eluri and Shilpi Majumdar翻译:Niket Nishant 和 Manya Saini 在班加罗尔的报道，Jaiveer Shekhawat 和 Mehnaz Yasmin 的补充报道；编辑：Krishna Chandra Eluri 和 Shilpi Majumdar</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 20:53:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">OEHVZVWCBZJ27PWBUKYGHVR32U</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/zeekr-makes-us-ipo-filing-public-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Niket Nishant]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ZEEKR</category>
                
                <category>IPO/ (UPDATE 4, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[耶伦寻求在APEC峰会前与中国副总理进行“实质性”会谈]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0CfW0zdhxZ1UYWzTZUWui4LV120=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3YZTFDIAZFNLFKE7LLFO5OJHCU.jpg" alt="Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen speaks at IRS Headquarters in Washington翻译:财政部长珍妮特·耶伦在华盛顿国税局总部发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen outlines the improvements the IRS will deliver to taxpayers in 2024, during remarks at IRS Headquarters in Washington, U.S., November 7, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦 (Janet Yellen) 于 2023 年 11 月 7 日在美国华盛顿国税局总部发表讲话时概述了国税局将在 2024 年为纳税人提供的改进。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen began two days of meetings with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng on Thursday in a bid to limit the economic fallout from tensions between Washington and Beijing and keep the lines of communication open on topics from national security to climate change.翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦周四开始与中国国务院副总理何立峰举行为期两天的会议，以限制华盛顿和北京之间紧张局势造成的经济影响，并就国家安全和气候变化等话题保持沟通畅通。</p>   <p>U.S. Treasury officials have sought to downplay expectations for any breakthroughs from the meetings in San Francisco, where U.S. President Joe Biden next week will host a summit of Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) country leaders, including Chinese President Xi Jinping.翻译:美国财政部官员试图淡化对旧金山会议取得任何突破的预期，美国总统乔·拜登下周将在旧金山主持亚太经合组织（APEC）国家领导人峰会，其中包括中国国家主席习近平。</p>   <p>Biden and Xi are expected to steal the spotlight with a planned meeting on the summit sidelines. Yellen first met with He during a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/yellen-says-china-us-have-significant-disagreements-that-must-be-communicated-2023-07-09/">visit to Beijing in July</a> that was among a series of cabinet-level engagements that paved the way for the two leaders to meet.翻译:预计拜登和习近平将在峰会间隙举行计划中的会晤，成为众人瞩目的焦点。耶伦<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/yellen-says-china-us-have-significant-disagreements-that-must-be-communicated-2023-07-09/">在七月份访问北京</a>期间首次会见了贺建奎，这是一系列内阁级别的接触之一，为两位领导人的会面铺平了道路。</p>   <p>In <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-treasurys-yellen-wants-open-substantive-talks-with-chinese-vice-premier-2023-11-09/">opening remarks</a>, Yellen said she wanted "an open and substantive discussion" on the U.S.-China economic relationship, Beijing's subsidy practices and global challenges such as climate change and debt relief, among other issues.翻译:耶伦在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-treasurys-yellen-wants-open-substantive-talks-with-chinese-vice-premier-2023-11-09/">开幕词</a>中表示，她希望就美中经济关系、北京的补贴做法以及气候变化和债务减免等全球挑战进行“公开和实质性的讨论”。</p>   <p>"The United States has no desire to decouple from China: A full separation of our economies would be economically disastrous for both our countries, and for the world," she told He.翻译:“美国无意与中国脱钩：我们经济的全面分离将对我们两国和世界造成经济灾难，”她告诉贺建奎。</p>   <p>Flanked by more than a dozen staff on each side facing each other across a swath of Marigold flowers, Yellen sought to reassure China that the U.S. wants a healthy economic relationship with China based on a level playing field.翻译:耶伦两侧都有十多​​名工作人员，隔着一大片万寿菊花面对面，试图向中国保证，美国希望与中国在公平竞争环境的基础上建立健康的经济关系。</p>   <p>She added she would discuss and explain the reasons behind continued U.S. national security restrictions.</p>    <h 1="">CHINA'S CONCERNS</h>  <p>He, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-new-economic-tsar-faces-challenges-emulating-his-predecessor-2023-11-01/">China's new economic czar</a>, who faces flagging growth at home, said through an interpreter that his engagements with Yellen so far have been "constructive." But he added that the two sides needed to bring their relationship "back to a healthy and stable development."翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-new-economic-tsar-faces-challenges-emulating-his-predecessor-2023-11-01/">中国新任经济沙皇</a>面临国内经济增长疲弱的局面，他通过翻译表示，迄今为止他与耶伦的接触是“建设性的”。但他补充说，双方需要使两国关系“恢复健康稳定发展”。</p>   <p>He said he would communicate China’s "key concerns on the economy," including improving the investment and business environment and "to also take effective measures to bring our economic and trade relations back on track" -- references to longstanding Chinese objections to U.S. tariffs on its exports and restrictions on U.S. investment in China.翻译:他表示，他将传达中国“对经济的主要关切”，包括改善投资和营商环境，并“采取有效措施让我们的经贸关系重回正轨”——指的是中国长期以来反对美国对美国加征关税的做法。其出口和美国对华投资的限制。</p>   <p>The San Francisco meetings mark the first in-person gatherings of new U.S.-China economic and financial forums involving staff-level officials from both sides after their launch in October.翻译:旧金山会议标志着新的美中经济和金融论坛自 10 月启动以来首次有双方官员级别的面对面聚会。</p>   <p>But in announcing the consultations on Monday, Yellen said this would not be a recreation of the Obama administration's U.S.-China Strategic and Economic Dialogue, a broad forum that was widely criticized for its lack of substance.翻译:但耶伦在周一宣布磋商时表示，这不会是奥巴马政府美中战略与经济对话的翻版，这一范围广泛的论坛因缺乏实质内容而受到广泛批评。</p>   <p>A U.S. Treasury official said that a key goal for the meetings was deepening communications with China, gaining a better understanding of the relationship, and avoiding any misunderstandings about U.S. policy decisions.</p>    <h 1="">'FRACTURED' RELATIONSHIP</h>  <p>Kelly Ann Shaw, a former White House trade adviser to former President Donald Trump, said it was important for Yellen to re-engage with China, but that the meeting would do little to change the overall trajectory of U.S.-China relations.翻译:前总统唐纳德·特朗普的前白宫贸易顾问凯莉·安·肖表示，耶伦重新与中国接触很重要，但这次会议对改变美中关系的整体轨迹无济于事。</p>   <p>"This relationship is fundamentally fractured. And I think it's going to stay that way for the foreseeable future," said Shaw, a partner at law firm Hogan Lovells.翻译:霍金路伟律师事务所合伙人肖说：“这种关系从根本上破裂了。我认为在可预见的未来，这种关系仍将保持这种状态。”</p>   <p>"So it's about figuring out, what do we want this relationship to look like knowing that? And just because you don't like each other doesn't mean you can't get along where your interests align."翻译:“所以关键是弄清楚，知道这一点后，我们希望这种关系是什么样子？仅仅因为你们不喜欢对方，并不意味着你们不能在利益一致的情况下相处。”</p>   <p>Yellen also said that she would discuss cooperation with China on global challenges, including climate change and debt relief for low-income countries, where the U.S. and China "have an obligation to lead."翻译:耶伦还表示，她将与中国讨论应对全球挑战的合作，包括气候变化和低收入国家债务减免，美国和中国“有义务在这些领域发挥领导作用”。</p>   <p>The meetings are being held just days after the U.S. Treasury's semi-annual currency report chided China over a lack of transparency in its foreign exchange intervention practices. But the Treasury report said <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/us-finds-no-major-trade-partners-manipulated-currencies-2023-11-07/">no major trading partners</a>, including China, met the thresholds for currency manipulation.翻译:这些会议是在美国财政部半年度货币报告指责中国外汇干预行为缺乏透明度几天后举行的。但财政部报告称，包括中国在内<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/us-finds-no-major-trade-partners-manipulated-currencies-2023-11-07/">的主要贸易伙伴均未</a>达到货币操纵的门槛。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Lawder; Editing by Angus MacSwan, Paul Simao and Daniel Wallis翻译:大卫·劳德报道；编辑：Angus MacSwan、Paul Simao 和 Daniel Wallis</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 20:01:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">PS3GFK7EKFJTZKDWKV4O4RSTSI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us-treasurys-yellen-chinese-vice-premier-he-set-meet-amid-pre-apec-friction-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Lawder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国财政部长耶伦希望与中国副总理进行“公开且实质性”的会谈]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/1IgL-ohs3UQKsFveVZnICU2KaIo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/I4BJQ4J7C5NFRF7LKBDQU4X4DY.jpg" alt="The United States hosts leaders from APEC nations in San Francisco翻译:美国在旧金山接待亚太经合组织国家领导人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen shakes hands with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng during a bilateral meeting ahead of a U.S.-hosted APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 9, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:2023 年 11 月 9 日，在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会之前，美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦 (Janet Yellen) 在双边会议上与中国国务院副总理何立峰握手。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/I5hCd9KEuj0rgGrd-0W2tIC9Q7Y=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NHPIY6W2R5IYLG2WL2QOFO6LKI.jpg" alt="The United States hosts leaders from APEC nations in San Francisco翻译:美国在旧金山接待亚太经合组织国家领导人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen meets with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng during a bilateral meeting ahead of a U.S.-hosted APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 9, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦于 2023 年 11 月 9 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的 APEC（亚太经合组织）峰会之前的双边会议上会见中国国务院副总理何立峰。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/--GwO009bveeFdvxmcW_jEkhx14=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/Q2R36VSOZ5PB5CCGBN5LOXAA6Y.jpg" alt="The United States hosts leaders from APEC nations in San Francisco翻译:美国在旧金山接待亚太经合组织国家领导人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen meets with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng (not pictured) during a bilateral meeting ahead of a U.S.-hosted APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 9, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦 (Janet Yellen) 于 2023 年 11 月 9 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的 APEC（亚太经合组织）峰会之前的双边会议上会见了中国国务院副总理何立峰（未图示）。 REUTERS/卡洛斯·巴里亚</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/XtbmkbDzHkzb1BqvR96omPpqEhg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2Q2XFQ57PNMZRGGJG6YY73ELPQ.jpg" alt="The United States hosts leaders from APEC nations in San Francisco翻译:美国在旧金山接待亚太经合组织国家领导人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng meets with U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen (not pictured) during a bilateral meeting ahead of a U.S.-hosted APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 9, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:2023 年 11 月 9 日，中国国务院副总理何立峰在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会之前举行双边会晤，会见美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦 (Janet Yellen)。 REUTERS/卡洛斯·巴里亚</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/uQl_G6_7uDa1QcJQjd25glco-v0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NGNOBTH7VVMEDPPUGURTHI4N24.jpg" alt="The United States hosts leaders from APEC nations in San Francisco翻译:美国在旧金山接待亚太经合组织国家领导人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen meets with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng during a bilateral meeting ahead of a U.S.-hosted APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 9, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦于 2023 年 11 月 9 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的 APEC（亚太经合组织）峰会之前的双边会议上会见中国国务院副总理何立峰。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ziGxAEY_G5M_z0HRRKYhpHcGeUM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3WRIX7GKZZIXFGBBCY7MAHDM5A.jpg" alt="The United States hosts leaders from APEC nations in San Francisco翻译:美国在旧金山接待亚太经合组织国家领导人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen shakes hands with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng during a bilateral meeting ahead of a U.S.-hosted APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 9, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:2023 年 11 月 9 日，在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会之前，美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦 (Janet Yellen) 在双边会议上与中国国务院副总理何立峰握手。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/JHOeN_A_Xb0R3nNNOc3evUcYYLg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BZUYXJPZDJI7DOTZZRM7DYJCEI.jpg" alt="U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen visits China翻译:美国财长耶伦访华" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen, left, shakes hands with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng during a meeting at the Diaoyutai State Guesthouse in Beijing, China, Saturday, July 8, 2023.      Mark Schiefelbein/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:2023 年 7 月 8 日星期六，美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦（左）在中国北京钓鱼台国宾馆会见时与中国国务院副总理何立峰握手。Mark Schiefelbein/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>                         <p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen on Thursday told Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng she wants to have an "open and substantive" discussion on the U.S.-China economic relationship, Beijing's subsidy practices and global challenges such as climate change and debt relief.翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦周四对中国国务院副总理何立峰表示，她希望就美中经济关系、北京的补贴做法以及气候变化和债务减免等全球挑战进行“公开和实质性”的讨论。</p>   <p>In prepared remarks at the start of two days of bilateral meetings in San Francisco ahead of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-treasurys-yellen-chinese-vice-premier-he-set-meet-amid-pre-apec-friction-2023-11-09/">a summit</a> of Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) country leaders, Yellen said she has worked in recent months to establish an economic dialogue with her Chinese counterparts.翻译:在亚太经合组织（APEC）国家领导人<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-treasurys-yellen-chinese-vice-premier-he-set-meet-amid-pre-apec-friction-2023-11-09/">峰会</a>之前，耶伦在旧金山举行的为期两天的双边会议开始时发表了事先准备好的讲话，她表示，近几个月来，她一直致力于与中国同行建立经济对话。</p>   <p>"I hope to build on this strong foundation with an open and substantive discussion over the next two days," Yellen said. "The United States has no desire to decouple from China: A full separation of our economies would be economically disastrous for both our countries, and for the world."翻译:耶伦表示：“我希望在接下来的两天里通过公开和实质性的讨论来建立这个坚实的基础。” “美国无意与中国脱钩：我们经济的全面分离将对我们两国和世界造成经济灾难。”</p>   <p>Instead, Yellen said the U.S. seeks a healthy economic relationship with China that benefits both countries over the long term and will raise concerns about Chinese policies that prohibit fair competition.翻译:相反，耶伦表示，美国寻求与中国建立健康的经济关系，使两国长期受益，并将对中国禁止公平竞争的政策表示担忧。</p>   <p>Yellen's second face-to-face meeting with He since she <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/yellen-says-china-us-have-significant-disagreements-that-must-be-communicated-2023-07-09/">visited Beijing</a> in July is among a series of cabinet-level engagements that paved the way for U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping to meet on the sidelines of the APEC summit next week.翻译:耶伦自7月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/yellen-says-china-us-have-significant-disagreements-that-must-be-communicated-2023-07-09/">访问北京</a>以来与贺建奎的第二次面对面会面是一系列内阁级别的接触之一，为美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平下周在亚太经合组织峰会期间会面铺平了道路。</p>   <p>The Biden administration is hoping to use the meetings in San Francisco to limit the economic fallout from US-Sino tensions and keep the lines of communication open on key issues. U.S. Treasury officials, however, have sought to downplay expectations for any breakthroughs.翻译:拜登政府希望利用旧金山的会议来限制美中紧张局势造成的经济影响，并在关键问题上保持沟通渠道畅通。然而，美国财政部官员试图淡化对任何突破的预期。</p>   <p>In her prepared remarks, Yellen said she looks forward to discussing collaboration on global challenges, from climate change to debt distress in low-income countries, adding that the U.S. and China "have an obligation to lead" on these issues.翻译:耶伦在准备好的讲话中表示，她期待讨论应对从气候变化到低收入国家债务困境等全球挑战的合作，并补充说美国和中国“有义务在这些问题上发挥领导作用”。</p>   <p>She also said she intends to discuss U.S. plans for continued national security restrictions on certain technology exports and on U.S. investment in China.翻译:她还表示，打算讨论美国继续对某些技术出口和美国对华投资实施国家安全限制的计划。</p>   <p>"The United States will continue to take targeted actions to protect our and our allies' national security. But we are also committed to communicating clearly about these actions to prevent any misunderstandings or miscalculations. And we welcome more clarity on China's thinking and actions," Yellen said.翻译:“美国将继续采取有针对性的行动，保护我们和我们盟友的国家安全。但我们也致力于就这些行动进行明确沟通，以防止任何误解或误判。我们欢迎中国更加明确地了解其想法和行动。”耶伦说道。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Lawder; Editing by Paul Simao翻译:大卫·劳德报道；保罗·西毛编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 19:57:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MXWOASWULJK6VPED6VEEUFXCVE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us-treasurys-yellen-wants-open-substantive-talks-with-chinese-vice-premier-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>YELLEN (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国立法者公布法案要求私募股权公司披露中国投资]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/byOjhKRTqjhw9EG2FbHlWtxFrFQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5VCZJEKSJFOBHLVRF7QSOFKGCQ.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris deliver remarks on the Biden-Harris economic agenda during a visit in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania翻译:美国总统乔·拜登和副总统卡马拉·哈里斯在宾夕法尼亚州费城访问期间就拜登-哈里斯经济议程发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Senator Bob Casey (D-PA) delivers remarks at the Belmont Water Treatment Center during a visit to Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, U.S., February 3, 2023. REUTERS/Elizabeth Frantz
翻译:美国参议员鲍勃·凯西 (D-PA) 于 2023 年 2 月 3 日访问美国宾夕法尼亚州费城期间在贝尔蒙特水处理中心发表讲话。路透社/Elizabeth Frantz</figcaption></figure>       <p>Two U.S. senators introduced a bipartisan bill on Thursday that would require private equity firms to make public how much they invest in China and other countries of concern.翻译:两名美国参议员周四提出了一项两党法案，要求私募股权公司公开其在中国和其他相关国家的投资金额。</p>   <p>The bill, introduced by Democratic Senator Bob Casey and Republican Senator Rick Scott, is the latest effort to track U.S. investments in China.翻译:该法案由民主党参议员鲍勃·凯西和共和党参议员里克·斯科特提出，是追踪美国在华投资的最新举措。</p>   <p>"The American people deserve to know where and how their savings are being invested," Casey said in a statement.翻译:凯西在一份声明中说：“美国人民应该知道他们的储蓄被投资到哪里以及如何投资。”</p>   <p>Reuters exclusively reported on the bill earlier Thursday.翻译:路透社周四早些时候独家报道了该法案。</p>   <p>The United States has sought to crack down on U.S. investment in China over fears U.S. dollars and know-how are aiding Beijing's technological advances to modernize its military.翻译:由于担心美元和技术正在帮助北京实现军事现代化的技术进步，美国一直试图打击美国对华投资。</p>   <p>U.S. private investment firms have poured more than $80 billion into China between 2018 and 2022, some via pension plans, according to Casey's office.翻译:凯西办公室称，2018年至2022年间，美国私人投资公司已向中国注入超过800亿美元，其中一些是通过养老金计划。</p>   <p>The new congressional measure would require private equity funds to annually disclose assets invested in China, Iran, Russia and North Korea to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, which would then be required to make public a report based on the information.翻译:新的国会措施将要求私募股权基金每年向美国证券交易委员会披露在中国、伊朗、俄罗斯和朝鲜投资的资产，然后要求美国证券交易委员会根据这些信息公开一份报告。</p>   <p>It would also require disclosure of certain information about private security sales.翻译:它还要求披露有关私人证券销售的某些信息。</p>   <p>"Our adversaries, like Communist China, benefit from a complete lack of transparency," Rick Scott said in a statement. "It is time to stop sending American dollars to these countries of concern."翻译:里克·斯科特在一份声明中表示：“我们的对手，比如共产主义中国，受益于完全缺乏透明度。” “是时候停止向这些令人担忧的国家发送美元了。”</p>   <p>A spokesperson for the Chinese embassy in Washington did not immediately respond to a request for comment.翻译:中国驻华盛顿大使馆发言人没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Casey has also co-sponsored a measure that would require government notification of investments in certain sensitive technology sectors in China. That measure has been added as an amendment to the Senate's National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA) and may or may not survive reconciliation with the House's version.翻译:凯西还共同发起了一项措施，要求政府通报对中国某些敏感技术领域的投资。该措施已作为参议院国防授权法案 (NDAA) 的修正案添加，并且可能会也可能不会在与众议院版本协调后继续存在。</p>   <p>The new bill also comes in the wake of an executive order on outbound investment to prohibit some U.S. investments in China in semiconductors and microelectronics, quantum computing and artificial intelligence, and require notification of others. The order has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-senate-backs-measure-requiring-reporting-china-tech-investments-2023-07-25/">not yet been implemented</a>.翻译:这项新法案也是在一项关于对外投资的行政命令之后出台的，该命令禁止美国在中国对半导体和微电子、量子计算和人工智能的部分投资，并要求其他方面进行通报。该命令<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-senate-backs-measure-requiring-reporting-china-tech-investments-2023-07-25/">尚未执行</a>。</p>    <span>Reporting by Karen Freifeld; Editing by Sharon Singleton and Lisa Shumaker翻译:凯伦·弗赖菲尔德报道；莎朗·辛格尔顿和丽莎·舒梅克编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 18:52:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">AUM35LSMAJO55ARZMPKFAZSVNE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-lawmakers-unveil-bill-requiring-private-equity-firms-reveal-china-investment-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Karen Freifeld]]></author>
            
                
                <category>US</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/OUTBOUND (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[分析师称英伟达计划向中国推出三款新芯片]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/iKuPmVnXANPE-kyjlM6GnY0YTLA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/QUKAGB44GZMWJFF3RK35POATP4.jpg" alt="Illustration shows NVIDIA logo翻译:插图显示 NVIDIA 徽标" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A smartphone with a displayed NVIDIA logo is placed on a computer motherboard in this illustration taken March 6, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张 2023 年 3 月 6 日拍摄的插图中，一台显示 NVIDIA 徽标的智能手机被放置在计算机主板上。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Nvidia <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NVDA.O" target="_blank">(NVDA.O)</a> plans to release new artificial intelligence chips aimed at the Chinese market less than a month after U.S. officials tightened the rules on selling high-end AI chips to China.翻译:在美国官员收紧向中国销售高端人工智能芯片的规定不到一个月后，英伟达<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NVDA.O" target="_blank">(NVDA.O)</a>计划针对中国市场发布新的人工智能芯片。</p>   <p>The chip industry newsletter SemiAnalysis said that the Nvidia chips are called the HGX H20, L20 PCIe and L2 PCIe and that Nvidia could announce them on Nov. 16 at the earliest. Nvidia's shares were up 3.3% in midday trading after the report.翻译:芯片行业时事通讯 SemiAnalysis 称，Nvidia 芯片被称为 HGX H20、L20 PCIe 和 L2 PCIe，Nvidia 最早可能在 11 月 16 日发布。报告发布后，Nvidia 股价在午盘交易中上涨 3.3%。</p>   <p>The chips include most of Nvidia's newest features for AI work, but have had some of their computing power measures cut back to comply with new U.S. rules, according to the newsletter's analysis of the chip's specifications.翻译:根据时事通讯对芯片规格的分析，这些芯片包含了英伟达人工智能工作的大部分最新功能，但为了遵守美国新规定，一些计算能力指标被削减。</p>   <p>Nvidia declined to comment when asked about the report. The White House and the Commerce Department did not immediately respond to requests for comment.翻译:当被问及该报告时，英伟达拒绝置评。白宫和商务部没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Last month, the U.S. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/nvidia-may-be-forced-shift-out-some-countries-after-new-us-export-curbs-2023-10-17/">AI chip giant</a>, whose graphics processing units (GPUs) dominate the market for AI, said <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/biden-cut-china-off-more-nvidia-chips-expand-curbs-more-countries-2023-10-17/">new export restrictions</a> announced by Washington would block it from selling two of its modified advanced AI chips - the A800 and H800 - both of which were created for the Chinese market last year to comply with previous export rules.翻译:上个月，这家图形处理单元（GPU）在人工智能市场占据主导地位的美国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/nvidia-may-be-forced-shift-out-some-countries-after-new-us-export-curbs-2023-10-17/">人工智能芯片巨头</a>表示，华盛顿宣布的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/biden-cut-china-off-more-nvidia-chips-expand-curbs-more-countries-2023-10-17/">新出口限制</a>将阻止其销售两款经过修改的先进人工智能芯片——A800和H800——这两款芯片去年为中国市场创建了这些产品，以遵守之前的出口规则。</p>   <p>The new rules put a cap on how much how much computing power a chip can pack into a small size. The rules also include what analysts call a "grey zone" in which the chips might still be allowed to ship to China but will require a license.翻译:新规则限制了芯片可以在小尺寸中容纳多少计算能力。这些规则还包括分析师所说的“灰色地带”，在该地带，芯片可能仍被允许运往中国，但需要获得许可证。</p>   <p>In a note to clients, Wells Fargo analyst Aaron Rakers wrote that all three of Nvidia's reported chips appear to fall below the absolute caps on computing power, but one of them appears to be in the grey zone and will require a license.翻译:富国银行分析师 Aaron Rakers 在给客户的一份报告中写道，英伟达报告的所有三款芯片似乎都低于计算能力的绝对上限，但其中一款似乎处于灰色地带，需要许可证。</p>   <p>"While we would consider an introduction of these three new GPUs as a positive, we would expect investors to question whether (Nvidia) is being a bit too aggressive in its efforts to circumvent U.S. restrictions and could ultimately just result in翻译:“虽然我们认为推出这三款新 GPU 是积极的，但我们预计投资者会质疑（Nvidia）在规避美国限制方面是否过于激进，最终可能会导致</p>   <p>further (U.S. government) moves going forward," Rakers wrote, noting that Nvidia gets about a quarter of its data center chip revenue from China.翻译:（美国政府）将进一步采取行动，”雷克斯写道，并指出英伟达约四分之一的数据中心芯片收入来自中国。</p>   <p>One of the Nvidia's top-of-the-line gaming chips, the RTX 4090, is also affected by the new rules, Nvidia has said.翻译:Nvidia 表示，Nvidia 的顶级游戏芯片之一 RTX 4090 也受到新规则的影响。</p>   <p>On Oct. 24, Nvidia said those curbs would take immediate effect, as U.S. regulators had sped up an original deadline.翻译:10 月 24 日，英伟达表示，这些限制措施将立即生效，因为美国监管机构已经加快了原定的最后期限。</p>   <p>Nvidia has commanded more than 90% share of China's $7 billion AI chip market, and analysts have said the U.S. curbs are likely to create opportunities for domestic firms such as Huawei Technologies (HWT.UL) to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-chip-curbs-give-huawei-chance-fill-nvidia-void-china-2023-10-20/">make inroads</a>.翻译:英伟达占据了中国 70 亿美元人工智能芯片市场 90% 以上的份额，分析师表示，美国的限制措施可能会为华为技术有限公司 (HWT.UL) 等国内公司创造<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-chip-curbs-give-huawei-chance-fill-nvidia-void-china-2023-10-20/">进入市场</a>的机会。</p>   <p>Chinese internet giant Baidu <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9888.HK" target="_blank">(9888.HK)</a> placed <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/baidu-placed-ai-chip-order-huawei-shift-away-nvidia-sources-2023-11-07/">a sizeable order</a> for Huawei AI chips this year, sources have said. One said Baidu had done so before the U.S. curbs were announced as it was preparing for a future when it would no longer be able to purchase from Nvidia.翻译:消息人士称，中国互联网巨头百度<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9888.HK" target="_blank">（9888.HK）</a>今年向华为人工智能芯片下了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/baidu-placed-ai-chip-order-huawei-shift-away-nvidia-sources-2023-11-07/">相当大的订单</a>。一位人士表示，百度在美国宣布限制措施之前就已经这样做了，因为它正在为未来不再能够从英伟达购买产品做准备。</p>    <span>Reporting by Brenda Goh, Max A. Cherney, Stephen Nellis, Fanny Potkin and Alexandra Alper; Editing by Christopher Cushing, Edwina Gibbs and David Evans翻译:Brenda Goh、Max A. Cherney、Stephen Nellis、Fanny Potkin 和 Alexandra Alper 报道；克里斯托弗·库欣、埃德温娜·吉布斯和大卫·埃文斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 18:38:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BG7ILF2EI5P5TM6FKXOHZP3ECE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/nvidia-plans-release-three-new-chips-china-local-media-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Stephen Nellis, Max Cherney, Fanny Potkin]]></author>
            
                
                <category>NVIDIA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[欧盟与中国将于12月举行峰会]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The European Union and China are set to hold a summit in December, a spokesperson for European Council President Charles Michel said on Thursday, confirming an earlier Bloomberg News report.翻译:欧洲理事会主席查尔斯·米歇尔的发言人周四表示，欧盟和中国将于 12 月举行峰会，这证实了彭博新闻社早些时候的报道。</p>   <p>While Bloomberg said the summit would take place on Dec. 7-8, Michel's spokesperson said the exact date was not set yet.翻译:虽然彭博社表示峰会将于 12 月 7 日至 8 日举行，但米歇尔的发言人表示，具体日期尚未确定。</p>    <span>Reporting by Nilutpal Timsina in Bengaluru, Jan Strupczewski in Brussels; writing by Charlotte Van Campenhout; editing by Mark Heinrich翻译:Nilutpal Timsina 在班加罗尔的报道，Jan Strupczewski 在布鲁塞尔的报道；夏洛特·范·坎彭豪特 (Charlotte Van Campenhout) 撰写；马克·海因里希编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 18:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">QNVYBMTPUBKP3B3SRMIYQCDFRU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/eu-china-set-hold-summit-early-december-bloomberg-news-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>EU</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/SUMMIT (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：吉利旗下 Zeekr 距离美国 IPO 更近了一步，将于本周公开备案--消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/isBe0IBRFwA4eM42jPY81Jc1rVY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CV7TH7NCVBPTTMD7I3TU5YBIJE.jpg" alt="People walk past a booth of Zeekr, Chinese automaker Geely's premium electric vehicle (EV) brand, at a shopping mall in Beijing翻译:在北京的一家购物中心，人们走过中国汽车制造商吉利旗下的高端电动汽车 (EV) 品牌 Zeekr 的展位" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk past a booth of Zeekr, Chinese automaker Geely's premium electric vehicle (EV) brand, at a shopping mall in Beijing翻译:在北京的一家购物中心，人们走过中国汽车制造商吉利旗下的高端电动汽车 (EV) 品牌 Zeekr 的展位, China November 3, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 3 日，在中国北京的一家购物中心，人们走过中国汽车制造商吉利旗下的高端电动汽车 (EV) 品牌 Zeekr 的展位。路透社/Tingshu Wang/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Zeekr, Chinese automaker Geely's (GEELY.UL) premium electric car brand, will this week publicly release some details of its plans to list shares in New York, according to two sources with direct knowledge of the matter, seeking to ride growing enthusiasm for EVs despite strained U.S.-China ties.翻译:据两位直接了解情况的消息人士透露，中国汽车制造商吉利 (GEELY.UL) 旗下的高端电动汽车品牌 Zeekr 将于本周公开发布其在纽约上市计划的一些细节，以期抓住人们对电动汽车日益高涨的热情。尽管美中关系紧张。</p>   <p>The EV brand will publish its prospectus and its shares could start being traded on the bourse within weeks of the announcement, the sources said.翻译:消息人士称，该电动汽车品牌将发布招股说明书，其股票可能会在公告发布后几周内开始在交易所交易。</p>   <p>Both sources declined to be identified discussing confidential information.翻译:两位消息人士在讨论机密信息时均拒绝透露姓名。</p>   <p>The underwriters are led by Goldman Sachs and Morgan Stanley, one source said, adding the size and price of the float will be decided later.翻译:一位消息人士称，承销商由高盛和摩根士丹利牵头，并补充说，发行规模和价格将在稍后决定。</p>   <p>Zeekr, Morgan Stanley and Goldman Sachs all declined comment.翻译:Zeekr、摩根士丹利和高盛均拒绝置评。</p>   <p>Zeekr <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-ev-maker-zeekr-start-investor-tour-ahead-1-bln-us-ipo-sources-2023-08-23/">confidentially filed</a> for a U.S. initial public offering last December, aiming to raise more than $1 billion, Reuters has reported.翻译:据路透社报道，Zeekr 去年 12 月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-ev-maker-zeekr-start-investor-tour-ahead-1-bln-us-ipo-sources-2023-08-23/">秘密申请</a>在美国进行首次公开​​募股，旨在筹集超过 10 亿美元。</p>   <p>However, the company is likely to raise less than the targeted amount from the IPO, one of the sources said.翻译:然而，一位消息人士称，该公司通过 IPO 筹集的资金可能会低于目标金额。</p>   <p>A confidential filing allows companies to keep details from rivals longer and gives them added flexibility particularly when a timeline for an IPO is not fixed.翻译:保密文件允许公司更长时间地向竞争对手保留详细信息，并为他们提供更大的灵活性，特别是在首次公开募股的时间表不固定的情况下。</p>   <p>The IPO
 could mark the first major float by a Chinese company in the United States in two years since Beijing tightened its grip on overseas share sales in 2021 -- a shift triggered by a cybersecurity probe into ride-hailing giant Didi Global on the heels of its U.S. stock market debut.翻译:此次 IPO 可能标志着自北京在 2021 年收紧对海外股票销售的控制以来，两年来首家中国公司在美国上市——这一转变是继网约车巨头滴滴出行之后进行的网络安全调查引发的。其在美国股市首次亮相。</p>   <p>In February, Zeekr raised $750 million in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/geelys-ev-brand-zeekr-raises-750-mln-fresh-funding-round-2023-02-12/">a funding round</a> that valued the brand at $13 billion from investors including Amnon Shashua, the CEO of autonomous driving technology company Mobileye Global <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MBLY.O" target="_blank">(MBLY.O)</a> - majority owned by Intel Corp <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/INTC.O" target="_blank">(INTC.O)</a> - and Chinese battery giant CATL <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300750.SZ" target="_blank">(300750.SZ)</a>.翻译:今年 2 月，Zeekr 在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/geelys-ev-brand-zeekr-raises-750-mln-fresh-funding-round-2023-02-12/">一轮融资</a>中筹集了 7.5 亿美元，该品牌估值达到 130 亿美元，投资方包括自动驾驶技术公司 Mobileye Global <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MBLY.O" target="_blank">(MBLY.O)</a>的首席执行官 Amnon Shashua，该公司的多数股权由英特尔公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/INTC.O" target="_blank">(INTC.O)</a>持有。以及中国电池巨头宁德时代<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300750.SZ" target="_blank">（300750.SZ）</a> 。</p>   <p>A price war started by Tesla <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a> in China at the beginning of the year is hitting the profitability of pure EV makers, which have stepped up efforts to prune costs and build partnerships to survive the consolidating competition.翻译:特斯拉<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a>年初在中国发起的价格战正在打击纯电动汽车制造商的盈利能力，这些制造商加大了削减成本和建立合作伙伴关系的力度，以在巩固的竞争中生存下来。</p>   <p>However, Zeekr, which is able to utilise Zhejiang Geely Holding Group's manufacturing facilities and cost-saving capabilities, has seen its profitability improve.翻译:然而，Zeekr能够利用浙江吉利控股集团的生产设施和成本节约能力，其盈利能力有所改善。</p>   <p>CEO Andy An told reporters in August that Zeekr achieved a double-digit gross profit in the first half of this year, compared to a 5% gross profit in 2022.翻译:首席执行官安迪·安（Andy An）8月份向记者表示，Zeekr今年上半年实现了两位数的毛利润，而2022年的毛利润为5%。</p>   <p>Zeekr, established in 2021, ranked 13th in EV sales in China among all brands with 79,028 units sold in the first nine months, more than double the same period in 2022.翻译:成立于2021年的Zeekr在中国电动汽车销量中排名第13位，前9个月销量为79,028辆，是2022年同期的两倍多。</p>   <p>It offers four EV models in China, with its 001 crossover priced from 269,000 yuan ($36,927.22) as its best-selling EV.翻译:该公司在中国提供四种电动车型，其中001跨界车的起售价为269,000元人民币（36,927.22美元），是其最畅销的电动汽车。</p>   <p>Zeekr has also announced plans to sell into overseas markets including the Netherlands, Sweden, Germany, Israel, Kazakhstan among others.翻译:Zeekr还宣布计划向荷兰、瑞典、德国、以色列、哈萨克斯坦等海外市场销售。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2846 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2846 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Zhang Yan in Shanghai and Scott Murdoch in Sydney. Additional reporting by Kane Wu in Hong Kong; Editing by Kim Coghill翻译:张岩上海报道和斯科特·默多克悉尼报道。吴凯恩 (Kane Wu) 在香港的补充报道；编辑：金·科吉尔</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 15:00:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">JLIEJI62RJOODJEKVY6W6ASICI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/geelys-zeekr-edges-closer-us-ipo-make-filing-public-this-week-sources-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GEELY</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/IPO (UPDATE 1, EXCLUSIVE, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国汽车制造商蔚来汽车高管仍在“争论”2025年进入北美市场]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Mgu-KssDSGxoI8Vymcvsmy4Rbl4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/W453EV2CXBK23LUCEMIK5TVBEM.jpg" alt="EXCLUSIVE-China's Nio considers tapping dealers to boost EV sales in Europe - sources翻译:独家报道：中国蔚来汽车考虑利用经销商来提高欧洲电动汽车销量 - 消息人士" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A NIO ET5 car model and the NIO EP9 sports car are pictured at the NIO House, the showroom of the Chinese premium smart electric vehicle manufacture NIO Inc. in Berlin, Germany August 17, 2023. REUTERS/Annegret Hilse/File Photo翻译:2023 年 8 月 17 日，蔚来 ET5 车型和蔚来 EP9 跑车在中国高端智能电动汽车制造商蔚来公司位于德国柏林的展厅 NIO House 拍摄。 REUTERS/Annegret Hilse/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Chinese automaker Nio <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9866.HK" target="_blank">(9866.HK)</a> is still "debating" a 2025 entry in North America, a top executive said on Thursday.翻译:中国汽车制造商蔚来汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9866.HK" target="_blank">（9866.HK）</a>一位高管周四表示，仍在“讨论”2025 年进入北美市场的计划。</p>   <p>Speaking at Reuters Events Automotive USA 2023 conference, Ganesh Iyer, chief executive officer of Nio USA, said the company is considering "any kind of partnerships" in North America.翻译:Nio USA 首席执行官 Ganesh Iyer 在路透社活动的 2023 年美国汽车会议上发表讲话时表示，该公司正在考虑在北美建立“任何形式的合作伙伴关系”。</p>   <p>Nio also needs to build infrastructure before bringing electric vehicles to North America, he said.翻译:他说，在将电动汽车引入北美之前，蔚来还需要建设基础设施。</p>   <p>Nio sees an "immersive user experience" as a differentiator for the brand, Iyer said.翻译:艾耶表示，蔚来汽车将“沉浸式用户体验”视为该品牌的差异化因素。</p>    <span>Reporting by Paul Lienert in Detroit; Editing by Mark Porter翻译:保罗·利纳特 (Paul Lienert) 底特律报道；马克·波特编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 14:50:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RIXADOP2RVO6VKK2XQVZ2DAKVU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinese-carmaker-nio-still-debating-2025-entry-north-america-executive-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>REUTERS EVENTS</category>
                
                <category>CONFERENCE/AUTOS (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国敦促G7停止“煽动对抗”]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/CqsFOdQZ3VQnyS3WCNxZQGh0UVQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6OFFW6A7BVNOLNFYR4P2EW5X3U.jpg" alt="U.S. Secretary of State Blinken visits Japan翻译:美国国务卿布林肯访问日本" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>High Representative of the European Union for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy Josep Borrell, British Foreign Secretary James Cleverly, German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Japanese Foreign Minister Yoko Kamikawa, Canadian Foreign Minister Melanie Joly, France's Foreign Minister Catherine Colonna and Italian Foreign Minister Antonio Tajani sit at a table at the start of a working dinner G7 ministerial meetings, in Tokyo, Japan, November 7, 2023. REUTERS/Jonathan Ernst/Pool/File photo翻译:欧盟外交与安全政策高级代表何塞普·博雷尔、英国外交大臣詹姆斯·克莱维利、德国外长安娜莱娜·贝尔博克、美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯、日本外相上川洋子、加拿大外长梅兰妮·乔利、法国外长凯瑟琳2023 年 11 月 7 日，日本东京，七国集团部长级会议工作晚宴开始时，科隆纳和意大利外交部长安东尼奥·塔亚尼坐在桌旁。路透社/乔纳森·恩斯特/泳池/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China expressed strong dissatisfaction with China-related comments made by G7 foreign ministers and urged the bloc to stop inciting confrontation, its embassy in Japan said in a statement on Thursday.翻译:中国驻日本大使馆周四发表声明称，中方对七国集团外长发表的涉华言论表示强烈不满，敦促七国集团停止煽动对抗。</p>   <p>A two-day <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/g7s-top-diplomats-discuss-what-happens-after-gaza-conflict-2023-11-08/">G7 foreign minister meeting</a> held in Tokyo ended on Wednesday and mainly called for humanitarian pauses in the Israel-Hamas war to allow in aid and help the release of hostages.翻译:周三在东京举行的为期两天的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/g7s-top-diplomats-discuss-what-happens-after-gaza-conflict-2023-11-08/">七国集团外长会议</a>主要呼吁暂停以色列与哈马斯的战争，以允许援助并帮助释放人质。</p>   <p>In a joint statement, the G7 nations also urged China to address its non-market policies, not to assist Russia in its war against Ukraine, to keep the peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait, and to allow a high level of autonomy for Hong Kong.翻译:七国集团在联合声明中还敦促中国纠正非市场政策，不要协助俄罗斯对乌克兰发动战争，维护台海和平稳定，并允许香港高度自治。孔.</p>   <p>"China will resolutely counter any smear campaigns from external forces," the embassy said, adding it strongly protested against other countries' intentions to curb China with regards to Taiwan.翻译:使馆表示，中方将坚决反制外部势力的抹黑行为，对其他国家在台湾问题上遏制中国的企图表示强烈抗议。</p>   <p>President Tsai Ing-wen, of the democratically governed Taiwan island, said she would continue to work with G7 members toward a free and open Indo Pacific.翻译:民主统治的台湾岛的总统蔡英文表示，她将继续与七国集团成员合作，以实现自由开放的印度太平洋地区。</p>   <p>Critical comments on Taiwan and Hong Kong have long riled Beijing, which considers such criticism as outside interference in its domestic affairs.翻译:对台湾和香港的批评言论长期以来一直激怒北京，北京认为此类批评是外部势力干涉其内政。</p>   <p>Democratically governed Taiwan, which China considers as part of its territory, is the most sensitive issue. Taiwan rejects Beijing’s claim.翻译:中国认为民主统治的台湾是其领土的一部分，这是最敏感的问题。台湾拒绝北京的主张。</p>   <p>Some Western nations have also regularly reminded Beijing to better protect Hong Kong’s democratic principles, freedoms and autonomy, which they say have weakened after the implementation of a national security law in 2020.翻译:一些西方国家还经常提醒北京更好地保护香港的民主原则、自由和自治，他们称这些原则在2020年实施国家安全法后受到削弱。</p>   <p>Hong Kong returned from British to Chinese rule in 1997 with the guarantee its freedoms would be protected under a "one country, two systems" formula for at least 50 years.翻译:香港于1997年从英国统治下回归中国，并保证其自由将在“一国两种制度”下受到至少50年的保护。</p>    <span>Reporting by Albee Zhang and Ryan Woo; Additional reporting by Ben Blanchard; Editing by Bernadette Baum翻译:Albee 张和 Ryan Woo 的报道；本·布兰查德 (Ben Blanchard) 的补充报道；伯纳黛特·鲍姆编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 10:22:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">LZMOZIMPUNNPJAR56PW3LFPULY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-urges-g7-stop-inciting-confrontation-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>G7/COMMENTS (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[阿根廷大选使中巴关系成为焦点]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/vm0eCr8CaCnPciEv5h4GIcW0yGE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WDVX23TZ2VJJNAMUHL4OSQCAXU.jpg" alt="Argentine presidential candidate Javier Milei meets supporters during a campaign rally, in Buenos Aires翻译:阿根廷总统候选人哈维尔·米莱在布宜诺斯艾利斯的竞选集会上会见支持者" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Argentine presidential candidate Javier Milei holds a chainsaw next to Carolina Piparo, candidate for Governor of the Province of Buenos Aires, during a campaign rally, in Buenos Aires, Argentina September 25, 2023. REUTERS/Cristina Sille/File Photo翻译:2023 年 9 月 25 日，在阿根廷布宜诺斯艾利斯举行的竞选集会上，阿根廷总统候选人哈维尔·米莱 (Javier Milei) 在布宜诺斯艾利斯省省长候选人卡罗莱纳·皮帕罗 (Carolina Piparo) 旁边拿着电锯。 REUTERS/Cristina Sille/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/2bnq1PecWFHI2xgqt2Ym-wrO9FU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6BRTT6IWIBJUXNDHDECTZPIPDY.jpg" alt="Argentina's Economic Minister Massa and Brazil's Finance Minister Haddad hold a news conference in Buenos Aires翻译:阿根廷经济部长马萨和巴西财政部长哈达德在布宜诺斯艾利斯举行新闻发布会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Argentina's Economic Minister Sergio Massa and Brazil's Finance Minister Fernando Haddad (not pictured) hold a news conference, at the Casa Rosada presidential palace in Buenos Aires, Argentina, January 23, 2023. REUTERS/Agustin Marcarian/File photo翻译:阿根廷经济部长塞尔吉奥·马萨和巴西财政部长费尔南多·哈达德（未上图）于2023年1月23日在阿根廷布宜诺斯艾利斯的卡萨罗萨达总统府举行新闻发布会。路透社/Agustin Marcarian/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/GBEtho-1jUd_yQYkQPJ-uAaNdJg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/E555DT66XRNPFAILDW2JCY7NWE.jpg" alt="Argentina's Economic Minister Massa and Brazil's Finance Minister Haddad hold a news conference in Buenos Aires翻译:阿根廷经济部长马萨和巴西财政部长哈达德在布宜诺斯艾利斯举行新闻发布会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Argentina's Economic Minister Sergio Massa and Brazil's Finance Minister Fernando Haddad (not pictured) hold a news conference, at the Casa Rosada presidential palace in Buenos Aires, Argentina, January 23, 2023. REUTERS/Agustin Marcarian/File Photo翻译:阿根廷经济部长塞尔吉奥·马萨和巴西财政部长费尔南多·哈达德（未上图）于 2023 年 1 月 23 日在阿根廷布宜诺斯艾利斯的卡萨罗萨达总统府举行新闻发布会。路透社/Agustin Marcarian/档案照片</figcaption></figure>                 <p>Argentina could see a resetting of some global ties depending on the result of its run-off presidential election later this month - although the value of trade with partners like China and Brazil may outweigh any short-term political posturing.翻译:阿根廷可能会看到一些全球关系的重置，具体取决于本月晚些时候第二轮总统选举的结果，尽管与中国和巴西等合作伙伴的贸易价值可能超过任何短期政治姿态。</p>   <p>While Economy Minister Sergio Massa, a pragmatist in the ruling left-leaning coalition, has signaled policy continuity, radical libertarian candidate Javier Milei has sharply lambasted China, Brazil, the pope, South America's Mercosur trade bloc and the China-led BRICS group.翻译:尽管执政的左翼联盟中的实用主义者、经济部长塞尔吉奥·马萨表示政策连续性，但激进的自由主义候选人哈维尔·米莱却严厉斥责了中国、巴西、教皇、南美南方共同市场贸易集团和中国领导的金砖国家集团。</p>   <p>Massa and Milei will compete in a Nov. 19 head-to-head that looks likely to be a tight race, with angry voters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/argentina-polls-show-election-race-tightening-winner-hard-to-call-2023-11-06/">deeply divided</a> amid inflation running at nearly 140%, two-fifths of the population in poverty, sky-high interest rates and capital controls hurting the economy.翻译:马萨和米雷将于 11 月 19 日进行正面交锋，这场比赛看起来可能会是一场<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/argentina-polls-show-election-race-tightening-winner-hard-to-call-2023-11-06/">激烈</a>的角逐，愤怒的选民在通货膨胀率接近 140%、五分之二的人口处于贫困之中、利益极高的情况下存在严重分歧。利率和资本管制损害了经济。</p>   <p>The vote could impact the global positioning of Argentina, South America's No. 2 economy, which is a major grains exporter as well as a lithium and shale producer. But years of volatility have made some international investors wary and it is the top debtor to the International Monetary Fund (IMF).翻译:此次投票可能会影响南美第二大经济体阿根​​廷的全球地位，该国是主要谷物出口国以及锂和页岩油生产国。但多年的波动让一些国际投资者保持警惕，而且它是国际货币基金组织（IMF）的最大债务国。</p>   <p>Gustavo Martinez Pandiani, current Argentine ambassador to Switzerland and Massa's likely foreign minister, said a future Massa government would seek to improve the country's global partnerships.翻译:现任阿根廷驻瑞士大使、可能担任马萨外交部长的古斯塔沃·马丁内斯·潘迪亚尼表示，未来的马萨政府将寻求改善该国的全球伙伴关系。</p>   <p>"While some promise to cut ties with Brazil or China, we want more markets and more trading partners, not less," he said.翻译:“虽然一些人承诺切断与巴西或中国的关系，但我们希望有更多的市场和更多的贸易伙伴，而不是更少，”他说。</p>   <p>Milei has said he "won't make deals with communists" in China or Brazil, though he does back private trade. He has described climate change as a "lie of socialism" and said Argentine Pope Francis is "on the side of bloody dictatorships."翻译:米雷表示，他“不会与中国或巴西的共产党人做交易”，但他确实支持私人贸易。他将气候变化描述为“社会主义的谎言”，并表示阿根廷教皇弗朗西斯“站在血腥独裁者一边”。</p>   <p>Diana Mondino, Milei's likely foreign minister, said some of his statements had been blown out of context, and that in fact he would look "to reinsert Argentina into the world."翻译:米莱可能担任外交部长的戴安娜·蒙迪诺表示，他的一些言论已经断章取义，事实上他会寻求“让阿根廷重新融入世界”。</p>   <p>"Not only is there not a problem with Brazil, but we hope to be able to trade as much as possible with Brazil," said Mondino, adding that with China - a key trade partner, creditor and investor - Milei would simply stop opaque state-to-state deals.翻译:蒙迪诺表示：“不仅与巴西没有问题，而且我们希望能够与巴西进行尽可能多的贸易。”他补充说，与中国这个重要的贸易伙伴、债权人和投资者相比，米莱将简单地停止不透明的国家- 州交易。</p>   <p>That could include the country's $18 billion currency swap line with China, which has helped cash-strapped Argentina pay back its IMF debt. China is also a big investor in local lithium projects, hydro and nuclear.翻译:这可能包括该国与中国的 180 亿美元货币互换额度，该额度帮助现金短缺的阿根廷偿还了国际货币基金组织的债务。中国也是当地锂项目、水电和核电项目的重要投资者。</p>   <p>"What we are not going to do are secret contracts. Argentina, this government, in the last 20 years, has had multiple secret negotiations," she said. "That is not normal and it is what we have said we are not going to do."翻译:“我们不会做的是秘密合同。阿根廷政府在过去20年里进行了多次秘密谈判，”她说。 “这是不正常的，我们已经说过我们不会这样做。”</p>   <p>A current senior Foreign Ministry source, from the same Peronist coalition as Massa, predicted that Argentina's ties with Brazil and China would continue regardless of who won the election.翻译:一位与马萨同属庇隆主义联盟的现任外交部高级消息人士预测，无论谁赢得选举，阿根廷与巴西和中国的关系都将继续下去。</p>   <p>"Relations with China are going to go as they have until now with either of the two candidates. The intense trade that exists with them cannot be dissolved," the person said, asking not to be identified.翻译:这位不愿透露姓名的人士表示：“与中国的关系将像两位候选人中的任何一位一样，与中国的关系将继续发展。与他们之间存在的激烈贸易关系无法消除。”</p>   <p>"The same thing would happen with Brazil: bad personal relations do not affect trade."翻译:“同样的事情也会发生在巴西：糟糕的个人关系不会影响贸易。”</p>   <p>TRADE BLOCS: MERCOSUR AND BRICS翻译:贸易集团：南方共同市场和金砖国家</p>   <p>Massa and Milei have also clashed on <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/mercosur-splits-dampen-eu-outlook-trade-deal-window-narrows-2023-09-12/">Mercosur</a>, the regional trade bloc led by Argentina and Brazil that has faced internal tension from other members who say it is not an effective trade mechanism for negotiating global deals.翻译:马萨和米莱还在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/mercosur-splits-dampen-eu-outlook-trade-deal-window-narrows-2023-09-12/">南方共同市场</a>问题上发生了冲突，南方共同市场是由阿根廷和巴西领导的区域贸易集团，该集团面临着其他成员的内部紧张局势，他们称这不是谈判全球协议的有效贸易机制。</p>   <p>The Peronists want to strengthen the bloc, while Milei has threatened to pull Argentina out of it.翻译:庇隆主义者希望加强欧盟，而米莱则威胁要让阿根廷退出欧盟。</p>   <p>Pandiani said member countries needed to "modernize Mercosur to make it more efficient," and added that a Massa government would consider it their "main platform" for global trade.翻译:潘迪亚尼表示，成员国需要“实现南方共同市场的现代化，以提高其效率”，并补充说，马萨政府将把它视为全球贸易的“主要平台”。</p>   <p>"Argentina has a very promising future, because it has what the world demands: proteins; traditional, green and transition energy; critical minerals such as lithium and copper; rare earths and qualified human resources," he said.翻译:他说：“阿根廷的未来非常有前途，因为它拥有世界所需要的东西：蛋白质；传统、绿色和转型能源；锂和铜等关键矿物；稀土和合格的人力资源。”</p>   <p>The current government has also pushed to have Argentina in the China-backed BRICS group of developing countries, which also includes India, Brazil, Russia and South Africa. Argentina was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/brics-poised-invite-new-members-join-bloc-sources-2023-08-24/">invited to join the group</a> in August. Milei opposes joining.翻译:本届政府还推动阿根廷加入中国支持的金砖国家集团，该集团还包括印度、巴西、俄罗斯和南非。阿根廷于八月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/brics-poised-invite-new-members-join-bloc-sources-2023-08-24/">受邀加入该小组</a>。米莱反对加入。</p>   <p>"The BRICS are not a trading bloc. As of now it's not clear why we would want to have membership in this group," said Mondino. The BRICS are a relatively loosely-formed group with diverse political and geographical positions.翻译:“金砖五国不是一个贸易集团。目前还不清楚我们为什么希望成为这个集团的成员，”蒙迪诺说。金砖国家是一个结构相对松散的组织，具有不同的政治和地理位置。</p>   <p>Pandiani disagreed. "Rejecting entry into BRICS is nonsense; we believe that Argentina should always sit at the negotiating tables where important issues for our future are discussed," he said.翻译:潘迪亚尼不同意。 “拒绝加入金砖国家是无稽之谈；我们认为阿根廷应该始终坐在谈判桌上，讨论我们未来的重要问题，”他说。</p>    <span>Reporting by Lucila Sigal; Additional reporting by Nicolás Misculin; Editing by Adam Jourdan and Rosalba O'Brien翻译:卢西拉·西格尔报道；尼古拉斯·米斯库林 (Nicolás Misculin) 的补充报道；亚当·乔丹和罗莎尔巴·奥布莱恩编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 10:03:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">L3TO4N3EMBOPBKBLOBSC7DQTPU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/argentina-election-puts-china-brazil-ties-spotlight-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Lucila Sigal]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ARGENTINA</category>
                
                <category>ELECTION/DIPLOMACY (ANALYSIS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[南航将兑现因故障而售出的 1.30 美元机票]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/a6IRpjP85RKKxbz8ghMwlNLkLdk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6U7MPFW3JFN4RFTJAWCOWG6SGQ.jpg" alt="A China Southern Airlines plane takes off from Sydney Airport in Sydney翻译:一架中国南方航空的飞机从悉尼机场起飞" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A China Southern Airlines Airbus A380-800 plane takes off from Sydney Airport in Sydney, Australia, October 28, 2020.  REUTERS/Loren Elliott/File Photo翻译:2020年10月28日，中国南方航空公司的一架空客A380-800飞机从澳大利亚悉尼机场起飞。路透社/Loren Elliott/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Chinese carrier China Southern Airlines <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/600029.SS" target="_blank">(600029.SS)</a> said on Thursday it would honor the sale of tickets priced as cheaply as $1.30 during a two-hour technical glitch on its mobile phone app and some ticket-booking platforms late on Wednesday.翻译:中国南方航空<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/600029.SS" target="_blank">（600029.SS）</a>周四表示，周三晚间其手机应用程序和一些订票平台出现了两小时的技术故障，该公司将接受低价至 1.30 美元的机票销售。</p>   <p>Consumers began reporting on Chinese social media at around 8 p.m. (1200 GMT) on Wednesday that many flights to and from the southwest metropolis of Chengdu were available at 10, 20 or 30 yuan ($1.37-$4.12) on China Southern's app.
One screenshot circulating online showed a ticket from Chengdu to Beijing priced at only 10 yuan, compared to the normal minimum price of 400 to 500 yuan.
Other online screenshots indicated the cheap prices were offered for about two hours on the carrier's app as well as across several ticket-booking platforms, including market leader Trip.com.翻译:周三晚上 8 点左右（格林威治标准时间 1200 点），消费者开始在中国社交媒体上报道称，在南航应用程序上，许多往返西南大都市成都的航班票价为 10 元、20 元或 30 元（1.37 美元至 4.12 美元）。网上流传的一张截图显示，从成都到北京的机票价格仅为10元，而正常最低票价为400至500元。其他在线屏幕截图显示，该航空公司的应用程序以及包括市场领导者 Trip.com 在内的多个机票预订平台都提供了大约两个小时的便宜价格。</p>   <p>On top of that price, buyers were required to pay at least an additional 110 yuan in airport fees and fuel surcharges.
"Passengers can use them as normal," Guangzhou-based China Southern said, on the proviso that tickets were already paid for and issued.翻译:除此之外，买家还需额外支付至少110元的机场费和燃油附加费。总部位于广州的南航表示，“乘客可以正常使用它们”，但前提是机票已经付款并出票。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2852 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2852 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Sophie Yu and Casey Hall;
Editing by Bernadette Baum翻译:Sophie Yu 和 Casey Hall 报道；伯纳黛特·鲍姆编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 09:15:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FR4KP6DARRME3AY2XBAT6DRHSI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-southern-honour-130-flight-tickets-sold-during-glitch-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AVIATION/CHINA SOUTHERN (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国11月新增人民币贷款回落，政策支持到位 - 路透调查]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Oct new loans seen at 665 bln yuan vs 2.31 trln yuan in Sept</li>  <li>Oct money supply growth seen at 10.3% y/y vs 10.3% in Sept</li>  <li>Oct TSF seen at 1.90 trln yuan vs 4.12 trln yuan in Sept</li>  <li>Loans, money supply data due Nov 10-15</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li> 10 月新增贷款 6,650 亿元人民币，9 月新增贷款 23.1 万亿元</li><li>10 月份货币供应量同比增长 10.3%，9 月份为 10.3%</li><li> 10 月 TSF 为 1.90 里拉人民币，9 月为 4.12 里拉人民币</li><li>贷款、货币供应数据将于 11 月 10 日至 15 日到期</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/-VsTvB7S1ZDStS_vSvJ7UAWvFaI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NHMJ6NDWB5PJPMEUUKGCJWH4DE.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of the app for China's digital currency翻译:中国数字货币应用图示" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>China's official app for digital yuan is seen in this illustration picture taken October 16, 2020. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo翻译:这张摄于 2020 年 10 月 16 日的插图图片中可以看到中国的数字人民币官方应用程序。REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's new yuan loans are expected to dip in October from the previous month because of seasonal factors, a Reuters poll showed, but the expected lending may exceed the year-earlier amount as the central bank sought to spur economic growth.翻译:路透调查显示，受季节性因素影响，中国10月份新增人民币贷款预计将环比下降，但由于央行寻求刺激经济增长，预计贷款额可能会超过去年同期。</p>   <p>Chinese banks are estimated to have issued 665 billion yuan ($91.29 billion) in net new yuan loans last month, less than a third of the 2.31 trillion yuan in September, according to the median estimate in the survey of 26 economists.翻译:根据对 26 名经济学家的调查的中值估计，上个月中国的银行估计发放了 6650 亿元人民币（合 912.9 亿美元）的新人民币贷款净额，不到 9 月份 2.31 万亿元人民币的三分之一。</p>   <p>But the expected tally would be still higher than the 615.2 billion yuan issued in the same month a year earlier.翻译:但预计发行总额仍高于去年同期发行的6152亿元人民币。</p>   <p>"October has always been a low season for new credit, and this year should be no exception," analysts at Citi said in a note.翻译:花旗分析师在一份报告中表示：“十月一直是新增信贷的淡季，今年也不例外。”</p>   <p>"Mortgage repricing effective at end-September could ease household early repayment pressures. Corporate borrowing could enjoy some support from improving profitability and bottoming exports, but we don't expect a buoyant number either."翻译:“9月底生效的抵押贷款重新定价可以缓解家庭提前还款的压力。企业借贷可能会因盈利能力提高和出口触底而得到一些支持，但我们预计数字也不会强劲。”</p>   <p>Beijing has been ramping up measures to support the economy, including 1 trillion yuan ($137.43 billion) in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/china-issue-137-bln-sovereign-debt-support-economy-2023-10-24/">sovereign bond</a> issuances and allowing local governments to frontload part of their 2024 bond quotas.翻译:北京一直在加大支持经济的措施，包括发行1万亿元人民币（1374.3亿美元）的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/china-issue-137-bln-sovereign-debt-support-economy-2023-10-24/">主权债券</a>，并允许地方政府提前加载2024年的部分债券配额。</p>   <p>But a property crisis, local debt risks and policy divergences with the West are all complicating the recovery process, highlighted by persistent <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">deflationary pressures</a>.翻译:但房地产危机、地方债务风险以及与西方的政策分歧都使复苏进程复杂化，持续的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">通货紧缩压力</a>凸显了这一点。</p>   <p>The People's Bank of China (PBOC), which has delivered modest interest rate cuts and pumped out more cash into the economy in recent months, has pledged to keep policy supports.翻译:近几个月来，中国人民银行（PBOC）小幅降息并向经济注入更多现金，并承诺维持政策支持。</p>   <p>In September, the PBOC cut banks' <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cuts-banks-reserve-ratio-second-time-2023-aid-recovery-2023-09-14/">reserve requirement ratio</a> for the second time this year, and analysts expect another cut in the coming weeks.翻译:9月，中国人民银行今年第二次下调银行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cuts-banks-reserve-ratio-second-time-2023-aid-recovery-2023-09-14/">存款准备金率</a>，分析师预计未来几周将再次下调。</p>   <p>China is expected to hit its annual <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-expected-achieve-2023-gdp-growth-target-cbank-governor-2023-11-08/">growth target</a> this year, and the country must transform its growth model to pursue high-quality and sustainable expansion, PBOC Governor Pan Gongsheng said on Wednesday.翻译:中国人民银行行长潘功胜周三表示，中国今年预计将实现全年<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-expected-achieve-2023-gdp-growth-target-cbank-governor-2023-11-08/">增长目标</a>，中国必须转变增长方式，实现高质量、可持续增长。</p>   <p>Outstanding yuan loans were expected to increase in October by 10.9% from a year earlier, the same as in September, the poll showed. Broad M2 money supply growth in October was seen at 10.3%, unchanged from September.翻译:调查显示，10月份人民币贷款余额预计同比增长10.9%，与9月份持平。 10 月份广义 M2 货币供应量增速为 10.3%，与 9 月份持平。</p>   <p>Local governments are allowed to issue 3.8 trillion yuan in special bonds this year to fund infrastructure projects to bolster the economy.翻译:今年允许地方政府发行3.8万亿元专项债券，为基础设施项目提供资金以提振经济。</p>   <p>Any acceleration in government bond issuance could help boost total social financing (TSF), a broad measure of credit and liquidity. Outstanding TSF was 9.0% higher at the end-September than a year earlier, the same as seen at end-August.翻译:政府债券发行的任何加速都可能有助于提高社会融资总额（TSF），这是衡量信贷和流动性的广泛指标。 9 月底未偿社会融资规模较去年同期增长 9.0%，与 8 月底相同。</p>   <p>In October, TSF is expected to fall to 1.9 trillion yuan from 4.12 trillion yuan in September, the poll showed.翻译:调查显示，10月份社会融资规模预计将从9月份的4.12万亿元降至1.9万亿元。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2841 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2841 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Judy Hua and Kevin Yao; Editing by Christian Schmollinger翻译:Judy Hua 和 Kevin Yao 报道；克里斯蒂安·施莫林格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 07:57:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">L5UG4772VFIE7FSJYLSKJM2ZAQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-nov-new-yuan-loans-seen-retreating-policy-support-place-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/LOANS (POLL)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国卫生部门认为反腐运动带来了更好的情绪——高管们]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Business activities in China's healthcare sector are returning from a sudden near freeze that began in July when Beijing kicked off a year-long anti-corruption campaign, two foreign industry executives said.翻译:两位外国行业高管表示，中国医疗保健行业的商业活动正在从七月份北京启动为期一年的反腐败运动时开始的突然近乎冻结中恢复过来。</p>   <p>The campaign targets the bribing of doctors in drug and medical equipment sales and marks a sharp escalation of an anti-corruption drive in the sector that started years ago. The latest campaign has sent a chill through the sector, pummeling healthcare stocks and prompting some firms to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-drugmakers-axe-ipo-plans-they-face-scrutiny-anti-graft-drive-2023-08-11/">cancel IPOs</a>.翻译:该行动的目标是在药品和医疗设备销售中贿赂医生，标志着多年前开始的该行业反腐败运动的急剧升级。最新的行动给整个行业带来了寒意，医疗保健股遭受重创，并促使一些公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-drugmakers-axe-ipo-plans-they-face-scrutiny-anti-graft-drive-2023-08-11/">取消首次公开募股</a>。</p>   <p>"We see a recovery in terms of engagements ... we see an improvement in that area," Zafer Unluer, China president of U.S. healthcare company Organon <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/OGN.N" target="_blank">(OGN.N)</a>, told Reuters on the sidelines of an industry event in Shanghai.翻译:美国医疗保健公司 Organon <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/OGN.N" target="_blank">(OGN.N)</a>中国区总裁 Zafer Unluer 在上海举行的一次行业活动间隙对路透表示：“我们看到参与度有所回升……我们看到该领域有所改善。”</p>   <p>"It is still as not high as before, but we see a bit of a balancing act."翻译:“它仍然不像以前那么高，但我们看到了一些平衡行为。”</p>   <p>The anti-graft drive initially caused huge business disruptions and many multinational pharmaceutical firms lost engagement with hospitals, executives said.翻译:高管们表示，反腐运动最初造成了巨大的业务中断，许多跨国制药公司失去了与医院的合作。</p>   <p>"We’ve seen some disruption in the ability of our medical representatives to visit hospitals, in our ability to implement some medical application activities," Larry Merizalde, China CEO of South African drugmaker Aspen <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/APNJ.J" target="_blank">(APNJ.J)</a>, told Reuters.翻译:南非制药商阿斯彭<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/APNJ.J" target="_blank">（APNJ.J）</a>中国区首席执行官拉里·梅里扎德（Larry Merizalde）对路透社表示：“我们发现我们的医疗代表访问医院的能力以及实施一些医疗应用活动的能力受到了一些干扰。”</p>   <p>AstraZeneca <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AZN.L" target="_blank">(AZN.L)</a>, the largest foreign drugmaker in China, said on Thursday <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/astrazeneca-raises-stakes-obesity-drug-race-with-eccogene-deal-2023-11-09/">sales in China</a> grew just 1% in the third quarter, partly impacted by "reduced promotional activities following the government campaign announced at the end of July".翻译:中国最大的外国制药商阿斯利康<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AZN.L" target="_blank">(AZN.L)</a>周四表示，第三季度<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/astrazeneca-raises-stakes-obesity-drug-race-with-eccogene-deal-2023-11-09/">在华销售额</a>仅增长 1%，部分原因是“7 月底宣布的政府行动后促销活动减少”。</p>   <p>The two executives said the overall mood, however, had improved over the past two months following communications such as a National Health Commission Q&amp;A and a presentation from a government official.翻译:不过，两位高管表示，在国家卫生健康委员会的问答和政府官员的演讲等沟通之后，过去两个月的整体情绪有所改善。</p>   <p>"Over the last month, since the latest announcements from the government to clarify the objectives of this anti-corruption policy, we see that overall activities are coming back to normal," Merizalde said.翻译:梅里扎德说：“上个月，自从政府最新宣布澄清反腐败政策的目标以来，我们看到整体活动正在恢复正常。”</p>   <p>China is one of the biggest healthcare markets for global healthcare companies but their business sentiment has turned fragile this year due to factors including the anti-graft drive.翻译:中国是全球医疗保健公司最大的医疗保健市场之一，但由于反腐等因素，今年他们的商业信心变得脆弱。</p>    <span>Reporting by Andrew Silver; Editing by Miyoung Kim, Robert Birsel翻译:安德鲁·西尔弗报道；编辑：Miyoung Kim、Robert Birsel</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 07:49:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BIDF64VYKNOYPCA357MGJI6IPU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-health-sector-sees-better-sentiment-anti-graft-drive-execs-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Andrew Silver]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PHARMA/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[小米新机销量强劲，中国智能手机市场回暖]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UEWRgU7UtJ4JghimK-x_ExTsX3c=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/UNFRTPI4WZMYLBPJGOCK4G54JU.jpg" alt="2023 Mobile World Congress in Barcelona翻译:2023 年巴塞罗那世界移动大会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People check new products of Xiaomi ahead of the 2023 Mobile World Congress in Barcelona翻译:2023 年巴塞罗那世界移动大会, Spain February 26, 2023. REUTERS/Nacho Doce/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Xiaomi's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/1810.HK" target="_blank">(1810.HK)</a> sales of more than 1 million units of its latest flagship smartphone in the week since its launch are a fresh sign that a slump in China's phone market could be nearing an end, analysts said.翻译:分析师表示，小米<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/1810.HK" target="_blank">（1810.HK）</a>最新旗舰智能手机自推出以来一周内销量超过 100 万部，这是中国手机市场低迷可能即将结束的新迹象。</p>   <p>Demand in the world's biggest smartphone market has long been in decline, with the COVID-19 pandemic and then a faltering economic recovery persuading customers to wait longer before upgrading their phones.翻译:全球最大智能手机市场的需求长期以来一直在下降，原因是新冠肺炎 (COVID-19) 疫情以及随后的经济复苏步履蹒跚，迫使客户在升级手机之前等待更长时间。</p>   <p>"Sales of the Mi 14 series have exceeded 1 million units and the phones are still in severe short supply," Xiaomi Chief Executive Lei Jun wrote on the microblogging platform Weibo this week.翻译:小米首席执行官雷军本周在微博平台上写道：“小米14系列销量已突破100万台，但手机仍严重供不应求。”</p>   <p>The model went on sale in China on Oct. 31. It uses Qualcomm's cutting-edge Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 processor and Xiaomi's proprietary HyperOS software.翻译:该机型于10月31日在中国上市。它采用高通尖端的Snapdragon 8 Gen 3处理器和小米专有的HyperOS软件。</p>   <p>The robust launch "reinforces signs of the market bottoming out," said Will Wong, an analyst with industry research firm IDC.翻译:行业研究公司 IDC 的分析师 Will Wong 表示，此次强劲的推出“强化了市场触底的迹象”。</p>   <p>It comes on the heels of a big jump in sales for Huawei (HWT.UL) as shoppers <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-smartphone-shipments-fall-5-yy-q3-667-mln-handsets-canalys-2023-10-26/">snapped up</a> its Mate 60 series phones - a comeback for the company after the U.S. imposed export controls on it in 2019.翻译:此前，随着消费者<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-smartphone-shipments-fall-5-yy-q3-667-mln-handsets-canalys-2023-10-26/">抢购</a>华为 Mate 60 系列手机，华为 (HWT.UL) 的销量大幅增长，这是该公司在 2019 年美国对其实施出口管制后卷土重来。</p>   <p>IDC predicts the Chinese market is on track to achieve year-on-year sales growth in the fourth quarter after ten consecutive quarters of decline. It did not specify the level of growth.翻译:IDC预计，中国市场在连续十个季度下滑后，第四季度有望实现销售额同比增长。它没有具体说明增长水平。</p>   <p>U.S. chip designer Qualcomm also said last week that it is seeing strong demand from smartphone companies, especially in China.翻译:美国芯片设计商高通公司上周也表示，它看到智能手机公司的强劲需求，尤其是在中国。</p>   <p>The Mi 14 series, priced between 3,999 yuan and 6,499 yuan ($550-$890), represents an attempt by Xiaomi to make deeper inroads into the premium smartphone market and compete with Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a> and Huawei.翻译:Mi 14系列的售价在3,999元至6,499元（550-890美元）之间，代表着小米进一步进军高端智能手机市场并与苹果<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">（AAPL.O）</a>和华为竞争的尝试。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2856 Chinese yuan)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2856 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Yelin Mo and Brenda Goh; Editing by Edwina Gibbs翻译:莫叶琳和吴布伦达报道；编辑：埃德温娜·吉布斯</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 07:23:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3O6HXRWR4RM2RHJYERG765MTR4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/china-smartphone-market-perks-up-sales-new-xiaomi-model-off-roaring-start-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Yelin Mo, Brenda Goh]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>SMARTPHONES/XIAOMI (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着复苏的摇摆不定，中国的消费者价格再次下降]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Oct CPI -0.2% y/y vs 0.0% in Sep</li>  <li>Oct CPI -0.1% m/m vs +0.2% in Sep</li>  <li>Oct PPI -2.6% y/y vs -2.5% in Sep</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li> 10 月 CPI 同比为 -0.2%，9 月为 0.0%</li><li> 10 月 CPI 环比为 -0.1%，9 月为 +0.2%</li><li> 10 月 PPI 同比为 -2.6%，9 月为 -2.5%</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/PS_qf2ssPbM3PhQM_xVvNaYjop0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YXI6FP5QXFOZHB2MQWQXFFK3MI.jpg" alt="Customers select tomatoes at a stall inside a morning market in Beijing翻译:北京早市内的摊位上，顾客挑选西红柿" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Customers select tomatoes at a stall inside a morning market in Beijing翻译:北京早市内的摊位上，顾客挑选西红柿, China August 9, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo翻译:2023 年 8 月 9 日，中国北京，顾客在早市内的摊位上挑选西红柿。路透社/Tingshu Wang/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's consumer prices swung lower in October, as key gauges of domestic demand pointed to weakness not seen since the pandemic, while factory-gate deflation deepened, casting doubts over the chances of a broad-based economic recovery.翻译:中国十月份的消费者价格下跌，因为国内需求的关键指标显示出自大流行以来未见的疲软，而工厂门口的通货紧缩加剧，使人们对广泛的经济复苏的机会产生了怀疑。</p>   <p>The consumer price index (CPI) dropped 0.2% in October from a year earlier and slipped 0.1% from September, data from the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) showed on Thursday.翻译:国家统计局周四公布的数据显示，10月份居民消费价格指数（CPI）同比下降0.2%，环比下降0.1%。</p>   <p>The declines undershot the median 0.1% year-on-year fall and flat month-on-month reading predicted in a Reuters poll. Both indicators were last negative at the same time in November 2020 during the COVID-19 pandemic.翻译:跌幅低于路透调查预测的同比跌幅中值 0.1% 和环比持平。这两项指标最后一次同时为负值是在 2020 年 11 月 COVID-19 大流行期间。</p>   <p>The headline figure was dragged by a further slump in pork prices, down 30.1%, speeding up from a 22% slide in September, amid an oversupply of pigs and weak demand.翻译:总体数据受到猪肉价格进一步下跌的拖累，在生猪供应过剩和需求疲软的情况下，猪肉价格下跌 30.1%，较 9 月份的 22% 降幅有所加快。</p>   <p>However, even core inflation, which excludes food and fuel prices, slowed to 0.6% in October from 0.8% in September, pointing to China's continued battle with disinflationary forces and the risk of again missing the government's full-year headline inflation target, set at around 3%.翻译:然而，即使是不包括食品和燃料价格的核心通胀率，也从 9 月的 0.8% 放缓至 10 月的 0.6%，这表明中国仍在继续与通货紧缩力量作斗争，并且有再次达不到政府设定的全年总体通胀目标的风险。 3%左右。</p>   <p>Consumer prices slipped into deflation in July and returned to positive territory in August but were flat in September. Factory deflation persisted for the 13th straight month in October.翻译:消费者价格在 7 月份陷入通货紧缩，并在 8 月份恢复正值，但 9 月份持平。 10 月份工厂通货紧缩已连续第 13 个月持续。</p>   <p>Combined with other economic indicators, the data in the fourth-quarter so far suggests a meaningful recovery in the world's second-largest economy remains elusive.翻译:结合其他经济指标，第四季度迄今为止的数据表明，世界第二大经济体的有意义的复苏仍然难以实现。</p>   <p>"The data shows combating persistent disinflation amid weak demand remains a challenge for Chinese policymakers," said Bruce Pang, chief economist at Jones Lang Lasalle.翻译:仲量联行首席经济学家布鲁斯·庞表示：“数据显示，在需求疲软的情况下应对持续的通货紧缩仍然是中国政策制定者面临的挑战。”</p>   <p>"An appropriate policy mix and more supportive measures are needed to prevent the economy from a downward drift in inflation expectations that could threaten business confidence and household spending."翻译:“需要采取适当的政策组合和更多的支持性措施，以防止经济出现通胀预期下滑，从而威胁企业信心和家庭支出。”</p>   <p>Month-on-month, CPI fell 0.1%, compared with a 0.2% gain in September.翻译:环比来看，CPI下降0.1%，而9月份上涨0.2%。</p>   <p>The producer price index (PPI) fell 2.6% year-on-year against a 2.5% drop in September. Economists had predicted a 2.7% fall in October.翻译:生产者出厂价格指数（PPI）同比下降2.6%，9月份为下降2.5%。经济学家此前预测 10 月份将下降 2.7%。</p>      <p>Authorities have repeatedly downplayed the risks.翻译:当局一再淡化这些风险。</p>   <p>"There is no deflation in China and there will be no deflation in the future," said a statistics bureau official in August.翻译:“中国不存在通缩，未来也不会出现通货紧缩，”国家统计局官员8月份表示。</p>   <p>Beijing has been ramping up measures to support the broader economy, including 1 trillion yuan ($137.43 billion) in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/china-issue-137-bln-sovereign-debt-support-economy-2023-10-24/">sovereign bond</a> issuance and a move to allow local governments to frontload part of their 2024 bond quotas.翻译:北京一直在加大力度支持更广泛的经济，包括发行1万亿元人民币（1,374.3亿美元）的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/china-issue-137-bln-sovereign-debt-support-economy-2023-10-24/">主权债券</a>，以及允许地方政府预付部分2024年债券配额。</p>   <p>But a property crisis, local debt risks and policy divergence with the West all complicate the recovery process.翻译:但房地产危机、地方债务风险以及与西方的政策分歧都使复苏进程变得复杂。</p>   <p>Recent indicators of the economy have been mixed.翻译:最近的经济指标好坏参半。</p>   <p>China's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-imports-unexpectedly-grow-oct-exports-extend-declines-2023-11-07/">imports</a> unexpectedly grew in October while exports contracted at a quicker pace. Meanwhile, the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-exports-imports-slump-narrows-sept-boost-recovery-prospects-2023-10-13/">official purchasing managers' index</a> showed factory activity unexpectedly contracting and services activity slowing last month.翻译:10月份中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-imports-unexpectedly-grow-oct-exports-extend-declines-2023-11-07/">进口</a>意外增长，而出口则加速收缩。与此同时， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-exports-imports-slump-narrows-sept-boost-recovery-prospects-2023-10-13/">官方采购经理人指数</a>显示上个月工厂活动意外收缩，服务业活动放缓。</p>   <p>China also recorded its first-ever <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-first-deficit-foreign-investment-signals-wests-de-risking-pressure-2023-11-06/">quarterly deficit</a> in foreign direct investment (FDI), underlining capital outflow pressure following Western governments' "de-risking" moves.翻译:中国还首次出现外国直接投资（FDI） <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-first-deficit-foreign-investment-signals-wests-de-risking-pressure-2023-11-06/">季度赤字</a>，凸显了西方政府“去风险”举措后的资本外流压力。</p>   <p>"We expect China's economy to grow by 5.0% in 2023, in accordance with the target set by authorities, followed by 4.0% growth in 2024 and 2025," said Moody's on Thursday.翻译:穆迪周四表示：“根据当局设定的目标，我们预计中国经济将在 2023 年增长 5.0%，随后在 2024 年和 2025 年增长 4.0%。”</p>   <p>"However, we see downside risks to China's trend growth on account of structural factors."翻译:“然而，由于结构性因素，我们认为中国的趋势增长存在下行风险。”</p>    <span>Reporting Liangping Gao, Ella Cao and Ryan Woo; Editing by Sam Holmes翻译:报道高亮平、Ella Cao 和 Ryan Woo；山姆·霍姆斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 06:43:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">JUF7LSHSHFOFJIJEGUJQ7QU4GU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Liangping Gao, Ryan Woo]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/INFLATION (UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[台湾在敏感的台湾海峡监视中国航母编队]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/POx5ksH1lYbINKqd4Uv37xdJg-A=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/Q7OETS3LNJIYXK5LD546A6LAYQ.jpg" alt="Illustration shows Chinese and Taiwanese flags翻译:插图显示中国和台湾国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Navy miniature is seen in front of displayed Chinese and Taiwanese flags in this illustration taken, April 11, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张摄于 2023 年 4 月 11 日的插图中，可以看到在展示的中国和台湾国旗前有一个海军微型模型。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Taiwan's military has sent forces to keep watch on a Chinese naval formation led by the aircraft carrier Shandong sailing through the sensitive Taiwan Strait, Taiwan's defence ministry said on Thursday.翻译:台湾国防部周四表示，台湾军方已派兵监视山东舰率领的中国海军编队穿越敏感的台湾海峡。</p>   <p>The Shandong participated in Chinese military drills around Taiwan in April, and again entered the Pacific last month.翻译:山东舰四月份参加了中国在台湾附近的军事演习，并于上个月再次进入太平洋。</p>   <p>The ministry said in a statement that the formation led by the Shandong entered the narrow Taiwan Strait on Wednesday afternoon sailing in a northerly direction but keeping to the Chinese side of the waterway's median line, an unofficial barrier between the two.翻译:国防部在一份声明中表示，由山东舰率领的编队于周三下午进入狭窄的台湾海峡，向北航行，但保持在水道中线的中国一侧，中线是两者之间的非官方屏障。</p>   <p>China says the Taiwan Strait is not an international waterway and that it alone has sovereignty there, which both Taiwan and the United States dispute. The United States frequently sends warships through the strait, most recently last week, that time accompanied by a Canadian frigate.翻译:中国表示，台湾海峡不是国际水道，只有中国拥有该海峡的主权，台湾和美国对此都存在争议。美国经常派军舰通过该海峡，最近一次是上周，当时有一艘加拿大护卫舰随行。</p>   <p>As of Thursday morning, the Chinese carrier group was continuing to sail northwards, Taiwan's defence ministry said. Taiwan has dispatched "appropriate" forces to keep watch, it added, without elaborating.翻译:台湾国防部表示，截至周四上午，中国航母编队仍在继续向北航行。声明补充称，台湾已派出“适当”部队进行警戒，但没有详细说明。</p>   <p>China's defence ministry did not immediately respond to a request for comment.翻译:中国国防部没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Japan's defence ministry said on Monday that the Shandong and other naval ships had sailed to the South China Sea after conducting landing drills in the Pacific Ocean for nine days.翻译:日本防卫省周一表示，山东舰等海军舰艇在太平洋进行了9天的登陆演习后已驶往南海。</p>   <p>The Shandong, commissioned in 2019, also sailed through the Taiwan Strait in June.翻译:2019年入役的山东舰也于6月穿越了台湾海峡。</p>   <p>Taiwan has repeatedly complained of Chinese air force planes crossing the strait's median line.翻译:台湾多次抱怨中国空军飞机越过海峡中线。</p>   <p>China, which has never renounced the use of force to bring Taiwan under its control, has stepped up military activity near the democratically governed island, responding to what it calls "collusion" between Taiwan and the United States.翻译:中国从未放弃使用武力将台湾置于其控制之下，并加强了在这个民主治理的岛屿附近的军事活动，以回应所谓的台湾与美国之间的“勾结”。</p>   <p>Taiwan's government strongly rejects Beijing's sovereignty claim.翻译:台湾政府强烈拒绝北京的主权主张。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ben Blanchard; Editing by Christopher Cushing &amp; Simon Cameron-Moore翻译:本·布兰查德报道；克里斯托弗·库欣和西蒙·卡梅伦-摩尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 02:55:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MOJLZ43U5NNY5PWD4AM45DMBOI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-monitors-chinese-carrier-group-sensitive-taiwan-strait-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>TAIWAN</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/DEFENCE (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：中国当局要求平安控股碧桂园]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/eBVgxhuGq-6QDT0424waw9E2jX4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VNN5BS7ZU5KSZJRW6XQ6PNSWHA.jpg" alt="The logo of Ping An Insurance is seen at the Global Mobile Internet Conference (GMIC) at the National Convention Center in Beijing翻译:平安保险标志亮相北京国家会议中心全球移动互联网大会（GMIC）" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of Ping An Insurance is seen at the Global Mobile Internet Conference (GMIC) at the National Convention Center in Beijing翻译:平安保险标志亮相北京国家会议中心全球移动互联网大会（GMIC）, China April 27, 2018.  REUTERS/Damir Sagolj/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/LeE1pEW6qsIl73AhRbqnmn0i92g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JGPVZE4RMFOFPMRNIPMXZH4S7M.jpg" alt="The company logo of Chinese developer Country Garden is pictured at the Shanghai Country Garden Center in Shanghai翻译:中国开发商碧桂园的公司标志位于上海碧桂园中心" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The company logo of Chinese developer Country Garden is pictured at the Shanghai Country Garden Center in Shanghai翻译:中国开发商碧桂园的公司标志位于上海碧桂园中心, China August 9, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:中国开发商碧桂园的公司标志于2023年8月9日在中国上海碧桂园中心拍摄。路透社/Aly Song/档案照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>Chinese authorities have asked Ping An Insurance Group to take a controlling stake in embattled Country Garden <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">(2007.HK)</a>, the nation's biggest private property developer, four people familiar with the plan said.翻译:四位知情人士称，中国当局已要求平安保险集团控股陷入困境的中国最大的私营房地产开发商碧桂园<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">（2007.HK）</a> 。</p>   <p>China's State Council, which is headed by Premier Li Qiang, has instructed the local government of Guangdong province, where both companies are based, to help arrange a rescue of Country Garden by Ping An, said two of the sources who have direct knowledge of the matter.翻译:两名直接了解情况的消息人士称，以李强总理为首的中国国务院已指示两家公司所在地广东省当地政府帮助安排平安对碧桂园的救助。事情。</p>   <p>A spokesperson for Ping An <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601318.SS" target="_blank">(601318.SS)</a> said the company had not been approached by the government and denied the information reported by Reuters.翻译:中国平安<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601318.SS" target="_blank">（601318.SS）</a>发言人表示，政府尚未与该公司接洽，并否认了路透社报道的信息。</p>   <p>Ping An has "not been asked by (the) Government to takeover Country Garden. We categorically deny this story. It is untrue," the company said in a statement to Reuters.翻译:该公司在给路透社的一份声明中表示，平安“没有被政府要求收购碧桂园。我们断然否认这个故事。这是不真实的”。</p>   <p>It reiterated its denial in a public statement after Reuters first published this report.翻译:在路透社首次发表这份报告后，它在一份公开声明中重申了其否认。</p>   <p>A Reuters spokesperson said: “We stand by our reporting.”翻译:路透社发言人表示：“我们坚持我们的报道。”</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-property-rescue-who-are-ping-an-insurance-group-country-garden-2023-11-08/">insurer</a>, which vies with China Life <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601628.SS" target="_blank">(601628.SS)</a> for the title of the country's biggest insurance group by market value, declined to make its founder and chairman, Ma Mingzhe, available for an interview. Ma, who also uses the English first name Peter, did not respond to an emailed Reuters request for comment.翻译:这家与中国人寿<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601628.SS" target="_blank">（601628.SS）</a>争夺中国市值最大保险集团称号的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-property-rescue-who-are-ping-an-insurance-group-country-garden-2023-11-08/">保险公司</a>拒绝接受其创始人兼董事长马明哲的采访。马云也使用英文名彼得，他没有回复路透社通过电子邮件发出的置评请求。</p>   <p>China's State Council Information Office and the Guangdong local government did not respond to requests for comment. Country Garden declined to comment.翻译:中国国务院新闻办公室和广东地方政府没有回应置评请求。碧桂园拒绝置评。</p>   <p>Ping An's Hong Kong-listed shares <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/ping-an-loses-21-bln-market-value-china-property-rallies-country-garden-rescue-2023-11-08/">finished 5.4% lower</a> in heavy trade, wiping about $2.1 billion off its market value. Country Garden shares surged 12.2%, valuing the company at about $3 billion, and stocks of other Chinese developers also jumped.翻译:平安在香港上市的股票在激烈的交投中<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/ping-an-loses-21-bln-market-value-china-property-rallies-country-garden-rescue-2023-11-08/">下跌 5.4%</a> ，市值蒸发约 21 亿美元。碧桂园股价飙升 12.2%，该公司估值约为 30 亿美元，其他中国开发商的股价也大幅上涨。</p>   <p>A state-engineered rescue of Country Garden by Ping An would be one of the most significant interventions to date by authorities to support the cash-squeezed and highly indebted property sector, which accounts for one-quarter of China's economic activity and has sparked fears of a broader financial crisis.翻译:平安对碧桂园的国家计划救助将是迄今为止当局为支持现金紧张且负债累累的房地产行业而采取的最重大干预措施之一，该行业占中国经济活动的四分之一，并引发了人们的担忧更广泛的金融危机。</p>   <p>"If this is true, it will have a very significant positive impact on the property and capital markets," said Xu Tianchen, senior economist at the Economist Intelligence Unit.翻译:“如果这是真的，将对房地产和资本市场产生非常重大的积极影响，”经济学人智库高级经济学家徐天辰表示。</p>   <p>"Only equity injections, such as corporate takeovers or nationalisations, are likely to turn around the confidence of home buyers and investors and materially change the situation."</p>    <h 1="">MITIGATING RISK</h>  <p>Authorities are keen that any risks posed by Country Garden's liquidity problems should not spill over to the wider economy, said three of the sources.翻译:其中三位消息人士表示，当局希望碧桂园的流动性问题带来的任何风险都不应蔓延到更广泛的经济领域。</p>   <p>While in China companies can rarely ignore a request from the central government, the three sources said Ping An has been asked to come up with details of the plan and will have leeway to negotiate terms of any deal.翻译:虽然在中国，企业很少会忽视中央政府的要求，但三位消息人士表示，平安已被要求提供该计划的细节，并将有余地来谈判任何交易的条款。</p>   <p>Talks between authorities and core Ping An leaders began in late August and are still at an early stage, said two of them.翻译:其中两位人士表示，当局与平安核心领导人之间的谈判于 8 月底开始，目前仍处于早期阶段。</p>   <p>Ping An has been asked to conduct due diligence on Country Garden, two sources also said, adding that authorities understood the insurer was a listed company answerable to shareholders.翻译:两位消息人士还表示，平安已被要求对碧桂园进行尽职调查，并补充说，当局了解该保险公司是一家对股东负责的上市公司。</p>   <p>A fifth person with knowledge of the matter said some talks between Ping An and the Guangdong local government about a rescue of Country Garden took place in September.翻译:第五位知情人士称，9月份中国平安与广东地方政府就救助碧桂园进行了一些会谈。</p>   <p>All sources declined to be identified due to the sensitivity of the matter.翻译:由于此事的敏感性，所有消息来源均拒绝透露姓名。</p>   <p>Discussions between Ping An and authorities are being led by officials in the financial markets department of the People's Bank of China (PBOC), which is the central bank, and include Country Garden, said two sources.翻译:两名消息人士称，平安与当局之间的讨论是由中国人民银行（中国人民银行）金融市场部官员主导的，其中包括碧桂园。</p>   <p>The National Financial Regulatory Administration (NFRA) is also involved in the talks, they added.翻译:他们补充说，国家金融监管局（NFRA）也参与了谈判。</p>   <p>Neither the PBOC nor the NFRA responded to Reuters requests for comment.翻译:中国人民银行和国家金融监管局均未回应路透社的置评请求。</p>   <p>Authorities want Ping An to take a stake of more than 50%, according to one person with direct knowledge and one person briefed on the plan.翻译:据一位直接知情人士和一位了解该计划的人士透露，当局希望平安持股超过 50%。</p>   <p>Country Garden's largest shareholder with a stake of about 52% is Yang Huiyan, chairperson and daughter of a co-founder. Reuters was not able to reach Yang for comment.翻译:碧桂园第一大股东为董事长、联合创始人之女杨惠妍，持股约52%。路透社未能联系到杨置评。</p>   <p>If Ping An were to become Country Garden's controlling shareholder, authorities would like it to inject capital in stages to ease the developer's liquidity problems, according to four sources.翻译:四位消息人士称，如果平安成为碧桂园的控股股东，当局希望其分阶段注资，以缓解开发商的流动性问题。</p>   <p>The property developer last month <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-country-garden-offshore-debt-default-looms-2023-10-18/">missed a deadline</a> to pay a $15 million coupon and the market has deemed it to be in default on its offshore bonds which total some $11 billion.翻译:该房地产开发商上个月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-country-garden-offshore-debt-default-looms-2023-10-18/">错过了支付 1500 万美元息票的最后期限</a>，市场认为该公司拖欠了总额约 110 亿美元的离岸债券。</p>   <p>Country Garden has said it expects to be unable to meet all of its offshore debt obligations and hopes to seek a "holistic" solution to its difficulties.翻译:碧桂园表示，预计无法履行所有离岸债务，并希望寻求“整体”解决方案来解决其困难。</p>   <p>Chinese authorities are eager to make the proposed takeover a possible template for other financially troubled developers, two of the sources also said.</p>    <h 1="">GUANGDONG SOLUTION</h>  <p>Authorities are keen for the Country Garden's liquidity problems to be resolved within Guangdong, three sources said. Ping An was a natural choice because it is based in Guangdong and has been a major Country Garden shareholder, according to two of the sources.翻译:三名消息人士称，当局希望碧桂园的流动性问题能够在广东境内得到解决。两位消息人士称，平安是一个自然选择，因为它总部位于广东，并且一直是碧桂园的主要股东。</p>   <p>Ping An said after Reuters first published this report that it no longer holds Country Garden shares. It held a 4.99% stake as of Aug. 11, according to Hong Kong stock exchange data.翻译:中国平安在路透社首次发布该报道后表示，其不再持有碧桂园股票。根据香港证券交易所数据，截至8月11日，该公司持有4.99%的股份。</p>   <p>A state-engineered takeover of one company by another is not without precedent in China. But there has not been one in the property sector since Beijing flagged measures in 2020 to tackle the industry's very high debt levels, triggering a liquidity crunch.翻译:国家策划的一家公司对另一家公司的收购在中国并非没有先例。但自北京在 2020 年宣布采取措施解决该行业极高的债务水平并引发流动性紧缩以来，房地产行业还没有出台任何措施。</p>   <p>Although many other Chinese property developers, including giant China Evergrande <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a>, have defaulted on their debt, policy steps have mostly concentrated on lowering mortgage rates and relaxing rules so that it is easier for people to buy homes.翻译:尽管包括巨头中国恒大<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）</a>在内的许多其他中国房地产开发商都出现了债务违约，但政策措施主要集中在降低抵押贷款利率和放宽规定，以便人们更容易购房。</p>   <p>But in a sign that governmental authorities are willing to play a bigger role, China Vanke's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/000002.SZ" target="_blank">(000002.SZ)</a> top shareholder, state-owned <a href="https://jp.reuters.com/article/china-property-debt-vanke-idUSL1N3C70KO">Shenzhen Metro</a> on Monday said it had prepared 10 billion yuan ($1.4 billion) worth of "market tools" to support the country's No. 2 developer.翻译:但万科<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/000002.SZ" target="_blank">(000002.SZ)</a>的最大股东、国有<a href="https://jp.reuters.com/article/china-property-debt-vanke-idUSL1N3C70KO">深圳地铁</a>周一表示，已准备了价值 100 亿元人民币（14 亿美元）的“市场工具”，这表明政府当局愿意发挥更大的作用。支持国家第二大开发商。</p>   <p>Country Garden had total liabilities of 1.4 trillion yuan ($190 billion) at the end of June. It has more than 3,000 projects under development nationwide.翻译:截至 6 月底，碧桂园的总负债为 1.4 万亿元人民币（1,900 亿美元）。全国在建项目超过3000个。</p>   <p>Ping An has been tapped by authorities as a rescuer for an ailing company before.翻译:平安此前曾被当局指派为一家陷入困境的公司的救助者。</p>   <p>It participated in state-guided aid for Peking University Founder Group in 2021 and 2022. Its main unit, Ping An Life, was part of a consortium that was involved in restructuring the group's debt and then the unit took 67% ownership of the reorganised company.翻译:2021年和2022年参与北大方正集团国家引导援助，其主体单位平安人寿是参与集团债务重组的财团成员，后持有重组后公司67%的股权。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2846 Chinese yuan)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2846 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Reuters staff; Editing by Anne Marie Roantree, Antoni Slodkowski, Don Durfee and Edwina Gibbs翻译:路透社工作人员的报道；编辑：Anne Marie Roantree、Antoni Slodkowski、Don Durfee 和 Edwina Gibbs</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 17:43:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">X243QMUNPVIGXP32RXOTX4GBEU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/COUNTRY GARDEN</category>
                
                <category>PING AN (UPDATE 4, EXCLUSIVE, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
