<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 16:40:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[亚洲和非洲移民激增，亚马逊丛林前哨变成十字路口]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/282G735Y9T0Tu0cEsX6Pt5LmUPc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BT553R2XRRNFVG4OQHCCZZHOMY.jpg" alt="Turquesa Operation, in Benjamin Constant翻译:绿松石行动，本杰明·康斯坦" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Federal Police officers conduct a raid in a port during the Turquesa Operation, in Benjamin Constant翻译:绿松石行动，本杰明·康斯坦 Brazil November 30, 2023. Policia Federal/Handout via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/OJ0YZmrL1DDxnOBsLyGhqGvISmA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5ZSVM53WPZMJFGJW23SOIAYAMA.jpg" alt="Turquesa Operation, in Benjamin Constant翻译:绿松石行动，本杰明·康斯坦" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Federal Police officers conduct a raid in a port during the Turquesa Operation, in Benjamin Constant翻译:绿松石行动，本杰明·康斯坦 Brazil November 30, 2023. Policia Federal/Handout via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/IsaELTW-UVV_w-TPgpAm_AomiTk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FUAX4US7FFLKLBZBXDCGLA75KQ.jpg" alt="Turquesa Operation, in Benjamin Constant翻译:绿松石行动，本杰明·康斯坦" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Federal Police officers hold weapons as they conduct a raid on a river during the Turquesa Operation, in Benjamin Constant翻译:绿松石行动，本杰明·康斯坦 Brazil November 30, 2023. Policia Federal/Handout via REUTERS翻译:2023 年 11 月 30 日，巴西本杰明康斯坦，联邦警察在 Turquesa 行动期间手持武器对一条河流进行突袭。联邦警察/路透社的讲义</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/wbQjo524ZcaduFnt9_UkI1QZEJg=/1280x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5PI6YPUL2BIAFM5Y5BDLKJCPAA.jpg" alt="Turquesa Operation, in Rio Branco翻译:Turquesa 行动，位于里约布兰科" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Passports are checked during the Turquesa Operation, in Rio Branco翻译:Turquesa 行动，位于里约布兰科 Brazil November 30, 2023. Policia Federal/Handout via REUTERS   翻译:2023 年 11 月 30 日，巴西里约布兰科，在 Turquesa 行动期间检查护照。联邦警察/路透社的讲义</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/bQESQqyg9GQxUIIcx-YP3sNsU7Y=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6SI47WB3FBI6RCYIM3Z7WDO7EY.jpg" alt="Turquesa Operation, in Benjamin Constant翻译:绿松石行动，本杰明·康斯坦" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Federal Police officers conduct a raid on a river during the Turquesa Operation, in Benjamin Constant翻译:绿松石行动，本杰明·康斯坦 Brazil November 30, 2023. Policia Federal/Handout via REUTERS/File photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/dXR_s4k9Op-O6nb5BjtceOMzgJM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/W34KZNAC7JLRFP2QDYX23GZNEQ.jpg" alt="2023 through the lens of Reuters photographers翻译:路透社摄影师镜头下的 2023 年" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Migrants wait for some food from an aid worker after gathering between the primary and secondary border fences between Mexico and the United States as they await processing by U.S immigration in San Diego, U.S., September 12, 2023. REUTERS/Mike Blake/File Photo翻译:2023 年 9 月 12 日，在美国圣地亚哥，移民聚集在墨西哥和美国之间的一级和二级边境围栏之间，等待援助人员提供的食物。路透社/迈克·布莱克/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/xtgWzEIBEqv0Dh5U0UJ1vkXrAM4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/O7JBMS36GBI7PKETJDYOQ7YF4I.jpg" alt="rcom_wFILE PHOTO: Migrants seeking asylum in the United States cross the Rio Bravo River, as seen from Ciudad Juarez翻译:rcom_wFILE 照片：从华雷斯城看到的在美国寻求庇护的移民穿过里奥布拉沃河" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Migrants seeking asylum in the United States cross the Rio Bravo River, the border between the U.S. and Mexico, as seen from Ciudad Juarez, Mexico, December 5, 2023. REUTERS/Jose Luis Gonzalez/File Photo翻译:2023 年 12 月 5 日，从墨西哥华雷斯城看到，在美国寻求庇护的移民越过美国和墨西哥之间的边界里奥布拉沃河。路透社/Jose Luis Gonzalez/资料照片</figcaption></figure>                         <p>A recent crackdown on migrant smuggling and human trafficking throughout the Americas turned up migrants from 69 countries, an indicator of the steep growth in Asians and Africans who are crossing oceans and continents to reach the United States.翻译:最近美洲各地打击移民走私和人口贩运的行动发现了来自 69 个国家的移民，这表明跨越大洋和大陆前往美国的亚洲和非洲人数量急剧增加。</p>   <p>Coordinated by the international police organization Interpol, the fifth annual Operation Turquesa united immigration enforcement officers from throughout the Americas from Nov. 27 to Dec. 1 in an attempt to dismantle international crime syndicates.翻译:在国际警察组织国际刑警组织的协调下，第五届年度绿松石行动于11月27日至12月1日联合美洲各地的移民执法人员，试图瓦解国际犯罪集团。</p>   <p>Among the victories officials claimed were stopping a Portuguese national who was buying newborn babies from impoverished Brazilian women for sale in Europe, arresting three suspects linked to the notorious Venezuelan prison gang Tren de Aragua, and freezing $286,000 worth of assets belonging to a ring that recruited Brazilians to a cyber fraud center in Cambodia.翻译:官员们声称取得的胜利包括阻止一名葡萄牙国民从巴西贫困妇女那里购买新生婴儿并在欧洲出售，逮捕了三名与臭名昭著的委内瑞拉监狱帮派 Tren de Aragua 有关的嫌疑人，并冻结了一个招募新成员的团伙价值 286,000 美元的资产。巴西人前往柬埔寨的一个网络欺诈中心。</p>   <p>In its fifth annual Operation Turquesa, Interpol brought together law enforcement from 31 countries in the Americas, including Cuba for the first time, plus France and Spain. Together they netted 257 arrests, rescued 163 suspected victims of human trafficking and detected nearly 12,000 undocumented immigrants from 69 countries, Interpol said.翻译:在第五次年度“绿松石行动”中，国际刑警组织首次汇集了美洲 31 个国家的执法部门，其中首次包括古巴、法国和西班牙。国际刑警组织称，他们总共逮捕了 257 人，解救了 163 名涉嫌人口贩运的受害者，并查获了来自 69 个国家的近 12,000 名无证移民。</p>   <p>Dozens of trafficking victims were children, including 12 in Honduras.翻译:数十名人口贩运受害者是儿童，其中 12 名来自洪都拉斯。</p>   <p>Sixty-nine countries is the highest number ever and is more than double the 28 countries reported in the first sweep in 2019.翻译:69 个国家是有史以来数量最多的，是 2019 年第一次扫描中报告的 28 个国家的两倍多。</p>      <p>Focused on migrants destined for the U.S. and Canada, this year's operation showed a "marked increase" in migrants from Asia and Africa, particularly from <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/usa-immigration-china/">China</a>, which was the third most popular country of origin behind Venezuela and Ecuador, Interpol said.翻译:国际刑警组织表示，今年的行动主要针对前往美国和加拿大的移民，显示来自亚洲和非洲的移民“显着增加”，特别是来自<a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/usa-immigration-china/">中国的</a>移民，中国是仅次于委内瑞拉和厄瓜多尔的第三大最受欢迎的原籍国。</p>   <p>"The number of nationalities detected during Operation Turquesa V demonstrates how this major migration corridor, once considered a route reserved to the Americas, has become the target of organized crime groups from around the world," Interpol Secretary General Jurgen Stock said in a statement.翻译:国际刑警组织秘书长于尔根·斯托克在一份声明中表示：“绿松石五号行动中发现的国籍数量表明，这条曾经被认为是美洲保留路线的主要移民走廊如何成为世界各地有组织犯罪集团的目标。”</p>   <p>Migrants who cooperated with police provided insight into recruitment tactics, travel conditions and the cost of being smuggled, which ranged from $2,700 to $20,000 per person depending on the journey, Interpol said. Smugglers often have ties with the illicit drug trade, adding untold fortunes to gangsters already awash in cash.翻译:国际刑警组织表示，与警方合作的移民提供了有关招募策略、旅行条件和偷渡成本的深入信息，根据旅程的不同，偷渡成本从每人 2,700 美元到 20,000 美元不等。走私者经常与非法毒品贸易有联系，为已经拥有大量现金的歹徒增加了无数的财富。</p>      <p>The number of migrants encountered at the U.S. border with Mexico from countries outside of Latin America and the Caribbean increased by 43% between the 2022 and 2023 fiscal years, according to CBP data.翻译:根据 CBP 的数据，2022 至 2023 财年，在美国与墨西哥边境遇到的来自拉丁美洲和加勒比海地区以外国家的移民数量增加了 43%。</p>   <p>In October, the first month of the 2024 fiscal year, there were nearly 12,000 migrants at the border from those "extracontinental" countries, nearly the same amount as arrived in all of 2021.翻译:10 月，即 2024 财年的第一个月，边境有近 12,000 名来自这些“洲外”国家的移民，几乎与 2021 年全年抵达的人数相同。</p>   <p>The U.S. Department of Homeland Security <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/sites/default/files/2022-12/22_1213_plcy_update-sw-border-security-preparedness.pdf" target="_blank">calls the current trend</a> "the highest level of mass migration since World War II." U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) attributed it to "economic distress and political upheaval" triggered in part by natural disasters and a worldwide pandemic.</p>    <h 1="">BRAZIL AS MIGRATION HUB</h>  <p>Operation Turquesa also offered a peek into Brazil's outsized role in the transcontinental trade, with migrants crisscrossing the country. Most were destined for the United States, others for Europe and some settled in Brazil itself, according to Brazil's Federal Police.翻译:绿松石行动还让人们一睹巴西在跨大陆贸易中的巨大作用，移民在全国各地穿梭。据巴西联邦警察称，大多数人的目的地是美国，其他人则前往欧洲，还有一些在巴西境内定居。</p>   <p>Federal Police deployed officers to nine points around Brazil, the fifth-largest nation in the world by area and one sharing a border with 10 other countries.翻译:联邦警察在巴西各地的九个地点部署了警力。巴西是世界上面积第五大的国家，并且与其他 10 个国家接壤。</p>      <p>Brazil has detected patterns such as migrants from Cuba and Haiti traveling to the tiny coastal nation of Guyana, then crossing illegally into Brazil and making a two-day overland journey to the Brazilian Amazon city of Manaus. There they begin a more than 1,000-kilometer (1,600-mile), weeklong riverboat journey up the Amazon to the jungle outpost of Tabatinga, on the border with Colombia and Peru.翻译:巴西发现了一些模式，例如来自古巴和海地的移民前往沿海小国圭亚那，然后非法越境进入巴西，并通过为期两天的陆路旅程前往巴西亚马逊城市马瑙斯。在那里，他们开始了为期一周、长达 1,000 多公里（1,600 英里）的河船之旅，沿亚马逊河而上，到达位于哥伦比亚和秘鲁边境的丛林前哨塔巴廷加。</p>   <p>Tabatinga also attracts migrants from elsewhere in the Caribbean basin who are destined for Europe, police said. In one route, Dominican Republic nationals obtain fake Colombian passports in Colombia, cross into Brazil at Tabatinga, then make the long journey to Sao Paulo, more than 2,000 miles (3,200 km) away, their last stop before Europe.翻译:警方表示，塔巴廷加还吸引了来自加勒比盆地其他地区前往欧洲的移民。在一条路线中，多米尼加共和国国民在哥伦比亚获得假哥伦比亚护照，从塔巴廷加进入巴西，然后长途跋涉前往 2,000 多英里（3,200 公里）外的圣保罗，这是他们前往欧洲之前的最后一站。</p>      <p>"We have this open arms (immigration) policy ... and we have some complicated neighbors regarding drug production and everything else," said Commissioner Cristiano Eloi, chief of Brazil's Federal Police enforcement for human trafficking and migrant smuggling.翻译:“我们有张开双臂的（移民）政策……而且我们在毒品生产和其他一切方面有一些复杂的邻国，”巴西联邦警察打击人口贩运和偷运移民执法负责人克里斯蒂亚诺·埃洛伊（Cristiano Eloi）专员说。</p>   <p>"And we have these more than 16,000 kilometers, 10,000 miles of border with all these Latin American countries. So it makes it absolutely impossible to take care of each centimeter of our borders."翻译:“我们与所有这些拉丁美洲国家都有超过16,000公里、10,000英里的边界。因此，我们绝对不可能照顾好我们边界的每一厘米。”</p>   <p>Another Federal Police officer, speaking on condition of anonymity because he was not the official spokesperson, said many criminal suspects blend in with the migrants, who are often reluctant to cooperate. Moreover, Brazilian law prevents police from arresting people simply for immigration violations.翻译:另一位因不是官方发言人而不愿透露姓名的联邦警察表示，许多犯罪嫌疑人与移民混在一起，而移民往往不愿合作。此外，巴西法律禁止警察仅仅因为违反移民法而逮捕人。</p>   <p>With those limitations, Brazil arrested only three suspects in Turquesa, but it did free four trafficking victims: the two babies who were to be sold, plus two women who were stopped at Sao Paulo airport before going to Europe, Eloi said.翻译:埃洛伊说，由于这些限制，巴西在图尔克萨只逮捕了三名嫌疑人，但释放了四名人口贩运受害者：两名将被出售的婴儿，以及两名在前往欧洲之前在圣保罗机场被拦截的妇女。</p>   <p>"We are not going after the migrants," Eloi told Reuters. "We are going for the smuggler ... for the traffickers that are sending people to be exploited."翻译:埃洛伊告诉路透社：“我们不会追捕移民。” “我们正在追捕走私犯……追捕那些送人去受剥削的人贩子。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Daniel Trotta in Carlsbad, California; Additional reporting by Mica Rosenberg in New York; Editing by Mary Milliken and Cynthia Osterman翻译:丹尼尔·特罗塔 (Daniel Trotta) 在加利福尼亚州卡尔斯巴德的报道； Mica Rosenberg 在纽约的补充报道；玛丽·米利肯和辛西娅·奥斯特曼编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:51:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">WQ5IZH7KORO3FOBC4ZMNFTPRSU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/spike-asia-africa-migrants-turns-amazon-jungle-outpost-into-crossroads-2023-12-11/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Daniel Trotta]]></author>
            
                
                <category>MIGRATION</category>
                
                <category>INTERPOL/ (PIX, TV, GRAPHICS)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[菲律宾称军事首领在被中国船只撞毁的船上]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Manila accuses China of firing water cannons, ramming ship</li>  <li>Top Philippine military leader was aboard one ship</li>  <li>Marcos says China's actions illegal, violate international law</li>  <li>United States tells China to stop 'dangerous' conduct</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>马尼拉指责中国发射水炮、冲撞船只</li><li>菲律宾最高军事领导人登上一艘船</li><li>马科斯称中国的行为非法，违反国际法</li><li>美国要求中国停止“危险”行为</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ZcJupIt32d-5vndT3PV4z-_jFyY=/1280x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7KR4AJPHENNRJF5FBQKUHZZFZI.jpg" alt="Chinese militia vessels operate at Whitsun Reef in South China Sea翻译:中国民兵船只在南海圣灵礁作业" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese militia vessels operate at Whitsun Reef in the South China Sea, December 2, 2023. Philippine Coast Guard/Handout via REUTERS. FILE PHOTO翻译:2023 年 12 月 2 日，中国民兵船只在南海圣灵礁作业。菲律宾海岸警卫队/路透社发布的资料。档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Philippines on Monday called the actions of Chinese vessels against its boats carrying out South China Sea resupply missions over the weekend - including one with a senior Philippine military official aboard - a "serious escalation".翻译:菲律宾周一称，中国船只对周末执行南海补给任务的中国船只的行动——其中包括一艘载有菲律宾高级军事官员的船只——是“严重升级”。</p>   <p>Manila accused the Chinese coastguard and maritime militia of repeatedly firing water cannons at its resupply boats, causing "serious engine damage" to one, and "deliberately" ramming another. Philippine Chief of Staff of the Armed Forces Romeo Brawner said he was onboard a vessel that was both sprayed with a water cannon and rammed.翻译:马尼拉指责中国海岸警卫队和海上民兵多次向其补给船发射高压水枪，造成其中一艘补给船“严重发动机损坏”，并“故意”撞击另一艘补给船。菲律宾武装部队参谋长罗密欧·布劳纳表示，他所乘坐的船只遭到水炮喷射和撞击。</p>   <p>"This is a serious escalation on the part of the agents of the People's Republic of China," Jonathan Malaya, spokesperson of the National Security Council, said in a press conference where officials showed images and videos of the water cannons and ramming.翻译:国家安全委员会发言人乔纳森·马来亚在新闻发布会上表示，“这是中华人民共和国特工的严重升级”。会上，官员们展示了高压水枪和撞击的图像和视频。</p>   <p>Brawner told Philippine radio station DZBB that he was unhurt and that he did not believe China knew he was onboard the boat.翻译:布劳纳告诉菲律宾广播电台 DZBB，他没有受伤，而且他不相信中国知道他在船上。</p>   <p>The Philippines has filed diplomatic protests and has summoned China's ambassador over its "aggressive" actions in the South China Sea, which a foreign ministry official said were a "threat to peace, good order and security".翻译:菲律宾已就其在南海的“侵略”行为提出外交抗议，并召见了中国大使，一名外交部官员表示，这是“对和平、良好秩序与安全的威胁”。</p>   <p>China's foreign ministry said on Monday it had lodged solemn representations and a strong protest with the Philippine side over what it said was a collision on Sunday.翻译:中国外交部周一表示，已就周日发生的撞船事件向菲律宾方面提出严正交涉和强烈抗议。</p>   <p>The Philippine vessels "ignored Chinese coastguard's warnings and insisted on rushing into" waters near the Second Thomas Shoal, ministry spokesperson Mao Ning told a news briefing, adding that China's operation was "professional, reasonable and legal".翻译:外交部发言人毛宁在新闻发布会上表示，菲律宾船只“无视中国海警的警告，执意闯入”仁爱礁附近海域，并补充说中方的行动“专业、合理、合法”。</p>   <p>The Philippine ships were attempting to resupply military personnel stationed on a warship run aground years ago for use as a base.翻译:菲律宾船只正试图为多年前搁浅的一艘用作基地的军舰上的军事人员提供补给。</p>   <p>Mao said the responsibility for the "current repeated emergencies" at the disputed shoal lay with the Philippine side, which "refused to tow away the illegally beached warships and attempted to reinforce them to achieve permanent occupation".翻译:毛泽东表示，争议浅滩“目前反复出现的紧急情况”的责任在于菲律宾方面，“拒绝拖走非法搁浅的军舰，并试图增援它们以实现永久占领”。</p>   <p>China urged the Philippines to stop its "maritime violations and provocations" and stop its "groundless attacks and smears" against China, she said.翻译:中方敦促菲律宾停止“海上侵犯和挑衅”，停止对中国的“无端攻击和抹黑”。</p>   <p>Jay Batongbacal, a Manila-based expert on maritime law, said the latest incidents were "clearly another incremental escalation".翻译:马尼拉海事法专家杰伊·巴通巴卡尔 (Jay Batongbacal) 表示，最近的事件“显然是又一次逐步升级”。</p>   <p>"The use of water cannon this time is not mere dousing but had forceful impact, deliberately causing damage to vessels. And harassment of the civilian convoy is another step up in their threats," Batongbacal said.</p>    <h 1="">'DISSONANCE'</h>  <p>It was not the first time China has used water cannons against Philippine vessels undertaking resupply missions for troops on features Manila occupies in the South China Sea; <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-completes-mission-disputed-shoal-after-chinese-water-cannon-incident-2023-08-22/">in August</a>, the Philippines delayed a resupply mission by two weeks after its boats were sprayed.翻译:这并不是中国第一次对在菲律宾占领的南海岛礁上执行部队补给任务的菲律宾船只使用高压水枪； <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-completes-mission-disputed-shoal-after-chinese-water-cannon-incident-2023-08-22/">8月</a>，菲律宾因船只遭到喷洒而将补给任务推迟了两周。</p>   <p>The maritime confrontation between the Philippines and China during the weekend comes less than a month after leaders of both nations met on the sidelines of an economic summit in San Francisco to formulate <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-marcos-chinas-xi-discuss-tensions-way-forward-south-china-sea-2023-11-17/">ways forward</a> in the South China Sea.翻译:菲律宾和中国周末发生海上对抗，距离两国领导人在旧金山举行的经济峰会期间会面，制定南海问题<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-marcos-chinas-xi-discuss-tensions-way-forward-south-china-sea-2023-11-17/">的解决方案</a>不到一个月。</p>   <p>"There is a dissonance between what is being said and promised with what's happening in the waters," Foreign Ministry spokesperson Teresita Daza said in the briefing on Monday.翻译:外交部发言人特雷西塔·达扎在周一的简报中表示：“所说的和承诺的与水域中发生的情况不一致。”</p>   <p>Philippine President Ferdinand Marcos Jr. has increasingly complained about China's "aggressive" behaviour, and he has sought closer ties with its treaty ally the United States.翻译:菲律宾总统小费迪南德·马科斯越来越多地抱怨中国的“侵略性”行为，并寻求与其条约盟友美国建立更密切的关系。</p>   <p>China claims sovereignty over nearly the entire South China Sea, pointing to a line on its maps that cuts into the exclusive economic zones of Vietnam, the Philippines, Malaysia, Brunei and Indonesia. Taiwan, which China also claims as part of its territory, has said it does not accept Beijing's maps.翻译:中国声称对几乎整个南海拥有主权，并指出其地图上有一条线切入了越南、菲律宾、马来西亚、文莱和印度尼西亚的专属经济区。中国也声称台湾是其领土的一部分，台湾已表示不接受北京的地图。</p>   <p>The Permanent Court of Arbitration in 2016 said the line on China's maps has no legal basis, a ruling the United States supports, but Beijing rejects.翻译:2016年，常设仲裁法院表示，中国地图上的这条线没有法律依据，美国支持这一裁决，但北京拒绝。</p>   <p>The United States has called out China for interfering in the Philippines' maritime operations and undermining regional stability, and urged Beijing to stop "<a href="https://www.state.gov/u-s-support-for-the-philippines-in-the-south-china-sea-7/" target="_blank">its dangerous and destabilising conduct"</a> in the strategic waters.翻译:美国指责中国干涉菲律宾的海上行动并破坏地区稳定，并敦促北京停止在战略海域“ <a href="https://www.state.gov/u-s-support-for-the-philippines-in-the-south-china-sea-7/" target="_blank">危险和破坏稳定的行为”</a> 。</p>   <p>It reaffirmed its commitment to the mutual defence pact between Washington and Manila, and called for stability after what it called China's "unsafe... operational behaviour," a Pentagon spokesperson said on Monday.翻译:五角大楼发言人周一表示，它重申了对华盛顿和马尼拉之间共同防御协定的承诺，并在称中国“不安全……行动行为”后呼吁稳定。</p>   <p>China's Mao said that the maritime disputes between China and the Philippines were an issue between the two countries and that "no third party has the right to intervene".翻译:中国毛泽东表示，中菲海上争端是两国之间的问题，“任何第三方无权干预”。</p>    <span>Reporting by Neil Jerome Morales and Mikhail Flores, and Liz Lee and Ethan Wang in Beijing; additional reporting by Susan Heavey in Washington; Editing by Kanupriya Kapoor and Gerry Doyle翻译:Neil Jerome Morales 和 Mikhail Flores 以及 Liz Lee 和 Ethan Wang 在北京的报道；苏珊·希维 (Susan Heavey) 在华盛顿的补充报道；卡努普里亚·卡普尔和格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 14:48:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">KSSC3W3NNRJZFOBL7BMPNKR5AA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/chinas-actions-s-china-sea-undermine-regional-stability-us-state-dept-2023-12-11/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Mikhail Flores, Karen Lema]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SOUTHCHINASEA</category>
                
                <category>PHILIPPINES/USA (UPDATE 5, TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[解释者：为什么中国和菲律宾不断为一个小浅滩而争斗]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/pV3lCFppyILWHIIjq3coR9nIRKY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XBHSKTXVTNMXTHN6JEZDIGTLXI.jpg" alt="Philippine Coast Guard flyby over the South China Sea翻译:菲律宾海岸警卫队飞越南海" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An aerial view shows the BRP Sierra Madre on the contested Second Thomas Shoal, locally known as Ayungin, in the South China Sea, March 9, 2023/File Photo翻译:2023 年 3 月 9 日鸟瞰南海有争议的仁爱礁（当地称为阿云金）的 BRP Sierra Madre/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Philippines on Monday described the actions of Chinese vessels against its boats carrying out South China Sea resupply missions over the weekend as a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/chinas-actions-s-china-sea-undermine-regional-stability-us-state-dept-2023-12-11/">"serious escalation".</a>翻译:菲律宾周一称，中国船只周末对其执行南海补给任务的船只采取的行动是<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/chinas-actions-s-china-sea-undermine-regional-stability-us-state-dept-2023-12-11/">“严重升级”。</a></p>   <p>In the latest in a series of confrontations, Manila accused Chinese coast guard and maritime militia vessels of repeatedly firing water cannon at its resupply boats and deliberately ramming another near the Second Thomas Shoal.</p>    <h 1="">HOW BAD HAS IT BECOME?</h>  <p>In recent years , Manila and Beijing have been embroiled in confrontations at the Second Thomas Shoal as China has become more assertive in pressing its maritime claims, alarming rival claimants and other states operating in the South China Sea, including the United States.翻译:近年来，随着中国在提出海洋主张方面变得更加自信，马尼拉和北京在仁爱礁卷入了对抗，这令其他声索国和包括美国在内的在南海活动的其他国家感到震惊。</p>   <p>China claims sovereignty over nearly the entire South China Sea, pointing to a line on its maps that cuts into the exclusive economic zones (EEZ) of Vietnam, the Philippines, Malaysia, Brunei and Indonesia. Taiwan, which China also claims as part of its territory, has said it does not accept Beijing's maps.翻译:中国声称对几乎整个南海拥有主权，并指出其地图上有一条线切入了越南、菲律宾、马来西亚、文莱和印度尼西亚的专属经济区（EEZ）。中国也声称台湾是其领土的一部分，台湾已表示不接受北京的地图。</p>   <p>While this was not the first time that China's coastguard vessels had fired water cannon at Philippine boats, the latest incident caused serious engine damage to one of the resupply vessels that it had to be towed back to the port preventing it from completing it mission.翻译:虽然这并不是中国海警船第一次向菲律宾船只发射高压水枪，但最近的事件导致其中一艘补给船发动机严重损坏，不得不被拖回港口，使其无法完成任务。</p>   <p>The Philippines military chief was onboard another boat which was also fired on by water cannoned and rammed while transporting food and water for Filipino soldiers living aboard the aging navy ship, BRP Sierra Madre.翻译:菲律宾军事首长所在的另一艘船在为居住在老化海军舰艇“BRP Sierra Madre”上的菲律宾士兵运送食物和水时也遭到水炮射击和撞击。</p>   <p>Sierre Madre was deliberately grounded by the Manila on the Second Thomas Shoal in 1999 to assert its sovereign rights over the atoll, that lies within the Philippines' EEZ.翻译:1999年，马尼拉号故意在仁爱礁搁浅，以维护其对位于菲律宾专属经济区内的环礁的主权。</p>   <p>Philippine Chief of Staff of the Armed Forces, General Romeo Brawner, told a radio interview he was unhurt and that he does not believe China knew he was on the boat. But Manila has summoned Beijing's ambassador and filed diplomatic protests over what it called China's "aggressive" actions that were a "threat to peace, good order and security".翻译:菲律宾武装部队参谋长罗密欧·布劳纳将军在接受电台采访时表示，他没有受伤，并且他不相信中国知道他在船上。但马尼拉已召见北京大使，并对中国所谓“对和平、良好秩序和安全构成威胁”的“侵略”行为提出外交抗议。</p>   <p>China's foreign ministry said on Monday it has lodged solemn representations and a strong protest with the Philippine side over the collision it blamed on Manila, which has accused Beijing of spreading false narratives.</p>    <h 1="">WHY IS THIS SIGNIFICANT FOR BOTH SIDES?</h>  <p>China's repeated attempts to blockade the Second Thomas Shoal, located less than 200 nautical miles from Philipines' province of Palawan, has made the submerged reef a flashpoint for conflict between Manila and Beijing.翻译:中国一再试图封锁距离菲律宾巴拉望省不到200海里的仁爱礁，使这片暗礁成为马尼拉和北京之间冲突的导火索。</p>   <p>Philippine officials and security experts fear Beijing is plotting to take over the shoal and militarise it as it did with Mischief Reef, which lies just 25 miles from the shoal.翻译:菲律宾官员和安全专家担心，北京正密谋接管该浅滩并将其军事化，就像对待距该浅滩仅 25 英里的美济礁那样。</p>   <p>"The shoal is a good site for a military base and China has the money to turn it into one," said Jonathan Malaya, a senior official at the Philippines' National Security Council. "That's why they wanted it."翻译:菲律宾国家安全委员会高级官员乔纳森·马拉亚表示：“该浅滩是建立军事基地的好地点，中国有资金将其建成军事基地。” “这就是他们想要它的原因。”</p>   <p>China, which has deployed vessels to patrol there, has repeatedly called on the Philippines to tow away the ship based on what it says was a "promise" made by Manila, but Philippine President Ferdinand Marcos Jr denied such a pact existed. If there ever were such a deal, he was rescinding it, he said.翻译:中国派出船只在那里巡逻，并多次呼吁菲律宾根据马尼拉做出的“承诺”拖走这艘船，但菲律宾总统小费迪南德·马科斯否认存在这样的协议。他说，如果有这样的协议，他就会废除它。</p>   <p>Jay Batongbacal, a Manila-based expert on maritime law, has said Second Thomas Shoal is not only close to the Philippines, but is also close to the sea lines of communication passing through the Palawan passage, making it an ideal extension of Mischief Reef.</p>    <h 1="">WHAT ARE THE RISKS IF THE TREND CONTINUES?</h>  <p>The latest confrontations are likely to further strain relations between the Philippines and Beijing, which have grown tense under Marcos. He has increasingly accused China of aggressive behaviour, while he has sought closer ties with the United States.翻译:最近的对抗可能会使菲律宾和北京之间的关系进一步紧张，两国在马科斯的领导下关系变得紧张。他越来越多地指责中国的侵略行为，同时寻求与美国建立更密切的关系。</p>   <p>But Justin Baquisal, National Security Analyst at FACTS Asia, thinks that would not affect the overall shape of high-level China-Philippines relations, since "a lot of the tit-for-tat on the South China Sea issue only happens at the ground-level."翻译:但FACTS Asia国家安全分析师贾斯汀·巴基萨尔认为，这不会影响中菲高层关系的整体形态，因为“南海问题上的很多针锋相对只发生在地面上” -等级。”</p>   <p>Philippine officials have also said that disputes in the South China Sea were not the sum of the country's relationship with China, which is among the Philippines' top trading partners.翻译:菲律宾官员还表示，南海争端并不是该国与中国关系的总和，中国是菲律宾最大的贸易伙伴之一。</p>   <p>Marcos has also kept the conversations with his Chinese counterpart going, and at the sidelines of an economic summit in San Francisco last month he and President Xi met to formulate <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-marcos-chinas-xi-discuss-tensions-way-forward-south-china-sea-2023-11-17/">ways forward</a> in the South China Sea.翻译:马科斯还与中国外长保持对话，上个月在旧金山举行的经济峰会期间，他与习近平主席会面，制定了南海问题<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-marcos-chinas-xi-discuss-tensions-way-forward-south-china-sea-2023-11-17/">的前进方向</a>。</p>    <span>Writing by Karen Lema and Kay Johnson, Editing by Angus MacSwan翻译:作者：Karen Lema 和 Kay Johnson，编辑：Angus MacSwan</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 13:13:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FOFSA33B7NJ7DCBTLJGPAZ7CK4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/why-china-philippines-keep-fighting-over-tiny-shoal-2023-12-11/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SOUTHCHINASEA</category>
                
                <category>PHILIPPINES/CHINA (EXPLAINER)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[军政府发言人：缅甸军方在中国的帮助下镇压反叛组织]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/bj255dGtsa_whRMMDXe82BfbUWs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YUXTYWCRHJKZPKROV75U46DPEI.jpg" alt="Myanmar's military junta spokesman Zaw Min Tun speaks during the information ministry's press conference in Naypyitaw翻译:缅甸军政府发言人佐敏敦在内比都新闻部新闻发布会上发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Myanmar's military junta spokesman Zaw Min Tun speaks during the information ministry's press conference in Naypyitaw翻译:缅甸军政府发言人佐敏敦在内比都新闻部新闻发布会上发表讲话, Myanmar, March 23, 2021. REUTERS/Stringer/File Photo翻译:缅甸军政府发言人 Zaw Min Tun 于 2021 年 3 月 23 日在缅甸内比都举行的信息部新闻发布会上发表讲话。 REUTERS/Stringer/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/G51-952fLuaPgzFibOO8k0JFqdI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PQ55UQBKF5IVJHSPFN6CVA3VMQ.jpg" alt="Volunteer members of Karenni insurgent forces walk in Moe Bye in Kayah State翻译:克伦尼叛乱部队志愿者在克耶邦莫拜耶行走" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Volunteer members of Karenni insurgent forces walk in Moe Bye in Kayah State翻译:克伦尼叛乱部队志愿者在克耶邦莫拜耶行走, Myanmar November 12, 2023. REUTERS/Stringer/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 12 日，克伦尼叛乱部队志愿者在缅甸克耶邦 Moe Bye 行走。 REUTERS/Stringer/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>Representatives from Myanmar's ruling military have held talks, facilitated by China, with three armed rebel groups leading an anti-junta offensive, state media reported a junta spokesperson as saying on Monday.翻译:据官方媒体报道，军政府发言人周一表示，在中国的推动下，缅甸执政军队的代表已与领导反军政府攻势的三个武装叛乱组织举行了会谈。</p>   <p>Myanmar's military is battling armed opponents on several fronts, in the fiercest <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/losing-ground-rebel-alliance-myanmar-junta-faces-biggest-test-since-coup-2023-11-10/">challenge</a> to its grip on the Southeast Asian country since it seized power from an elected government in a 2021 coup.翻译:缅甸军方正在多条战线上与武装反对派作战，这是自 2021 年政变中从民选政府手中夺取政权以来，对其对这个东南亚国家控制力的最激烈<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/losing-ground-rebel-alliance-myanmar-junta-faces-biggest-test-since-coup-2023-11-10/">挑战</a>。</p>   <p>Rebel groups aligned with a pro-democracy parallel government launched a <a href="https://tmsnrt.rs/49BGAJW" target="_blank">coordinated offensive</a> in late October, taking control of several military posts and towns near the border with China in the north and in western states.翻译:与支持民主的平行政府结盟的反叛组织于10月下旬发起了<a href="https://tmsnrt.rs/49BGAJW" target="_blank">协调一致的攻势</a>，控制了北部和西部各州与中国接壤的多个军事哨所和城镇。</p>   <p>"Myanmar's National Unity and Peacemaking Coordination Committee met with representatives of MNDAA, TNLA and AA with the help of China," said Zaw Min Tun, according to MRTV's Telegram channel, referring to the armed ethnic groups spearheading the offensive.翻译:据 MRTV 的 Telegram 频道报道，佐敏吞 (Zaw Min Tun) 表示：“在中国的帮助下，缅甸民族团结与和平协调委员会会见了民族民主同盟军、德军和若开军的代表。”他指的是带头攻势的武装少数民族团体。</p>   <p>"Based on the development of the conversation, there will likely be another meeting at the end of this month."翻译:“根据对话的进展，本月底可能会再次举行会议。”</p>   <p>It was unclear when or where the meeting took place and Zaw Min Tun did not elaborate on what was discussed.翻译:目前尚不清楚会议何时何地举行，Zaw Min Tun 也没有详细说明讨论的内容。</p>   <p>Representatives of the three rebel groups did not immediately respond to Reuters' request for comment. Chinese officials could not immediately be reached for comment.翻译:三个反叛组织的代表没有立即回应路透社的置评请求。未能立即联系到中国官员置评。</p>   <p>The statement comes as fighting continues across two-thirds of the country, killing more than 360 civilians and displacing more than half a million, according to the United Nations.翻译:据联合国称，该声明发表之际，该国三分之二地区的战斗仍在继续，造成 360 多名平民死亡，超过 50 万人流离失所。</p>    <span>Reporting by Reuters staff; Writing by Kanupriya Kapoor; Editing by Alison Williams翻译:路透社工作人员的报道；卡努普里亚·卡普尔 (Kanupriya Kapoor) 撰写；艾莉森·威廉姆斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 12:40:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">VTKI2TMWTNL7NB4TF72CP5WKYU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/myanmar-military-meets-rebel-groups-with-chinas-help-junta-spokesperson-2023-12-11/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>MYANMAR</category>
                
                <category>VIOLENCE/MEETING (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2023年，大胆的电动汽车战略遭遇现实打击]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/mDz5AprJU_6DJN7pVOcLO_-ApaY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7HIPT5WFZFPK3IZLW3C2ZDUOZ4.jpg" alt="An Audi electric vehicle is being charged in a charging station in Drogenbos翻译:一辆奥迪电动汽车正在德罗亨博斯的充电站充电" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An Audi electric vehicle is being charged in a charging station in Drogenbos翻译:一辆奥迪电动汽车正在德罗亨博斯的充电站充电, Belgium November 25, 2023. REUTERS/Yves Herman/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 25 日，一辆奥迪电动汽车正在比利时德罗亨博斯的充电站充电。路透社/Yves Herman/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/AuTBI86vXt5w4Bt6I2EMgboib2A=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2JFVZZFCNRIXVJHODWKYQLXGVQ.jpg" alt="Volkswagen premieres new ID.7 electric sedan, ahead of the Shanghai Auto Show翻译:大众汽车在上海车展前夕推出新款 ID.7 电动轿车" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Volkswagen electric vehicle is debuted at an event ahead of the Shanghai Auto Show, in Shanghai, China April 17, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:大众电动汽车于 2023 年 4 月 17 日在中国上海举行的上海车展前夕的一次活动中首次亮相。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/jxgZptb12oG1H5ENm1tZ6A0ljFE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2EUD57ZY65NTHJBZROS2YNQ534.jpg" alt="A Ford Mustang Mach-e electric vehicle is seen plugged into a charging station in Bilbao翻译:一辆福特野马 Mach-e 电动汽车被插入毕尔巴鄂的充电站" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Ford Mustang Mach-e electric vehicle is seen plugged into a charging station in Bilbao翻译:一辆福特野马 Mach-e 电动汽车被插入毕尔巴鄂的充电站, northern Spain, November 10, 2023. REUTERS/Vincent West/File Photo</figcaption></figure>                 <p>This was the year the auto industry's race toward an all-electric future took a detour.翻译:今年，汽车行业迈向全电动未来的竞赛出现了弯路。</p>   <p>Heading into 2023, automakers were gearing up to invest $1.2 trillion by 2030 to move electric vehicles from niche products to mass-market models - many with batteries and software developed in-house, according to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/exclusive-automakers-double-spending-evs-batteries-12-trillion-by-2030-2022-10-21/">a Reuters analysis</a>.翻译:据<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/exclusive-automakers-double-spending-evs-batteries-12-trillion-by-2030-2022-10-21/">路透社分析</a>，进入 2023 年，汽车制造商准备在 2030 年之前投资 1.2 万亿美元，将电动汽车从小众产品转向大众市场车型，其中许多车型配备内部开发的电池和软件。</p>   <p>As the year closes, legacy automakers as well as Tesla <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a>, Rivian <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RIVN.O" target="_blank">(RIVN.O)</a> and other EV startups are throttling back investments and reworking product strategies. Legacy automakers are appealing to policymakers for more help to offset the high costs of the EV transition, on top of billions of dollars already pumped into EV subsidies.翻译:随着年底，传统汽车制造商以及特斯拉<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a> 、Rivian <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RIVN.O" target="_blank">(RIVN.O)</a>和其他电动汽车初创公司都在缩减投资并重新制定产品战略。除了已经投入电动汽车补贴的数十亿美元之外，传统汽车制造商还呼吁政策制定者提供更多帮助，以抵消电动汽车转型的高昂成本。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/global-ev-sales-stay-strong-china-hits-record-despite-end-subsidies-2023-11-14/">Consumer demand for EVs</a> is growing worldwide. But EV adoption is not happening as fast or as profitably as industry executives anticipated, especially in the United States.翻译:全球<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/global-ev-sales-stay-strong-china-hits-record-despite-end-subsidies-2023-11-14/">消费者对电动汽车的需求</a>正在增长。但电动汽车的采用并没有像行业高管预期的那么快或盈利，尤其是在美国。</p>   <p>High interest rates have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/electric-car-demand-set-stall-europes-valley-death-2023-11-13/">pushed many EVs out of reach</a> for middle-income consumers. Lack of charging infrastructure is a deal-breaker for buyers used to adding hundreds of miles of gasoline driving range in just a few minutes.翻译:高利率使中等收入消费者<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/electric-car-demand-set-stall-europes-valley-death-2023-11-13/">无法购买许多电动汽车</a>。对于习惯在短短几分钟内增加数百英里汽油行驶里程的买家来说，缺乏充电基础设施是一个大问题。</p>   <p>"EVs are going to be the future of the passenger automobile business," said Jeff Parent, COO of AutoNation <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AN.N" target="_blank">(AN.N)</a>, the U.S. auto dealership chain. But because of consumer concerns about price and charging, he said, "the next three to four years, things are going to be bumpy."翻译:美国汽车经销商连锁店 AutoNation <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AN.N" target="_blank">(AN.N)</a>首席运营官杰夫·帕伦特 (Jeff Parent) 表示：“电动汽车将成为乘用车行业的未来。”但由于消费者对价格和收费的担忧，他表示，“未来三到四年，事情将会变得崎岖不平。”</p>   <p>Industry CEOs are amplifying hedges on their goals of shifting to all-electric fleets by the middle of the next decade.翻译:行业首席执行官们正在加大对在下一个十年中期转向全电动车队的目标的对冲力度。</p>   <p>"We’ll adjust to where the customer is," General Motors <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GM.N" target="_blank">(GM.N)</a> CEO Mary Barra told the Detroit Automotive Press Association earlier this month when asked if GM still aims to be all-electric by 2035.翻译:本月早些时候，当被问及通用汽车是否仍计划到 2035 年实现全电动化时，通用汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GM.N" target="_blank">(GM.N)</a>首席执行官玛丽·巴拉 (Mary Barra) 向底特律汽车新闻协会表示：“我们将根据客户的情况进行调整。”</p>   <p>THE F-150 LIGHTNING: HIGH HOPES, THEN DISAPPOINTMENT翻译:F-150 闪电：满怀希望，然后失望</p>   <p>Ford's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/F.N" target="_blank">(F.N)</a> F-150 Lightning electric truck shows how bullish forecasts got corralled.翻译:福特<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/F.N" target="_blank">(FN)</a>的 F-150 Lightning 电动卡车展示了乐观的预测是如何被整合起来的。</p>   <p>Buoyed by enthusiastic early demand for the Lightning, Ford in August added a third work crew at its historic Rouge assembly complex in Dearborn, Michigan, to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/ford-revs-up-electric-truck-output-testing-mainstream-ev-demand-2023-08-01/">triple the production rate</a> of the electric pickup truck to 150,000 vehicles a year.翻译:受到早期对 Lightning 的热烈需求的推动，福特于 8 月在其位于密歇根州迪尔伯恩历史悠久的 Rouge 装配厂增加了第三个工作人员，将电动皮卡车的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/ford-revs-up-electric-truck-output-testing-mainstream-ev-demand-2023-08-01/">生产率提高了两倍，</a>达到每年 15 万辆。</p>   <p>But in October, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/ford-temporarily-cut-one-shift-michigan-ev-plant-2023-10-13/">Ford cancelled the third shift</a>, conceding that demand for electric F-150s was not enough to sustain the planned production pace. About 700 workers were furloughed.翻译:但 10 月份， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/ford-temporarily-cut-one-shift-michigan-ev-plant-2023-10-13/">福特取消了第三班</a>，承认对电动 F-150 的需求不足以维持计划的生产速度。大约700名工人被迫休假。</p>   <p>In China, Europe and the United States - the main EV markets - electric-vehicle demand is still growing faster than demand for vehicles overall.翻译:在中国、欧洲和美国这些主要电动汽车市场，电动汽车需求的增长速度仍然快于汽车整体需求的增长速度。</p>   <p>Global EV production is on track to triple by 2030 to 33.4 million vehicles, about a third of total production, according to AutoForecast Solutions. Much of that growth will happen in China, where government subsidies and a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/teslas-china-made-ev-sales-fall-178-nov-biggest-drop-since-dec-2022-2023-12-04/">price war</a> led by Chinese EV market leader BYD <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002594.SZ" target="_blank">(002594.SZ)</a> and Tesla are making EVs more affordable than combustion vehicles, according to an analysis by JATO Dynamics.翻译:据 AutoForecast Solutions 称，到 2030 年，全球电动汽车产量有望增加两倍，达到 3340 万辆，约占总产量的三分之一。 JATO Dynamics 的分析显示，其中大部分增长将发生在中国，政府补贴以及中国电动汽车市场领导者比亚迪<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002594.SZ" target="_blank">（002594.SZ）</a>和特斯拉主导的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/teslas-china-made-ev-sales-fall-178-nov-biggest-drop-since-dec-2022-2023-12-04/">价格战</a>使电动汽车比燃油汽车更便宜。</p>   <p>In North America, production of battery-electric vehicles could increase sixfold to nearly 7 million vehicles by 2030, according to AFS. That is equivalent to roughly 40% of the projected U.S. market - but well short of the Biden administration's goals.</p>    <h 1="">LOBBYING FOR RELIEF</h>  <p>Industry executives are <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/automakers-warn-biden-vehicle-rules-not-feasible-could-cost-14-bln-fines-2023-09-29/">lobbying the Biden administration</a> to back away from emissions rules that effectively require EVs to account for two-thirds of U.S. new-vehicle sales by 2032.翻译:行业高管正在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/automakers-warn-biden-vehicle-rules-not-feasible-could-cost-14-bln-fines-2023-09-29/">游说拜登政府</a>放弃排放规定，该规定实际上要求到 2032 年电动汽车占美国新车销量的三分之二。</p>   <p>Looking ahead, industry executives raise two concerns about the challenge of expanding the EV market beyond adventurous early adopters of technology: Affordability and access to charging.翻译:展望未来，行业高管对将电动汽车市场扩展到敢于冒险的技术早期采用者之外的挑战提出了两个担忧：负担能力和充电机会。</p>   <p>The slow pace of charging infrastructure development forced major legacy automakers to cut deals this year with Tesla to allow buyers of their EVs to use Tesla's Supercharger network - a competitive coup for Tesla.翻译:充电基础设施发展缓慢，迫使主要传统汽车制造商今年与特斯拉达成协议，允许其电动汽车购买者使用特斯拉的超级充电网络——这对特斯拉来说是一个有竞争力的妙招。</p>   <p>"The automakers' capitulation to the (Tesla) standard is a clear signal that they are realizing that demand is held back by fears on charging," said Mark Wakefield, co-leader of consultancy AlixPartners' automotive practice.翻译:咨询公司 AlixPartners 汽车业务联合负责人马克·韦克菲尔德 (Mark Wakefield) 表示：“汽车制造商对特斯拉标准的屈服是一个明确的信号，表明他们意识到需求因对充电的担忧而受到抑制。”</p>   <p>"Affordability" is industry code for convincing mainstream, middle-income consumers to pay enough for an EV to cover higher production costs and still yield a profit. For most legacy automakers, that has so far proven impossible.翻译:“可负担性”是说服主流中等收入消费者支付足够的价格购买电动汽车的行业代码，以覆盖更高的生产成本并仍然产生利润。对于大多数传统汽车制造商来说，迄今为止这被证明是不可能的。</p>   <p>Even Tesla, which makes money on EVs, has been forced to cut prices to keep assembly lines running at full speed in China and the United States.翻译:即使是靠电动汽车赚钱的特斯拉也被迫降价，以保持中国和美国装配线的全速运转。</p>   <p>"If our car cost the same as a (Toyota <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/7203.T" target="_blank">(7203.T)</a>) RAV4, no one would buy a RAV4, or, at least, they would be very unlikely to," Tesla CEO <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/elon-musk-interest-rates-uncertainty-teslas-costs-2023-10-19/">Elon Musk told analysts</a> in October. “Our car is still much more expensive than a RAV4."翻译:“如果我们的汽车成本与（丰田<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/7203.T" target="_blank">（7203.T）</a> ）RAV4 相同，那么没有人会购买 RAV4，或者至少他们不太可能购买，”特斯拉首席执行官<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/elon-musk-interest-rates-uncertainty-teslas-costs-2023-10-19/">埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 10 月份对分析师表示</a>。 “我们的车还是比 RAV4 贵很多。”</p>   <p>RAV4 models start at $28,475. Model Y's start at $43,990, and until Dec. 31 come with $7,500 tax credits. Tesla has warned those credits could be reduced as tougher domestic content rules kick in.翻译:RAV4 车型起价为 28,475 美元。 Model Y 起价为 43,990 美元，12 月 31 日之前可享受 7,500 美元的税收抵免。特斯拉警告称，随着更严格的国内含量规则的实施，这些积分可能会减少。</p>    <span>Reporting by Joe White in Detroit
Editing by Matthew Lewis翻译:乔·怀特在底特律的报道 马修·刘易斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 11:22:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2Z4YNQOGTVOWBDBPDEZ42FJGHE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/2023-bold-ev-strategies-took-punch-reality-2023-12-11/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Joseph White]]></author>
            
                
                <category>YEAR</category>
                
                <category>END/AUTOS</category>
                
                <category>ELECTRIC (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[选举临近，台湾再次报道中国航母战斗群在台湾海峡]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/M3snZk1qXIt8lKu3Wt2vtHrBazQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VOZGH2M4RRPWPMOQKAM3BOZWOE.jpg" alt="Chinese aircraft carrier Shandong sails in Pacific Ocean waters, south of Okinawa prefecture, Japan翻译:中国航母山东号在日本冲绳县以南太平洋海域航行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese aircraft carrier Shandong sails in Pacific Ocean waters, about 300 kms (186 miles) south of Okinawa prefecture, Japan, in this handout image taken by Japan Self-Defence Force on April 5, 2023 and released by the Joint Staff Office of the Defense Ministry of Japan April 6, 2023. Joint Staff Office of the Defense Ministry of Japan/HANDOUT via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:在这张由日本自卫队于 2023 年 4 月 5 日拍摄、防卫联合参谋部发布的宣传图片中，中国航母山东号在日本冲绳县以南约 300 公里（186 英里）的太平洋水域航行日本防卫省，2023 年 4 月 6 日。日本防卫省联合参谋部/路透社的资料/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Taiwan's military sent forces to watch a Chinese naval formation, led by the aircraft carrier Shandong, sailing through the Taiwan Strait on Monday, Taiwan's defence ministry said, as Beijing keeps up pressure ahead of elections next month.翻译:台湾国防部表示，台湾军方周一派出部队观看由山东号航空母舰率领的中国海军编队穿越台湾海峡，北京方面在下个月的选举前继续施压。</p>   <p>The Shandong, commissioned in 2019, last transited the sensitive strait in early November. The latest sailing comes about one month before presidential and parliamentary elections on the island.翻译:山东舰于 2019 年投入使用，最后一次穿越敏感海峡是在 11 月初。最近一次航行大约是在该岛总统和议会选举前一个月。</p>   <p>The ministry said in a statement that the formation sailed south through the strait but kept to the western side of the waterway's median line - the Chinese side of the unofficial barrier between the two.翻译:该部在一份声明中表示，编队向南航行穿过海峡，但保持在水道中线的西侧，即两者之间的非官方屏障的中国一侧。</p>   <p>China says the Taiwan Strait is not an international waterway and that it alone has sovereignty there, which both Taiwan and the United States dispute.翻译:中国表示，台湾海峡不是国际水道，只有中国拥有该海峡的主权，台湾和美国对此都存在争议。</p>   <p>Taiwan dispatched "appropriate" forces to keep watch on the formation, the ministry added, without elaborating.翻译:国防部补充说，台湾派出了“适当”的部队来监视编队，但没有详细说明。</p>   <p>"The security and prosperity of the Indo-Pacific region are closely related to global development and stability, and are obligations and responsibilities that all parties in the region must share," the ministry said.翻译:印太地区的安全与繁荣与全球发展与稳定密切相关，是地区各方必须共同承担的义务和责任。</p>   <p>Taiwan's military will "prepare for war without seeking war", strengthen its self-defence capabilities, and respond to regional threats, it added.翻译:台湾军队将“备战而不求战”，加强自卫能力，应对地区威胁。</p>   <p>China's defence ministry did not immediately respond to a request for comment.翻译:中国国防部没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>During the past four years Taiwan has repeatedly complained of stepped-up Chinese military activity nearby, including fighters and drones crossing the strait's median line.翻译:过去四年来，台湾多次抱怨中国在附近加强军事活动，包括战斗机和无人机越过海峡中线。</p>   <p>Last week, Taiwan reported a rare <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-spots-chinese-balloon-strait-month-before-election-2023-12-08/">night mission</a> by China's air force over the strait.翻译:上周，台湾报道称中国空军在海峡上空执行了一次罕见的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-spots-chinese-balloon-strait-month-before-election-2023-12-08/">夜间任务</a>。</p>   <p>Taiwan is on high alert for Chinese activities, both military and political, ahead of its election, especially what Taipei views as Beijing's efforts to interfere in the ballot to get electors to vote for candidates China may prefer.翻译:台湾在选举前对中国的军事和政治活动保持高度警惕，特别是台北认为北京试图干预投票，让选民投票给中国可能更喜欢的候选人。</p>   <p>Vice President Lai Ching-te and running mate Hsiao Bi-khim from the ruling Democratic Progressive Party are leading in the polls. China views them as separatists and has rebuffed Lai's offers of talks.翻译:执政党民进党的副总统赖清德和竞选伙伴萧美琴在民调中领先。中国将他们视为分裂分子，并拒绝了赖清德的会谈提议。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ben Blanchard; Editing by Edmund Klamann and Gerry Doyle翻译:本·布兰查德报道；埃德蒙·克拉曼和格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 09:53:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FLCZQ3Z7TNKAJNDHF6OGRZKEGM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-again-reports-chinese-carrier-group-taiwan-strait-election-looms-2023-12-11/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>TAIWAN</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/DEFENCE (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国称90%以上新能源汽车继续享受税收优惠]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/P1YUB1J5wccero84WrzZ3eYppfU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2GELMU4GJBMMVMJJSERORBJH5M.jpg" alt="Staff member hooks up a charging cable to EV at a charging station in Liuzhou翻译:工作人员在柳州充电站为电动汽车连接充电电缆" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A staff member hooks up a charging cable to an electric vehicle (EV) at a charging station in Liuzhou, Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, China July 31, 2017. REUTERS/Stringer/File Photo翻译:2017 年 7 月 31 日，中国广西壮族自治区柳州的充电站，一名工作人员正在为电动汽车 (EV) 连接充电电缆。 REUTERS/Stringer/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>More than 90% of China's existing new energy vehicle (NEV) models will continue to receive tax breaks on purchases, under new technical requirements unveiled on Monday, China's industry ministry said.翻译:中国工信部表示，根据周一公布的新技术要求，中国现有 90% 以上的新能源汽车 (NEV) 车型将继续享受购置税减免。</p>   <p>The technical requirements for NEV eligibility for purchase tax exemptions from 2024 state that pure electric cars should have a driving range of at least 200 kilometres per charge while plug-in hybrid cars should be able to run at least 43 kilometres on electricity, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology said in a statement.翻译:工信部发布的《2024年起新能源汽车免征购置税资格技术要求》规定，纯电动汽车一次充电续驶里程不少于200公里，插电式混合动力汽车一次充电续驶里程不少于43公里。工业和信息化部在一份声明中表示。</p>   <p>The new regulations require a range attenuation rate of no higher than 35% under low temperatures for electric vehicles (EVs), and allows EVs capable of battery swapping to be eligible for the tax breaks.翻译:新规定要求电动汽车在低温下的续航里程衰减率不高于35%，并允许可更换电池的电动汽车享受税收减免。</p>   <p>In June, China unveiled a 520 billion yuan ($72.41 billion)package of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-announces-extension-purchase-tax-break-nevs-until-2027-2023-06-21/">tax breaks</a> over four years for EVs and other green cars, its biggest yet for the industry as it seeks to boost auto sales growth.翻译:6月，中国推出了四年内针对电动汽车和其他绿色汽车的5200亿元人民币（724.1亿美元）的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-announces-extension-purchase-tax-break-nevs-until-2027-2023-06-21/">税收减免</a>计划，这是该行业迄今为止最大的税收减免计划，旨在促进汽车销售增长。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1817 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.1817 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Qiaoyi Li, Zhang Yan and Brenda Goh; Editing by Edmund Klamann翻译:李巧仪、张岩、Brenda Goh 报道；编辑：埃德蒙·克拉曼</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 08:23:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TVQV3KCHHBOELF7I3CLRTDZAF4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/china-says-tax-breaks-stay-over-90-new-energy-vehicles-2023-12-11/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AUTOS/NEV (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[习近平访问期间，中国向越南提供铁路援助，推动数字丝绸之路]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/9WhAnNsRhA8vqMorreV7OaneoKo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MSURVCXYBFIATI6OGHPLJ2ULSY.jpg" alt="Journalists watch a giant screen broadcasting footage of Chinese President Xi Jinping at the opening ceremony of BRF in Beijing翻译:记者在北京举行的高峰论坛开幕式上观看大屏幕播放中国国家主席习近平的镜头" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Journalists watch a giant screen broadcasting footage of Chinese President Xi Jinping speaking at the opening ceremony of the Third Belt and Road Forum (BRF), at the media centre in Beijing, October 18, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/FILE PHOTO翻译:2023 年 10 月 18 日，北京媒体中心，记者们观看中国国家主席习近平在第三届“一带一路”论坛开幕式上讲话的大屏幕。 REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/FILE PHOTO</figcaption></figure>       <p>China and Vietnam are set to agree this week on upgraded rail links and other infrastructure, possibly including digital projects, officials said, in moves that would bring Hanoi closer to Beijing as great powers jostle for influence in Vietnam.翻译:官员们表示，中国和越南将于本周就升级铁路和其他基础设施（可能包括数字项目）达成一致，此举将使河内与北京更加接近，因为大国都在争夺对越南的影响力。</p>   <p>The announcements are expected during President Xi Jinping's visit to Hanoi from Tuesday, the first in six years to the Southeast Asian neighbour, and shortly after U.S. President Joe Biden travelled to the Vietnamese capital in September to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-vietnam-elevate-ties-during-biden-visit-with-eye-china-2023-09-09/">strengthen</a> bilateral ties.翻译:预计这些消息将在习近平主席周二访问河内期间宣布，这是六年来首次访问这个东南亚邻国，也是在美国总统乔·拜登于 9 月访问越南首都以<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-vietnam-elevate-ties-during-biden-visit-with-eye-china-2023-09-09/">加强</a>双边关系后不久。</p>   <p>China is ready to offer grants to Vietnam to boost the railway between Kunming and the Vietnamese port city of Haiphong, and other transport links from southern China to Hanoi, Vietnamese state paper Tuoi Tre reported, citing the Chinese ambassador to Vietnam Xiong Bo.翻译:越南官方报纸《Tuoi Tre》援引中国驻越南大使熊波的话说，中国准备向越南提供赠款，以加强昆明和越南港口城市海防之间的铁路建设，以及从中国南部到河内的其他交通联系。</p>   <p>He said China was ready to provide "non-refundable aid" for these projects, the paper reported late on Sunday, in an offer that, if confirmed, would represent a major concession to a country that is traditionally loath of taking loans.翻译:该报周日晚间报道称，他表示中国已准备好为这些项目提供“不可退还的援助”，这一提议如果得到确认，将是对一个传统上不愿接受贷款的国家的重大让步。</p>   <p>It is however unclear whether grants would come with loans and the share of both.翻译:然而，尚不清楚赠款是否会与贷款一起提供以及两者的份额。</p>   <p>A sizeable offer of grants could also be perceived as a blow to the United States and other Western backers of infrastructure projects in Vietnam, who under a climate plan <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/g7-offers-costly-loans-few-grants-help-vietnam-cut-coal-documents-2023-10-30/">have offered</a> mostly loans at market values to help Vietnam reduce its coal use.翻译:提供大量赠款也可能被视为对美国和越南基础设施项目的其他西方支持者的打击，根据气候计划，这些国家主要以市场价值<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/g7-offers-costly-loans-few-grants-help-vietnam-cut-coal-documents-2023-10-30/">提供</a>贷款，以帮助越南减少煤炭使用。</p>   <p>The Kunming-Haiphong rail upgrade plan, which Reuters first <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-vietnam-consider-rail-link-through-rare-earths-heartland-2023-12-01/">reported</a> earlier in December, passes through the region where Vietnam has its biggest rare earths mines, which it has so far been unable to exploit because of a lack of processing technology.翻译:路透社12月初首次<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-vietnam-consider-rail-link-through-rare-earths-heartland-2023-12-01/">报道的</a>昆明至海防铁路升级计划经过越南拥有最大稀土矿的地区，但由于缺乏加工技术，越南迄今为止无法开采该矿。</p>   <p>Vietnam is estimated to hold the world's second largest deposits of the strategic minerals which are at the moment crucial for electric vehicles and wind turbines.翻译:据估计，越南拥有世界第二大战略矿产资源，目前对电动汽车和风力涡轮机至关重要。</p>   <p>China is by far the world's biggest producer and refiner of rare earths, but is unclear what deal could be reached on that, as Beijing is usually reluctant to share its refining technology and Hanoi largely prevents export of unprocessed rare earths.翻译:中国是迄今为止世界上最大的稀土生产国和精炼国，但尚不清楚能否就此达成什么协议，因为北京通常不愿分享其精炼技术，而河内则在很大程度上阻止未加工稀土的出口。</p>   <p>Vietnam's foreign affairs ministry did not reply on Monday to a request for comment about the possible grants, but Prime Minister Pham Minh Chinh in November supported the upgrade of the Kunming-Haiphong rail.</p>    <h 1="">DIGITAL SILK ROAD</h>  <p>China's ambassador also mentioned digital interconnections among the priorities to strengthen cooperation between the two countries, which are already enjoying <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/chinas-investments-vietnam-boom-xi-visits-hanoi-us-spending-down-2023-12-08/">booming economic exchanges</a>.翻译:中国大使还提到，数字互联是两国加强合作的优先事项之一，两国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/chinas-investments-vietnam-boom-xi-visits-hanoi-us-spending-down-2023-12-08/">经济交流已经蓬勃发展</a>。</p>   <p>"Both of our countries need to enhance interconnections on land, sea, air and on the internet," Xiong Bo was reported saying.翻译:据报道，熊波表示：“我们两国都需要加强陆地、海洋、空中和互联网上的互联互通。”</p>   <p>Diplomats, officials and Vietnamese experts said digital interconnections meant including Vietnam in Chinese plans for a Digital Silk Road, Beijing's flagship programme under the wider Belt and Road Initiative focussed on optical fibre cables, data centres and other telecoms infrastructure in friendly countries.翻译:外交官、官员和越南专家表示，数字互联意味着将越南纳入中国的数字丝绸之路计划，这是北京在更广泛的“一带一路”倡议下的旗舰计划，重点关注友好国家的光纤电缆、数据中心和其他电信基础设施。</p>   <p>Additional submarine cables could be part of the discussion, one diplomat said, as Vietnam has experienced disruptions this year in its undersea digital infrastructure. Vietnam also plans to build a fully-fledged 5G network, an infrastructure in which China's telecom giant Huawei excels.翻译:一位外交官表示，由于越南今年的海底数字基础设施出现中断，因此可能会讨论增加海底电缆。越南还计划建设成熟的5G网络，这是中国电信巨头华为擅长的基础设施。</p>   <p>Vietnam's foreign ministry did not comment on Monday but President Vo Van Thuong at the Belt and Road forum in China in October urged to boost cooperation on digital infrastructure.翻译:越南外交部周一没有发表评论，但越南国家主席武文上在 10 月份中国“一带一路”论坛上敦促加强数字基础设施合作。</p>   <p>It is however unclear whether Vietnam is only paying lip service to that, as national security concerns tend to prevail on strategic projects, said Le Hong Hiep, a senior fellow at Singapore's Iseas–Yusof Ishak Institute, especially in the South China Sea, where Hanoi and Beijing disagree over borders.翻译:然而，新加坡尤索夫伊萨研究所高级研究员 Le Hong Hiep 表示，目前还不清楚越南是否只是口头上说说而已，因为国家安全问题往往在战略项目上占主导地位，特别是在南中国海，河内和北京在边界问题上存在分歧。</p>    <span>Reporting by Francesco Guarascio and Khanh Vu; Editing by Michael Perry翻译:Francesco Guarascio 和 Khanh Vu 的报道；迈克尔·佩里编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 04:48:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">KSZ2R55J6JLAXIXS5ML6H73YB4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/xi-visits-china-offers-rail-grants-vietnam-pushes-digital-silk-road-2023-12-11/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Francesco Guarascio, Khanh Vu]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>VIETNAM/ (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[香港“只有爱国者”选举表现平平，投票率创历史新低]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Wo_NylOP1_U595iUn6OtLBNzELU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/EDR76FG6PRJOVBRR4V6YYBJBDI.jpg" alt="A volunteer campaigns for the New People's Party during the District Council election&nbsp;in Hong Kong翻译:一名志愿者在香港区议会选举期间为新民党竞选" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A volunteer campaigns for the New People's Party during the District Council election&nbsp;in Hong Kong翻译:一名志愿者在香港区议会选举期间为新民党竞选, China, December 10, 2023. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu翻译:2023 年 12 月 10 日，中国香港区议会选举期间，一名志愿者为新民党竞选。REUTERS/Tyrone Siu</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/AobTixCJj8Tike_qvhj0ieurXew=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/436GILCNYBK43LAI6W7ZK7EXWE.jpg" alt="Posters encouraging people to vote in the District Council Election are seen at a polling station in Hong Kong翻译:香港一投票站张贴海报鼓励民众参与区议会选举投票" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Posters encouraging people to vote in the District Council Election are seen at a polling station in Hong Kong翻译:香港一投票站张贴海报鼓励民众参与区议会选举投票, China, December 10, 2023. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu翻译:2023 年 12 月 10 日，中国香港的一个投票站张贴鼓励人们在区议会选举中投票的海报。REUTERS/Tyrone Siu</figcaption></figure>               <p>A "patriots only" district election in Hong Kong that barred opposition democrats from the ballot sheet amid a national security squeeze had a record low voter turnout of 27.5% as many voters spurned what was seen as an undemocratic poll.翻译:在国家安全压力下，香港举行的“仅限爱国者”区选举禁止反对派民主党人参与投票，投票率创历史新低，仅为 27.5%，因为许多选民拒绝接受被视为不民主的民意调查。</p>   <p>The sharp slide in turnout since the last such election in 2019 comes after Beijing imposed a sweeping national security law that has been used to clamp down on dissent, and overhauled the electoral system to shut out democrats and other liberals.翻译:自2019年上次此类选举以来，投票率大幅下滑，此前北京实施了一项全面的国家安全法，该法用于压制异见，并彻底改革了选举制度以将民主党人和其他自由派人士拒之门外。</p>   <p>"It can be seen that everyone has begun to feel that the election has no meaning," said Lemon Wong, one of the few remaining democrats still involved in local politics.翻译:“可以看出，每个人都开始觉得选举没有意义，”仅存的少数仍参与当地政治的民主党人之一莱蒙·黄(Lemon Wong)说。</p>   <p>"Even pro-establishment supporters are asking themselves why they need to vote because it's all the same."翻译:“即使是建制派的支持者也在问自己为什么需要投票，因为都是一样的。”</p>   <p>The previous lowest turnout was 35.8% in 1999. Four years ago at the last such election during Hong Kong's mass pro-democracy protests, a record 71% turnout brought about a landslide victory for the democratic camp in a fiercely contested poll.翻译:此前的最低投票率是1999年的35.8%。四年前，在香港大规模民主抗议期间的最后一次此类选举中，创纪录的71%投票率在一场激烈的民意调查中为民主阵营带来了压倒性胜利。</p>   <p>For this election, directly elected seats were slashed by nearly 80%, while all candidates were required to undergo national security background checks and secure nominations from two pro-government committees.翻译:这次选举，直选席位被削减近80%，所有候选人都必须接受国家安全背景调查，并获得两个亲政府委员会的提名。</p>   <p>At least three pro-democracy and non pro-establishment groups, including moderates, and even some pro-Beijing figures failed to meet those thresholds.翻译:至少三个亲民主和非建制派团体，包括温和派，甚至一些亲北京人士未能达到这些门槛。</p>   <p>An unprecedented electronic poll register system failure caused some disruptions and an eventual switch to a manual system, with polling times extended by 90 minutes till midnight.翻译:前所未有的电子投票登记系统故障造成了一些干扰，最终切换到手动系统，投票时间延长了 90 分钟，直到午夜。</p>   <p>The electoral commission said the extension wasn't linked at all to the turnout rate.翻译:选举委员会表示，延期与投票率完全无关。</p>   <p>Security was tight, with over ten thousand police deployed. At least six people were arrested for alleged offences including posting online for people to cast invalid ballots, or to incite others to disrupt the polls, according to statements from the police and the city's anti-corruption authority.</p>    <h 1="">"BIRDCAGE" ELECTION</h>  <p>Three members of the "League of Social Democrats" were among those followed and arrested just before they planned to protest against what they described as a "birdcage election" and a "big leap backwards" for electoral and democratic rights.翻译:“社会民主党联盟”的三名成员在计划抗议他们所说的“鸟笼选举”以及选举和民主权利的“大倒退”之前遭到跟踪和逮捕。</p>   <p>The police said in a statement the three were arrested on suspicion of attempting to "incite others" to disrupt the poll.翻译:警方在一份声明中表示，三人因涉嫌试图“煽动他人”扰乱投票而被捕。</p>   <p>Hong Kong's leader John Lee, who had sought in recent weeks to rally public support for the polls, again defended their legitimacy given a need to secure stability in Hong Kong that returned from British to Chinese rule in 1997.翻译:香港领导人李家超最近几周一直在寻求争取公众对这次民意调查的支持，鉴于需要确保1997年从英国回归中国统治的香港的稳定，他再次捍卫了民意调查的合法性。</p>   <p>"It is the last piece of the puzzle for us to implement the principles of patriots governing Hong Kong," Lee said after casting his vote. He added that the 2019 election had been used to sabotage governance and endanger national security.翻译:李在投票后表示：“这是我们落实爱国者治港原则的最后一块拼图。”他补充说，2019 年选举被用来破坏治理并危害国家安全。</p>   <p>While some western governments have been critical of Hong Kong's authoritarian turn under the national security law, China says it has brought stability to the financial hub after protracted pro-democracy protests in 2019.翻译:尽管一些西方政府一直批评香港根据国家安全法转向独裁，但中国表示，在 2019 年旷日持久的民主抗议活动之后，该法为这个金融中心带来了稳定。</p>    <span>Reporting by Edward Cho, Dorothy Kam, Jessie Pang and James Pomfret; writing by James Pomfret; Editing by Sonali Paul翻译:Edward Cho、Dorothy Kam、Jessie Pang 和 James Pomfret 报道；詹姆斯·庞弗雷特 (James Pomfret) 撰写；索纳利·保罗编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:36:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6AVOFSVVMFL4HC4TN775HQZJK4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-patriots-only-election-falls-flat-with-record-low-turnout-2023-12-11/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Edward Cho, Dorothy Kam]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HONGKONG</category>
                
                <category>POLITICS/ELECTION (PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国美容市场放缓，大品牌折扣并不能解决问题]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/2IZY8VKZy5je1BsX2uqW_kRLFxA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CG4BRP6745NHLI366Y6TYJ2JGE.jpg" alt="Customers wearing face masks shop at a Chinese cosmetics brand Perfect Diary store, following the coronavirus disease (COVID-19) outbreak  in Beijing翻译:北京爆发冠状病毒病 (COVID-19) 后，戴着口罩的顾客在中国化妆品品牌完美日记店购物" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Customers wearing face masks shop at a Chinese cosmetics brand Perfect Diary store, following the coronavirus disease (COVID-19) outbreak  in Beijing翻译:北京爆发冠状病毒病 (COVID-19) 后，戴着口罩的顾客在中国化妆品品牌完美日记店购物, China August 25, 2020. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ohDfsnUvS4GXyCLF4hIUFwrGNI4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/QUHKWECF6RIXJAFZAJVBB5LMAA.jpg" alt="A customer wearing a face mask tries on makeup products at a Chinese cosmetics brand Perfect Diary store, following the coronavirus disease (COVID-19) outbreak  in Beijing翻译:北京爆发冠状病毒病 (COVID-19) 后，一名戴着口罩的顾客在中国化妆品品牌完美日记店试妆产品" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A customer wearing a face mask tries on makeup products at a Chinese cosmetics brand Perfect Diary store, following the coronavirus disease (COVID-19) outbreak  in Beijing翻译:北京爆发冠状病毒病 (COVID-19) 后，一名戴着口罩的顾客在中国化妆品品牌完美日记店试妆产品, China August 25, 2020. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo翻译:2020 年 8 月 25 日，中国北京爆发冠状病毒病 (COVID-19) 后，一名戴着口罩的顾客在中国化妆品品牌完美日记店试戴化妆品。 REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/档案照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>Expensive beauty hauls are a thing of the past for Evelyn Zhu. The Chinese branding professional says she now only spends on skincare essentials, joining millions of other consumers who have cut back on cosmetics in the world's second biggest market.翻译:对于 Evelyn Zhu 来说，昂贵的美容服务已经成为过去。这位中国品牌专业人士表示，她现在只在护肤必需品上花钱，加入了全球第二大市场数百万其他消费者的行列，减少了化妆品的消费。</p>   <p>"In recent years we all bought so many products," the 32-year-old from the affluent eastern city of Hangzhou said. "My bathroom cupboard is full, it's hard to say I need much more."翻译:“这几年我们都买了很多产品，”这位来自东部富裕城市杭州的 32 岁男子说。 “我的浴室柜子已经满了，很难说我还需要更多。”</p>   <p>This restraint, which has taken hold amid a slowing economy, spells bad news for global firms such as L'Oreal <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/OREP.PA" target="_blank">(OREP.PA)</a>, Estee Lauder <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/EL.N" target="_blank">(EL.N)</a> and LVMH <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LVMH.PA" target="_blank">(LVMH.PA)</a> who for years banked on China's $52 billion beauty market for growth.翻译:这种限制在经济放缓的情况下生效，对欧莱雅<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/OREP.PA" target="_blank">（OREP.PA）</a> 、雅诗兰黛<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/EL.N" target="_blank">（EL.N）</a>和路威酩轩<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LVMH.PA" target="_blank">（LVMH.PA）</a>等跨国公司来说是个坏消息，这些公司多年来一直寄希望于中国的52美元。亿美元的美容市场增长。</p>   <p>Regional brands such as Japan's Shiseido <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/4911.T" target="_blank">(4911.T)</a>, which counted China as its top market for years, are also struggling.翻译:多年来将中国视为其最大市场的日本资生堂<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/4911.T" target="_blank">（4911.T）</a>等区域品牌也陷入困境。</p>   <p>But while the economic woes have certainly weighed on sales, analysts say the main issue facing the multinationals is their slowness to adjust to the shifting priorities of consumers, who have become more discerning about what they buy and are increasingly finding that local brands are more suited to their needs.翻译:不过，尽管经济困境无疑对销售造成了压力，但分析人士表示，跨国公司面临的主要问题是它们适应消费者需求变化的速度缓慢，消费者对购买的商品越来越挑剔，并且越来越发现本土品牌更适合。以满足他们的需求。</p>   <p>"What Chinese consumers are still keen to spend on are high efficacy products," said William Lau, chief executive of multibrand beauty retailer Bonnie and Clyde, which stocks luxury international brands including Chantecaille and 111skin.翻译:“中国消费者仍然热衷于购买高效能产品，”多品牌美容零售商 Bonnie and Clyde 首席执行官 William Lau 表示，该公司销售 Chantecaille 和 111skin 等国际奢侈品牌。</p>   <p>"What you're seeing is a downgrade in lifestyle-driven luxury and premium brands," he added.翻译:“你所看到的是生活方式驱动的奢侈品牌和高端品牌的降级，”他补充道。</p>   <p>Botanee Biotech's sensitive skincare brand Winona is one of the beneficiaries of this paring back.翻译:Botanee Biotech 的敏感护肤品牌 Winona 是此次削减的受益者之一。</p>   <p>The Chinese brand, which is priced at around the same level as L'Oreal products, is known for combating redness, a concern that marketing firm iResearch reported affects two-fifth of women. Analysts from CMB International estimate Botanee's revenue will grow almost 18% this year to 5.9 billion yuan ($824 million), with Winona responsible for most of these gains.翻译:这个中国品牌的价格与欧莱雅产品大致相同，以抗红血丝而闻名，营销公司艾瑞咨询报告称，五分之二的女性都担心红血丝问题。 CMB International 的分析师估计 Botanee 今年的收入将增长近 18%，达到 59 亿元人民币（8.24 亿美元），其中大部分收益来自 Winona。</p>   <p>By comparison, sales for the global beauty giants are expected to fall.</p>    <h 1="">DEEP DISCOUNTS</h>  <p>An analysis from brokerage Jefferies showed first half China sales down 8% at LVMH's beauty division, while sales at Estée Lauder Companies, which counts on China for one-third of its business, fell 12 percent over the same period.翻译:经纪公司 Jefferies 的分析显示，上半年 LVMH 旗下美容部门的中国销售额下降了 8%，而三分之一业务依赖中国的雅诗兰黛公司同期销售额下降了 12%。</p>   <p>Shiseido reduced its full-year profit forecast in November on slower China demand, which has also been hit by a boycott by some consumer of Japanese products following the release of treated radioactive wastewater in August.翻译:由于中国需求放缓，资生堂在 11 月份下调了全年利润预期，而在 8 月份处理后的放射性废水排放后，一些日本产品消费者抵制日本产品也受到了打击。</p>   <p>L'Oreal, Estee Lauder and Shiseido did not respond to a request for comment.翻译:欧莱雅、雅诗兰黛和资生堂没有回应置评请求。</p>   <p>These results also come off the lower base of 2022, when the combined colour cosmetics and skincare markets in China lost 9.5% of their value, data from Euromonitor shows.翻译:Euromonitor 的数据显示，这些结果也是基于 2022 年的较低基数得出的，当时中国彩妆和护肤品市场的总价值损失了 9.5%。</p>   <p>While the market research firm expects growth of around 6% this year, it forecast won't get back to its 2021 market size of $54.4 billion until 2025.翻译:尽管这家市场研究公司预计今年的增长率约为 6%，但预计要到 2025 年才能恢复到 2021 年 544 亿美元的市场规模。</p>   <p>So far, the multinationals have responded to the slowdown by offering deep discounts of up to 40% and gifts during peak shopping events such as the annual online Singles Day festival, but analysts say the data shows even that isn't really helping.翻译:到目前为止，跨国公司已经通过在一年一度的在线双十一等高峰购物活动期间提供高达 40% 的大幅折扣和礼品来应对经济放缓，但分析师表示，数据显示，即使这样也没有真正的帮助。</p>   <p>Luxe skincare brand La Mer, which rarely discounts, gave so many gifts-with-purchase over Singles Day that every sale resulted in almost the same amount of product being given away.翻译:很少打折的奢华护肤品牌 La Mer 在双十一期间赠送了如此多的购物赠品，以至于每次销售都会赠送几乎相同数量的产品。</p>   <p>Independent data firm Syntun estimated that GMV, or gross merchandising volume, of beauty and personal care fell 6% year-on-year across all online shopping platforms. GMV is commonly used proxy for sales among e-commerce operators.翻译:独立数据公司Syntun估计，所有在线购物平台的美容和个人护理商品的GMV（商品交易总额）同比下降了6%。 GMV是电商运营商常用的销售额指标。</p>   <p>"The biggest global names have seen their Tmall GMV decrease by about 40% on average during 11.11," said Jacques Roizen, the Shanghai-based managing director of consulting at Digital Luxury Group, a digital agency for luxury brands.翻译:奢侈品牌数字代理机构 Digital Luxury Group 驻上海的咨询董事总经理雅克·罗伊森 (Jacques Roizen) 表示：“11.11 期间，全球最大品牌的天猫 GMV 平均下降了约 40%。”</p>   <p>"Now we see you don't have discounting as an acceleration lever you can press to go deeper or wider, because they're already maxed out," Roizen added.翻译:罗伊森补充道：“现在我们发现，你已经没有折扣作为加速杆了，你可以按下去更深或更广，因为它们已经达到了极限。”</p>   <p>Gregoire Grandchamp, co-founder of Next Beauty, a brand management partner for niche beauty players looking to grow in the China market, said the discounts offered by the beauty brands online this year have been "insane".翻译:Next Beauty 是寻求在中国市场发展的小众美容品牌的品牌管理合作伙伴，其联合创始人格雷瓜尔·格兰尚 (Gregoire Grandchamp) 表示，今年美容品牌在网上提供的折扣“疯狂”。</p>   <p>But while these larger brands are better able to compete online than smaller companies that lack their marketing budgets, they are not immune to the slowdown in demand.翻译:不过，尽管这些大品牌比缺乏营销预算的小公司更有能力在线竞争，但它们也无法免受需求放缓的影响。</p>   <p>According to Grandchamp, the sooner they adjust to China's new normal of single-digit growth rather than chasing the growth of yesteryear with brand equity-eroding discounts, the better.翻译:Grandchamp 表示，他们越早适应中国单位数增长的新常态，而不是通过削弱品牌资产的折扣来追逐去年的增长，就越好。</p>   <p>"I think the way groups like L'Oreal will react will be to say, Okay, maybe it's better not to have this euphoric growth, but to be more in a more rational market," he said.翻译:“我认为像欧莱雅这样的集团的反应方式会是说，好吧，也许最好不要出现这种欣喜若狂的增长，而是更多地处于一个更加理性的市场中，”他说。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1608 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.1608 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Casey Hall; editing by Miral Fahmy翻译:凯西·霍尔报道；米拉尔·法赫米 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 01:07:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">PXWGH7I2OFJPHBRONCR2JYHEZE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/chinas-slowing-beauty-market-big-brand-discounts-wont-cut-it-2023-12-08/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Casey Hall]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>BEAUTY/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
