<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 20:27:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[我们对中国呼吸系统疾病激增了解多少？]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Q7abqBe6IkmHHOQtC6ZUal536-M=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KMICRD27ZZOX7L3WUCG2Q2IBTA.jpg" alt="People wait for bus at a bus stop in Beijing翻译:北京，人们在公交车站等车" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People wait for bus at a bus stop in Beijing翻译:北京，人们在公交车站等车, China February 16, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0u6WJipVNQT4ya2HInVPQ-CJ-gw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/K6P5N7CEHBMHDGXYLMM6KFZ7WQ.jpg" alt="People wait outside a children's hospital in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家儿童医院外等候" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People wait for their rides outside a children's hospital in Beijing, China November 24, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo /File photo翻译:2023年11月24日，中国北京，人们在一家儿童医院外等待乘车。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>A request by the World Health Organization for more information on <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/who-asks-china-details-respiratory-illness-outbreaks-2023-11-23/">a surge</a> in respiratory illnesses and clusters of pneumonia in children in China has attracted global attention.翻译:世界卫生组织要求提供有关中国呼吸道疾病<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/who-asks-china-details-respiratory-illness-outbreaks-2023-11-23/">激增</a>和儿童聚集性肺炎的更多信息，引起了全球关注。</p>   <p>Health authorities have not detected any unusual or novel pathogens, the WHO later said, and doctors and public health researchers say there is no evidence for international alarm.翻译:世界卫生组织后来说，卫生当局尚未发现任何不寻常或新颖的病原体，医生和公共卫生研究人员表示，没有证据表明国际社会发出警报。</p>   <p>Authorities in Taiwan, however, this week <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-urges-elderly-young-avoid-china-visits-due-respiratory-illnesses-2023-11-30/">advised</a> the elderly, very young and those with poor immunity to avoid travel to China.翻译:然而，台湾当局本周<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-urges-elderly-young-avoid-china-visits-due-respiratory-illnesses-2023-11-30/">建议</a>老年人、幼儿和免疫力差的人避免前往中国大陆。</p>   <p>The following is what we know about the surge in illness in the world's second most populous country so far, and why experts think there is no need to panic.</p>    <h 1="">WHAT IS HAPPENING ON THE GROUND?</h>  <p>The rise in respiratory illnesses comes as China braces for its first full winter season since it lifted strict COVID-19 restrictions in December last year.翻译:呼吸道疾病的增加正值中国准备迎接自去年 12 月取消严格的 COVID-19 限制以来的第一个完整冬季。</p>   <p>The spike in illness came into the spotlight when the WHO asked China for more information last week, citing a report by the Program for Monitoring Emerging Diseases (ProMED) on clusters of undiagnosed pneumonia in children.翻译:上周，世界卫生组织援引新发疾病监测计划（ProMED）关于儿童未确诊肺炎群发的报告，要求中国提供更多信息，使疾病激增成为人们关注的焦点。</p>   <p>Some social media users have also posted photos of children receiving intravenous drips in hospital, while media in cities such as Xian in the northwest have posted videos of crowded hospitals, fanning concerns potential strains on the healthcare system.</p>    <h 1="">HOW BIG IS THE SURGE?</h>  <p>The National Health Commission told a news conference on Nov. 13 that there was an increase in incidence of respiratory disease without providing further details.翻译:国家卫健委在11月13日的新闻发布会上表示，呼吸道疾病发病率有所上升，但没有提供更多细节。</p>   <p>WHO China told Reuters in an email that "Chinese health authorities advised that the current numbers they are observing is not greater than the peak in the most recent cold season prior to the COVID-19 pandemic".</p>    <h 1="">WHAT PATHOGENS ARE CIRCULATING?</h>  <p>The data suggests the increase is linked to the lifting of COVID-19 restrictions along with the circulation of known pathogens such as mycoplasma pneumoniae, a common bacterial infection that typically affects younger children and which has circulated since May.翻译:数据表明，这一增长与取消 COVID-19 限制以及肺炎支原体等已知病原体的传播有关，肺炎支原体是一种常见的细菌感染，通常影响年幼的儿童，自 5 月份以来一直在传播。</p>   <p>Influenza, respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) and adenovirus have been in circulation since October.</p>    <h 1="">IS MYCOPLASMA PNEUMONIAE A BIG WORRY?</h>  <p>One concern about the surge in respiratory illness is mycoplasma pneumoniae, which has also spiked in other countries.翻译:呼吸道疾病激增的一个担忧是肺炎支原体，这种疾病在其他国家也出现激增。</p>   <p>Maria Van Kerkhove, COVID-19 Technical Lead at the World Health Organization told reporters on Wednesday that mycoplasma pneumonia is not a reportable disease to the WHO, and it was on the rise for the last couple of months but now appears to be declining.翻译:世界卫生组织 COVID-19 技术负责人 Maria Van Kerkhove 周三告诉记者，支原体肺炎不是世界卫生组织可报告的疾病，过去几个月它的发病率呈上升趋势，但现在似乎正在下降。</p>   <p>"We're following up through our clinical networks and working with clinicians in China to better understand resistance to antibiotics, which is a problem across the world, but is a particular problem in the Western Pacific and South East Asia region," she said.翻译:她说：“我们正在通过我们的临床网络进行跟进，并与中国的临床医生合作，以更好地了解抗生素耐药性，这是世界各地的一个问题，但在西太平洋和东南亚地区是一个特殊的问题。”</p>   <p>Rajib Dasgupta, an epidemiologist and professor of community health at Jawaharlal Nehru University in New Delhi, told Reuters in some cases there may be serious complications from infection caused by mycoplasma pneumoniae, but most people will recover without antibiotics.</p>    <h 1="">WHY EXPERTS AREN'T CONCERNED?</h>  <p>Doctors in China and experts abroad are not too worried about the situation in China, noting many other countries saw similar increases in respiratory diseases after easing pandemic measures.翻译:中国的医生和国外的专家对中国的情况并不太担心，他们指出，在放松流行病措施后，许多其他国家的呼吸道疾病也出现了类似的增长。</p>   <p>"The cases that we are seeing is nothing unusual at the moment, because it's still the same cough, colds, fever presentation, and the good thing about it is that it's actually treatable," said Cecille Brion, head of the pediatrics department at Raffles Medical Group Beijing.翻译:莱佛士医院儿科主任塞西尔·布里昂 (Cecille Brion) 表示：“目前我们看到的病例并不罕见，因为仍然是同样的咳嗽、感冒、发烧症状，好处是它实际上是可以治疗的。”北京医疗集团.</p>   <p>Van Kerkhove said that the rise in cases was expected.翻译:范科霍夫表示，病例增加是预料之中的。</p>   <p>"We are seeing, in general, an increase in respiratory infections around the world. We do tend to see increases in children because they're the school-aged children, and in the northern hemisphere it's the autumn already. We're entering the winter months," she said.翻译:“总体而言，我们看到世界各地呼吸道感染病例有所增加。我们确实倾向于看到儿童病例有所增加，因为他们是学龄儿童，而在北半球，已经是秋天了。我们正在进入冬天的几个月，”她说。</p>    <span>Reporting by Andrew Silver; Editing by Miyoung Kim and Miral Fahmy翻译:安德鲁·西尔弗报道；编辑：Miyoung Kim 和 Miral Fahmy</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 19:46:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">SBN7CTAOSJJSZOOBY7JNT4U2EU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/what-do-we-know-about-chinas-respiratory-illness-surge-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Andrew Silver]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>HEALTH/ (EXPLAINER, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TikTok 要求欧盟法院暂停欧盟看门人标签，直至做出裁决]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/syjA7k6R5IAo7BWrmeFdjt7_UGQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/LFE4IH6RLRMEPPJCZI3IQOBIQM.jpg" alt="Illustration shows EU flag and TikTok logo翻译:插图显示欧盟旗帜和 TikTok 徽标" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>EU flag and TikTok logo are seen in this illustration taken, June 2, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration//File Photo翻译:这张摄于 2023 年 6 月 2 日的插图中可以看到欧盟旗帜和 TikTok 标志。 REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration//File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Chinese conglomerate ByteDance's TikTok has asked Europe's second highest court to suspend its designation as a gatekeeper under onerous new EU tech rules until judges rule on its challenge against the label.翻译:中国企业集团字节跳动旗下的 TikTok 已要求欧洲第二最高法院暂停将其指定为严格的欧盟新科技规则下的看门人，直到法官对其针对该标签的挑战作出裁决。</p>   <p>The Digital Markets Act (DMA) requires TikTok and other designated gatekeepers Alphabet's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GOOGL.O" target="_blank">(GOOGL.O)</a> Google, Meta Platforms <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/META.O" target="_blank">(META.O)</a>, Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a>, Amazon <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AMZN.O" target="_blank">(AMZN.O)</a> and Microsoft <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O" target="_blank">(MSFT.O)</a> to make their messaging apps interoperate with rivals and let users decide which apps to pre-install on their devices.翻译:《数字市场法案》(DMA) 要求 TikTok 和其他指定的看门人 Alphabet <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GOOGL.O" target="_blank">(GOOGL.O)</a> 、谷歌、Meta Platforms <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/META.O" target="_blank">(META.O)</a> 、苹果<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a> 、亚马逊<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AMZN.O" target="_blank">(AMZN.O)</a>和微软<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O" target="_blank">(MSFT.O)</a>使他们的消息应用程序与竞争对手互操作，并让用户决定在其设备上预安装哪些应用程序。</p>   <p>They are not allowed to favour their own services over rivals' or prevent users from removing pre-installed software or apps.翻译:他们不得偏袒自己的服务而不是竞争对手的服务，也不得阻止用户删除预装的软件或应用程序。</p>   <p>TikTok last month challenged <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/tiktok-joins-meta-appealing-against-eu-gatekeeper-status-2023-11-16/">the EU decision</a> at the Luxembourg-based General Court, saying its designation risks undermining the DMA goal of protecting gatekeepers from newer competitors like itself.翻译:TikTok 上个月在卢森堡普通法院对<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/tiktok-joins-meta-appealing-against-eu-gatekeeper-status-2023-11-16/">欧盟的决定</a>提出质疑，称其指定可能会破坏 DMA 保护看门人免受像其这样的新竞争对手侵害的目标。</p>   <p>"We have applied for interim measures," a spokesperson said.翻译:“我们已申请临时措施，”一位发言人说。</p>   <p>The bar for the court to approve interim measures is very high. Companies must show that situation is urgent and that they would suffer irreparable harm without an interim measure.翻译:法院批准临时措施的门槛非常高。公司必须表明情况紧急，如果不采取临时措施，他们将遭受无法弥补的伤害。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/meta-appeals-against-eu-gatekeeper-status-messenger-marketplace-2023-11-15/">Meta</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/transactional/apple-files-legal-challenge-eus-digital-markets-act-2023-11-17/">Apple</a> have also sued the Commission over their gatekeeper status.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/meta-appeals-against-eu-gatekeeper-status-messenger-marketplace-2023-11-15/">Meta</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/transactional/apple-files-legal-challenge-eus-digital-markets-act-2023-11-17/">苹果</a>还就其看门人地位起诉了委员会。</p>    <span>Reporting by Foo Yun Chee; editing by Barbara Lewis翻译:符润芝报道；芭芭拉·刘易斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 18:46:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">KQDS3Z7KYVMOHOK5FNMHFYKHVE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/tiktok-asks-eu-court-suspend-eu-gatekeeper-label-until-its-ruling-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Foo Yun Chee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>EU</category>
                
                <category>TECH/TIKTOK (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国限制中国企业和电池零部件获得电动汽车税收抵免]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/WWp0hUEZB5dbfycV3o6T4OdvmRI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/B5CCNPOGUNJNRM5S7C3OPMTBAE.jpg" alt="General Motors assembly workers connect a battery pack underneath a partially assembled 2018 Chevrolet Bolt EV vehicle on the assembly line at  Orion Assembly in Lake Orion,翻译:在猎户座湖猎户座装配厂的装配线上，通用汽车装配工人在部分组装的 2018 款雪佛兰 Bolt 电动汽车下方连接电池组，" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>General Motors assembly workers connect a battery pack underneath a partially assembled 2018 Chevrolet Bolt EV vehicle on the assembly line at  Orion Assembly in Lake Orion,翻译:在猎户座湖猎户座装配厂的装配线上，通用汽车装配工人在部分组装的 2018 款雪佛兰 Bolt 电动汽车下方连接电池组， Michigan, U.S., March 19, 2018. REUTERS/Rebecca Cook/File Photo/File Photo翻译:2018 年 3 月 19 日，美国密歇根州猎户座湖 Orion 装配厂的装配线上，通用汽车装配工人在部分组装的 2018 款雪佛兰 Bolt 电动汽车下方连接电池组。 REUTERS/Rebecca Cook/档案照片/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Biden administration on Friday issued-long awaited guidance that will limit Chinese content in batteries eligible for electric vehicle tax credits starting next year.翻译:拜登政府周五发布了期待已久的指导意见，该指导意见将从明年开始限制符合电动汽车税收抵免资格的电池中的中国成分。</p>   <p>In a win for automakers, the U.S. Treasury will temporarily exempt some trace critical minerals from new strict rules barring materials from China and other countries deemed a "Foreign Entity of Concern." (FEOC)翻译:为了汽车制造商的胜利，美国财政部将暂时免除一些痕量关键矿物，使其免受新的严格规定的限制，禁止来自中国和其他被视为“外国关注实体”的国家的材料。 （远东石油公司）</p>   <p>The new rules, required under an August 2022 law, are designed to wean the U.S. electric vehicle battery chain away from China and are being closely watched by automakers as they make investment decisions on producing batteries for their transition to electric vehicles.翻译:根据 2022 年 8 月颁布的法律，新规定旨在让美国电动汽车电池链摆脱中国的束缚，汽车制造商在为向电动汽车过渡而做出电池生产投资决策时受到密切关注。</p>   <p>The FEOC rules come into effect in 2024 for completed batteries and 2025 for critical minerals used to produce them.翻译:FEOC 规则对于成品电池将于 2024 年生效，对于用于生产电池的关键矿物则于 2025 年生效。</p>   <p>The Alliance for Automotive Innovation, a group representing nearly all major automakers, said the decision to exempt trace materials for two years "was significant and well-advised" and without it could have made nearly all vehicles ineligible.翻译:代表几乎所有主要汽车制造商的汽车创新联盟表示，免除微量材料两年的决定“意义重大且明智”，否则几乎所有车辆都将不再符合资格。</p>   <p>Treasury said the few materials being exempted each account for less than 2% of the value of battery critical minerals.翻译:财政部表示，少数获得豁免的材料各自占电池关键矿物价值的不到 2%。</p>   <p>General Motors said on Friday it believes it is "well positioned to maintain the consumer purchase incentive for many of our EVs in 2024 and beyond."翻译:通用汽车周五表示，它相信“有能力在 2024 年及以后维持消费者对我们许多电动汽车的购买动力”。</p>   <p>Ford Motor said in October it was awaiting the guidance to determine if its licensing agreement with Chinese battery maker CATL <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300750.SZ" target="_blank">(300750.SZ)</a>, as part of the automaker's planned Michigan battery plant, would run afoul of the rules. Biden administration officials would not comment on whether that arrangement is permissible under the rules. Ford declined to comment.翻译:福特汽车公司10月份表示，正在等待指导意见，以确定其与中国电池制造商CATL <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300750.SZ" target="_blank">（300750.SZ）</a>的许可协议（作为该汽车制造商计划的密歇根电池工厂的一部分）是否会违反规定。拜登政府官员不会就规则是否允许这种安排发表评论。福特拒绝发表评论。</p>   <p>Republican Senator Marco Rubio said the guidance appears to allow the Ford CATL agreement to qualify. He criticized the decision, arguing the administration was putting "EV special interest groups ahead of America's interests."翻译:共和党参议员马可·卢比奥 (Marco Rubio) 表示，该指导意见似乎使福特 CATL 协议符合资格。他批评了这一决定，认为政府将“电动汽车特殊利益集团置于美国利益之上”。</p>   <p>The Energy Department said a company would be deemed a FEOC if owned or controlled by a named foreign government. Companies will also be ineligible if an entity of concern holds 25% of that entity’s board seats, voting rights, or equity.翻译:美国能源部表示，如果一家公司由指定外国政府拥有或控制，则该公司将被视为 FEOC。如果相关实体持有该实体 25% 的董事会席位、投票权或股权，该公司也将不符合资格。</p>   <p>Those countries include North Korea, China, Russia and Iran.翻译:这些国家包括朝鲜、中国、俄罗斯和伊朗。</p>   <p>The automaker group said "it appears that companies operating in China are considered FEOC. Chinese entities with specific ownership or governance structures might be permitted in certain circumstances."翻译:该汽车制造商集团表示，“看来在中国运营的公司被视为 FEOC。在某些情况下，具有特定所有权或治理结构的中国实体可能会被允许。”</p>   <p>The rules are expected to further reduce the number of electric vehicles eligible for EV tax credits. The law immediately made any vehicle ineligible if not assembled in North America. Earlier this year, new battery and mineral sourcing requirements took effect with price and buyer income eligibility caps from Jan. 1.翻译:预计这些规则将进一步减少有资格获得电动汽车税收抵免的电动汽车数量。该法律立即规定任何车辆如果不是在北美组装的，则不符合资格。今年早些时候，新的电池和矿物采购要求从 1 月 1 日起生效，价格和买家收入资格受到限制。</p>   <p>Senator Energy Committee chair Joe Manchin blasted Treasury for allowing some trace critical minerals from China to qualify and vowed to take every opportunity "to reverse this unlawful, shameful proposed rule and protect our energy security."翻译:参议员能源委员会主席乔·曼钦（Joe Manchin）谴责财政部允许来自中国的一些微量关键矿物符合资格，并发誓要抓住一切机会“扭转这一非法、可耻的拟议规则，保护我们的能源安全。”</p>   <p>Treasury said to allow compliant vehicles to qualify until the rules are finalized, it will have an expedited compliance method for automakers with clean supply chains.翻译:财政部表示，在规则最终确定之前，允许合规车辆符合资格，将为拥有清洁供应链的汽车制造商提供快速合规方法。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Shepardson翻译:大卫·谢泼德森报道 and David Lawder in Washington; Editing by Chizu Nomiyama, Kirsten Donovan</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 18:19:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">M5GSKOWSWBJGJCS7ZLRZQSJQ64</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/us-limit-chinese-firms-battery-parts-winning-ev-tax-credits-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Shepardson, David Lawder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>AUTOS/CHINA (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[通用汽车相信其许多电动汽车将有资格在 2024 年获得税收抵免]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Tsyog27shuX7QKpJDq9CRpfPVNs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SXOLF4NM5NOOPJYANK6L2FJCCM.jpg" alt="Logo of GM atop the company headquarters翻译:公司总部顶部的通用汽车标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The GM logo is seen on the facade of the General Motors headquarters in Detroit, Michigan, U.S., March 16, 2021. REUTERS/Rebecca Cook/File Photo翻译:2021 年 3 月 16 日，通用汽车标志出现在美国密歇根州底特律通用汽车总部的正面。路透社/丽贝卡·库克/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/WWp0hUEZB5dbfycV3o6T4OdvmRI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/B5CCNPOGUNJNRM5S7C3OPMTBAE.jpg" alt="General Motors assembly workers connect a battery pack underneath a partially assembled 2018 Chevrolet Bolt EV vehicle on the assembly line at  Orion Assembly in Lake Orion,翻译:在猎户座湖猎户座装配厂的装配线上，通用汽车装配工人在部分组装的 2018 款雪佛兰 Bolt 电动汽车下方连接电池组，" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>General Motors assembly workers connect a battery pack underneath a partially assembled 2018 Chevrolet Bolt EV vehicle on the assembly line at  Orion Assembly in Lake Orion,翻译:在猎户座湖猎户座装配厂的装配线上，通用汽车装配工人在部分组装的 2018 款雪佛兰 Bolt 电动汽车下方连接电池组， Michigan, U.S., March 19, 2018. REUTERS/Rebecca Cook/File Photo/File Photo翻译:2018 年 3 月 19 日，美国密歇根州猎户座湖 Orion 装配厂的装配线上，通用汽车装配工人在部分组装的 2018 款雪佛兰 Bolt 电动汽车下方连接电池组。 REUTERS/Rebecca Cook/档案照片/档案照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>General Motors said Friday that it expects many of its electric vehicles to qualify for U.S. tax credits next year after new stricter rules limiting Chinese battery content take effect.翻译:通用汽车周五表示，在限制中国电池含量的新规定生效后，预计其许多电动汽车明年将有资格获得美国税收抵免。</p>   <p>"Due to GM’s historic investments in the U.S and efforts to build more secure and resilient supply chains we believe GM is well positioned to maintain the consumer purchase incentive for many of our EVs in 2024 and beyond," the automaker said after <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/us-limit-chinese-firms-battery-parts-winning-ev-tax-credits-2023-12-01/">the Biden administration issued new guidance</a>.翻译:“由于通用汽车在美国的历史性投资以及建立更安全、更有弹性的供应链的努力，我们相信通用汽车处于有利位置，可以在 2024 年及以后维持消费者对我们许多电动汽车的购买动力，”该汽车制造商在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/us-limit-chinese-firms-battery-parts-winning-ev-tax-credits-2023-12-01/">拜登政府发布</a>后表示。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/us-limit-chinese-firms-battery-parts-winning-ev-tax-credits-2023-12-01/">新的指导</a>。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Shepardson翻译:大卫·谢泼德森报道</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 17:48:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">KMJXNQ5X7VJJ7MHUUIJDVQIFVU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/gm-believes-many-its-evs-will-qualify-tax-credits-2024-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>AUTOS/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>GM (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[五名参议员要求拜登在出现呼吸道疾病病例后实施中国旅行禁令]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/fD2NdIrJxedGL40uidVW0OONz-g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/LUQFVFBOSBJSFAILFQ6MLT7PGA.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden visits CS Wind, in Pueblo翻译:美国总统乔·拜登参观普韦布洛的 CS Wind" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden delivers remarks at CS Wind, the largest wind tower manufacturer in the world, in Pueblo, Colorado, U.S., November 29, 2023. REUTERS/Evelyn Hockstein/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 29 日，美国总统乔·拜登在美国科罗拉多州普韦布洛市全球最大的风塔制造商 CS Wind 发表讲话。路透社/Evelyn Hockstein/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Five Republican senators led by Marco Rubio on Friday asked President Joe Biden's administration to ban travel between the United States and China after a spike in Chinese respiratory illness cases.翻译:在中国呼吸道疾病病例激增后，以马可·卢比奥为首的五名共和党参议员周五要求总统乔·拜登政府禁止美国和中国之间的旅行。</p>   <p>"We should immediately restrict travel between the United States and (China) until we know more about the dangers posed by this new illness," <a href="https://www.rubio.senate.gov/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/12.01.23-Rubio-et-al-Letter-to-POTUS-re-China-travel-pause.pdf" target="_blank">said the letter</a> signed by Rubio, the top Republican on the Senate Intelligence Committee.翻译:参议院情报委员会共和党领袖卢比奥签署的<a href="https://www.rubio.senate.gov/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/12.01.23-Rubio-et-al-Letter-to-POTUS-re-China-travel-pause.pdf" target="_blank">信中说</a>：“我们应该立即限制美国和（中国）之间的旅行，直到我们更多地了解这种新疾病带来的危险。”</p>   <p>The rise in cases became a global issue last week when the World Health Organization <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/who-asks-china-details-respiratory-illness-outbreaks-2023-11-23/">ask</a>ed China for more information, citing a report on clusters of undiagnosed pneumonia in children by the Program for Monitoring Emerging Diseases.翻译:上周，世界卫生组织<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/who-asks-china-details-respiratory-illness-outbreaks-2023-11-23/">援引</a>新发疾病监测计划关于儿童未确诊肺炎集群的报告，要求中国提供更多信息，病例上升成为一个全球性问题。</p>   <p>The White House and the Chinese Embassy in Washington did not immediately comment.翻译:白宫和中国驻华盛顿大使馆没有立即发表评论。</p>   <p>Maria Van Kerkhove, acting director of the WHO's department of epidemic and pandemic preparedness and prevention, said earlier this week the increase appeared to be driven by a rise in the number of children contracting pathogens that they had avoided during two years of COVID-19 restrictions.翻译:世界卫生组织流行病和大流行防范部门代理主任玛丽亚·范·科霍夫(Maria Van Kerkhove)本周早些时候表示，这一增长似乎是由于感染病原体的儿童数量增加所致，而他们在两年的COVID-19限制期间避免了感染病原体。 。</p>   <p>In recent months, the United States and China have been steadily increasing flights between the countries, that are still far below 2019 levels. The number rose on Nov. 9 to 35 per week for each country, up from 12 per week in August.翻译:近几个月来，美国和中国一直在稳步增加两国之间的航班，但仍远低于 2019 年的水平。 11 月 9 日，每个国家/地区的数量从 8 月份的每周 12 个增加到了 35 个。</p>   <p>In January 2020, then President Donald Trump barred most non-U.S. citizens who had been in China in the prior two weeks from coming to the United States over concerns about COVID-19. However, he did not restrict or limit flights between the two countries.翻译:2020 年 1 月，时任总统唐纳德·特朗普出于对 COVID-19 的担忧，禁止过去两周去过中国的大多数非美国公民来美国。不过，他并没有限制或限制两国之间的航班。</p>   <p>The United States lifted the unprecedented travel restrictions for fully vaccinated international visitors starting in November 2021, including from China. The United States <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-drop-covid-testing-incoming-international-air-travelers-2022-06-10/">rescinded a separate requirement</a> air travelers test negative before arriving in June 2022.翻译:从 2021 年 11 月开始，美国取消了对已接种疫苗的国际游客前所未有的旅行限制，其中包括来自中国的游客。美国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-drop-covid-testing-incoming-international-air-travelers-2022-06-10/">取消了一项单独的要求，</a>要求航空旅客在 2022 年 6 月抵达之前必须检测呈阴性。</p>   <p>The United States in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-impose-mandatory-covid-19-tests-travelers-china-2022-12-28/">January started requiring</a> air passengers to get negative COVID tests after Beijing's decision to lift its stringent zero-COVID policies and lifted the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/us-cdc-confirms-it-plans-lift-covid-19-testing-requirements-travelers-china-2023-03-08/">requirements in March</a>.翻译:在北京决定取消严格的零新冠病毒政策后，美国从<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-impose-mandatory-covid-19-tests-travelers-china-2022-12-28/">一月份开始要求</a>航空乘客进行新冠病毒阴性检测，并<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/us-cdc-confirms-it-plans-lift-covid-19-testing-requirements-travelers-china-2023-03-08/">于三月份取消了这一要求</a>。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Shepardson翻译:大卫·谢泼德森报道; Editing by Chizu Nomiyama翻译:大卫·谢泼德森报道；编辑：野宫千津</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 17:41:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZDEITZ2RKFJ4ZM5IF6I6MS5EZU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/five-senators-ask-biden-impose-china-travel-ban-after-respiratory-illness-cases-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Shepardson]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HEALTH</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/USA</category>
                
                <category>TRAVEL (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[印度恢复进口委内瑞拉石油，信实集团寻求直接协议]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/pjpgkm0G-ihN0YJEJnYev6Zhbwo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/IITY5J7ANVLQDK4HRZS25FYG2U.jpg" alt="A worker holds a nozzle to pump petrol into a vehicle at a fuel station in Mumbai翻译:在孟买的一个加油站，一名工人拿着喷嘴向车辆加油" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A worker holds a nozzle to pump petrol into a vehicle at a fuel station in Mumbai翻译:在孟买的一个加油站，一名工人拿着喷嘴向车辆加油, India, May 21, 2018. REUTERS/Francis Mascarenhas/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Indian refiners have resumed Venezuelan oil purchases through intermediaries, with Reliance <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RELI.NS" target="_blank">(RELI.NS)</a> set to meet executives from state firm PDVSA next week to discuss direct sales following the easing of U.S. sanctions on the South American country, people familiar with the matter said.翻译:知情人士称，印度炼油商已恢复通过中间商购买委内瑞拉石油，信实公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RELI.NS" target="_blank">(RELI.NS)</a>将于下周与国营公司 PDVSA 的高管会面，讨论美国放松对这个南美国家制裁后的直接销售问题。</p>   <p>The resumption in trade between the OPEC producer and what was the second largest destination for its oil comes after Washington in October temporarily lifted sanctions banning Venezuelan oil exports, prompting a flurry of spot sales of crude and fuel <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/big-traders-strike-deals-with-middlemen-tap-venezuelas-free-flowing-oil-2023-11-09/">through middlemen</a> and traders, mostly to China.翻译:在华盛顿于10月暂时取消禁止委内瑞拉石油出口的制裁后，OPEC产油国与其第二大石油目的地之间的贸易恢复，引发了一系列原油和燃料<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/big-traders-strike-deals-with-middlemen-tap-venezuelas-free-flowing-oil-2023-11-09/">通过中间商</a>和贸易商的现货销售，其中大部分销往中国。</p>   <p>But Venezuela's oil output has been volatile, limiting what it can offer for export.翻译:但委内瑞拉的石油产量一直不稳定，限制了其出口。</p>   <p>India last imported Venezuelan crude in 2020. Access to Venezuela's heavy oil could cap import costs for India, which has become a major Russian oil buyer, and further reduce its reliance on the Middle East.翻译:印度上次进口委内瑞拉原油是在2020年。获得委内瑞拉重油可能会限制印度的进口成本，并进一步减少其对中东的依赖。印度已成为俄罗斯石油的主要买家。</p>   <p>Three Indian refiners have bought some 4 million barrels of Venezuelan crude for February delivery at between $7.50 and $8 per barrel below dated Brent on a delivered ex-ship basis, five trade sources said.翻译:五位贸易消息人士称，三家印度炼油厂已购买约 400 万桶 2 月交割的委内瑞拉原油，价格按离船交货价格比布伦特原油价格低 7.5 至 8 美元/桶。</p>   <p>Of those, trading house Vitol sold 1.5 million barrels to Indian Oil Corp <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/IOC.NS" target="_blank">(IOC.NS)</a> and 500,000 barrels to HPCL-Mittal Energy (HMEL), a joint venture between state-run Hindustan Petroleum Corp <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/HPCL.NS" target="_blank">(HPCL.NS)</a> and Mittal Energy Investment, they added.翻译:其中，维多贸易公司向印度石油公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/IOC.NS" target="_blank">(IOC.NS)</a>出售了 150 万桶，向国营印度斯坦石油公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/HPCL.NS" target="_blank">(HPCL.NS)</a>和米塔尔能源投资公司的合资企业 HPCL-米塔尔能源公司 (HMEL) 出售了 50 万桶。 ，他们补充道。</p>   <p>Reliance had previously received an offer for a prompt cargo at $16 a barrel below dated Brent, another source said, but it was unclear if the deal had gone through.翻译:另一位消息人士称，Reliance 此前已收到以比布伦特原油每桶价格低 16 美元的价格购买即期船货的报价，但目前尚不清楚该交易是否已达成。</p>   <p>The South American country is producing some 850,000 barrels per day (bpd) of crude with a target of soon reaching 1 million bpd, Venezuela's deputy oil minister said last month, a goal it has repeatedly missed.翻译:委内瑞拉石油部副部长上个月表示，这个南美国家的原油产量约为每天 85 万桶，目标是很快达到 100 万桶，但该国已多次未能实现这一目标。</p>   <p>Reliance once was PDVSA's second-largest crude customer and in turn an important supplier of fuel to Venezuela.翻译:Reliance曾经是PDVSA的第二大原油客户，也是委内瑞拉重要的燃料供应商。</p>   <p>"The Reliance team has already scheduled meetings with PDVSA executives in Caracas," one of the people said, adding that the discussions are expected to include crude sales to India and fuel imports for Venezuela.翻译:一位知情人士表示，“Reliance 团队已安排在加拉加斯与 PDVSA 高管举行会议”，并补充说，预计讨论内容将包括向印度销售原油和向委内瑞拉进口燃料。</p>   <p>PDVSA, Reliance, IOC, HPCL-Mittal Energy and Vitol did not immediately reply to requests for comment.翻译:PDVSA、Reliance、IOC、HPCL-Mittal Energy 和 Vitol 没有立即回复置评请求。</p>   <p>The Venezuelan firm is separately negotiating crude sales to PetroChina <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601857.SS" target="_blank">(601857.SS)</a>, but no deal has been signed.</p>    <h 1="">ON THEIR WAY</h>  <p>No cargoes have reached India yet, but some vessels finished loading in late November, so are expected to be authorized to depart in December, according to tanker tracking data and shipping schedules.翻译:目前尚未有货物抵达印度，但根据油轮跟踪数据和船期表，部分船只已于 11 月下旬完成装载，因此预计将于 12 月获准出发。</p>   <p>Taking cargoes largely will depend on the buyers' ability to charter tankers that agree to load at Venezuelan ports, where delays and quality issues are common, and their willingness to pay upfront, as demanded by PDVSA, some of the sources said.翻译:一些消息人士称，货物的运输很大程度上取决于买家是否有能力租用同意在委内瑞拉港口装载的油轮，而委内瑞拉港口的延误和质量问题很常见，以及他们是否愿意按照委内瑞拉国家石油公司的要求预先付款。</p>   <p>PDVSA's use of trading houses and intermediaries to negotiate oil sales to Asian refiners is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-slows-venezuela-crude-buys-us-sanctions-lifting-triggers-disarray-2023-11-23/">creating confusion</a>, some buyers have said. Customers including China's independent refiners have recently held off on making new purchases as they struggle to agree on prices.翻译:一些买家表示，委内瑞拉国家石油公司利用贸易公司和中介机构来谈判向亚洲炼油商出售石油的做法正在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-slows-venezuela-crude-buys-us-sanctions-lifting-triggers-disarray-2023-11-23/">造成混乱</a>。包括中国独立炼油厂在内的客户最近因难以就价格达成一致而推迟了新采购。</p>    <span>Reporting by Nidhi Verma in New Delhi, Marianna Parraga and Arathy Somasekhar in Houston, and Florence Tan and Muyu Xu in Singapore; Editing by Kirsten Donovan翻译:Nidhi Verma 在新德里、Marianna Parraga 和 Arathy Somasekhar 在休斯顿、Florence Tan 和 Muyu Xu 在新加坡的报道；克尔斯滕·多诺万编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 15:50:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">OWLJ6HZXUZNJJJ3N7OU3BAX7V4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/india/india-resumes-imports-venezuelan-oil-reliance-seeks-direct-deal-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Nidhi Verma, Marianna Parraga, Florence Tan]]></author>
            
                
                <category>VENEZUELA</category>
                
                <category>INDIA/OIL (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着拼多多抢占中国最有价值电子商务公司的宝座，阿里巴巴因微软评级下调而下跌]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/WQESpa2Uc4JE2M54WaRLYm-r1Iw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/RTYYNLBKRVJOHKPLTVV6OGQNNY.jpg" alt="Illustration shows Alibaba logo翻译:插图显示阿里巴巴标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Shopping trolley is seen in front of Alibaba logo in this illustration, July 24, 2022. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张图中，2022 年 7 月 24 日，购物车出现在阿里巴巴标志前。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S.-listed shares of Alibaba Group Holding declined on Friday following a Morgan Stanley downgrade on concerns over slower turnaround in its key businesses, hours after PDD raced past its rival to become the most valuable Chinese e-commerce firm.翻译:周五，在拼多多超越竞争对手成为中国最有价值的电子商务公司数小时后，摩根士丹利因担心其关键业务周转速度放缓而下调其评级，阿里巴巴集团控股公司在美国上市的股价下跌。</p>   <p>Alibaba's stock slipped 3.2% to $72.5, touching a fresh one-year low. The shares are down nearly 17% since the company last month <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/alibaba-quarterly-revenue-line-with-expectations-2023-11-16/">posted</a> in line second-quarter revenue and scrapped plans to spin off its cloud business.翻译:阿里巴巴股价下跌 3.2%，至 72.5 美元，触及一年新低。自该公司上个月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/alibaba-quarterly-revenue-line-with-expectations-2023-11-16/">公布</a>第二季度营收并取消剥离云业务的计划以来，该公司股价已下跌近 17%。</p>   <p>Meanwhile, shares of PDD Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PDD.O" target="_blank">(PDD.O)</a> have surged this week following stellar quarterly <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/pdd-beats-quarterly-revenue-estimates-2023-11-28/">results</a> from the Temu parent. The company closed with a market capitalization of nearly $196 billion on Thursday, surpassing Alibaba's market value of $190.45 billion.翻译:与此同时，继 Temu 母公司公布出色的季度<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/pdd-beats-quarterly-revenue-estimates-2023-11-28/">业绩</a>后，PDD Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PDD.O" target="_blank">(PDD.O)</a>的股价本周大幅上涨。该公司周四收盘市值接近1960亿美元，超过阿里巴巴1904.5亿美元的市值。</p>   <p>Morgan Stanley analysts downgraded Alibaba to "equal-weight" from "overweight", flagging concerns over softness in its customer management revenue and cloud business due to sagging economic recovery in China.翻译:摩根士丹利分析师将阿里巴巴的评级从“增持”下调至“平配”，表达了对其客户管理收入和云业务因中国经济复苏疲软而疲软的担忧。</p>   <p>They also noted uncertainties from Alibaba's decision to scrap the spin-off of its cloud business.翻译:他们还指出阿里巴巴决定放弃分拆云业务的不确定性。</p>   <p>Morgan Stanley cut its price target on the stock to $90 from $110, the second lowest among analysts, as per LSEG data. The downgrade is the third in as many weeks by Wall Street brokerages.翻译:根据 LSEG 的数据，摩根士丹利将该股目标价从 110 美元下调至 90 美元，是分析师中第二低的价格。这是华尔街券商几周内第三次下调评级。</p>   <p>Alibaba's U.S. shares, down about 18% so far this year, are set for their third consecutive year of losses.翻译:阿里巴巴的美国股价今年迄今已下跌约18%，预计将连续第三年下跌。</p>   <p>On the other hand, Morgan Stanley named PDD as its top pick in the sector, saying the company is best placed to navigate the current economic environment with its heavy discounting steps.翻译:另一方面，摩根士丹利将拼多多列为该行业的首选，并表示该公司最有能力通过大幅折扣措施应对当前的经济环境。</p>   <p>"We expect PDD to continue to gain share in the domestic market thanks to its favorable business model amid consumers' behavior shift," Morgan Stanley's Eddy Wang noted, adding that its cross-border e-commerce business, Temu, is not fully valued by the market.翻译:摩根士丹利的 Eddy Wang 表示：“我们预计拼多多将在消费者行为转变的背景下，凭借其良好的商业模式，继续扩大国内市场份额。”他补充说，拼多多的跨境电商业务 Temu 并未得到充分重视。市场。</p>   <p>PDD shares were down 2.1% at $144.4 but have surged almost 80% in 2023, handily outperforming its peers.翻译:PDD 股价下跌 2.1%，至 144.4 美元，但 2023 年已飙升近 80%，轻松跑赢同行。</p>   <p>At 21.4, PDD has the highest forward price-to-earnings ratio among rivals including JD.com and Vipshop Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VIPS.N" target="_blank">(VIPS.N)</a>. Alibaba's forward PE was 7.62, according to LSEG estimates.翻译:拼多多的预期市盈率为 21.4，是京东和唯品会<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VIPS.N" target="_blank">(VIPS.N)</a>等竞争对手中最高的。据 LSEG 估计，阿里巴巴的远期市盈率为 7.62。</p>    <span>Reporting by Sruthi Shankar in Bengaluru; Editing by Sriraj Kalluvila翻译:Sruthi Shankar 在班加罗尔的报道；斯里拉杰·卡卢维拉编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 14:54:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">22BYB4KH55JVRBR23UCHESGVDA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/alibaba-dips-ms-downgrade-pdd-grabs-spot-most-valuable-chinese-e-commerce-firm-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>STOCKS/ALIBABA (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着比特币触及 19 个月高点，加密货币股票将于 12 月开局走高]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/E_Ctsb4mSXvDccV5wnpzjZKOQ7c=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/Z6W7XLSDB5LDFBJUR7R26BBNYQ.jpg" alt="Illustration shows words &quot;Cryptocurrency market&quot;, stock graph and representation of cryptocurrencies翻译:插图显示“加密货币市场”、股票图和加密货币的表示" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Representations of cryptocurrencies are seen in front of displayed words "Cryptocurrency market" and decreasing stock graph in this illustration taken November 10, 2022. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张 2022 年 11 月 10 日拍摄的插图中，在显示的“加密货币市场”字样和不断减少的股票图表前面可以看到加密货币的表示。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/插图/文件照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Shares of crypto miners and bitcoin-tracking companies rose on Friday as the world's largest cryptocurrency extended a recent rally to touch a near 19-month high on improving risk appetite.翻译:由于风险偏好改善，全球最大的加密货币延续近期涨势，触及近 19 个月高点，加密货币矿商和比特币追踪公司的股价周五上涨。</p>   <p>Bitcoin , up 1.6% at $38,337, has been gaining since October on optimism that a potential approval of a spot exchange-traded fund is likely to unleash more capital investments in the digital asset sector.翻译:比特币上涨 1.6%，至 38,337 美元，自 10 月份以来一直在上涨，因为人们乐观地认为，现货交易所交易基金的潜在批准可能会在数字资产领域释放更多资本投资。</p>   <p>"Tailwinds have been gathering strength all year, especially in recent months, as spot ETF expectations build, the Binance uncertainty is resolved, and 2024's accelerated money printing becomes more inevitable," crypto-focused economist Noelle Acheson said, referring to the bitcoin rally.翻译:专注于加密货币的经济学家 Noelle Acheson 在谈到比特币涨势时表示：“全年顺风顺水的势头一直在增强，尤其是近几个月，随着现货 ETF 预期的增强，币安的不确定性得到解决，2024 年的加速印钞变得更加不可避免。”</p>   <p>Shares of bitcoin miners - whose profitability improves as bitcoin climbs - including Riot Platforms <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RIOT.O" target="_blank">(RIOT.O)</a>, Marathon Digital <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MARA.O" target="_blank">(MARA.O)</a> and TeraWulf <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/WULF.O" target="_blank">(WULF.O)</a> rose between 1.7% and 4%.翻译:Riot Platforms <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RIOT.O" target="_blank">(RIOT.O)</a> 、Marathon Digital <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MARA.O" target="_blank">(MARA.O)</a>和 TeraWulf <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/WULF.O" target="_blank">(WULF.O)</a>等比特币矿商的股价上涨了 1.7% 至 4%，这些矿商的盈利能力随着比特币的上涨而提高。</p>   <p>J.P.Morgan raised its price targets on Cipher Mining <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/CIFR.O" target="_blank">(CIFR.O)</a>, CleanSpark <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/CLSK.O" target="_blank">(CLSK.O)</a>, Iris Energy <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/IREN.O" target="_blank">(IREN.O)</a>, Marathon Digital and Riot Platforms to reflect the rally in bitcoin.翻译:摩根大通上调了 Cipher Mining <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/CIFR.O" target="_blank">(CIFR.O)</a> 、CleanSpark <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/CLSK.O" target="_blank">(CLSK.O)</a> 、Iris Energy <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/IREN.O" target="_blank">(IREN.O)</a> 、Marathon Digital 和 Riot Platforms 的价格目标，以反映比特币的上涨。</p>   <p>The mining companies are also <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cryptoverse-bitcoin-miners-make-money-ahead-halving-2023-11-14/">increasing production</a> before bitcoin's "halving" event next year, when rewards for producing the tokens are cut in half.翻译:矿业公司也在明年比特币“减半”事件之前<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cryptoverse-bitcoin-miners-make-money-ahead-halving-2023-11-14/">增加产量</a>，届时生产代币的奖励将减少一半。</p>   <p>Coinbase's shares <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/COIN.O" target="_blank">(COIN.O)</a> rose about 2.5% following the 62% jump in November that outperformed bitcoin's 11% climb even as the U.S. crypto exchange reported a decline in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/coinbase-revenue-declines-previous-quarter-trading-volumes-remain-muted-2023-11-02/">trading volume</a> earlier in the month.翻译:Coinbase 的股价<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/COIN.O" target="_blank">(COIN.O)</a>继 11 月份上涨 62% 后，上涨约 2.5%，表现优于比特币 11% 的涨幅，尽管美国加密货币交易所本月早些时候报告<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/coinbase-revenue-declines-previous-quarter-trading-volumes-remain-muted-2023-11-02/">交易量</a>下降。</p>   <p>"Higher crypto prices should lead to a boost in transaction volume and transaction revenues for Coinbase as we enter 2024," said CFRA Research analyst Michael Elliott.翻译:CFRA Research 分析师 Michael Elliott 表示：“进入 2024 年，加密货币价格上涨应该会导致 Coinbase 交易量和交易收入增加。”</p>   <p>However, Elliott cautioned the crypto exchange faces both legal challenges and new regulations that are likely to take time to play out and will continue to result in volatility for the stock.翻译:然而，埃利奥特警告说，加密货币交易所面临着法律挑战和新规定，这些挑战和新规定可能需要时间才能发挥作用，并将继续导致股票波动。</p>   <p>The ETF approval bets have helped counter latest concerns after Changpeng Zhao, the founder of the world's largest crypto exchange, stepped down and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-authorities-set-unveil-settlement-with-binance-source-2023-11-21/">pleaded guilty</a> to breaking U.S. anti-money laundering laws.翻译:全球最大加密货币交易所创始人赵长鹏辞职并<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-authorities-set-unveil-settlement-with-binance-source-2023-11-21/">承认</a>违反美国反洗钱法后，ETF 的批准押注有助于平息最新的担忧。</p>   <p>Among other gainers were U.S. software developer and bitcoin investor Microstrategy <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSTR.O" target="_blank">(MSTR.O)</a>, up nearly 3.5%, and ProShares Bitcoin Strategy ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BITO.P" target="_blank">(BITO.P)</a>, which added 2.1%.翻译:其他上涨者包括美国软件开发商和比特币投资者 Microstrategy <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSTR.O" target="_blank">(MSTR.O)</a> ，上涨近 3.5%，以及 ProShares Bitcoin Strategy ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BITO.P" target="_blank">(BITO.P)</a> ，上涨 2.1%。</p>    <span>Reporting by Medha Singh in Bengaluru; Editing by Sriraj Kalluvila and Krishna Chandra Eluri翻译:Medha Singh 在班加罗尔的报道； Sriraj Kalluvila 和 Krishna Chandra Eluri 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 14:41:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">GOB6CBJIQBKCBDSMLEWG4XTMMU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/crypto-stocks-set-start-december-high-note-bitcoin-hits-near-19-month-high-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CRYPTO STOCKS/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国和越南正在考虑修建穿越稀土中心地带的铁路]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>China's foreign minister visits Hanoi amid plans for Xi's trip</li>  <li>Upgraded rail link may be part of Belt Road</li>  <li>China is top investor in Vietnam despite maritime tensions</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>中国外交部长在习近平访问河内的计划中访问</li><li>升级后的铁路线可能是“一带一路”的一部分</li><li>尽管海上局势紧张，中国仍是越南最大投资者</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0D28hF_KEBAQtfoCT4iVEE39vy0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NR7MBKEHOBMVJIFE4KCXDBJ7VU.jpg" alt="A Vietnamese pupil holds Vietnamese and Chinese flags before the welcoming ceremony at the Presidential Palace in Hanoi翻译:在河内总统府举行的欢迎仪式前，一名越南学生举着越南和中国国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Vietnamese pupil holds Vietnamese and Chinese flags before the welcoming ceremony at the Presidential Palace in Hanoi翻译:在河内总统府举行的欢迎仪式前，一名越南学生举着越南和中国国旗, Vietnam November 12, 2017. REUTERS/Hoang Dinh Nam/Pool/File Photo翻译:2017 年 11 月 12 日，越南河内总统府，一名越南学生在欢迎仪式前举起越南和中国国旗。 REUTERS/Hoang Dinh Nam/Pool/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China and Vietnam are working on a possible significant upgrade of their underdeveloped rail links to boost a line that crosses Vietnam's rare earths heartland and reaches the country's top port in the north, senior officials and diplomats said.翻译:高级官员和外交官表示，中国和越南正在努力对其欠发达的铁路线进行可能的重大升级，以加强一条穿越越南稀土中心地带并到达该国北部主要港口的线路。</p>   <p>The talks are part of preparations for a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/chinas-top-diplomat-wang-yi-visit-vietnam-thursday-sources-2023-11-29/">possible visit</a> to Hanoi in coming weeks by Chinese President Xi Jinping, officials and diplomats said, which would further confirm Vietnam's increasingly strategic role in global supply chains as major powers including the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/news/picture/us-and-vietnam-ink-historic-partnership-idUSKBN30F0GR">United States</a> vie to gain influence there.翻译:官员和外交官表示，这些会谈是中国国家主席习近平未来几周<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/chinas-top-diplomat-wang-yi-visit-vietnam-thursday-sources-2023-11-29/">可能访问</a>河内的准备工作的一部分，这将进一步证实越南在全球供应链中日益重要的战略作用，因为包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/news/picture/us-and-vietnam-ink-historic-partnership-idUSKBN30F0GR">美国</a>在内的主要大国都在争夺在那里的影响力。</p>   <p>The two countries agreed to boost trade ties and promote railways connections, according to a readout published on the Vietnamese government portal on Friday after China's top diplomat Wang Yi met Vietnamese leaders in Hanoi.翻译:中国最高外交官王毅在河内会见越南领导人后，越南政府门户网站上周五发布的消息称，两国同意加强贸易关系并促进铁路连接。</p>   <p>Vietnamese Prime Minister Pham Minh Chinh had previously called for the upgrade of the railway linking Kunming in southern China to Vietnam's port city of Haiphong in a statement released last month, after China's Commerce Minister Wang Wentao made a rare visit to Vietnam.翻译:在中国商务部部长王文涛罕见访问越南后，越南总理范明正在上个月发布的一份声明中呼吁升级连接中国南部昆明和越南港口城市海防的铁路。</p>   <p>Chinese officials have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-says-held-frank-friendly-talks-with-vietnam-bilateral-ties-2023-11-10/">stressed</a> the importance of boosting infrastructure connectivity with their southern neighbour.翻译:中国官员<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-says-held-frank-friendly-talks-with-vietnam-bilateral-ties-2023-11-10/">强调</a>了加强与南方邻国基础设施互联互通的重要性。</p>   <p>Vietnam already has rail connections to China, but the system is old with limited capacity on the Vietnam side. The two systems are also not interoperable at the moment, meaning trains have to stop at the border where passengers and goods are transferred to domestic services.翻译:越南已经与中国建立了铁路连接，但该系统陈旧，越南一侧的运力有限。目前，这两个系统还无法互操作，这意味着火车必须在边境停靠，乘客和货物才能转乘国内服务。</p>   <p>The upgraded railway would pass through the region where Vietnam has its largest deposits of rare earths, of which China is by far the world's biggest refiner.翻译:升级后的铁路将穿过越南拥有最大稀土矿藏的地区，而中国是迄今为止世界上最大的稀土精炼国。</p>   <p>Vietnam is trying to build its own industry in what is seen as a possible challenge to China's dominance, but what appear as internal fights have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/vietnam-rare-earths-arrests-include-key-figure-bid-build-industry-2023-10-20/">cast a shadow</a> over these efforts.翻译:越南正试图建立自己的工业，这被视为可能挑战中国的主导地位，但看似内部的斗争给这些努力<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/vietnam-rare-earths-arrests-include-key-figure-bid-build-industry-2023-10-20/">蒙上了阴影</a>。</p>   <p>Chinese and Vietnamese rare earths industry experts discussed last week stronger cooperation on processing the minerals, according to Vietnamese state media.</p>    <h 1="">BELT AND ROAD TRACK?</h>  <p>It is unclear how much China would contribute to the upgraded railway track in Vietnam and whether Hanoi would accept sizeable financing from Beijing on this.翻译:目前尚不清楚中国将为越南铁路升级改造贡献多少资金，以及河内是否会接受北京方面的巨额融资。</p>   <p>The line could be seen as part of China's flagship Belt and Road Initiative (BRI) which is supporting infrastructure investment across the world, but is not clear whether it would be labelled as a BRI project, one diplomat said.翻译:一位外交官表示，该线路可以被视为中国旗舰“一带一路”倡议的一部分，该倡议正在支持全球基础设施投资，但尚不清楚它是否会被标记为“一带一路”项目。</p>   <p>On Friday, the Vietnamese government said the two countries had completed negotiations to promote connections between infrastructure projects in Vietnam and the BRI.翻译:越南政府周五表示，两国已完成促进越南基础设施项目与“一带一路”倡议对接的谈判。</p>   <p>A strengthened railway link could also boost Vietnam's exports to China, mostly of agriculture products, boost Chinese tourism to northern Vietnam and further integrate the two countries' manufacturing industries, which experts already consider as symbiotic, with factories in Vietnam largely assembling components produced in China.翻译:加强铁路连接还可以促进越南对中国的出口，主要是农产品，促进中国对越南北部的旅游业，并进一步整合两国的制造业，专家已经认为这是共生的，越南的工厂主要组装中国生产的零部件。</p>   <p>China is Vietnam's largest trading partner and so far this year is also the main investor, taking into account investment from Hong Kong, as many Chinese companies <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinese-suppliers-race-vietnam-covid-let-up-opens-escape-route-sino-us-trade-war-2023-03-16/">move south</a> some of their operations amid trade tensions between Beijing and Washington.翻译:中国是越南最大的贸易伙伴，考虑到来自香港的投资，今年迄今为止也是主要投资者，因为许多中国公司在北京和华盛顿之间的贸易紧张局势中将部分业务<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinese-suppliers-race-vietnam-covid-let-up-opens-escape-route-sino-us-trade-war-2023-03-16/">南迁</a>。</p>   <p>Despite the booming economic links, the two communist nations are embroiled in a years-long maritime dispute in the South China Sea and fought a brief war in the late 70s.翻译:尽管经济联系蓬勃发展，但这两个共产主义国家却在南中国海卷入了长达数年的海上争端，并在 70 年代末爆发了短暂的战争。</p>       <span>Reporting Francesco Guarascio and Khanh Vu; additional reporting by Phuong Nguyen; Editing by Stephen Coates and Toby Chopra翻译:报道 Francesco Guarascio 和 Khanh Vu； Phuong Nguyen 的补充报告；斯蒂芬·科茨和托比·乔普拉编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:50:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">JNSCKSYFSZKWHFJJC3DATCNMZM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-vietnam-consider-rail-link-through-rare-earths-heartland-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Francesco Guarascio, Khanh Vu]]></author>
            
                
                <category>VIETNAM</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (UPDATE 2, GRAPHIC, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[亚洲黄金 金价创下历史新高，加剧了印度节后需求的低迷]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>India dealers offer $9/oz discount</li>  <li>China premiums little changed at $25-$35/ounce this week</li>  <li>Sellers emerge as gold prices notch higher - traders</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>印度经销商提供 9 美元/盎司折扣</li><li>本周中国升水几乎没有变化，为 25-35 美元/盎司</li><li>随着金价上涨，卖家出现——交易员</li></ul>     <p>Physical gold dealers in India were forced to offer steeper discounts this week as record high prices accelerated a post-festival slowdown in demand, with the rise in local prices hurting activity in other Asian hubs as well.翻译:印度的实物黄金交易商本周被迫提供更大的折扣，因为创纪录的高价加速了节后需求的放缓，而当地价格的上涨也损害了亚洲其他中心的活动。</p>   <p>Indian dealers offered discounts of up to $9 an ounce over official domestic prices — inclusive of 15% import and 3% sales levies — up from the last week's discounts of $6.翻译:印度经销商提供比国内官方价格最高每盎司 9 美元的折扣（包括 15% 的进口税和 3% 的销售税），高于上周的 6 美元折扣。</p>   <p>Demand was good for a few days after the Diwali festival last month, but rising prices have brought the market to a standstill, a New Delhi-based bullion dealer said.翻译:一位新德里金银交易商表示，上个月排灯节后几天需求良好，但价格上涨导致市场陷入停滞。</p>   <p>Local gold prices hit a record high of 62,675 rupees per 10 grams this week, and have risen more than 11% in two months.翻译:当地金价本周创下每10克62,675卢比的历史新高，两个月内上涨逾11%。</p>   <p>"Buyers are grappling with the sudden surge in prices. They are waiting to see whether prices will sustain at these levels," a Mumbai-based dealer with a bullion importing bank said.翻译:“买家正在努力应对价格的突然飙升。他们正在等待价格是否能维持在目前的水平，”一家金银进口银行的孟买交易商表示。</p>   <p>In top gold consumer China, dealers charged premiums of $25-$35 per ounce over global spot prices , which were hovering near a seven-month peak, versus the $20-$40 premiums last week.翻译:在最大的黄金消费国中国，交易商对全球现货价格收取了每盎司 25 至 35 美元的溢价，该价格徘徊在七个月高点附近，而上周的溢价为 20 至 40 美元。</p>   <p>However, "the absence of new import quotas, the Federal Reserve's interest rate trajectory, and escalating geopolitical and economic risks collectively suggest a positive trend for the gold premium in the coming year," said Bernard Sin, regional director of Greater China at MKS PAMP.翻译:不过，MKS PAMP 大中华区总监 Bernard Sin 表示，“新进口配额的缺失、美联储的利率轨迹以及不断升级的地缘政治和经济风险，共同表明未来一年黄金溢价将呈现积极趋势。” 。</p>   <p>Hong Kong dealers charged $1.00-$2.00 per ounce premiums. In Singapore, premiums rose slightly to $1.25- $3. .翻译:香港经销商收取每盎司 1.00-2.00 美元的溢价。在新加坡，保费小幅上涨至 1.25-3 美元。 。</p>   <p>"We are noticing a slowdown in buying activity (in Singapore) with retailers more willing to sell than buy at this level. Dealers' inventory remains more or less the same week on week," Hugo Pascal, precious metals trader at InProved said.翻译:InProved 贵金属交易员 Hugo Pascal 表示：“我们注意到（新加坡）购买活动放缓，零售商更愿意在这个水平上出售而不是购买。经销商的库存每周基本保持不变。”</p>   <p>In Japan, gold changed hands at anywhere between a $1 discount to $0.5 premium over global spot rates this week.翻译:在日本，本周黄金易手价格较全球现货价格有 1 美元折扣至 0.5 美元溢价之间。</p>    <span>Reporting by Harshit Verma, Anjana Anil in Bengaluru and Rajendra Jadhav in Mumbai, additional reporting by Brijesh Patel; editing by Arpan Varghese and Mrigank Dhaniwala翻译:Harshit Verma、Anjana Anil 在班加罗尔和 Rajendra Jadhav 在孟买的报道，Brijesh Patel 的补充报道；编辑：Arpan Varghese 和 Mrigank Dhaniwala</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:35:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">IKLXYW6BHBPKLMKGR46V5C5AZM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/asia-gold-record-high-gold-prices-add-post-festival-lull-india-demand-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Rajendra Jadhav, Harshit Verma]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ASIA</category>
                
                <category>GOLD/DEMAND (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Signify 将在改造中裁员，每年节省 2 亿欧元]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/LQ_l0vSFdr06zsYaQMgBgDMv0FE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HUZR6BBWJNOJXHKKDADHTX4O5I.jpg" alt="Signify logo is pictured at the headquarters in Eindhoven翻译:Signify 徽标位于埃因霍温总部" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Signify logo is pictured at the headquarters in Eindhoven翻译:Signify 徽标位于埃因霍温总部, Netherlands August 30, 2018. REUTERS/Piroschka van de Wouw/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Signify <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LIGHT.AS" target="_blank">(LIGHT.AS)</a> is to cut jobs as part of a restructuring that is targeting annual savings of 200 million euros ($218 million), sending shares in the world's biggest light maker up as much as 6.6%.翻译:Signify <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LIGHT.AS" target="_blank">(LIGHT.AS)</a>将进行裁员，作为重组的一部分，目标是每年节省 2 亿欧元（2.18 亿美元），这使得这家全球最大的照明制造商的股价上涨了 6.6%。</p>   <p>Signify, spun off from Dutch technology group Philips in 2016, has already been cutting costs, including through layoffs, in response to a sluggish recovery in key market China and lower sales volumes.翻译:2016年从荷兰科技集团飞利浦分拆出来的Signify已经在削减成本，包括通过裁员，以应对中国主要市场复苏缓慢和销量下降的情况。</p>   <p>"We will further adjust the size of our central organisation and reduce our costs to support the company's performance," CEO Eric Rondolat said in a statement.翻译:首席执行官埃里克·朗多拉特(Eric Rondolat)在一份声明中表示：“我们将进一步调整中央组织的规模并降低成本，以支持公司的业绩。”</p>   <p>A company spokesperson told Reuters the plan would involve "some job losses", without providing further details.翻译:公司发言人告诉路透社，该计划将涉及“一些失业”，但没有提供更多细节。</p>   <p>As part of the restructuring there will be four vertical businesses which will aim to enhance speed of execution and focus on customers, the group said.翻译:该集团表示，作为重组的一部分，将有四个垂直业务，旨在提高执行速度并以客户为中心。</p>   <p>The maker of LED lighting systems and electrical components said three of the new units would focus on customers, while the fourth would be dedicated to conventional lighting technologies.翻译:这家 LED 照明系统和电气元件制造商表示，其中三个新部门将专注于客户，而第四个部门将专注于传统照明技术。</p>   <p>Signify's shares rose 5.6% to 28.16 euros at 1110 GMT on Friday, among top performers on Europe's benchmark STOXX 600 index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.STOXX" target="_blank">(.STOXX)</a>.翻译:格林尼治标准时间周五 1110 点，Signify 股价上涨 5.6%，至 28.16 欧元，在欧洲基准 STOXX 600 指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.STOXX" target="_blank">(.STOXX)</a>中表现最佳。</p>   <p>Signify did not disclose how many people would be affected by the revamp, but reiterated its aim to keep non-manufacturing costs within 25%-29% of sales.翻译:Signify 没有透露有多少人会受到此次改造的影响，但重申其目标是将非制造成本控制在销售额的 25%-29% 之内。</p>   <p>In the third quarter, its adjusted indirect costs as a percentage of sales increased by 160 basis points to 30.2%.翻译:第三季度，调整后的间接成本占销售额的百分比增加了160个基点，达到30.2%。</p>   <p>Rondolat had said <a href="https://tinyurl.com/3x62x346" target="_blank">in October</a> that the group was doing whatever it could to return the costs to a targeted range.翻译:Rondolat<a href="https://tinyurl.com/3x62x346" target="_blank">在 10 月份</a>曾表示，该集团正在尽一切努力将成本控制在目标范围内。</p>   <p>J.P. Morgan said the magnitude of the cost saving plan was higher and came in earlier than the brokerage had expected.翻译:摩根大通表示，成本节约计划的规模更大，而且实施时间早于券商预期。</p>   <p>"The new segment structure will also improve the disclosure and bring Signify closer to the customers, " it added.翻译:它补充说：“新的部门结构还将改善信息披露，并使 Signify 更贴近客户。”</p>   <p>The changes will be implemented through 2024, with most of them set to be completed by the second quarter.翻译:这些变化将实施到 2024 年，其中大部分将于第二季度完成。</p>   <p>Signify's nominal sales fell by 13.8% in the third quarter hit by slow demand across its geographies, it said in October.翻译:Signify 10 月份表示，由于各地区需求放缓，第三季度名义销售额下降了 13.8%。</p>   <p>($1 = 0.9179 euros)翻译:（1 美元 = 0.9179 欧元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Diana Mandiá in Gdansk; editing by Milla Nissi and Jane Merriman翻译:戴安娜·曼迪亚 (Diana Mandia) 在格但斯克的报道；米拉·尼西和简·梅里曼编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:33:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">I6Y3DVLIZ5OAZLXIUCU2JZQ5BM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/signify-cut-jobs-revamp-save-200-mln-euros-annually-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Diana Mandia]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SIGNIFY</category>
                
                <category>SAVINGS/ (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[比亚迪12月部分车型补贴、折扣]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/cXwR9N4A-mOz7qq30Hzaka6XQ84=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FAQORN4WYRLFHIEUVLLDEPJNKM.jpg" alt="Auto Shanghai show, in Shanghai翻译:上海车展，上海" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Security guards stand at the BYD booth at the Auto Shanghai show, in Shanghai翻译:上海车展，上海, China April 19, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song翻译:2023 年 4 月 19 日，中国上海，保安人员站在上海车展比亚迪展台前。路透社/Aly Song</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's electric vehicle giant BYD Co Ltd <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002594.SZ" target="_blank">(002594.SZ)</a> on Friday announced subsidies for some models and a discount of up to 20,000 yuan ($2,803) in December for buyers who are switching from oil to electric cars.翻译:中国电动汽车巨头比亚迪有限公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002594.SZ" target="_blank">（002594.SZ）</a>周五宣布对部分车型提供补贴，并为从燃油汽车转向电动汽车的买家提供高达 20,000 元人民币（2,803 美元）的折扣。</p>   <p>BYD in March set a target to sell 3 million vehicles by the end of this year, local media Yicai has reported.翻译:据当地媒体第一财经报道，比亚迪3月份设定了今年年底销售300万辆汽车的目标。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.1353 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.1353 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Brenda Goh and Beijing Newsroom; Editing by Sonali Paul翻译:Brenda Goh 和北京新闻编辑室的报道；索纳利·保罗编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:26:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">Z6VIENTP7ZOJNLORP5GX4VPUZI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-byd-offers-subsidies-discount-some-models-december-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AUTO/BYD (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[英国数据监管机构拒绝因基因组问题调查中国华大基因]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/pJc_2rJjqFzMUzlbPi5VCSkkg7o=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/UH4IJG5M2VLE7JANOJ6UW3O5OA.jpg" alt="Chinese gene firm BGI Group in Beijing翻译:位于北京的中国基因公司华大基因集团" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of Chinese gene firm BGI Group is seen at its building in Beijing, China March 25, 2021. Picture taken March 25, 2021. REUTERS/Carlos Garcia Rawlins/ File photo翻译:2021年3月25日，中国基因公司华大基因集团的标志出现在中国北京的大楼内。图片摄于2021年3月25日。路透社/Carlos Garcia Rawlins/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Britain's data regulator has resisted calls from lawmakers to investigate the prenatal tests of a Chinese gene company over how it handles the genomic data of consumers, letters reviewed by Reuters show.翻译:路透社看到的信件显示，英国数据监管机构拒绝了立法者就一家中国基因公司如何处理消费者基因组数据进行产前测试的呼吁。</p>   <p>Reuters has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/health-china-bgi-dna/">previously reported</a> China's BGI Group was collecting genetic data from millions of women for research on the traits of populations using tests developed in collaboration with the country's military.翻译:路透社<a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/health-china-bgi-dna/">此前曾报道称</a>，中国华大基因集团正在收集数百万女性的基因数据，以便利用与中国军方合作开发的测试来研究人群的特征。</p>   <p>British lawmakers from across the political spectrum had written to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO) to ask for an investigation into privacy concerns around genome sequencing by BGI, citing the July 2021 Reuters report into the prenatal "NIFTY" tests, which detect abnormalities such as Down syndrome in a foetus.翻译:来自不同政治派别的英国立法者已写信给信息专员办公室 (ICO)，要求对华大基因基因组测序的隐私问题进行调查，并援引了 2021 年 7 月路透社对产前“NIFTY”测试的报告，该测试可检测诸如以下异常情况：胎儿患有唐氏综合症。</p>   <p>But in a letter seen by Reuters, the ICO said the threshold of evidence to carry out an investigation had not been reached.翻译:但在路透社看到的一封信中，ICO 表示尚未达到开展调查的证据门槛。</p>   <p>"We have not received any complaints from individuals concerned with how BGI Group have processed their data, and we have not received any evidence indicating that a breach has occurred," the ICO's letter to lawmakers said.翻译:ICO 在给立法者的信中表示：“我们没有收到任何有关 BGI 集团如何处理其数据的个人投诉，也没有收到任何表明发生违规行为的证据。”</p>   <p>Opposition Labour lawmaker Taiwo Owatemi said she was "dismayed" by the decision.翻译:反对党工党议员塔伊沃·奥瓦特米 (Taiwo Owatemi) 表示，她对这一决定感到“沮丧”。</p>   <p>"We are deeply concerned the ICO is not proactively delivering on its duty to protect the public," she said in a letter co-signed by fellow Labour lawmaker Siobhain McDonagh.翻译:她在工党议员西奥本·麦克唐纳 (Siobhain McDonagh) 共同签署的一封信中表示：“我们对 ICO 没有积极履行保护公众的职责深感担忧。”</p>   <p>Britain has so far not followed the likes of the United States which has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-adds-chinese-genetics-company-units-trade-blacklist-2023-03-02/">added</a> three units of BGI Group to its trade blacklist, including the Hong Kong lab where genetic samples from the prenatal tests are processed and stored.翻译:迄今为止，英国尚未效仿美国等国家，将华大基因集团的三个子公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-adds-chinese-genetics-company-units-trade-blacklist-2023-03-02/">列入</a>其贸易黑名单，其中包括处理和储存产前检测基因样本的香港实验室。</p>   <p>BGI said it disagreed with the U.S trade blacklist decision, and said it "does not engage in unethical practices" and denied being involved in human rights abuses, including the surveillance of minority groups.翻译:华大基因表示不同意美国贸易黑名单的决定，并表示“不从事不道德行为”，并否认参与侵犯人权，包括监视少数群体。</p>   <p>"Our labs internationally, including the one in Hong Kong, meet stringent standards in data security," BGI Group said when asked for comment by Reuters about the British lawmakers' concerns and ICO decision.翻译:当路透社要求华大基因就英国立法者的担忧和 ICO 决定发表评论时，华大基因集团表示：“我们的国际实验室，包括香港的实验室，都符合严格的数据安全标准。”</p>   <p>"We have never been asked to provide, nor provided, testing data to Chinese authorities for national security or national defence purposes."翻译:“我们从未被要求或出于国家安全或国防目的向中国当局提供检测数据。”</p>   <p>Asked to comment further on the lawmakers' concerns, the ICO said it would "continue to engage with this issue should further information come to light" and that "international transfers of data remain a focus for the ICO".翻译:当被要求对立法者的担忧进一步发表评论时，ICO 表示，“如果有更多信息曝光，它将继续处理这个问题”，并且“国际数据传输仍然是 ICO 的重点”。</p>   <p>"In addition, we are currently reviewing genomic technologies and the novel and heightened privacy risks they pose," an ICO spokesperson said in an emailed comment.翻译:“此外，我们目前正在审查基因组技术及其带来的新的和更高的隐私风险，”ICO 发言人在一封电子邮件评论中表示。</p>   <p>British Deputy Prime Minister Oliver Dowden has said that Britain is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/britain-may-designate-genomics-sector-critical-infrastructure-2023-09-11/">considering</a> labelling genomics as an area of "critical national infrastructure".翻译:英国副首相奥利弗·道登表示，英国正在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/britain-may-designate-genomics-sector-critical-infrastructure-2023-09-11/">考虑</a>将基因组学标记为“关键国家基础设施”领域。</p>    <span>Reporting by Alistair Smout;
Editing by Alison Williams翻译:阿利斯泰尔·斯莫特报道；艾莉森·威廉姆斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:13:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">NMMYPSOK2NIHXJ4DCRFZERBYKE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/uks-data-regulator-resists-call-investigate-chinas-bgi-over-genomic-concerns-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Alistair Smout]]></author>
            
                
                <category>BRITAIN</category>
                
                <category>POLITICS/GENOMICS</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国习近平要求海警加强海事执法]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Gm8HsJnJfoWb2NNPD1vXLShu8pk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/QCLUQFN42VMHFMKP4X5ZTVV5PI.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>China's President Xi Jinping attends the Leaders Retreat at the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 17, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 17 日，中国国家主席习近平出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会领导人非正式会议。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's President Xi Jinping has said the country's coast guard must enforce maritime law and crack down on "criminal activities" to defend China's territorial sovereignty, state media reported on Friday.翻译:据官方媒体周五报道，中国国家主席习近平表示，中国海警必须执行海事法并打击“犯罪活动”，以捍卫中国的领土主权。</p>   <p>Xi made the comments as he inspected the China Coast Guard's command office for the East China Sea area and the performance of the coast guard's ships by video, Xinhua news agency reported.翻译:据新华社报道，习近平是在视察中国海警东海指挥部和海警舰艇性能时作出上述表示的。</p>   <p>"It is necessary to establish and improve the coordination and cooperation mechanism of maritime law enforcement, severely crack down on illegal and criminal activities at sea," Xi said.翻译:习近平指出，要建立健全海上执法协调配合机制，严厉打击海上违法犯罪活动。</p>   <p>The president also said it is necessary to "pragmatically carry out exchanges and cooperation with foreign countries in maritime law enforcement, and actively participate in international and regional maritime governance."翻译:总统还表示，要“务实开展与国外海上执法交流与合作，积极参与国际和地区海洋治理”。</p>   <p>The Chinese coast guard has had several <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-coast-guard-urges-philippines-stop-infringing-sovereignty-2023-11-10/">confrontations</a> with vessels from the Philippines in disputed territorial waters in the South China Sea.翻译:中国海警已在南海争议领海与菲律宾船只发生数次<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-coast-guard-urges-philippines-stop-infringing-sovereignty-2023-11-10/">对抗</a>。</p>   <p>China's top leader also said it was important to maintain the healthy development of China's marine economy.翻译:中国最高领导人还表示，保持中国海洋经济健康发展非常重要。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ella Cao and Bernard Orr, editing by Christina Fincher and Barbara Lewis翻译:艾拉·曹和伯纳德·奥尔报道，克里斯蒂娜·芬奇和芭芭拉·刘易斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 11:28:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B5H2JOIMZZKVLPPRCUOGKXIZRE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-xi-tells-coast-guard-enforce-maritime-law-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>XI/COASTGUARD (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[菲律宾在南海岛屿上建立新的海岸警卫队站]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/HiC5Q1sdWwaAPLh2ikUzJQgJ_Bw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BRJYFOPHJFNYBNG3K4PUW2FALE.jpg" alt="Philippine Coast Guard flyby over the South China Sea翻译:菲律宾海岸警卫队飞越南海" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An aerial view shows the Philippine-occupied Thitu Island, locally known as Pag-asa, in the contested Spratly Islands, South China Sea, March 9, 2023. REUTERS/Eloisa Lopez/File Photo翻译:2023 年 3 月 9 日，鸟瞰南海有争议的南沙群岛中菲律宾占领的中业岛，当地称为 Pag-asa。REUTERS/Eloisa Lopez/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Philippines has built a new coast guard station on the contested island of Thitu in the South China Sea, boosting its ability to monitor movements of Chinese vessels and aircraft in the busy disputed waterway.翻译:菲律宾在南海有争议的中业岛上建立了一个新的海岸警卫队站，增强了其监控中国船只和飞机在繁忙的争议航道上活动的能力。</p>   <p>As tension mounts over territorial claims in the area, the Philippine coast guard had early this year <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-says-chinese-navy-ship-spotted-near-disputed-island-2023-03-04/">spotted</a> a Chinese navy ship and dozens of militia vessels around the island, one of nine features Manila occupies in the Spratly archipelago.翻译:随着该地区领土主张的紧张局势加剧，菲律宾海岸警卫队今年年初在该岛周围<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-says-chinese-navy-ship-spotted-near-disputed-island-2023-03-04/">发现了</a>一艘中国海军舰艇和数十艘民兵船只，该岛是马尼拉在南沙群岛占据的九个岛礁之一。</p>   <p>Inaugurated on Friday, the new three-storey facility is equipped with state-of-the art technology such as radar, automatic identification, satellite communication, and coastal cameras, the Philippine coast guard said in a statement.翻译:菲律宾海岸警卫队在一份声明中表示，这座新的三层设施于周五落成，配备了雷达、自动识别、卫星通信和沿海摄像机等最先进的技术。</p>   <p>"The behaviour of the Chinese coast guard, People's Liberation Army (PLA) Navy and Chinese militias are sometimes unpredictable," Eduardo Ano, the Philippine national security adviser, said during a visit to the island.翻译:菲律宾国家安全顾问爱德华多·阿诺在访问该岛时表示：“中国海警、中国人民解放军海军和中国民兵的行为有时难以预测。”</p>   <p>"They do not adhere to the international order, to the rule of law," he told reporters on Friday.翻译:“他们不遵守国际秩序和法治，”他周五告诉记者。</p>   <p>"What they're describing as gray-zone tactics ... are pure bullying and it's purely illegal. It's not acceptable in the international order."翻译:“他们所描述的灰色地带策略……纯粹是欺凌行为，完全是非法的。这在国际秩序中是不可接受的。”</p>   <p>The Chinese embassy in Manila did not immediately respond to a request for comment.翻译:中国驻马尼拉大使馆没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Manila's outpost of Thitu is its biggest and most strategically important in the South China Sea, largely claimed by Beijing, despite conflicting territorial claims by several regional nations.翻译:马尼拉的中业岛前哨基地是其在南中国海最大、最具战略意义的前哨基地，尽管该地区多个国家的领土主张存在冲突，但北京主要声称对南海拥有主权。</p>   <p>Known locally as Pag-asa, Thitu lies about 300 miles (480 km) west of the Philippine province of Palawan. Home to about 200 people, it is used by Manila to maintain its territorial claim.翻译:中业岛在当地被称为 Pag-asa，位于菲律宾巴拉望省以西约 300 英里（480 公里）处。这里居住着约 200 人，马尼拉用它来维持其领土主张。</p>   <p>Besides the Philippines, Brunei, China, Malaysia, Taiwan and Vietnam have competing claims of sovereignty in the South China Sea, a conduit for goods in excess of $3 trillion every year.翻译:除菲律宾外，文莱、中国、马来西亚、台湾和越南也对南海提出主权主张，南海是每年超过 3 万亿美元商品的通道。</p>    <span>Reporting by Karen Lema and Mikhail Flores; Editing by Clarence Fernandez翻译:凯伦·莱玛 (Karen Lema) 和米哈伊尔·弗洛雷斯 (Mikhail Flores) 报道；克拉伦斯·费尔南德斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 10:45:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4WXOAKKCH5MP3EAX35XEVIK5OA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-builds-new-coast-guard-station-island-south-china-sea-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SOUTHCHINA</category>
                
                <category>PHILIPPINES/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：中国在选举前以廉价旅行吸引数百名台湾政客]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/pa9QKUhYqtrLkobYVRv6wnx8_6Q=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/INDAJXSXVNOHRP7KVZEIEFC54M.jpg" alt="People walk near a fluttering Taiwanese flag outside the Sun Yat-Sen Memorial Hall in Taipei翻译:人们在台北国父纪念馆外走过飘扬的台湾国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk near a fluttering Taiwanese flag outside the Sun Yat-Sen Memorial Hall in Taipei翻译:人们在台北国父纪念馆外走过飘扬的台湾国旗, Taiwan November 16, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Garcia Rawlins/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Beijing has sponsored cut-price trips to China for hundreds of Taiwanese politicians ahead of key elections on the island, according to Taiwan sources and documents, unnerving officials with a broad campaign that one called "election interference".翻译:据台湾消息人士和文件称，北京在岛上的重大选举之前赞助了数百名台湾政界人士前往中国大陆的低价旅行，这场被称为“选举干预”的广泛活动让官员们感到不安。</p>   <p>President Tsai Ing-wen and other Taiwan officials have warned that China might try to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-alert-chinese-funded-election-interference-2023-06-21/">sway voters</a> toward candidates seeking closer ties with Beijing in the elections, which could define the island's relations with China. But the scale of the Chinese activity has not previously been reported.翻译:总统蔡英文和其他台湾官员警告说，中国可能会试图在选举中<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-alert-chinese-funded-election-interference-2023-06-21/">引导选民</a>支持寻求与北京建立更密切关系的候选人，这可能会决定台湾与中国的关系。但此前并未报道过中国活动的规模。</p>   <p>Beijing, which claims democratically governed Taiwan as its own and has ramped up military and political pressure to force the island to accept its sovereignty, frames the Jan. 13 presidential and legislative elections as a choice between "peace and war", calling the ruling party dangerous separatists and urging Taiwanese to make the "right choice".翻译:北京声称对台湾实行民主治理，并加大了军事和政治压力，迫使台湾接受其主权，并将1月13日的总统和立法院选举视为“和平与战争”之间的选择，并称执政党危险的分裂分子并敦促台湾人做出“正确的选择”。</p>   <p>Taiwanese law forbids election campaigns from receiving money from "external hostile forces", including China, and prosecutors in southern Taiwan this week said they were investigating 22 people, including grassroots politicians, for potential violations of election and security laws.翻译:台湾法律禁止竞选活动接受来自包括中国在内的“外部敌对势力”的资金，台湾南部检察官本周表示，他们正在调查包括草根政客在内的 22 人，涉嫌违反选举法和安全法。</p>   <p>Across Taiwan security agencies are looking into more than 400 visits to China in the past month, most led by local opinion leaders such as borough chiefs and village heads, a Taiwan security official looking into China's activities told Reuters.翻译:一名调查中国活动的台湾安全官员告诉路透社，过去一个月，台湾各地的安全机构正在调查 400 多次对中国的访问，其中大多数是由当地意见领袖（例如区长和村长）领导的。</p>   <p>The agencies believe the trips, with discounted accommodations, transportation and meals, were subsidised by units under China's Taiwan Affairs Office, said the person, who requested anonymity due to the sensitivity of the matter.翻译:该人士表示，这些机构认为，这些住宿、交通和餐饮折扣的旅行是由中国台湾事务办公室下属单位提供补贴的。由于此事敏感，该人士要求匿名。</p>   <p>The Chinese office did not respond to a request for comment. It has previously said it respects Taiwan's "social systems" when commenting on the elections.翻译:中国办公室没有回应置评请求。它此前曾表示在评论选举时尊重台湾的“社会制度”。</p>   <p>Asked for comment, Taiwan's Mainland Affairs Council, the top China-policy body, referred Reuters to comments this week by its minister, Chiu Tai-san. He said it was "self-evident" Beijing was trying to sway Taiwan elections through means including free trips for politicians.翻译:在被要求置评时，台湾最高的中国政策机构陆委会向路透社转介了其部长邱大山本周的评论。他表示，北京试图通过政客免费旅行等手段影响台湾选举，这是“不言而喻的”。</p>   <p>"They have already made it clear that a so-called 'right choice' has to be made, meaning choosing candidates that the Chinese Communist Party prefers," he told reporters without elaborating.</p>    <h 1="">'ELECTION INTERFERENCE'</h>  <p>People taking these trips typically pay their own airfare, but other expenses are offered by Chinese authorities, officials looking into the matter said.翻译:调查此事的官员表示，参加这些旅行的人通常自己支付机票费用，但其他费用由中国当局提供。</p>   <p>"Election interference has started under the name of group tours," said a second Taiwan security official, who was briefed on the matter, adding Beijing was targeting politicians crucial to the island's administrative systems who play key roles in shaping public opinion.翻译:另一位获悉此事的台湾安全官员表示：“选举干扰是以团体旅游的名义开始的。”他补充说，北京的目标是对台湾行政系统至关重要的政客，他们在塑造公众舆论方面发挥着关键作用。</p>   <p>More than 300 borough chiefs or village heads from populous central Taiwan alone have participated in such trips to China in the past few months, this person said.翻译:这位人士称，过去几个月，仅人口稠密的台湾中部就有超过 300 名区长或村长参加了此类中国之行。</p>   <p>More than 20 borough chiefs from a district of the capital Taipei joined a China-sponsored trip to Shanghai with their families in September, while more than 10 people from an association for local politicians in neighbouring New Taipei City joined a trip this week, according to two security reports reviewed by Reuters.翻译:据报道，9月份，来自首都台北一个区的20多名区长与家人一起参加了中国赞助的上海之旅，而邻近的新北市地方政治家协会的10多名人士本周也参加了一次旅行。路透社审阅了两份安全报告。</p>   <p>The number from the Taipei district has "increased significantly" compared with elections four years ago and registrations have been "fairly enthusiastic", one report said. "Certain borough chiefs have become the window of contacts in Taiwan for some Chinese units."翻译:一份报告称，与四年前的选举相比，台北选区的人数“显着增加”，登记“相当热情”。 “某些区长已成为一些中方单位在台的联络窗口。”</p>   <p>So far this year, more than 1,000 borough chiefs or village heads joined such trips, more than last time, the second official said, adding China was targeting electoral districts where support was strong for candidates campaigning for closer China ties.</p>    <h 1="">HARD TO BUILD A LEGAL CASE</h>  <p>In the investigation in the southern city of Kaohsiung, prosecutors said they believed the five trips from there were fully funded by China's Taiwan Affairs Office.翻译:在南部城市高雄的调查中，检察官表示，他们相信从那里出发的五次旅行完全由中国台湾事务办公室资助。</p>   <p>Chinese officials allegedly asked participants to support certain political parties and "oppose Taiwan independence", the prosecutors said in a statement.翻译:检察官在一份声明中表示，据称中国官员要求参与者支持某些政党并“反对台独”。</p>   <p>"There is no such thing as a free lunch," Prosecutor-General Hsing Tai-chao said on Thursday. He said external forces were trying to influence citizens in an "unprecedented fashion" and urged Taiwanese not to accept perks or instructions from Chinese authorities when travelling there.翻译:“天下没有免费的午餐，”检察长邢台超周四表示。他表示，外部势力正试图以“前所未有的方式”影响公民，并敦促台湾人在台湾旅行时不要接受中国当局的福利或指示。</p>   <p>Building criminal cases against trip-takers is challenging, security officials said, because it can be hard to establish a money trail to Chinese state agencies behind the tours, which often come much below going market rate, and to establish what was said during meetings with Chinese officials.翻译:安全官员表示，对旅游者提起刑事诉讼具有挑战性，因为很难确定旅游背后的中国国家机构的资金来源（这些资金往往远低于市场价格），也很难确定在与旅游团的会面中所说的内容。中国官员。</p>   <p>Taiwan suspended group tours to China via travel agencies after the COVID-19 pandemic, but there are no restrictions on individuals visiting.翻译:COVID-19 大流行后，台湾暂停了通过旅行社前往中国的团体旅游，但对个人旅游没有限制。</p>   <p>Recent government scrutiny has prompted some politicians to be more low-key about such trips, the two officials said, with some making arrangements separately, then gathering in China.翻译:两位官员表示，最近政府的审查促使一些政界人士对此类访问更加低调，其中一些人分别做出安排，然后聚集在中国。</p>   <p>"They now even avoid sitting in seats next to one another during their flight."翻译:“他们现在甚至避免在飞行过程中坐在彼此相邻的座位上。”</p>    <span>Reporting By Yimou Lee; Additional reporting by Ben Blanchard; Editing by William Mallard翻译:李艺谋报道；本·布兰查德 (Ben Blanchard) 的补充报道；威廉·马拉德编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 07:10:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TQ3XPAN6RFJ3PG3OOANZHULO2Q</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-lures-hundreds-taiwan-politicians-with-cheap-trips-before-election-sources-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Yimou Lee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>TAIWAN</category>
                
                <category>ELECTION/CHINA (EXCLUSIVE, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[调查显示，11月份中国新建住宅价格连续第三个月上涨]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/8AvfZqMNkJxaKzUuTVC1A3mJfcY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/AHFGX532RRMZNCMIOA45SMLXYE.jpg" alt="A man works near apartment blocks under construction on the outskirts of Beijing翻译:一名男子在北京郊区正在建设的公寓楼附近工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A man works near apartment blocks under construction on the outskirts of Beijing翻译:一名男子在北京郊区正在建设的公寓楼附近工作, China December 16, 2017. REUTERS/Jason Lee/File Photo翻译:2017 年 12 月 16 日，一名男子在中国北京郊区正在建设的公寓楼附近工作。路透社/Jason Lee/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's new home prices rose slightly for a third straight month in November, a private survey showed on Friday, as the crisis-hit property sector struggles to stabilise despite a slew of government support measures.翻译:周五的一项私人调查显示，中国11月份新房价格连续第三个月小幅上涨，尽管政府采取了一系列支持措施，但受危机打击的房地产行业仍难以企稳。</p>   <p>Prices rose 0.05% on average from the previous month after gains of 0.07% and 0.05%, according to the survey by real estate research firm China Index Academy.翻译:房地产研究公司中国指数研究院的调查显示，继上涨0.07%和0.05%之后，价格平均环比上涨0.05%。</p>   <p>Only 38 of the 100 cities surveyed reported increases in new home prices.翻译:接受调查的 100 个城市中，只有 38 个城市报告新房价格上涨。</p>   <p>China's property sector, which makes up about one-quarter of the world's second-biggest economy, has stumbled from crisis to crisis in a major blow to consumer and investor confidence, keeping economic growth from resuming a solid footing this year.翻译:中国的房地产行业约占全球第二大经济体的四分之一，该行业在一次又一次的危机中陷入困境，对消费者和投资者的信心造成重大打击，导致今年的经济增长无法恢复稳固的基础。</p>   <p>Government support for the property sector in recent months has included easing curbs on home purchases and cutting mortgage costs.翻译:近几个月来，政府对房地产行业的支持包括放松购房限制和降低抵押贷款成本。</p>   <p>China Index Academy said in a report the policy direction for the national property market was clear, and support from the supply and demand sides was expected to continue until the market shows recovery.翻译:中国指数研究院在报告中表示，全国楼市政策方向明确，供需双方的支持预计将持续到市场出现复苏。</p>   <p>A <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-new-home-prices-now-seen-climbing-this-year-after-policy-steps-2023-11-29/">Reuters poll</a> on Wednesday found expectations for 1% growth in new home prices next year, little changed from an August poll.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-new-home-prices-now-seen-climbing-this-year-after-policy-steps-2023-11-29/">路透社周三的一项民意调查</a>显示，明年新房价格增长 1% 的预期与 8 月份的民意调查相比几乎没有变化。</p>   <p>"Beijing is turning more proactive to stabilise growth and the new dual-track housing model may help stabilise the property sector in the coming quarters," HSBC said on Thursday.翻译:汇丰银行周四表示：“北京正在更加积极主动地稳定经济增长，新的双轨住房模式可能有助于在未来几个季度稳定房地产行业。”</p>   <p>"This includes making affordable housing accessible and allowing the commercial real estate to return to its commercial nature, i.e., it could be for living or for speculation."翻译:“这包括提供经济适用房，并让商业地产回归其商业性质，即可以用于居住，也可以用于投机。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Liangping Gao and Ryan Woo; Editing by William Mallard翻译:高亮平、吴瑞安报道；威廉·马拉德编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:38:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">QX5IUV4F65NDBKZZDHB6ZD37CU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-new-home-prices-inch-up-third-month-november-survey-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/HOMEPRICES</category>
                
                <category>SURVEY (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国恒大债权人在新提案中寻求控股权]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/m6X12UWexYPh8qKO7fVksXbuc0Q=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GM262RZCLBJI3K4YRH47BUT2BU.jpg" alt="An Evergrande sign is seen near residential buildings at an Evergrande residential complex in Beijing翻译:北京恒大住宅小区附近的恒大标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An Evergrande sign is seen near residential buildings at an Evergrande residential complex in Beijing翻译:北京恒大住宅小区附近的恒大标志, China September 27, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo翻译:2023 年 9 月 27 日，中国北京恒大住宅小区的住宅楼附近出现了恒大标志。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A group of offshore creditors to China Evergrande Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a> is asking for a controlling equity stake of the developer and two of its Hong Kong subsidiaries as part of company's revised debt restructuring proposal, a source familiar with the matter said on Friday.翻译:一位知情人士周五表示，中国恒大集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）</a>的一组海外债权人正在要求获得该开发商及其两家香港子公司的控股权，作为该公司修订后的债务重组方案的一部分。</p>   <p>Bloomberg News first reported the request on Friday, citing people familiar with the matter.翻译:彭博新闻社周五首先援引知情人士的话报道了这一请求。</p>   <p>The group, which works as an ad hoc group of Evergrande's offshore creditors, made the request after the developer earlier this week made a new offer to repay their offshore debts, the source said.翻译:消息人士称，该小组是恒大海外债权人的一个特别小组，在恒大本周早些时候提出偿还其海外债务的新提议后，提出了这一要求。</p>   <p>Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-seeks-avoid-liquidation-with-last-ditch-debt-plan-sources-2023-11-30/">reported</a> on Thursday that Evergrande had offered to swap some offshore debt into equity in the company and two Hong Kong-listed units, and repay the rest with non-tradeable "certificates" backed by offshore assets.翻译:路透社周四<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-seeks-avoid-liquidation-with-last-ditch-debt-plan-sources-2023-11-30/">报道称</a>，恒大集团已提出将部分离岸债务转换为该公司和两家香港上市子公司的股权，并以离岸资产支持的不可交易“证书”偿还其余部分。</p>   <p>Evergrande has until a Hong Kong court hearing on Monday to present a "concrete" revised debt restructuring proposal for offshore creditors, a judge said last month after its original plan had lapsed.翻译:上个月，在恒大原计划失效后，一名法官表示，恒大必须在周一香港法庭听证会上向海外债权人提交一份“具体的”修订后的债务重组方案。</p>   <p>The source declined to be named as the discussions were private.翻译:由于讨论是私下进行，消息人士拒绝透露姓名。</p>   <p>Evergrande declined to comment.翻译:恒大拒绝置评。</p>    <span>Reporting by Xie Yu in Hong Kong, Gnaneshwar Rajan in Bengaluru; Editing by Stephen Coates翻译:谢宇香港报道、Gnaneshwar Rajan 班加罗尔报道；斯蒂芬·科茨编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:24:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">NYK4CJFYARKW5G3HCYHZYLHNXI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-creditors-seek-controlling-stakes-new-proposal-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/DEBT</category>
                
                <category>CHINA EVERGRANDE (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[马来西亚邀请中国习近平访华并提高旅游目标]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/YClWBr6H241GzRhsiaMgliLOAeM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/QE7YGD7ZPRLLDPSOPYKVMKLPRI.jpg" alt="Journalists watch a giant screen broadcasting footage of Chinese President Xi Jinping at the opening ceremony of BRF in Beijing翻译:记者在北京举行的高峰论坛开幕式上观看大屏幕播放中国国家主席习近平的镜头" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Journalists watch a giant screen broadcasting footage of Chinese President Xi Jinping speaking at the opening ceremony of the Third Belt and Road Forum (BRF), at the media centre in Beijing, China October 18, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File photo翻译:2023年10月18日，中国北京媒体中心，记者们观看中国国家主席习近平在第三届“一带一路”论坛开幕式上讲话的大屏幕。路透社/Tingshu Wang/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Malaysia has invited China's President Xi Jingping to visit, its ambassador to Beijing said on Friday, as the Southeast Asian country also seeks to boost the number of Chinese tourists to five million a year to fuel economic growth.翻译:马来西亚驻北京大使周五表示，马来西亚已邀请中国国家主席习近平访问，该东南亚国家还寻求将中国游客数量增加到每年 500 万人次，以推动经济增长。</p>   <p>China and Malaysia will mark the 50th anniversary of their bilateral diplomatic relations next year, and Malaysia recently <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/malaysia-allow-visa-free-entry-china-india-citizens-dec-1-pm-2023-11-27/">announced</a> tourists from China would be able to travel visa free for 30 days, a move mirroring Thailand.翻译:中国和马来西亚明年将庆祝双边建交50周年，马来西亚最近<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/malaysia-allow-visa-free-entry-china-india-citizens-dec-1-pm-2023-11-27/">宣布</a>中国游客将可以免签旅行30天，此举与泰国类似。</p>   <p>Government data showed Malaysia welcomed 498,540 Chinese tourists in the six months to June this year, a figure almost a third of pre-pandemic levels. In comparison, Thailand said it expected 3.4-3.5 million visitors from China this year.翻译:政府数据显示，今年截至6月的六个月内，马来西亚接待了498,540名中国游客，这一数字几乎是大流行前水平的三分之一。相比之下，泰国预计今年将有 340 至 350 万名中国游客。</p>   <p>"We see that we have a big capacity to receive tourists," Ambassador Norman Muhamad said at an event at the Malaysian embassy in Beijing, adding that the goal is not "far-fetched" even if it may take more than a couple of years to achieve.翻译:大使诺曼·穆罕默德在马来西亚驻北京大使馆举行的一次活动中表示：“我们看到我们有很大的接待游客的能力。”他补充说，这一目标并不“牵强”，即使可能需要几年以上的时间实现。</p>   <p>"Since we are seeking more investment from China, this visa-free travel to Malaysia will also help Chinese investors to come to Malaysia to find opportunities," he added.翻译:他补充说：“由于我们正在寻求更多来自中国的投资，马来西亚的免签证旅行也将有助于中国投资者来马来西亚寻找机会。”</p>   <p>Malaysia's economic growth is expected to meet the government's target of 4% this year, driven in part by stronger tourism.翻译:马来西亚今年的经济增长预计将达到政府 4% 的目标，部分原因是旅游业的强劲增长。</p>   <p>Malaysia's Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim has also invited China's President Xi Jinping to visit the country, Norman said.翻译:诺曼说，马来西亚总理安瓦尔·易卜拉欣还邀请中国国家主席习近平访问该国。</p>   <p>"We are hoping that President Xi will consent to visiting Malaysia," he added.翻译:“我们希望习主席同意访问马来西亚，”他补充道。</p>   <p>Earlier this week, China's foreign minister Wang Yi was seen holding hands with his Malaysian counterpart Zambry Abdul Kadir in New York, <a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/wjbzhd/202311/t20231129_11188982.shtml" target="_blank">photos</a> released by the Chinese foreign ministry show.翻译:中国外交部发布的<a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/wjbzhd/202311/t20231129_11188982.shtml" target="_blank">照片</a>​​显示，本周早些时候，中国外交部长王毅在纽约与马来西亚外长赞布里·阿卜杜勒·卡迪尔手牵着手。</p>    <span>Reporting by Liz Lee, Bernard Orr and Ethan Wang; Editing by Jacqueline Wong and Miral Fahmy翻译:Liz Lee、Bernard Orr 和 Ethan Wang 报道；编辑：Jacqueline Wong 和 Miral Fahmy</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 05:46:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">VC6T7RMJMJJF3IJJ4YEKNYK7RM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/malaysia-invites-chinas-xi-visit-ramps-up-tourism-target-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Liz Lee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>MALAYSIA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[对比中国 11 月工厂调查凸显需要采取更强有力的刺激措施]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/5-_t0LZrr7dSATflCTBGaSLapN0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/N5ZTDIW3YNNQJIG3FYWHT5DWE4.jpg" alt="Worker welds automobile parts at a workshop manufacturing automobile accessories in Huaibei, Anhui翻译:安徽淮北一家汽车配件生产车间，工人焊接汽车零部件" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A worker welds automobile parts at a workshop manufacturing automobile accessories in Huaibei, Anhui province, China June 28, 2019. Picture taken June 28, 2019. REUTERS/Stringer/File Photo翻译:2019年6月28日，中国安徽省淮北市，一名工人在汽车配件生产车间焊接汽车零部件。照片摄于2019年6月28日。REUTERS/Stringer/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Mixed factory activity data for China in November suggests more stimulus will be needed to shore up economic growth, analysts said on Friday, as two surveys came to contrasting conclusions on the sector's health.翻译:分析师周五表示，中国 11 月份工厂活动数据好坏参半，表明需要采取更多刺激措施来支撑经济增长，因为两项调查对该行业健康状况得出了截然不同的结论。</p>   <p>China's economy has struggled to mount a strong post-COVID recovery due to an ailing housing market, local government debt risks and slow global growth. That has squeezed factory owners who have had to contend with high input costs, overcapacity, soft demand, and officials prioritising rescuing other parts of the economy.翻译:由于房地产市场不景气、地方政府债务风险和全球经济增长放缓，中国经济在疫情后难以实现强劲复苏。这对工厂主造成了压力，他们不得不应对高投入成本、产能过剩、需求疲软以及优先拯救经济其他部分的官员。</p>   <p>The Caixin/S&amp;P Global manufacturing purchasing managers' index (PMI) unexpectedly rose to 50.7 in November from a 49.5 reading in October.翻译:财新/标普全球制造业采购经理人指数 (PMI) 意外从 10 月份的 49.5 升至 11 月份的 50.7。</p>   <p>That was the fastest expansion in three months, but stands in contrast to the official PMI which <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-factory-activity-contracts-second-month-november-2023-11-30/">fell</a> to 49.4 on Thursday. The 50-point mark separates growth from contraction.翻译:这是三个月来最快的扩张，但与周四<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-factory-activity-contracts-second-month-november-2023-11-30/">跌至</a>49.4 的官方 PMI 形成鲜明对比。 50分是增长与收缩的分界线。</p>   <p>"At face value, the average of the two is consistent with factory activity remaining largely unchanged last month," said Sheana Yue, China economist at Capital Economics.翻译:凯投宏观(Capital Economics)中国经济学家谢娜·岳(Sheana Yue)表示：“从表面上看，两者的平均值与上个月工厂活动基本保持不变是一致的。”</p>   <p>"But that may not be the case in practice - the hard data have held up better than survey-based measures lately."翻译:“但实际情况可能并非如此——硬数据最近比基于调查的措施更有效。”</p>   <p>The official and Caixin surveys have different samples, with the Caixin PMI focusing on export-oriented enterprises and small- and medium-sized enterprises in the country's coastal region.翻译:官方和财新调查的样本不同，财新PMI主要针对沿海地区的出口导向型企业和中小企业。</p>   <p>"The economy is running at different speeds across industries, though we expect the policy stance to remain proactive which will help to sustain overall growth momentum into the coming quarters," economists at HSBC said on Thursday.翻译:汇丰银行经济学家周四表示：“各行业经济运行速度不同，但我们预计政策立场将保持积极主动，这将有助于维持未来几个季度的整体增长势头。”</p>   <p>The Caixin survey data was supported by the quickest rise since June in new orders received by Chinese goods producers in November, but in the official survey new orders dipped back into contraction.翻译:财新调查数据得到了11月份中国商品生产商收到的新订单自6月份以来最快增长的支撑，但官方调查显示新订单再次陷入萎缩。</p>   <p>The official survey has contracted for seven out of the past eight months, while the Caixin survey has been more volatile, dipping in and out of contraction three times over the same period.翻译:过去八个月中，官方调查有七个月出现收缩，而财新调查的波动性更大，同一时期内出现了三次收缩。</p>   <p>The last time the official indicator was negative for more than three consecutive months was in the six months to October 2019, suggesting pessimism has become entrenched among some factory owners.翻译:官方指标上一次连续三个月以上为负值是在截至2019年10月的六个月内，这表明一些工厂主的悲观情绪已经根深蒂固。</p>   <p>"I don't think there can be a fix," said Dan Wang, chief economist at Hang Seng Bank China on Thursday, warning factory activity was unlikely to improve anytime soon as other economic problems dominate.翻译:恒生银行中国首席经济学家王丹周四表示：“我认为没有解决办法。”他警告说，由于其他经济问题占主导地位，工厂活动不太可能很快改善。</p>   <p>"The priority now is clearly containing the local government debt risk and the risk posed by regional banks."翻译:“现在的首要任务显然是控制地方政府债务风险和地方银行带来的风险。”</p>   <p>China's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">consumer prices</a> swung lower in October, as key gauges of domestic demand pointed to weakness not seen since the pandemic, while factory-gate deflation deepened.翻译:中国十月份的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">消费者价格</a>下跌，因为国内需求的关键指标显示出自疫情大流行以来未见的疲软，同时工厂通货紧缩加剧。</p>   <p>In a nod to the need to step up support for industry, Chinese president Xi Jinping <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-xi-calls-yangtze-river-delta-economic-energy-powerhouse-2023-11-30/">visited</a> the Yangtze River Delt region on Thursday. He called for closer integration across the sprawling industrial hub encompassing several major cities with millions of people, as well as China's biggest port in Shanghai.翻译:为了加强对工业的支持，中国国家主席习近平周四<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-xi-calls-yangtze-river-delta-economic-energy-powerhouse-2023-11-30/">访问了</a>长江三角洲地区。他呼吁在这个庞大的工业中心进行更紧密的整合，其中包括几个拥有数百万人口的主要城市以及中国最大的港口上海。</p>   <p>But weak external demand remained an important factor affecting factory activity in both surveys, with the new export index registering 49.0 and contracting for a fifth consecutive month in November in the Caixin survey and 46.8 in the official one.翻译:但两次调查中，外部需求疲软仍然是影响工厂活动的重要因素，财新调查显示，11月份新出口指数为49.0，连续第五个月收缩，官方调查为46.8。</p>   <p>Payroll cuts in the sector persisted for the third month in the Caixin survey and a ninth month in the official PMI.翻译:财新调查显示，该行业已连续第三个月出现裁员，官方 PMI 数据显示，该行业已连续第九个月出现裁员。</p>    <span>Reporting by Liangping Gao and Joe Cash; Editing by Jacqueline Wong and Lincoln Feast.翻译:高亮平和乔·卡什的报道；杰奎琳·王和林肯·费斯特编辑。</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 03:38:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">LQBJNJPTBJLRPPIASGOSD6AWKA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-activity-surprisingly-expands-november-caixin-pmi-2023-12-01/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Liangping Gao, Joe Cash]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/PMI</category>
                
                <category>CAIXIN (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
