<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 16:29:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[拜登称习主席会晤的目标是恢复正常沟通]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/SFmRtqPmpDU0oQvqzVeyXmjCW8Y=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/RB5ZXO6VRJPJVKYIQJAO7VQMEY.jpg" alt="G20 summit in Bali翻译:G20巴厘岛峰会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of the G20 leaders' summit in Bali, Indonesia, November 14, 2022.  REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque/File Photo翻译:美国总统乔·拜登于 2022 年 11 月 14 日在印度尼西亚巴厘岛举行的 G20 领导人峰会期间会见中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S. President Joe Biden said on Tuesday his goal during talks with Chinese President Xi Jinping this week is to resume normal communications between the two superpowers, including military-to-military contacts.翻译:美国总统乔·拜登周二表示，他本周与中国国家主席习近平会谈的目标是恢复两个超级大国之间的正常沟通，包括军事接触。</p>   <p>Speaking to reporters after remarks on climate change at the White House, Biden said he is trying to change the U.S. relationship with China for the better, after a period of strained ties. The two leaders meet on Wednesday in the San Francisco area.翻译:拜登在白宫就气候变化发表讲话后对记者表示，在经历了一段时间的紧张关系后，他正在努力让美中关系变得更好。两位领导人周三在旧金山地区会面。</p>    <span>Reporting by Andrea Shalal and Steve Holland; Editing by Chizu Nomiyama翻译:安德里亚·沙拉尔和史蒂夫·霍兰德报道；编辑：野宫千津</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 16:08:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RJDCB6GNGBKALJQAZKZIEASA44</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-says-goal-xi-meeting-is-resume-normal-communications-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>SUMMIT/BIDEN (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国通胀数据疲弱后，华尔街和欧洲股市飙升]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ItQxZFQLmBqVfiQQB949qnzBRZU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/77MCTTZKNRP7DILM2MYZY2AZ2M.jpg" alt="A street sign for Wall Street hangs in front of the New York Stock Exchange翻译:纽约证券交易所前悬挂着华尔街的路牌" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A street sign for Wall Street hangs in front of the New York Stock Exchange翻译:纽约证券交易所前悬挂着华尔街的路牌 May 8, 2013. REUTERS/Lucas Jackson/File Photo翻译:2013 年 5 月 8 日，纽约证券交易所前悬挂着华尔街的路标。路透社/卢卡斯·杰克逊/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/HpoUHi0XooVGUvgYzw8hqfadOfo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/LJICNHJPUJM5DPR3JJPGUZV62I.jpg" alt="People walk past the London Stock Exchange Group offices in the City of London, Britain翻译:人们走过英国伦敦金融城的伦敦证券交易所集团办公室" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk past the London Stock Exchange Group offices in the City of London, Britain翻译:人们走过英国伦敦金融城的伦敦证券交易所集团办公室, December 29, 2017. REUTERS/Toby Melville</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/8ZJvzLv1Z8S2nWZwdUAeaW3w2Ck=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/H3NFM5EQBRIVNGAREZACU6XADY.jpg" alt="People walk past a screen displaying the Hang Seng stock index at Central district, in Hong Kong翻译:人们走过香港中环显示恒生股票指数的屏幕" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk past a screen displaying the Hang Seng stock index at Central district, in Hong Kong翻译:人们走过香港中环显示恒生股票指数的屏幕, China October 25, 2022. REUTERS/Lam Yik/File Photo</figcaption></figure>                 <p>World stocks soared on Tuesday after U.S. inflation data came in cooler than forecast in October, fuelling investor bets that an era of interest rate rises is over and borrowing costs may even soon start to fall.翻译:美国10月份通胀数据低于预期后，世界股市周二飙升，投资者押注加息时代已经结束，借贷成本甚至可能很快开始下降。</p>   <p>Data showed <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-consumer-prices-unchanged-october-2023-11-14/">U.S. consumer prices</a> were unchanged in October amid lower gasoline prices, while underlying inflation showed signs of slowing. Excluding volatile food and energy components, the CPI increased 0.2% amid higher costs for rental housing. Analysts polled by Reuters had expected a 0.3% gain.翻译:数据显示，由于汽油<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-consumer-prices-unchanged-october-2023-11-14/">价格下跌，美国十月份消费者价格</a>没有变化，而潜在通胀显示出放缓迹象。剔除波动较大的食品和能源成分后，由于租赁住房成本上涨，CPI 上涨 0.2%。路透社调查的分析师此前预计将上涨 0.3%。</p>   <p>By 1452 GMT, the MSCI World Equity index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIWD00000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIWD00000PUS)</a> surged 1.7%, its best day in almost two weeks.翻译:截至格林威治标准时间 1452，MSCI 世界股票指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIWD00000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIWD00000PUS)</a>飙升 1.7%，这是近两周来最好的一天。</p>   <p>Stocks also rallied across the board <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-edge-higher-ahead-inflation-data-2023-11-14/">on Wall Street</a>. The S&amp;P 500 index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a> leapt 1.7%, the Dow Jones Industrial Average <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DJI" target="_blank">(.DJI)</a> jumped 1.4%, and the Nasdaq Composite Index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.IXIC" target="_blank">(.IXIC)</a> bounded 2.2%, on track for its best day in about six months.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-edge-higher-ahead-inflation-data-2023-11-14/">华尔街</a>股市也全线上涨。标准普尔 500 指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a>上涨 1.7%，道琼斯工业平均指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DJI" target="_blank">(.DJI)</a>上涨 1.4%，纳斯达克综合指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.IXIC" target="_blank">(.IXIC)</a>上涨 2.2%，有望创下约六个月来的最佳单日表现。</p>   <p>"You can say goodbye to the rate hiking era," said Brian Jacobsen, the chief economist at Annex Wealth Management in Wisconsin, adding that investors will now turn to bets on when U.S. Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell might start to cut rates.翻译:威斯康星州Annex Wealth Management首席经济学家布莱恩·雅各布森(Brian Jacobsen)表示：“你可以告别加息时代了。”他补充说，投资者现在将转向押注美联储主席杰罗姆·鲍威尔何时可能开始降息。</p>   <p>"If the Powell Pause began in July, we'll have to see how long he can hold rates here. In the soft landing of 1994-1995, the pause only last five months."翻译:“如果鲍威尔暂停政策从7月开始，我们就得看看他能维持利率多久。在1994-1995年的软着陆中，暂停政策只持续了五个月。”</p>   <p>Powell and other policymakers <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/feds-powell-not-confident-policy-is-tight-enough-supply-side-help-may-be-2023-11-09/">have said</a> before the latest U.S. inflation data that they are still not sure that interest rates are high enough to tame inflation.翻译:鲍威尔和其他政策制定者在美国最新通胀数据公布前曾<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/feds-powell-not-confident-policy-is-tight-enough-supply-side-help-may-be-2023-11-09/">表示</a>，他们仍不确定利率是否高到足以抑制通胀。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/european-shares-inch-higher-ahead-us-inflation-data-2023-11-14/">pan-European STOXX 600</a> also jumped after the benign U.S. inflation report, and was last up 1.3%.翻译:美国通胀报告公布后， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/european-shares-inch-higher-ahead-us-inflation-data-2023-11-14/">泛欧斯托克 600 指数</a>也大幅上涨，最终上涨 1.3%。</p>   <p>In line with expectations that U.S. rates might have peaked, Treasury yields dropped on Tuesday.翻译:与美国利率可能已见顶的预期一致，美国国债收益率周二下跌。</p>   <p>U.S. two-year yields, which reflect interest rate expectations, slid to two-week lows of 4.855%, and the benchmark 10-year yield fell 15.20 bps to 4.480%.翻译:反映利率预期的美国两年期国债收益率跌至两周低点4.855%，基准10年期国债收益率下跌15.20个基点至4.480%。</p>   <p>Lower yields dragged the U.S. dollar index down 1%. A softer dollar boosted the euro up 1.3% to $1.08350 .翻译:收益率下降拖累美元指数下跌1%。美元走软推动欧元上涨1.3%至1.08350美元。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/yens-slide-multi-decade-lows-keeps-markets-intervention-alert-2023-11-14/">Dollar weakness</a> gave the yen, which has been stuck near its lowest level in three decades against the dollar, a little reprieve.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/yens-slide-multi-decade-lows-keeps-markets-intervention-alert-2023-11-14/">美元疲软</a>给日元兑美元汇率带来了一点喘息，日元兑美元汇率一直徘徊在三十年来的最低水平附近。</p>   <p>The pair hovered around 150.76 , with the yen recovering slightly from Monday's 151.92.翻译:该货币对徘徊在150.76附近，日元较周一的151.92小幅回升。</p>   <p>"We expect the Bank of Japan to move very, very gradually out of yield curve control and eventually out of negative rate policy, but this is unlikely to happen anytime soon," Pictet Wealth Management's Ducrozet said.翻译:百达财富管理公司的杜克罗泽特表示：“我们预计日本央行将非常非常逐步地摆脱收益率曲线控制，并最终摆脱负利率政策，但这不太可能很快发生。”</p>   <p>In the meantime, the pair is more likely to be driven by anything that moves the dollar, Ducrozet added.翻译:杜克罗泽特补充道，与此同时，该货币对更有可能受到任何影响美元走势的因素的推动。</p>   <p>Euro zone government bond yields were also down. The benchmark 10-year German yield was at 2.615% .翻译:欧元区政府债券收益率也有所下降。德国10年期国债基准收益率为2.615%。</p>   <p>The Israel-Hamas war turned traders risk-averse in October, but world stocks have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/global-markets-wrapup-1-2023-11-13/">recovered</a> almost 5% so far this month as investors bet major central banks have ended a lengthy run of interest rate hikes.翻译:以色列与哈马斯的战争在 10 月份让交易者厌恶风险，但本月迄今为止，世界股市已<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/global-markets-wrapup-1-2023-11-13/">回升</a>近 5%，因为投资者押注主要央行已结束长期加息。</p>   <p>Asked how long rates would have to stay high to beat inflation, European Central Bank President Christine Lagarde <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/ecb-rates-held-long-enough-could-get-inflation-target-lagarde-2023-11-10/">said</a> in an interview over the weekend that no change should be expected in the "next couple of quarters".翻译:当被问及利率必须保持高位多久才能战胜通胀时，欧洲央行行长拉加德在周末接受采访时<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/ecb-rates-held-long-enough-could-get-inflation-target-lagarde-2023-11-10/">表示</a>，预计“未来几个季度”不会有任何变化。</p>   <p>Wages in Britain <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/uk-wage-growth-edges-down-stays-close-record-high-2023-11-14/">grew slightly less quickly</a> in the three months to September, official data on Tuesday showed. Wages previously rose at a record pace, leaving the Bank of England on alert for inflation.翻译:周二的官方数据显示，截至 9 月份的三个月里，英国的工资<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/uk-wage-growth-edges-down-stays-close-record-high-2023-11-14/">增长速度略有放缓</a>。工资此前以创纪录的速度上涨，令英国央行对通胀保持警惕。</p>   <p>The euro zone economy <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/euro-zone-q3-gdp-shrinks-employment-rises-2023-11-14/">contracted</a> marginally quarter-on-quarter in the third quarter, a new estimate confirmed, underlining expectations of a technical recession if the fourth quarter turns out equally weak, but employment still rose.翻译:一项新的估计证实，欧元区第三季度经济环比小幅<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/euro-zone-q3-gdp-shrinks-employment-rises-2023-11-14/">收缩</a>，这突显了如果第四季度同样疲软但就业仍然增长的话，欧元区经济将出现技术性衰退的预期。</p>   <p>Oil prices <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/oil-prices-edge-up-after-opec-says-market-fundamentals-are-strong-2023-11-14/">rose</a> nearly a dollar after the International Energy Agency (IEA) raised its demand growth forecasts, adding to bullish sentiment from the previous day's OPEC guidance, with Brent crude futures at $83.45 a barrel, and WTI crude futures at $79.22 .翻译:国际能源署(IEA)上调需求增长预测后，油价<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/oil-prices-edge-up-after-opec-says-market-fundamentals-are-strong-2023-11-14/">上涨</a>近一美元，加剧了前一天OPEC指引的看涨情绪，布伦特原油期货报每桶83.45美元，WTI原油期货报79.22美元。</p>    <span>Reporting by Elizabeth Howcroft; Editing by Alexander Smith, Mark Potter and Nick Zieminski翻译:伊丽莎白·豪克罗夫特报道；编辑：亚历山大·史密斯、马克·波特和尼克·齐明斯基</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 15:38:24 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">M4JUJL3VLFI6FDCSDZZNKDD2UI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/global-markets-wrapup-1-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Koh Qing, Elizabeth Howcroft]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/ (WRAPUP 5, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[尽管有新规定，中国仍接收美国设备来制造先进芯片]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/7GbXW86TjQSJFxmL_X2sD26EPNQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/E33PAY34EFISFKBKGOM2MJWQIE.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of Chinese and U.S. flags with semiconductor chips翻译:半导体芯片中美两国国旗插画图" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Flags of China and U.S. are displayed on a printed circuit board with semiconductor chips, in this illustration picture taken February 17, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张摄于 2023 年 2 月 17 日的插图中，中国和美国的国旗显示在带有半导体芯片的印刷电路板上。REUTERS/Florence Lo/插图/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Chinese companies are buying up U.S. chipmaking equipment to make advanced semiconductors, despite a raft of new export curbs aimed at thwarting advances in the country's semiconductor industry, a congressional report said on Tuesday.翻译:国会报告周二称，尽管一系列新的出口限制旨在阻碍中国半导体行业的进步，但中国公司仍在购买美国芯片制造设备来制造先进的半导体。</p>   <p>The 741 page annual report, released by the House of Representative's bipartisan select committee on China, takes aim at the Biden administration's Oct. 2022 export curbs, which seek to bar Chinese chipmakers from getting U.S. chipmaking tools if they would be used to manufacture advanced chips at the 14 nanometer node or below.翻译:众议院两党中国特别委员会发布的这份长达 741 页的年度报告瞄准了拜登政府 2022 年 10 月的出口限制措施，该措施旨在禁止中国芯片制造商获得用于制造先进芯片的美国芯片制造工具在14纳米节点或以下。</p>   <p>With the Commerce Department using the 14 nanometer restriction limit, "importers are often able to purchase the equipment if they claim it is being used on an older production line, and with limited capacity for end-use inspections, it is difficult to verify the equipment is not being used to produce more advanced chips," the report stated.翻译:由于商务部使用 14 纳米限制，“如果进口商声称该设备用于较旧的生产线，则通常能够购买该设备，但由于最终用途检查能力有限，因此很难验证该设备不会被用来生产更先进的芯片，”报告指出。</p>   <p>The finding comes as the United States scrambles to figure out how Chinese telecoms giant Huawei was able to produce an advanced 7 nanometer chip to power its Mate 60 Pro smartphone at China's top chipmaker SMIC, despite the export curbs announced last year.翻译:这一发现发布之际，美国正忙于弄清楚中国电信巨头华为如何能够在中国顶级芯片制造商中芯国际生产先进的 7 纳米芯片，为其 Mate 60 Pro 智能手机提供动力，尽管去年宣布了出口限制。</p>   <p>Huawei and SMIC were also added to a trade restriction list in 2019 and 2020, which in theory bars U.S. suppliers from shipping certain technology to the companies.翻译:华为和中芯国际还于2019年和2020年被列入贸易限制名单，理论上禁止美国供应商向这些公司运送某些技术。</p>   <p>China watchers had theorized that SMIC could have made the chip with equipment obtained prior to the October 2022 rules, but it had other options for obtaining the equipment from oversees, the report shows.翻译:报告显示，中国观察人士推测，中芯国际本可以使用 2022 年 10 月规定之前获得的设备来制造芯片，但它还有其他选择从海外获取设备。</p>   <p>The United States managed to plug a key loophole in its efforts to stymie China's access to advanced chipmaking tools by convincing allies Japan and the Netherlands, with similarly robust chipmaking equipment industries, to announce their own restrictions on exports of the coveted technology.翻译:美国成功地堵住了阻止中国获得先进芯片制造工具的一个关键漏洞，说服了拥有同样强大芯片制造设备行业的盟友日本和荷兰宣布对令人垂涎的技术的出口实施限制。</p>   <p>But China stockpiled equipment by taking advantage of the lagtime between the United States' October 2022 rules, and Japan and the Netherlands' similar moves in July and September of 2023 respectively, the report details.翻译:但报告详细介绍，中国利用美国 2022 年 10 月规定与日本和荷兰分别于 2023 年 7 月和 9 月采取类似举措之间的滞后时间囤积设备。</p>   <p>According to the document, between January and August 2023, China imported $3.2 billion (RMB 23.5 billion) worth of semiconductor manufacturing machines from the Netherlands, a 96.1% increase over the $1.7 billion (RMB 12 billion) recorded over the same period in 2022. China's imports of semiconductor equipment from all countries totaled $13.8 billion (RMB 100 billion) over the first eight months of 2023, it added.翻译:该文件显示，2023年1月至8月，中国从荷兰进口了价值32亿美元（235亿元人民币）的半导体制造设备，比2022年同期的17亿美元（120亿元人民币）增长了96.1%。报告补充称，2023年前8个月，中国从各国进口的半导体设备总额达138亿美元（1000亿元人民币）。</p>   <p>The report does not outline a specific recommendation to address the gaps in the U.S. rules, but urges Congress to request an annual evaluation, to be completed within 6 months by the General Accountability Office and later made public, of the effectiveness of export controls on chipmaking equipment to China.翻译:该报告没有概述解决美国规则缺陷的具体建议，但敦促国会要求对芯片制造出口管制的有效性进行年度评估，由总问责办公室在 6 个月内完成并随后公布。设备运往中国。</p>    <span>Reporting by Alexandra Alper; Editing by Chizu Nomiyama翻译:亚历山德拉·阿尔珀报道；编辑：野宫千津</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 15:32:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ACNBD7VIKFIGBCVFUN65DRKKWQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/china-receives-us-equipment-make-advanced-chips-despite-new-rules-report-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Alexandra Alper]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/CONGRESS</category>
                
                <category>CHIPS (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[尽管降低了风险，中国企业仍看到欧盟的前景——调查]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UH9rid9jkLEt5JsGOJYMoQt30ok=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OOV6PN5M3NOQ3ACUIZ6AADBDYY.jpg" alt="An attendant walks past EU and China flags ahead of the EU-China High-level Economic Dialogue in Beijing翻译:在北京举行的中欧高层经济对话之前，一名与会者走过欧盟和中国国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An attendant walks past EU and China flags ahead of the EU-China High-level Economic Dialogue at Diaoyutai State Guesthouse in Beijing, China June 25, 2018. REUTERS/Jason Lee翻译:2018年6月25日，在中国北京钓鱼台国宾馆举行的中欧高层经济对话之前，一名与会者走过欧盟和中国国旗。路透社/Jason Lee</figcaption></figure>       <p>Most Chinese companies operating in the European Union are feeling a pinch from the bloc's de-risking strategy, but still see more opportunity than challenge in Europe's green and digital transitions, according to a survey published on Tuesday.翻译:周二发布的一项调查显示，大多数在欧盟经营的中国企业都感受到了欧盟去风险战略的压力，但在欧洲的绿色和数字化转型中，机遇仍然多于挑战。</p>   <p>The survey for the China Chamber of Commerce to the EU, conducted by consultants Roland Berger, gauged the views of 180 Chinese enterprises in the EU, including telecoms and smartphone companies Huawei (HWT.UL) and ZTE <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/000063.SZ" target="_blank">(000063.SZ)</a>, electric vehicle maker BYD<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002594.SZ" target="_blank">(002594.SZ)</a>, COSCO Shipping and China's largest banks.翻译:罗兰贝格咨询公司为欧盟中国商会进行的这项调查收集了180家在欧盟中国企业的观点，其中包括电信和智能手机公司华为（HWT.UL）和中兴通讯<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/000063.SZ" target="_blank">（000063.SZ）</a> 、电动汽车制造商比亚迪<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/002594.SZ" target="_blank">（002594.SZ）</a> 、中远海运和中国最大的银行。</p>   <p>Their overall rating of the EU's business environment fell for the fourth consecutive year, with views of the political landscape declining most steeply.翻译:他们对欧盟商业环境的总体评级连续第四年下降，其中对政治格局的看法下降幅度最大。</p>   <p>Some 72% of respondents said their business operations had been negatively impacted by the EU's de-risking strategy, particularly semiconductor and telecoms suppliers. The strategy partly seeks to reduce EU dependence on China, especially for minerals and products required for its green and digital transitions.翻译:约 72% 的受访者表示，他们的业务运营受到了欧盟去风险战略的负面影响，特别是半导体和电信供应商。该战略的部分目的是减少欧盟对中国的依赖，特别是在绿色和数字化转型所需的矿产和产品方面。</p>   <p>China processes nearly 90% of rare earth elements and 60% of lithium globally and has announced export restrictions for other key materials - gallium, germanium and graphite.翻译:中国加工了全球近90%的稀土元素和60%的锂，并宣布对其他关键材料——镓、锗和石墨——进行出口限制。</p>   <p>A number of Chinese companies felt the EU had become more unfair in terms of single market access, import tariffs, public procurement opportunities and scrutiny of investments. The EU is also looking into <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/eu-launches-anti-subsidy-investigation-into-chinese-electric-vehicles-2023-09-13/">possible tariffs on Chinese electric vehicles</a>.翻译:许多中国企业认为欧盟在单一市场准入、进口关税、公共采购机会和投资审查方面变得更加不公平。欧盟也在研究<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/eu-launches-anti-subsidy-investigation-into-chinese-electric-vehicles-2023-09-13/">可能对中国电动汽车征收的关税</a>。</p>   <p>However, despite these challenges, 83% of respondent companies said they still had faith in the EU market and would continue to expand their presence.翻译:然而，尽管面临这些挑战，83%的受访企业表示，他们仍然对欧盟市场充满信心，并将继续扩大业务。</p>   <p>On the EU's transition to a greener and more digital economy, most companies expressed optimism that China-EU cooperation and technology collaboration would intensify in the coming years.翻译:对于欧盟向更绿色、更数字化的经济转型，大多数企业对未来几年中欧合作和技术协作将加强表示乐观。</p>   <p>About 90% replied that they saw more opportunities than challenges in green and digital fields.翻译:约90%的人回答说，他们在绿色和数字领域看到的机遇多于挑战。</p>   <p>The report also noted that bilateral trade was continuing to grow, reaching 857 billion euros ($917 billion) in 2022, making the EU and China each other's second-largest trading partner.翻译:报告还指出，双边贸易持续增长，到2022年将达到8570亿欧元（9170亿美元），使欧盟和中国互为第二大贸易伙伴。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/eu-trade-chief-seeks-more-balanced-economic-ties-china-visit-2023-09-21/">EU has said it wants a more balanced relationship with China</a> and that its trade deficit of about 400 billion euros is partly due to Chinese restrictions on European companies compared with an EU market that is largely open.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/eu-trade-chief-seeks-more-balanced-economic-ties-china-visit-2023-09-21/">欧盟表示希望与中国建立更加平衡的关系</a>，其约4000亿欧元的贸易逆差部分是由于中国对欧洲企业的限制，而欧盟市场基本上是开放的。</p>   <p>($1 = 0.9343 euros)翻译:（1 美元 = 0.9343 欧元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Philip Blenkinsop; Editing by Emelia Sithole-Matarise翻译:菲利普·布伦金索普报道；编辑：埃米莉亚·西托尔-马塔里斯</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 15:03:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">32WA3DBAGRKQFJ6YBZ2IC2QEN4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/chinese-companies-still-see-promise-eu-despite-de-risking-survey-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Philip Blenkinsop]]></author>
            
                
                <category>EU</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[尽管中国赌博业受到打击，腾讯音乐的收入仍超出预期]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ykNQfTxt8FcJnbaGt_HyPLPElnc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2SVLPV55RZMTNMSI3UWVRICQNI.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of China's Tencent Music Entertainment Group翻译:中国腾讯音乐娱乐集团插画图片" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of China's Tencent Music Entertainment Group is seen next to an earphone in this illustration picture taken March 22, 2021. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张摄于 2021 年 3 月 22 日的插图图片中，中国腾讯音乐娱乐集团的标志位于耳机旁边。路透社/Florence Lo/插图/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's Tencent Music <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/1698.HK" target="_blank">(1698.HK)</a> beat third-quarter revenue estimates on Tuesday, as steady growth in paid subscriptions on its streaming platforms helped offset the impact of Beijing's ongoing crackdown on online gambling.翻译:中国腾讯音乐<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/1698.HK" target="_blank">（1698.HK）</a>周二第三季度营收超出预期，其流媒体平台付费订阅量的稳定增长有助于抵消北京持续打击在线赌博的影响。</p>   <p>Tencent Music, which operates music streaming platforms such as QQ Music and Kugou Music, said its total revenue fell 10.8% to 6.57 billion yuan ($901 million) in the three-month period to the end of September versus the same period last year.翻译:运营QQ音乐和酷狗音乐等音乐流媒体平台的腾讯音乐表示，截至9月底的三个月内，其总收入较去年同期下降10.8%，至65.7亿元人民币（9.01亿美元）。</p>   <p>However, Tencent Music's results exceeded Wall Street revenue estimates of 6.31 billion yuan, LSEG data showed.翻译:然而，伦敦证券交易所数据显示，腾讯音乐的业绩超出了华尔街63.1亿元人民币的收入预期。</p>   <p>Controlled by Chinese tech giant Tencent, the company is among a list of online entertainment groups, including Huya <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/HUYA.N" target="_blank">(HUYA.N)</a> and Cloud Music <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9899.HK" target="_blank">(9899.HK)</a>, that have been feeling the impact of Beijing's crackdown on online gambling this year.翻译:该公司由中国科技巨头腾讯控股，是包括虎牙<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/HUYA.N" target="_blank">（HUYA.N）</a>和云音乐<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9899.HK" target="_blank">（9899.HK）</a>在内的一系列在线娱乐集团之一，这些集团今年一直受到北京打击在线赌博的影响。</p>   <p>While companies like Tencent Music explicitly prohibit online gambling, regulators began targeting live streaming platforms' game-like features such as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/china-online-platforms-scrap-lucky-draw-features-amid-gambling-crackdown-2023-08-25/">virtual lucky draws</a> earlier this year, saying that they could be abused by malicious users for gambling purposes.翻译:虽然腾讯音乐等公司明确禁止在线赌博，但监管机构今年早些时候开始针对直播平台的游戏类功能，例如<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/china-online-platforms-scrap-lucky-draw-features-amid-gambling-crackdown-2023-08-25/">虚拟抽奖</a>，称这些功能可能会被恶意用户滥用于赌博目的。</p>   <p>Many companies including Tencent Music then opted to remove these popular and lucrative features from their platforms. As a result, the group's social entertainment services posted a 48.8%drop in revenue for the quarter.翻译:随后，包括腾讯音乐在内的许多公司选择从其平台上删除这些流行且有利可图的功能。因此，该集团的社交娱乐服务本季度收入下降了48.8%。</p>   <p>"The decrease was mainly caused by our adjustments to certain app streaming interactive functions and the more stringent procedures as we have implemented," Tencent Music Chief Financial Officer Min Hu said.翻译:腾讯音乐首席财务官胡敏表示：“减少的主要原因是我们对某些应用流媒体交互功能的调整以及我们实施的更严格的程序。”</p>   <p>Tencent Music had already posted a 24% revenue decline for its social entertainment services in the previous quarter.翻译:腾讯音乐上一季度其社交娱乐服务收入已下降 24%。</p>   <p>Its executive chairman Cussion Pang said Tencent Music is confident that it can get the issue under control next year.翻译:其执行主席庞嘉信表示，腾讯音乐有信心明年能够控制这一问题。</p>   <p>"For 2024, our primary target is to stabilize the business and better serve our core users. As part of our holistic music ecosystem, we expect our social entertainment business to continue generating a healthy cash flow for us," he said.翻译:他表示：“2024年，我们的首要目标是稳定业务，更好地服务核心用户。作为我们整体音乐生态系统的一部分，我们预计社交娱乐业务将继续为我们带来健康的现金流。”</p>   <p>Excluding items, Tencent Music earned 89 yuan per American depository share (ADS), slightly above expectations of 88 yuan.翻译:不计项目，腾讯音乐每股美国存托股票（ADS）盈利89元，略高于预期的88元。</p>   <p>Net profit attributable to equity holders rose to 1.71 billion yuan, from 1.06 billion yuan a year earlier.翻译:归属于股东的净利润从上年同期的10.6亿元增至17.1亿元。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2924 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2924 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Harshita Mary Varghese and Akash Sriram in Bengaluru; Editing by Pooja Desai and Alexander Smith翻译:Harshita Mary Varghese 和 Akash Sriram 在班加罗尔的报道；普贾·德赛 (Pooja Desai) 和亚历山大·史密斯 (Alexander Smith) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 13:37:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BQAYQGW6WZK65DISHMIMXLBQII</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/chinas-tencent-music-tops-quarterly-revenue-estimates-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Josh Ye, Harshita Varghese, Akash Sriram]]></author>
            
                
                <category>TENCENT MUSIC</category>
                
                <category>RESULTS/ (UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[在公众强烈反对后，泰国放弃与中国警方的联合巡逻]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/10H1uESP3RtmhD5d0-YWV_bYh3o=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TQJR7FOV3FL4TJSZF5ICEE4VHU.jpg" alt="Aftermath of shooting at the luxury Siam Paragon shopping mall, in Bangkok翻译:曼谷豪华暹罗百丽宫购物中心发生枪击事件后" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Helen Yi, a tourist from Taiwan, looks at candles placed outside the luxury Siam Paragon shopping mall where Thai police arrested a teenage gunman who is suspected of killing foreigners and wounding other people in a shooting, in Bangkok, Thailand, October 4, 2023. REUTERS/Jorge Silva/File Photo翻译:2023 年 10 月 4 日，泰国曼谷，来自台湾的游客海伦·伊 (Helen Yi) 看着豪华暹罗百丽宫 (Siam Paragon) 购物中心外摆放的蜡烛，泰国警方在该购物中心逮捕了一名涉嫌在枪击事件中杀害外国人并伤人的青少年枪手。路透社/豪尔赫·席尔瓦/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Thailand rolled back on Tuesday plans of joint patrols with Chinese police in popular tourist spots after public backlash.翻译:在公众强烈反对后，泰国周二取消了与中国警方在热门旅游景点联合巡逻的计划。</p>   <p>Tourism officials on Sunday floated the idea of having Chinese and Thai police patrol much-visited areas to build confidence among tourists, including Chinese nationals.翻译:周日，旅游官员提出了让中国和泰国警察在游客较多的地区巡逻的想法，以建立包括中国公民在内的游客的信心。</p>   <p>The plan, however, sparked uproar online, drawing criticism that it compromised national sovereignty, and a rebuke from the country's police chief.翻译:然而，该计划在网上引发轩然大波，批评其损害国家主权，并遭到该国警察局长的斥责。</p>   <p>"There are many alternative ways to build confidence for tourists in Thailand ... but we will not have joint patrols," Tourism Minister Sudawan Wangsuphakijkosol told reporters on Tuesday.翻译:“有很多替代方法可以为泰国游客建立信心……但我们不会进行联合巡逻，”旅游部长苏达万·旺苏帕基科索尔 (Sudawan Wangsuphakijkosol) 周二告诉记者。</p>   <p>"The Thai police force is already adequate and are working hard to restore confidence," Sudawan said.翻译:苏达万说：“泰国警察力量已经足够，正在努力恢复信心。”</p>   <p>Thai authorities have rushed to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/thailand-vows-measures-restore-tourist-confidence-after-mall-shooting-2023-10-04/">tighten security</a> after last month's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/suspected-gunman-mall-shooting-modified-handgun-designed-fire-blanks-police-2023-10-04/">shooting spree</a> at a luxury mall in Bangkok in which two people, including one Chinese national, were killed, fanned safety concerns.翻译:上个月，曼谷一家豪华购物中心<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/suspected-gunman-mall-shooting-modified-handgun-designed-fire-blanks-police-2023-10-04/">发生枪击事件</a>，造成两人死亡，其中包括一名中国公民，引发安全担忧，泰国当局迅速<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/thailand-vows-measures-restore-tourist-confidence-after-mall-shooting-2023-10-04/">加强安保</a>。</p>   <p>Restoring confidence is critical for Thailand's tourism industry, especially among Chinese visitors.翻译:恢复信心对于泰国旅游业，尤其是中国游客来说至关重要。</p>   <p>They accounted for 11 million out of record 39.9 million foreign tourist arrivals in Thailand in 2019, but their return after the COVID-19 pandemic has been <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/indian-tourists-flock-southeast-asia-chinas-reopening-falters-2023-07-17/">sluggish</a>, prompting the government in September to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/chinese-tourists-get-vip-welcome-thai-visa-waiver-scheme-begins-2023-09-25/">waive</a> visa requirements for Chinese nationals.翻译:2019 年，泰国入境外国游客达到创纪录的 3,990 万人次，其中 1,100 万人次是中国游客，但在新冠肺炎 (COVID-19) 大流行之后，他们的回归一直<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/indian-tourists-flock-southeast-asia-chinas-reopening-falters-2023-07-17/">缓慢</a>，促使泰国政府于 9 月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/chinese-tourists-get-vip-welcome-thai-visa-waiver-scheme-begins-2023-09-25/">免除了</a>对中国公民的签证要求。</p>   <p>So far this year, Thailand has welcomed 23.2 million foreign arrivals.翻译:今年迄今，泰国已接待外国游客2320万人次。</p>    <span>Reporting by Chayut Setboonsarng, Editing by Tomasz Janowski翻译:Chayut Setboonsarng 报道，Tomasz Janowski 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 12:36:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B4AKGKWIYFLGRAYNQMDFJOWH5Y</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/thailand-drops-joint-patrols-with-chinese-police-after-public-backlash-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>THAILAND</category>
                
                <category>TOURISM/CHINA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[富士康季度利润意外增长，对 2024 年前景持保守态度]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/O92w2pzChnoQk5XMRWae2GQKJmY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/X6QXPC37M5JNFK73VE2WES7OSU.jpg" alt="People wear masks to protect themselves from the coronavirus disease (COVID-19) while passing a Foxconn office building in Taipei翻译:人们在经过台北富士康办公楼时戴上口罩以保护自己免受冠状病毒病（COVID-19）的感染" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People wear masks to protect themselves from the coronavirus disease (COVID-19) while passing a Foxconn office building in Taipei翻译:人们在经过台北富士康办公楼时戴上口罩以保护自己免受冠状病毒病（COVID-19）的感染, Taiwan, July 14, 2020. REUTERS/Ann Wang/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lh63FHjzwWItgT6jNTFRq_1MpIs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/LJVTOZFBPVPMDD23BUC6X24TJM.jpg" alt="Illustration shows Foxconn logo翻译:插图显示富士康标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Foxconn logo is seen in this illustration taken, May 2, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:富士康标志可见于 2023 年 5 月 2 日拍摄的这张插图中。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>Apple Inc <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a> supplier Foxconn <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2317.TW" target="_blank">(2317.TW)</a> logged a surprise 11% increase in third-quarter profit, helped by gains in non-operating income but reiterated revenue was set to fall slightly for the year.翻译:苹果公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a>供应商富士康<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2317.TW" target="_blank">(2317.TW)</a>第三季度利润意外增长11%，得益于非营业收入增长，但重申今年收入将小幅下降。</p>   <p>For 2024, the world's largest contract electronics maker has a "relatively conservative and neutral" outlook, its chairman, Young Liu, said, adding that expected growth of 5% for the market "could easily be offset by geopolitics."翻译:这家全球最大的电子合同制造商董事长 Young Liu 表示，对于 2024 年的前景持“相对保守和中性”的态度，并补充说，市场预期 5% 的增长“很容易被地缘政治所抵消”。</p>   <p>Net profit for the July-September quarter came in at T$43.1 billion ($1.3 billion), beating market estimates for an 11% drop and despite a sharp 12% tumble in revenue that was a second straight quarter of decline.翻译:7 月至 9 月季度的净利润为 431 亿新台币（13 亿美元），超出市场预期的 11% 下降，尽管收入大幅下降 12%，这是连续第二个季度下降。</p>   <p>Income from investments in subsidiaries, interest revenue and foreign exchange gains quadrupled during the quarter, the company said.翻译:该公司表示，本季度来自子公司的投资收入、利息收入和外汇收益翻了两番。</p>   <p>Liu added that while the Taiwanese company did expect revenue to continue to fall in the important holiday season quarter, its performance was likely to be a bit better than previously expected with the decline slight.翻译:刘补充道，虽然这家台湾公司确实预计在重要的假日季节季度收入将继续下降，但其业绩可能会好于之前的预期，略有下降。</p>   <p>"We have entered the traditional season of hot sales in the second half and our operations are set to gradually improve quarter on quarter," he told an earnings briefing.翻译:他在财报发布会上表示：“下半年我们已经进入了传统的热销季节，我们的运营将逐季逐步改善。”</p>   <p>Apple, which in September launched a new series of iPhones, this month gave a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/apple-beats-quarterly-estimates-iphone-sales-edge-up-2023-11-02/">sales forecast</a> for the holiday quarter that missed Wall Street expectations, hurt by weak demand for iPads and wearables.翻译:苹果公司在 9 月份推出了一系列新 iPhone，但由于 iPad 和可穿戴设备需求疲软，该公司本月给出的假日季度<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/apple-beats-quarterly-estimates-iphone-sales-edge-up-2023-11-02/">销售预测</a>未达到华尔街预期。</p>   <p>Foxconn said it expects to embark on capital expenditure of more than T$90 billion in 2024 - in line with this year, the bulk of which would be spent on expanding its business in China.翻译:富士康表示，预计 2024 年的资本支出将超过 900 亿新台币，与今年一致，其中大部分将用于扩大在中国的业务。</p>   <p>Its electric vehicle business may also benefit from headwinds such as increased competition and rising labour costs in the industry as those factors might push automakers to outsource production, Liu said.翻译:刘表示，其电动汽车业务也可能受益于行业竞争加剧和劳动力成本上升等不利因素，因为这些因素可能会促使汽车制造商外包生产。</p>   <p>The earnings report comes amid much investor focus on Chinese authorities having opened a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/apple-supplier-foxconns-q3-profit-rises-11-much-better-than-forecasts-2023-11-14/">tax probe</a> into the company.翻译:该财报发布之际，投资者普遍关注中国当局对该公司展开<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/apple-supplier-foxconns-q3-profit-rises-11-much-better-than-forecasts-2023-11-14/">税务调查</a>。</p>   <p>Liu said Foxconn's business in China was operating normally and there had been no outcome from the investigation as yet.翻译:刘说，富士康在华业务正常运营，调查尚未有结果。</p>   <p>The tax probe was first reported by the state-backed, nationalist Chinese tabloid the Global Times, but in its English version of the story it suggested what China was actually unhappy about was that Foxconn founder Terry Gou is running for president as an independent, a decision he announced in August.翻译:这项税务调查最先由国家支持的中国民族主义小报《环球时报》报道，但在其英文版报道中，它暗示中国实际上不满意的是富士康创始人郭台铭以无党派人士身份竞选总统。他在八月宣布了决定。</p>   <p>Liu said Foxconn management had to be prepared for all eventualities with regard to Gou's run for president. Gou is its biggest shareholder, owning 12.6% of the company as of end-June.翻译:刘说，富士康管理层必须为郭台铭竞选总裁的所有可能发生的情况做好准备。郭台铭是其第一大股东，截至6月底持有该公司12.6%的股份。</p>   <p>Shares of Foxconn closed up 2.4% ahead of the earnings announcement, beating a 0.5% gain for the benchmark index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.TWII" target="_blank">(.TWII)</a>.翻译:富士康股价在财报公布前收盘上涨 2.4%，超过基准指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.TWII" target="_blank">(.TWII)</a> 0.5% 的涨幅。</p>   <p>($1 = 32.3430 Taiwan dollars)翻译:(1 美元 = 32.3430 新台币)</p>    <span>Reporting by Yimou Lee and Sarah Wu; Editing by Anne Marie Roantree and Edwina Gibbs翻译:李艺谋、吴莎拉报道；安妮·玛丽·罗恩特里和埃德温娜·吉布斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 12:13:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RIAHJ2UZ3NMMZBJBHRJRMIFEYI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/apple-supplier-foxconns-q3-profit-rises-11-much-better-than-forecasts-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Yimou Lee, Sarah Wu]]></author>
            
                
                <category>FOXCONN</category>
                
                <category>RESULTS/ (UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IEA上调石油需求增长预测，预计2024年可能出现盈余]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Boosts 2023 growth forecast to 2.4 mln bpd</li>  <li>Lifts 2024 growth forecast to 930,000 bpd</li>  <li>Oil supply could go into surplus in 2024</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>将 2023 年增长预测提高至 240 万桶/日</li><li>将 2024 年增长预测上调至 93 万桶/日</li><li>2024年石油供应可能出现过剩</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/JW0uT37qdKkD8tT4bLTQfJQaM7E=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5DE46B727ZICJJZ3TW535PBEAE.jpg" alt="An oil pump of IPC Petroleum France is seen at sunset outside Soudron翻译:日落时分，Soudron 外可见法国 IPC 石油公司的油泵" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An oil pump of IPC Petroleum France is seen during sunset outside Soudron, near Reims, France, February 6, 2023.  REUTERS/Pascal Rossignol/File Photo翻译:2023 年 2 月 6 日，法国兰斯附近的 Soudron 外，日落时分可以看到 IPC Petroleum France 的油泵。REUTERS/Pascal Rossignol/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The International Energy Agency (IEA) on Tuesday raised its oil demand growth forecasts for this year and next despite slower economic growth in nearly all major economies, although its 2024 outlook remains much lower than that of producer group OPEC.翻译:国际能源署(IEA)周二上调了今明两年的石油需求增长预测，尽管几乎所有主要经济体的经济增长均放缓，但其2024年的前景仍远低于产油国组织OPEC的预测。</p>   <p>The Paris-based IEA said the market could shift into surplus at the start of 2024 having been kept in a "significant deficit" through year-end by voluntary cuts from Saudi Arabia and Russia which last until the end of December.翻译:总部位于巴黎的国际能源署表示，由于沙特阿拉伯和俄罗斯的自愿减产一直持续到12月底，市场在年底之前一直处于“严重赤字”，因此市场可能会在2024年初转为盈余。</p>   <p>"For now, with demand still exceeding available supplies heading into the Northern Hemisphere winter, market balances will remain vulnerable to heightened economic and geopolitical risks – and further volatility ahead," the IEA said in a monthly report.翻译:国际能源署在月度报告中表示：“目前，随着北半球冬季到来，需求仍超过可用供应，市场平衡仍将容易受到经济和地缘政治风险加剧以及未来进一步波动的影响。”</p>   <p>Oil has weakened to around $82 a barrel for Brent crude from a 2023 high in September near $98. Concern about economic growth and demand has pressured prices, despite support from supply cuts by OPEC and its allies, and conflict in the Middle East.翻译:布伦特原油价格已从 9 月份每桶 98 美元附近的 2023 年高点下跌至 82 美元左右。尽管欧佩克及其盟友减产以及中东冲突为油价提供了支撑，但对经济增长和需求的担忧仍给价格带来压力。</p>   <p>The IEA joins the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries in raising its <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/opec-says-oil-market-remains-strong-despite-negative-sentiment-2023-11-13/">oil demand growth</a> forecast for 2023. Demand in 2023 has been supported by resilient U.S. deliveries and record September demand from China, the IEA said.翻译:IEA 与石油输出国组织一起上调了 2023 年<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/opec-says-oil-market-remains-strong-despite-negative-sentiment-2023-11-13/">石油需求增长</a>预测。IEA 表示，2023 年的需求得到了美国强劲的交付量和中国创纪录的 9 月份需求的支撑。</p>   <p>In 2023, the IEA expects world demand to rise by 2.4 million barrels per day (bpd), up from 2.3 million bpd seen previously and bringing its view closer to that of OPEC, which on Monday nudged up its forecast to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/opec-says-oil-market-remains-strong-despite-negative-sentiment-2023-11-13/">2.46 million bpd</a>.</p>    <h 1="">SLOWDOWN IN VIEW</h>  <p>For 2024, the IEA raised its oil demand growth forecast to 930,000 bpd from 880,000 bpd. Expectations are underpinned by hopes of interest rate cuts and the recent fall in crude prices, the IEA, the energy adviser to industrialised nations, said.翻译:IEA 将 2024 年石油需求增长预测从 88 万桶/日上调至 93 万桶/日。工业化国家能源顾问国际能源署表示，降息希望和近期原油价格下跌支撑了预期。</p>   <p>This is still well below OPEC's forecast of 2.25 million bpd. The difference - 1.32 million bpd - is equivalent to roughly 1% of daily world oil use and translates into more than the daily production of an OPEC member such as Libya.翻译:这仍远低于 OPEC 预测的 225 万桶/日。这一差异 - 132 万桶/日 - 大约相当于世界每日石油使用量的 1%，并且超过了利比亚等欧佩克成员国的每日产量。</p>   <p>OPEC and the IEA have clashed in recent years over issues such as the long-term oil demand outlook and the need for investment in new supplies.翻译:近年来，欧佩克和国际能源署在长期石油需求前景和新供应投资需求等问题上发生了冲突。</p>   <p>The IEA said the 2024 demand slowdown will arise as "the last phase of the pandemic economic rebound dissipates and as advancing energy efficiency gains, expanding electric vehicle fleets and structural factors reassert themselves."翻译:IEA表示，随着“大流行病经济反弹的最后阶段消散，以及能源效率的提高、电动汽车保有量的扩大和结构性因素的重新出现，2024年的需求将会放缓。”</p>   <p>The 2024 outlook will be in focus at the next meeting of OPEC and its allies, known as OPEC+, on Nov. 26. The group's existing deal limits supply into 2024, although the extra Saudi and Russian voluntary cuts last until the end of December.翻译:11 月 26 日举行的 OPEC 及其盟友下一次会议（即 OPEC+）将关注 2024 年前景。该组织现有协议将供应限制到 2024 年，不过沙特和俄罗斯的额外自愿减产将持续到 12 月底。</p>    <span>Reporting by Natalie Grover and Alex Lawler in London; editing by David Goodman, Jason Neely and David Evans翻译:娜塔莉·格罗弗和亚历克斯·劳勒在伦敦的报道；大卫·古德曼、杰森·尼利和大卫·埃文斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 11:50:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">EUZRVS6BP5I5RFZQ55BBAYLALU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/iea-raises-oil-demand-growth-forecasts-despite-economic-gloom-ahead-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Natalie Grover, Alex Lawler]]></author>
            
                
                <category>IEA</category>
                
                <category>OIL/ (UPDATE 4, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[华为销量增长83%，带动中国10月智能手机销量]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/6ySIsGuIa9sUwFu6UtnwWaadErk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZIRCMLFCZNKD7P75AHTMVZTDOM.jpg" alt="Huawei store in Shanghai翻译:华为上海专卖店" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Chinese flag flutters near a Huawei store in Shanghai翻译:华为上海专卖店, China September 8, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Strong sales growth at Huawei (HWT.UL) helped power an 11% rise in China's total smartphone shipments in October, data from research firm Counterpoint showed on Tuesday, indicating signs of recovery in its lagging mobile market.翻译:研究公司 Counterpoint 周二的数据显示，华为 (HWT.UL) 强劲的销售增长推动 10 月份中国智能手机总出货量增长 11%，这表明落后的移动市场出现复苏迹象。</p>   <p>Huawei was a major contributor to the average year-on-year growth in the first four weeks of October, with its sales surging 83%, a note from the firm showed.翻译:该公司的一份报告显示，华为是 10 月前 4 周平均同比增长的主要贡献者，其销售额猛增 83%。</p>   <p>According to the Counterpoint data, Xiaomi <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/1810.HK" target="_blank">(1810.HK)</a> also saw a 33% increase in smartphone sales in October. It did not provide specifics around Apple's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a> performance in the period.翻译:根据Counterpoint数据，小米<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/1810.HK" target="_blank">（1810.HK）</a> 10月份智能手机销量也增长33%。它没有提供有关苹果公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a>在此期间业绩的具体信息。</p>   <p>In August, Huawei <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chip-stocks-rally-after-huaweis-low-key-launch-new-mate-60-pro-phone-2023-08-30/">launched</a> its Mate 60 smartphone series powered by what analysts said are a self-developed advanced chip, seen by some analysts as an answer to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/biden-cut-china-off-more-nvidia-chips-expand-curbs-more-countries-2023-10-17/">U.S. sanctions</a> aimed at halting shipments of some chips to China.翻译:8月，华为<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chip-stocks-rally-after-huaweis-low-key-launch-new-mate-60-pro-phone-2023-08-30/">推出了</a>Mate 60智能手机系列，该系列智能手机搭载了分析师所说的自主研发的先进芯片，一些分析师认为这是对<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/biden-cut-china-off-more-nvidia-chips-expand-curbs-more-countries-2023-10-17/">美国旨在停止向中国出口部分芯片的制裁</a>的回应。</p>   <p>"The clear standout in October has been Huawei, with its turnaround on the back of its Mate 60 series devices. Growth has been stellar," said Counterpoint China analyst Archie Zhang.翻译:Counterpoint 中国分析师 Archie Zhang 表示：“10 月份最引人注目的是华为，凭借 Mate 60 系列设备实现了扭亏为盈。增长速度非常惊人。”</p>   <p>"Demand continues to be high double-digits and we’re also seeing a halo effect, with other models from the vendor performing well."翻译:“需求继续保持两位数的高位，我们也看到了光环效应，供应商的其他型号表现良好。”</p>   <p>However, Counterpoint said there could be lingering bottlenecks for Huawei as it may still experience certain production issues.翻译:然而，Counterpoint 表示，华为可能会遇到一些挥之不去的瓶颈，因为它可能仍会遇到某些生产问题。</p>   <p>"Huawei’s ability to scale up to this new normal will be a major determinant not just for their own growth, but for the broader market,” said Ivan Lam, senior Counterpoint analyst.翻译:Counterpoint 高级分析师伊万·林 (Ivan Lam) 表示：“华为适应新常态的能力将不仅是其自身增长的主要决定因素，也是更广泛市场的主要决定因素。”</p>   <p>China's smartphone market has seen sales fall over several quarters, with a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-smartphone-shipments-fall-5-yy-q3-667-mln-handsets-canalys-2023-10-26/">3% drop</a> in the quarter ending June, according to Counterpoint.翻译:据 Counterpoint 称，中国智能手机市场销量连续几个季度下滑，截至 6 月份的季度销量<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-smartphone-shipments-fall-5-yy-q3-667-mln-handsets-canalys-2023-10-26/">下降了 3%</a> 。</p>   <p>Analysts expect the market may be poised for a rebound, with research firm IDC predicting unspecified year-on-year sales growth in the fourth quarter after ten consecutive quarters of falling shipments.翻译:分析师预计市场可能会出现反弹，研究公司 IDC 预测，在连续十个季度出货量下降之后，第四季度销售量将出现同比增长，但具体数字未具体说明。</p>    <span>Reporting by Yelin Mo and Brenda Goh; Editing by Jan Harvey翻译:莫叶琳和吴布伦达报道；扬·哈维编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 11:35:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">E5DFIZOBQZKOFBK3OYGMNFRVMU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/huawei-sales-up-83-boosting-chinas-october-smartphone-sales-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Yelin Mo, Brenda Goh]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>SMARTPHONES/HUAWEI</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早盘竞价：美国通胀形势不明朗]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/XXJ8vN7_65mGhd8Fo6yDVbyUQo4=/800x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WTCZQW4QJBOR7MHL3LQJZXA5WI.jpg" alt="A trader works on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange shortly before the closing bell as the market takes a significant dip in New York翻译:由于纽约市场大幅下跌，一名交易员在收盘前不久在纽约证券交易所工作。" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A trader works on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange shortly before the closing bell as the market takes a significant dip in New York翻译:由于纽约市场大幅下跌，一名交易员在收盘前不久在纽约证券交易所工作。, U.S., February 25, 2020.  REUTERS/Lucas Jackson/File Photo翻译:2020 年 2 月 25 日，美国纽约，市场大幅下跌，一名交易员在收盘前不久在纽约证券交易所工作。路透社/卢卡斯·杰克逊/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A look at the day ahead in U.S. and global markets from Mike Dolan翻译:迈克·多兰 (Mike Dolan) 对美国和全球市场未来一天的展望</p>   <p>If investors were wondering why <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/feds-jefferson-inflation-uncertainty-can-warrant-stronger-response-2023-11-14/">Federal Reserve</a> rhetoric remains so doggedly hawkish, the latest U.S. consumer price <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-dip-focus-shifts-economic-data-2023-11-13/">inflation</a> report on Tuesday will likely explain why.翻译:如果投资者想知道为什么<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/feds-jefferson-inflation-uncertainty-can-warrant-stronger-response-2023-11-14/">美联储的</a>言论仍然如此顽固地强硬，周二最新的美国消费者价格<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-dip-focus-shifts-economic-data-2023-11-13/">通胀</a>报告可能会解释原因。</p>   <p>According to consensus forecasts at least, U.S. headline inflation is expected to have retreated sharply again in October back toward midyear lows around 3.3%. A near 15% drop in retail gasoline prices since late September should help see to that.翻译:至少根据普遍预测，美国总体通胀率预计将在 10 月份再次大幅回落，回到年中低点 3.3% 左右。自 9 月下旬以来，零售汽油价格下降了近 15%，这应该有助于实现这一目标。</p>   <p>But underlying 'core' inflation is expected to stay stickier at an unchanged annual rate of 4.1% last month and still more than twice the Fed's target.翻译:但潜在的“核心”通胀预计将保持较高水平，上个月年率保持在 4.1% 不变，仍是美联储目标的两倍以上。</p>   <p>There's been more encouraging news on inflation expectations, however, with the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/ny-fed-finds-softer-inflation-expectations-october-2023-11-13/">New York Fed's</a> latest survey of household sentiment showing a one-year inflation outlook slipping to 3.6% last month and as low as 2.7% over five years.翻译:然而，通胀预期方面出现了更多令人鼓舞的消息， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/ny-fed-finds-softer-inflation-expectations-october-2023-11-13/">纽约联储</a>最新的家庭情绪调查显示，一年期通胀前景上个月下滑至 3.6%，五年内低至 2.7%。</p>   <p>But the Fed may want to hang tough long enough into a slowing economy to ensure that inflation is squeezed back to its 2% goal. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/us-rate-cut-not-seen-until-q4-2024-due-strong-gdp-growth-goldman-economists-2023-11-13/">Goldman Sachs</a>, for example, reckons the hard part of the Fed's fight is over but it may not start cutting rates until the fourth quarter of 2024.翻译:但美联储可能希望在经济放缓的情况下坚持足够长的时间，以确保通胀率回落至 2% 的目标。例如， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/us-rate-cut-not-seen-until-q4-2024-due-strong-gdp-growth-goldman-economists-2023-11-13/">高盛</a>认为美联储斗争的艰难部分已经结束，但可能要到 2024 年第四季度才会开始降息。</p>   <p>Futures markets are still more optimistic - seeing the first quarter-point cut fully priced by July and 75 basis points of easing in total in the mix by the end of next year. The worrying state of U.S. small businesses will be seen in the NFIB report for October out later today.翻译:期货市场仍然更加乐观——预计到 7 月份，第一季度的降息已完全体现出来，到明年年底，降息总量将达到 75 个基点。美国小企业令人担忧的状况将在今天晚些时候发布的 NFIB 10 月报告中看到。</p>   <p>Long-term investors think the Fed is just playing a holding game and ultimately the cooling economy will allow it to ease enough to make today's juicy bond yields worth snapping up.翻译:长期投资者认为，美联储只是在玩持有游戏，最终经济降温将使其放松足够多的货币政策，从而使当今丰厚的债券收益率值得抢购。</p>   <p>Bank of America's latest monthly funds survey shows global asset managers holding their biggest overweight position in bonds since March 2009 - and some 61% think yields will be lower in 12 months' time than they are now.翻译:美国银行最新的月度基金调查显示，全球资产管理公司持有自 2009 年 3 月以来最大的债券增持头寸，约 61% 的人认为 12 个月后收益率将低于现在。</p>   <p>And perhaps the negative tilt on October core inflation going into today's release leaves more room for a positive surprise. Ten-year U.S. Treasury yields hovered just above 4.60%, the dollar index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DXY" target="_blank">(.DXY)</a> was a touch softer and S&amp;P500 futures were marginally positive ahead of the bell.翻译:今天发布的 10 月核心通胀可能呈现负面倾向，为积极的惊喜留下了更多空间。十年期美国国债收益率徘徊在略高于 4.60% 的水平，美元指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DXY" target="_blank">(.DXY)</a>略有走软，标准普尔 500 指数期货在盘前小幅上涨。</p>   <p>Although U.S. crude oil prices have backed up again in recent days, they remain 18% below September's peak and year-on-year losses are running at almost 10%.翻译:尽管美国原油价格最近几天再次回升，但仍比 9 月份峰值低 18%，同比跌幅接近 10%。</p>   <p>The global demand picture remains hard to parse.翻译:全球需求情况仍然难以解析。</p>   <p>The International Energy Agency on Tuesday raised its oil demand growth forecasts for this year and next despite the weakening economic picture.翻译:尽管经济形势疲软，国际能源署周二上调了今明两年的石油需求增长预测。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/euro-zone-q3-gdp-shrinks-employment-rises-2023-11-14/">euro zone</a> economy contracted 0.1% as expected in the third quarter, meantime, raising the prospects of a technical yearend recession and contrasting with the U.S. boom during the same quarter. However, the data wasn't all bad and employment continued to increase in the bloc in Q3.翻译:与此同时， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/euro-zone-q3-gdp-shrinks-employment-rises-2023-11-14/">欧元区</a>经济第三季度如预期收缩0.1%，提高了年底出现技术性衰退的可能性，与美国同一季度的繁荣形成鲜明对比。然而，数据也不全是坏事，第三季度该地区就业人数继续增长。</p>   <p>Elsewhere, the focus shifts to California as China's President Xi Jinping starts his first U.S. visit since 2017 ahead of Wednesday's summit with President Joe Biden in San Francisco during the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation gathering there this week.翻译:在其他地方，焦点转移到加州，中国国家主席习近平开始自 2017 年以来首次访问美国，周三亚太经合组织在旧金山举行峰会期间将与美国总统乔·拜登举行峰会。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-chinas-xi-will-discuss-communication-competition-apec-summit-2023-11-13/">White House</a> said on Monday that Biden and Xi will discuss strengthening communication and managing competition.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-chinas-xi-will-discuss-communication-competition-apec-summit-2023-11-13/">白宫</a>周一表示，拜登和习近平将讨论加强沟通和管理竞争的问题。</p>   <p>In the background for XI is the country's ongoing property sector and local debt concerns. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-orders-local-governments-cut-exposure-public-private-projects-debt-risks-2023-11-14/">Reuters reported</a> on Tuesday that China has ordered its local governments to halt public-private partnership projects identified as "problematic" and replaced a 10% budget spending allowance for these ventures with a vetting mechanism as it tries to curb municipal debt risks.翻译:十一月的背景是该国持续存在的房地产行业和地方债务问题。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-orders-local-governments-cut-exposure-public-private-projects-debt-risks-2023-11-14/">路透社周二报道称</a>，中国已下令地方政府停止被认定为“有问题”的公私合作项目，并以审查机制取代了对这些企业的 10% 预算支出补贴，以试图遏制市政债务风险。</p>   <p>In Japan, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/yens-slide-multi-decade-lows-keeps-markets-intervention-alert-2023-11-14/">the yen</a> continued to stalk 33-year lows set in October last year at 151.94 per dollar - with markets wary of Bank of Japan intervention should it plunge through there. Japan's Finance Minister Shunichi Suzuki said the government would take all necessary steps to respond to currency moves, repeating his mantra that excessive swings were undesirable.翻译:在日本， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/yens-slide-multi-decade-lows-keeps-markets-intervention-alert-2023-11-14/">日元</a>继续逼近去年 10 月创下的 33 年来的低点，即 1 美元兑 151.94 日元，市场对日本央行的干预持谨慎态度，以防日元跌破该水平。日本财务大臣铃木俊一表示，政府将采取一切必要措施应对汇率波动，并重申过度波动是不可取的。</p>   <p>In corporate news, Home Depot reports earnings in a big week for <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/walmart-target-earnings-offer-clues-crucial-holiday-season-2023-11-13/">U.S. retailers</a>.翻译:企业新闻方面，家得宝 (Home Depot) 报告了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/walmart-target-earnings-offer-clues-crucial-holiday-season-2023-11-13/">美国零售商</a>重要的一周盈利情况。</p>   <p>In deals, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/glencore-buy-majority-stake-teck-coal-assets-693-bln-2023-11-14/">Glencore</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GLEN.L" target="_blank">(GLEN.L)</a> sealed a deal for a 77% stake in Canadian miner Teck Resources' <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TECKb.TO" target="_blank">(TECKb.TO)</a> steelmaking coal business for $6.93 billion in cash, paving the way for a spin-off of the commodity giant's own coal business.翻译:在交易中， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/glencore-buy-majority-stake-teck-coal-assets-693-bln-2023-11-14/">嘉能可</a><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GLEN.L" target="_blank">(GLEN.L)</a>以 69.3 亿美元现金达成了收购加拿大矿商 Teck Resources <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TECKb.TO" target="_blank">(TECKb.TO)</a>炼钢煤炭业务 77% 股权的交易，为分拆这家大宗商品巨头自己的业务铺平了道路煤炭业务。</p>   <p>Key developments that should provide more direction to U.S. markets later on Tuesday:翻译:周二晚些时候将为美国市场提供更多方向的关键事态发展：</p>   <p>* U.S. Oct consumer price inflation, NFIB Oct small business survey翻译:* 美国 10 月消费者价格通胀、NFIB 10 月小企业调查</p>   <p>* Federal Reserve Vice Chair Philip Jefferson, Cleveland Fed President Loretta Mester and Chicago Fed chief Austan Goolsbee all speak; Fed Vice Chair for Supervision Michael Barr testifies before Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs; Bank of England Chief Economist Huw Pill speaks翻译:* 美联储副主席菲利普·杰斐逊、克利夫兰联储行长洛雷塔·梅斯特和芝加哥联储行长奥斯坦·古尔斯比均发表讲话；美联储负责监督的副主席迈克尔·巴尔在参议院银行、住房和城市事务委员会作证；英国央行首席经济学家休·皮尔发表讲话</p>   <p>* China's President Xi Jinping starts visit to United States翻译:* 中国国家主席习近平开始对美国进行访问</p>   <p>* U.S. corporate earnings: Home Depot翻译:* 美国企业盈利：家得宝</p>                   <span>By Mike Dolan, editing by Christina Fincher, &lt;a href="mailto:mike.dolan@thomsonreuters.com" target="_blank"&gt;mike.dolan@thomsonreuters.com&lt;/a&gt;. Twitter: @reutersMikeD翻译:作者：Mike Dolan，编辑：Christina Fincher，&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mike.dolan@thomsonreuters.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mike.dolan@thomsonreuters.com&lt;/a&gt;。推特：@reutersMikeD</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 11:02:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2ETVZLRBMFL27PG6XJ6IOEAPHY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/global-markets-view-usa-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[高管被捕如何对日中业务造成打击]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/s0GPpO0IkZ_1R8Mh9711ClhGXDU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MD32VUIFXVIFHDYZQNZKV2OKKI.jpg" alt="Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida meets Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of the APEC leaders' summit in Bangkok翻译:日本首相岸田文雄在曼谷亚太经合组织领导人峰会期间会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida meets Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Summit in Bangkok, Thailand November 17, 2022, in this photo released by Kyodo. Mandatory credit Kyodo via REUTERS ATTENTION EDITORS - THIS IMAGE WAS PROVIDED BY A THIRD PARTY. MANDATORY CREDIT. JAPAN OUT. NO COMMERCIAL OR EDITORIAL SALES IN JAPAN/File Photo翻译:共同社发布的这张照片显示，日本首相岸田文雄于 2022 年 11 月 17 日在泰国曼谷举行的亚太经济合作组织 (APEC) 峰会期间会见了中国国家主席习近平。强制性信用共同社通过路透社注意编辑 - 该图像由第三方提供。强制性信用。日本出局。在日本禁止商业或社论销售/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>If Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida meets Chinese President Xi Jinping for the first time in a year later this week, he will likely raise the case of a detained company executive that has dealt an outsized blow to their close economic ties.翻译:如果日本首相岸田文雄本周晚些时候一年内首次会见中国国家主席习近平，他可能会提出一名被拘留的公司高管的案件，该案对两国密切的经济关系造成了巨大打击。</p>   <p>The employee of drugmaker Astellas Pharma <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/4503.T" target="_blank">(4503.T)</a>, as well as other Japanese imprisoned or under criminal probes in China, would probably be among the topics to be discussed as plans take shape for the leaders to talk on the sidelines of the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">APEC summit</a> in San Francisco, sources familiar with the planning said.翻译:制药商安斯泰来制药<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/4503.T" target="_blank">(Astellas Pharma, 4503.T)</a>的员工，以及其他在中国被监禁或接受刑事调查的日本人，可能会成为领导人在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">APEC 峰会</a>期间谈话的计划中讨论的话题之一熟悉该计划的消息人士称，在旧金山。</p>   <p>The arrest of the well-connected veteran of the Japanese community in China has had what some Tokyo officials described as a considerable chilling effect on business, contributing to a drop in foreign investment to its lowest level since at least 2014 and accelerating an exodus of expats.翻译:一些东京官员称，这名在中国的日本人社区中人脉广泛的资深人士被捕，对企业产生了相当大的寒蝉效应，导致外国投资降至至少 2014 年以来的最低水平，并加速了外籍人士的外流。</p>   <p>"I know Japanese businesses are rethinking," Rahm Emanuel, the U.S. ambassador to Japan, told Reuters in an interview. "Right now, you can't get people to go staff the companies in China because they're scared of their own safety."翻译:美国驻日本大使拉姆·伊曼纽尔在接受路透社采访时表示：“我知道日本企业正在重新考虑。” “现在，你无法让人们去中国的公司工作，因为他们担心自己的安全。”</p>   <p>China detained the executive, named in several media reports as Hiroshi Nishiyama, on suspicion of espionage in March, and he was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-formally-arrests-astellas-employee-suspected-spying-japan-urges-release-2023-10-19/">formally arrested</a> last month. Japan's then foreign minister <a href="https://www.mofa.go.jp/press/kaiken/kaiken24e_000210.html" target="_blank">protested</a> the executive's detention with his Chinese counterpart on a visit to Beijing in April.翻译:中国于三月份以涉嫌间谍罪拘留了这位在多家媒体报道中被称为西山宏的高管，并于上个月被<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-formally-arrests-astellas-employee-suspected-spying-japan-urges-release-2023-10-19/">正式逮捕</a>。时任日本外务大臣在四月访问北京时向中国外长<a href="https://www.mofa.go.jp/press/kaiken/kaiken24e_000210.html" target="_blank">提出抗议</a>，抗议这名高管被拘留。</p>   <p>There has been no official confirmation that Kishida and Xi will hold a meeting, which some Japanese news outlets have said is being prepared for Thursday.翻译:目前还没有官方证实岸田和习近平将举行会面，一些日本新闻媒体表示正在为周四的会面做准备。</p>   <p>A spokesperson for Japan's foreign ministry said in an emailed statement that Tokyo had repeatedly urged Beijing at various levels to repatriate Japanese nationals detained in China and to ensure transparency in the judicial process.翻译:日本外务省发言人在一份电子邮件声明中表示，东京已多次敦促北京各级遣返在中国被拘留的日本公民，并确保司法程序的透明度。</p>   <p>"Although nothing has been decided on future Japan-China bilateral summit meetings, including on the occasion of the APEC summit meeting to be held this week, we will continue to urge the Chinese side to do so," Masashi Mizobuchi, assistant press secretary at the ministry, said.翻译:日本媒体助理新闻秘书沟渕正志表示：“虽然未来的日中双边峰会，包括本周即将举行的亚太经合组织峰会，尚未做出任何决定，但我们将继续敦促中方这样做。”该部表示。</p>   <p>China's foreign ministry said in a statement: "China has always supported China-Japan trade and economic cooperation, and provides a good environment for the lawful operation of Japanese companies in China and their employees."</p>    <h 1="">RISKY BUSINESS</h>  <p>Five Japanese nationals are currently detained in China with a total of 17 detained since 2015, the year after China's anti-espionage law went into effect, according to Japan's foreign ministry.翻译:日本外务省表示，目前有 5 名日本公民在中国被拘留，自 2015 年（中国反间谍法生效次年）以来，共有 17 人被拘留。</p>   <p>But the arrest of Nishiyama hit a nerve partly because of the timing - coming during a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/eu-ambassador-china-says-chinas-anti-espionage-law-not-good-news-2023-05-09/">sweeping national security crackdown</a> and because of the executive's high profile.翻译:但西山的被捕触动了人们的神经，部分原因是时机—— <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/eu-ambassador-china-says-chinas-anti-espionage-law-not-good-news-2023-05-09/">正值大规模的国家安全镇压</a>期间，以及这位高管的高调。</p>   <p>Nishiyama, a fluent Mandarin speaker and former board member of the Japanese Chamber of Commerce in China, attended several high-profile events with officials from both countries in recent years.翻译:西山能说一口流利的普通话，也是中国日本商会前董事会成员，近年来与两国官员一起出席了多次备受瞩目的活动。</p>   <p>He often spoke about his connections to officialdom, two people who knew him said on condition of anonymity.翻译:两位不愿透露姓名的认识他的人士表示，他经常谈论自己与官场的关系。</p>   <p>Because of Nishiyama's status, his arrest had symbolic importance, according to five Japanese government officials, who also spoke on condition of anonymity due to the sensitivity of the case.翻译:五名日本政府官员表示，由于西山的身份，他的被捕具有象征意义。由于案件敏感性，这些官员也要求匿名。</p>   <p>The officials said that since his detention there has been a sharp uptick in questions from business people asking if it is safe to travel to China, while some Japanese companies in China have been telling employees to keep a low profile and not push too hard in sales and other activities.翻译:官员们表示，自他被拘留以来，商界人士询问前往中国是否安全的问题急剧增加，而一些在华日本公司则一直告诉员工要保持低调，不要在销售上太卖力。和其他活动。</p>   <p>"People are worried that they may be arrested suddenly when they go to China," Takeshi Niinami, chairman of the Japan Association of Corporate Executives, told a news conference last month.翻译:日本企业高管协会会长新波武史在上个月的新闻发布会上表示：“人们担心他们去中国时可能会突然被捕。”</p>   <p>"Considering the current situation in China, it is very difficult to create an atmosphere that encourages people to do something new," said Niinami, who is also the CEO of drinks giant Suntory.</p>    <h 1="">DIFFICULT DECISIONS</h>  <p>In the first nine months of this year, Japan's net foreign direct investment (FDI) into mainland China slumped 30.6% on the year to 393.4 billion yen ($2.6 billion), even as its total worldwide FDI grew by nearly a fifth, according to ministry of finance data.翻译:日本经济部表示，今年前 9 个月，日本对中国大陆的外国直接投资净额 (FDI) 同比下降 30.6%，至 3,934 亿日元（26 亿美元），尽管其全球 FDI 总额增长了近五分之一的财务数据。</p>   <p>That is the lowest amount for the period going back to at least 2014 when the data series begins.翻译:这是至少可以追溯到 2014 年数据系列开始以来的最低金额。</p>   <p>Half the respondents in a recent survey of Japanese companies doing business in China said they would cut investments this year. Only 10% of the 8,300 firms said they would increase investments, according to the inaugural poll by the Japanese Chamber of Commerce in China published last month.翻译:最近一项针对在中国开展业务的日本企业的调查显示，一半受访者表示今年将削减投资。中国日本商会上个月发布的首次民意调查显示，8,300家企业中只有10%表示将增加投资。</p>   <p>The reasons for caution given by respondents included sluggish demand, cross border regulation and "concerns about the risk of investment in China at head office".翻译:受访者给出的谨慎理由包括需求低迷、跨境监管以及“总部对中国投资风险的担忧”。</p>   <p>Alongside the U.S., China is Japan's biggest trade partner, and a major unwind of that relationship is not on the immediate horizon, economists say.翻译:经济学家表示，中国与美国一样是日本最大的贸易伙伴，而且这种关系短期内不会出现大幅缓解。</p>   <p>But finding Japanese to staff offices in China could become more of a problem for Japanese firms.翻译:但对于日本公司来说，在中国的办事处寻找日本人可能会成为一个更大的问题。</p>   <p>The number of Japanese living in China has been on a steady decline over the last decade and totalled 102,066 in 2022, according to data collected by Japan's foreign ministry. A similar drop this year would mark the lowest number of expats there since at least 2004.翻译:日本外务省收集的数据显示，过去十年来，居住在中国的日本人数量持续下降，到 2022 年总数将达到 102,066 人。今年的类似下降将标志着至少自 2004 年以来的最低外籍人士数量。</p>   <p>A real estate agent in Beijing, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the Astellas case had a "huge impact" on his Japanese clients with people refusing assignments in China or their families opposing the moves because they are "scared" about getting in legal trouble.翻译:北京一位不愿透露姓名的房地产经纪人表示，安斯泰来案对他的日本客户产生了“巨大影响”，一些人拒绝在中国派遣工作，或者他们的家人反对此举，因为他们“害怕”陷入法律麻烦。</p>   <p>Stefan Angrick, a senior economist for Moody's Analytics based in Tokyo, said even some of the most pro-China business executives in Japan are now wary of security risks there.翻译:东京穆迪分析公司高级经济学家斯蒂芬·安格里克表示，即使是一些最亲中国的日本企业高管现在也对那里的安全风险保持警惕。</p>   <p>"Japan and China are two economies that are deeply intertwined with one another and are incredibly important for one another. It's a very difficult point in time to be navigating that as a decision maker, in business or politics," he said.翻译:“日本和中国是两个紧密相连的经济体，对彼此来说都极其重要。作为商业或政治决策者，现在是一个非常困难的时刻，”他说。</p>   <p>($1 = 151.7200 yen)翻译:（1 美元 = 151.7200 日元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Yukiko Toyoda, Kiyoshi Takenaka, John Geddie, Sakura Murakami and Francis Tang in Tokyo; Laurie Chen and Antoni Slodkowski in Beijing; and Andrew Silver in Shanghai; Writing by John Geddie; Editing by Lincoln Feast and Alexander Smith翻译:丰田由纪子、竹中清、约翰·格迪、村上樱和弗朗西斯·唐在东京的报道； Laurie Chen 和 Antoni Slodkowski 在北京；和安德鲁·西尔弗 (Andrew Silver) 在上海；约翰·格迪撰写；林肯·法斯特和亚历山大·史密斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 10:21:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">U7SABO3LJFKRTDPRCCTJUDDK4E</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/how-an-executives-arrest-struck-blow-japan-china-business-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Yukiko Toyoda, Kiyoshi Takenaka, Laurie Chen]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/ JAPAN</category>
                
                <category>CHINA (UPDATE 2, ANALYSIS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[富士康创始人郭台铭有资格竞选台湾总统]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/KJ3He8vvLhxVwVbzv4ORR0vID7w=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HCCPKSFQOFMV5C3TX3COYHIRIM.jpg" alt="Terry Gou, the founder of Taiwan's Foxconn, makes a speech at Banqiao Cihui Temple in New Taipei City翻译:台湾富士康创始人郭台铭在新北市板桥慈惠寺演讲" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Terry Gou, the founder of Taiwan's Foxconn, makes a speech at Banqiao Cihui Temple in New Taipei City翻译:台湾富士康创始人郭台铭在新北市板桥慈惠寺演讲, Taiwan October 29, 2023. REUTERS/Ann Wang/File Photo翻译:台湾富士康创始人郭台铭于2023年10月29日在台湾新北市板桥慈惠寺发表演讲。REUTERS/Ann Wang/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Terry Gou, the billionaire founder of major Apple supplier Foxconn <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2317.TW" target="_blank">(2317.TW)</a>, has collected three times the amount of signatures needed to qualify to run in Taiwan's presidential elections, the government said on Tuesday.翻译:政府周二表示，苹果主要供应商富士康<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2317.TW" target="_blank">（2317.TW）</a>的亿万富翁创始人郭台铭收集的签名数量是参加台湾总统选举所需数量的三倍。</p>   <p>In a statement, Gou thanked his backers for their "enthusiastic support" and vowed to work hard to achieve "peace across the Taiwan Strait".翻译:郭台铭在一份声明中感谢其支持者的“热情支持”，并发誓将努力实现“台海和平”。</p>   <p>Gou announced his bid in August, saying he wanted to unite the opposition and ensure the island did not become "the next Ukraine", blaming the ruling Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) for taking Taiwan to the brink of war by antagonising China which claims the island as its own territory.翻译:郭台铭在八月宣布参选，称他希望团结反对派，确保台湾不会成为“下一个乌克兰”，并指责执政的民进党与中国对抗，将台湾推向战争边缘。岛作为自己的领地。</p>   <p>Gou, who stepped down as Foxconn chief in 2019, had to gather around 300,000 voter signatures by Nov. 2 to qualify as an independent candidate, according election regulations.翻译:根据选举规定，于 2019 年辞去富士康首席执行官职务的郭台铭必须在 11 月 2 日之前收集约 30 万选民的签名，才有资格成为独立候选人。</p>   <p>The election commission said he got more than 900,000 valid signatures. He now has until next Friday to formally register his candidacy with the election commission.翻译:选举委员会表示，他获得了超过90万个有效签名。他现在必须在下周五之前向选举委员会正式登记其候选人资格。</p>   <p>Gou, 73, is one of four candidates in the election, due to be held in January. Opinion polls show he is the least favoured candidate, well behind front-runner, Lai Ching-te of the DPP and who is currently vice president.翻译:73 岁的郭台铭是定于 1 月份举行的选举的四名候选人之一。民意调查显示，他是最不受欢迎的候选人，远远落后于领先者、民进党现任副总统赖清德。</p>   <p>Gou has kept a low profile since a Chinese newspaper last month implied a tax probe into Foxconn's operations in China was due to Beijing's unhappiness with his campaign, given he could split the opposition vote and ensure victory for Lai.翻译:自从上个月一家中国报纸暗示对富士康在中国业务的税务调查是由于北京对他的竞选活动不满以来，郭台铭一直保持低调，因为他可以分散反对派的选票并确保赖智的胜利。</p>   <p>China's government detests Lai and views him as a separatist. He says only Taiwan's people can decide their future and has repeatedly offered talks with China which Beijing has rebuffed.翻译:中国政府厌恶黎智英，并将他视为分裂分子。他表示，只有台湾人民才能决定自己的未来，并多次提出与中国进行会谈，但遭到北京方面的拒绝。</p>   <p>While China's government has not confirmed the Foxconn investigation, Lai has assailed Beijing for targeting the firm. Gou has not commented on the matter.翻译:虽然中国政府尚未证实对富士康的调查，但黎智英批评北京针对该公司进行调查。郭台铭尚未对此事发表评论。</p>   <p>Speaking to reporters on Monday, Wellington Koo, head of Taiwan's National Security Council, said China "definitely" did not want Gou running given he could split the opposition vote.翻译:台湾国家安全委员会主席顾维钧周一对记者表示，中国“绝对”不希望郭台铭参选，因为他可能会瓜分反对派的选票。</p>   <p>"Aren't we all waiting to see if Terry Gou will run until the end?" he said.翻译:“我们不是都在等着看郭台铭是否会跑到最后吗？”他说。</p>   <p>The other two opposition candidates have shown little interest in wanting to work with Gou, and are instead talking to each other about cooperating against Lai.翻译:另外两名反对派候选人并没有表现出与郭台铭合作的兴趣，而是互相谈论合作对抗赖清德。</p>   <p>Foxconn says Gou no longer has anything to do with the company's day-to-day operations, though he remains its largest single shareholder.翻译:富士康表示，郭台铭不再与公司的日常运营有任何关系，但他仍然是公司最大的单一股东。</p>   <p>Asked on an earnings call on Tuesday about potential political risks from Gou's election bid, Foxconn Chairman Young Liu said Gou had the right to make his own decisions, but added that the company has "prepared for all possible cases".翻译:富士康董事长刘扬在周二的财报电话会议上被问及郭台铭竞选潜在的政治风险时表示，郭台铭有权做出自己的决定，但补充说该公司已“为所有可能的情况做好了准备”。</p>   <p>"I wish him the best. That's all I can say," Liu added.翻译:“我祝他一切顺利。这就是我能说的，”刘补充道。</p>    <span>Reporting by Jeanny Kao and Yimou Lee; Writing by Ben Blanchard; Editing by Jacqueline Wong and Miral Fahmy翻译:Jeanny Kao 和 Yimou Lee 报道；本·布兰查德 (Ben Blanchard) 撰写；编辑：Jacqueline Wong 和 Miral Fahmy</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 10:02:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7YATRJCSMBMITH5ZAF6DWHY4ZA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/foxconn-founder-terry-gou-qualifies-run-taiwan-president-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jeanny Kao, Yimou Lee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>TAIWAN</category>
                
                <category>ELECTION/ (UPDATE 2, TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国计划提供 1,370 亿美元的新资金来提振房地产市场 - 彭博社]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/r8ILxoZiJhU_3yqSeF8gca7Cwqw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YELOYXYU4FM2BACH3XYFXU2WWU.jpg" alt="Buildings of a residential compound are seen in Shanghai翻译:上海一处住宅小区的建筑" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Buildings of a residential compound are seen in Shanghai翻译:上海一处住宅小区的建筑, China, March 17, 2016. REUTERS/Aly Song</figcaption></figure>       <p>China plans to provide at least 1 trillion yuan ($137.22 billion) of low-cost financing to the nation's urban village renovation and affordable housing programs, Bloomberg News reported on Tuesday, citing people familiar with the matter.翻译:彭博社周二援引知情人士的话报道称，中国计划为全国城中村改造和保障性住房项目提供至少 1 万亿元人民币（1372.2 亿美元）的低成本融资。</p>   <p>The People's Bank of China (PBOC) will inject funds in phases through policy banks, with the money ultimately trickling down to households for home purchases, Bloomberg News reported.翻译:据彭博社报道，中国人民银行（PBOC）将通过政策性银行分阶段注入资金，资金最终流向家庭用于购房。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2875 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2875 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Nilutpal Timsina in Bengaluru; Editing by Kim Coghill翻译:Nilutpal Timsina 班加罗尔报道；编辑：金·科吉尔</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 09:55:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">S2A56FSFGVP4VHJMUX656IQC3I</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-is-eyeing-137-bln-new-funding-boost-housing-market-bloomberg-news-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/ (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[在中国与梵蒂冈关系紧张之际，北京主教访问香港]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>China's state-backed Bishop of Beijing visited Hong Kong on Tuesday amid fears among some Catholics that Beijing wants tighter control over religious affairs in Hong Kong.翻译:中国政府支持的北京主教周二访问了香港，一些天主教徒担心北京希望加强对香港宗教事务的控制。</p>   <p>The visit is the first trip by a mainland Chinese bishop since the former British colony was returned to China in 1997 and follows a landmark visit to the Chinese capital by his Hong Kong counterpart in April.翻译:此次访问是自1997年香港回归中国以来中国大陆主教的首次访问，此前香港主教于四月对中国首都进行了具有里程碑意义的访问。</p>   <p>For decades mainland Catholics have been split between an official church loyal to Beijing and an underground flock loyal to the Pope and the visit by Bishop Joseph Li will be closely watched given lingering tensions between China and the Vatican.翻译:几十年来，大陆天主教徒一直分裂为忠于北京的官方教会和忠于教皇的地下教会，鉴于中国和梵蒂冈之间挥之不去的紧张关系，李约瑟主教的访问将受到密切关注。</p>   <p>Li did not answer questions from the media on Tuesday, but visited the Hong Kong Catholic Cathedral of the Immaculate Conception in the financial hub's Mid-Levels district, and was due to tour other church facilities and a seminary.翻译:李嘉诚周二没有回答媒体提问，但参观了位于金融中心半山区的香港天主教圣母无染原罪主教座堂，并计划参观其他教堂设施和神学院。</p>   <p>When asked by the media whether Li would meet officials from Hong Kong Liaison Office, Beijing's core representatives in the city, the Bishop of Hong Kong Stephen Chow said that "they were not an obstacle, but played an active role" because mainland China has their own standards and systems.翻译:当被媒体问及李克强是否会见北京在香港的核心代表香港中联办官员时，香港主教周星驰表示，“他们不是障碍，而是发挥了积极作用”，因为中国大陆有自己的标准和体系。</p>   <p>Speaking to local media earlier this month ahead of the visit, Chow said Li's presence would serve to deepen connections between the Vatican and China.翻译:本月早些时候，周在访问前接受当地媒体采访时表示，李克强的到来将有助于加深梵蒂冈与中国之间的联系。</p>   <p>Hong Kong has traditionally been seen as a regional Catholic hub on the edge of the Chinese mainland under officially-atheist Communist Party rule.翻译:传统上，在无神论的共产党统治下，香港一直被视为位于中国大陆边缘的地区天主教中心。</p>   <p>Beijing has been following a policy of "Sinicisation" of religion, trying to root out foreign influences and enforce obedience to the Communist Party. There are an estimated 10-12 million Catholics in China. Hong Kong has 600,000 Catholics.翻译:北京一直奉行宗教“中国化”政策，试图根除外国影响并强制人们服从共产党。据估计，中国有 10-1200 万天主教徒。香港有60万天主教徒。</p>   <p>Tensions between Beijing and the Vatican over the appointment of bishops saw a confidential pact struck in 2018. The pact has been renewed twice, but remains tenuous, with the Vatican complaining Beijing has broken it several times.翻译:北京和梵蒂冈之间因主教任命问题而紧张，2018年达成了一项保密协议。该协议已两次续签，但仍然脆弱，梵蒂冈抱怨北京多次违反该协议。</p>   <p>Cardinal Joseph Zen, 91, former Bishop of Hong Kong and one of the most prominent Catholic clerics in Asia, wrote in a blog ahead of the visit on Thursday night that even though the situation may be more difficult than before, people still have to persevere, stay calm, and hold their heads high.翻译:91岁的香港前主教、亚洲最著名的天主教神职人员之一陈日君枢机在周四晚上访问之前在博客中写道，尽管情况可能比以前更加困难，但人们仍然必须坚持下去，保持冷静，昂首挺胸。</p>   <p>"Never consecrate a bishop without permission. Sacraments can be sacrificed, but faith cannot be sacrificed! Remember! Remember!" Cardinal Zen wrote.翻译:“未经许可，切勿祝圣主教。圣礼可以被牺牲，但信仰不能被牺牲！记住！记住！”陈枢机写道。</p>    <span>Reporting by Jessie Pang, Tyrone Siu and Joyce Zhou; Editing by Michael Perry翻译:Jessie Pang、Tyrone Siu 和 Joyce Zhou 报道；迈克尔·佩里编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:17:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RPMAACZ2UVM6HOI4F4VEUJ22EE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/beijing-bishop-visits-hong-kong-amid-tensions-between-china-vatican-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jessie Pang, Joyce Zhou]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>POLITICS/RELIGION (TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中东资产管理公司Investcorp拟设立首支人民币基金，规模高达5.5亿美元]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/OAqooqq-SYr6e475VYV28WO96HE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/G7UXAIAMRZONFNRTPTBZPYT5HM.jpg" alt="Signs of Chinese yuan and U.S. dollar are seen at a currency exchange store in Shanghai翻译:上海一家货币兑换店里出现人民币和美元的标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Signs of Chinese yuan and U.S. dollar are seen at a currency exchange store in Shanghai翻译:上海一家货币兑换店里出现人民币和美元的标志, China August 8, 2019. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2019 年 8 月 8 日，中国上海一家货币兑换店里出现人民币和美元的标志。REUTERS/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Bahrain-based alternative asset manager Investcorp is aiming to raise 2 billion to 4 billion yuan ($274 million-$548 million) for its first private equity fund in the Chinese currency, its executive said, to explore buyout opportunities in the country.翻译:总部位于巴林的另类资产管理公司 Investcorp 高管表示，其计划为其首支人民币私募股权基金筹集 20 亿至 40 亿元人民币（2.74 亿至 5.48 亿美元）资金，以探索该国的收购机会。</p>   <p>Investcorp plans to apply in the next few months for a license with Chinese regulatory bodies that will allow it to start raising funds from domestic institutions next year, Investcorp's co-chief executive officer Hazem Ben-Gacem said.翻译:Investcorp 联席首席执行官 Hazem Ben-Gacem 表示，Investcorp 计划在未来几个月内向中国监管机构申请许可，以便明年开始从国内机构筹集资金。</p>   <p>"I hope over time, we will be more than just a Middle East investor in China. I want us to be perceived also as a local Chinese investor," Ben-Gacem told Reuters, adding that the final fundraising size will depend on investor appetite and market conditions.翻译:Ben-Gacem 告诉路透社：“我希望随着时间的推移，我们将不仅仅是中国的中东投资者。我希望我们也被视为中国本土投资者。”他补充说，最终的融资规模将取决于投资者的兴趣和市场状况。</p>   <p>Abu Dhabi sovereign investor Mubadala holds a 20% stake in Investcorp.翻译:阿布扎比主权投资者穆巴达拉持有 Investcorp 20% 的股份。</p>   <p>Investcorp's China fundraising plan comes as business ties between the Middle East and the world's second-largest economy pick up amid the Gulf states' infrastructure, technology and financial push, and Sino-U.S. geopolitical tensions.翻译:Investcorp在中国的融资计划正值中东与世界第二大经济体之间的商业关系在海湾国家的基础设施、技术和金融推动以及中美地缘政治紧张局势的背景下得到加强。</p>   <p>Buyers from the Gulf states have announced 13 acquisitions of public and private Chinese targets this year, versus just one during the same period in 2022 and more than any other year since at least 1980, according to data compiled by LSEG.翻译:伦敦证券交易所集团 (LSEG) 汇编的数据显示，今年海湾国家的买家宣布了 13 起对中国公共和私人目标的收购，而 2022 年同期只有 1 起，而且比至少 1980 年以来的任何一年都要多。</p>   <p>Investcorp completed its first buyout in China in May, purchasing a controlling stake in Shandong Jianuo Electronics, which provides components used in applications such as electric vehicle power management and battery charging infrastructure.翻译:Investcorp于5月完成了在中国的首次收购，收购了山东嘉诺电子的控股权，该公司提供用于电动汽车电源管理和电池充电基础设施等应用的组件。</p>   <p>The deal size was about $100 million, according to a statement by the government in the city of Tengzhou, where Jianuo is based.翻译:根据嘉诺所在地滕州市政府的一份声明，此次交易规模约为 1 亿美元。</p>   <p>Other major transactions by Middle East investors in Chinese firms this year include <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/saudis-china-refinery-deal-covers-crude-oil-storage-petrochemical-supplies-2023-03-29/">Aramco's purchase</a> of a 10% stake in Rongsheng Petrochemical for 24.6 billion yuan, and Abu Dhabi government-backed CYVN Holdings' $738.5 million <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinas-nio-get-near-740-mln-investment-abu-dhabi-backed-firm-2023-06-20/">equity investment</a> in electric car maker NIO Inc.翻译:今年中东投资者对中国企业的其他重大交易包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/saudis-china-refinery-deal-covers-crude-oil-storage-petrochemical-supplies-2023-03-29/">沙特阿美公司以246亿元人民币收购</a>熔盛石化10%的股权，以及阿布扎比政府支持的CYVN Holdings对电动汽车制造商蔚来汽车公司7.385亿美元<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinas-nio-get-near-740-mln-investment-abu-dhabi-backed-firm-2023-06-20/">的股权投资</a>。</p>   <p>Ben-Gacem said the Gulf region might prove an important source of yuan-denominated capital, as Middle East countries and China settle some trades in their local currencies.翻译:本-加塞姆表示，随着中东国家和中国以当地货币结算一些贸易，海湾地区可能会成为人民币计价资本的重要来源。</p>   <p>"You have an increasing quantum of renminbi (yuan) sitting within the Gulf Cooperation Council that needs to go back to be reinvested in China," he said.翻译:他说：“海湾合作委员会内有越来越多的人民币需要回流到中国进行再投资。”</p>   <p>Sino-U.S. tensions and an uneven Chinese economic recovery have made many U.S. investors cautious about deploying fresh capital in China, complicating money managers' efforts to raise dollars for China-focused funds.翻译:中美紧张局势和中国经济复苏的不平衡使得许多美国投资者对在中国部署新资本持谨慎态度，这使得基金经理为专注于中国的基金筹集美元的努力变得更加复杂。</p>   <p>Some private equity and venture funds are stepping up efforts to raise yuan funds. Still, convincing yuan-based investors to commit capital could be challenging amid economic headwinds.翻译:一些私募股权和风险基金正在加紧募集人民币基金。尽管如此，在经济逆风的情况下，说服人民币投资者投入资金可能具有挑战性。</p>   <p>The yuan-denominated capital raised by China-focused venture funds totalled $7.5 billion so far this year, less than half of what was raised last year, while no China-focused buyout funds have been raised yet in 2023, according to data provider Preqin.翻译:数据提供商 Preqin 的数据显示，今年迄今为止，专注于中国的风险基金筹集的人民币计价资金总额为 75 亿美元，不到去年筹集的一半，而 2023 年尚未筹集到专注于中国的收购基金。</p>   <p>Investcorp, which manages over $42 billion in assets, has invested more than $500 million in China. It <a href="https://www.investcorp.com/investcorp-launches-its-debut-investment-in-china-in-partnership-with-china-everbright-limited/" target="_blank">kicked off</a> its private equity business in China in 2018 by investing in a tech-focused fund backed by China Everbright.翻译:Investcorp管理着超过420亿美元的资产，已在中国投资超过5亿美元。 2018年，该公司通过投资光大控股支持的科技型基金， <a href="https://www.investcorp.com/investcorp-launches-its-debut-investment-in-china-in-partnership-with-china-everbright-limited/" target="_blank">开启了</a>在中国的私募股权业务。</p>   <p>In 2022 it launched a $500 million fund with the Hong Kong-based private investment office of the Fung family, focusing on mid-cap companies across the southern Chinese province of Guangdong as well as Hong Kong and Macau.翻译:2022年，它与冯氏家族驻香港的私人投资办公室共同推出了一只5亿美元的基金，重点关注中国南部广东省以及香港和澳门的中型企业。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2884 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2884 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Roxanne Liu and Kane Wu; Editing by Sumeet Chatterjee and Gerry Doyle翻译:Roxanne Liu 和 Kane Wu 报道；编辑：Sumeet Chatterjee 和 Gerry Doyle</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:14:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">W6PWPIAJKFICNCF6Y5XABCWKWI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/middle-east-asset-manager-investcorp-eyes-up-550-mln-first-china-yuan-fund-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Roxanne Liu, Kane Wu]]></author>
            
                
                <category>INVESTCORP</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/FUND</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：随着债务风险上升，中国要求地方政府削减公私合营项目的投资]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/AQ1mTGyGkgwf9cQi1R7rzspzSGk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/Y6RFL5TNYFLRBNUGFPHDEQ3N3I.jpg" alt="A worker walks across a construction site in the Central Business District, ahead of the opening of the National People's Congress (NPC) in Beijing翻译:北京全国人民代表大会开幕前，一名工人走过中央商务区的建筑工地" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A worker walks across a construction site in the Central Business District, ahead of the opening of the National People's Congress (NPC) in Beijing翻译:北京全国人民代表大会开幕前，一名工人走过中央商务区的建筑工地, China, February 28, 2023. REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0pA1nwRqt-clfDTW7eE759y2vtA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SARTGOY64NJZFJNVRDTASS7IWM.jpg" alt="China showcases poverty alleviation during a government organised tour of Tibet翻译:中国在政府组织的西藏之旅中展示脱贫攻坚成果" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A man works at a construction site in Nyingchi, during a government-organised tour of the Tibet Autonomous Region, China, October 20, 2020. Picture taken October 20, 2020. REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2020年10月20日，在政府组织的中国西藏自治区考察期间，一名男子在林芝的一个建筑工地工作。照片拍摄于2020年10月20日。路透社/Thomas Peter/档案照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>China has ordered its local governments to halt public-private partnership projects identified as "problematic" and replaced a 10% budget spending allowance for these ventures with a vetting mechanism by Beijing as it tries to curb municipal debt risks.翻译:中国已下令地方政府停止被认定为“有问题”的公私合作项目，并用北京的审查机制取代了对这些项目的10%预算支出补贴，以试图遏制市政债务风险。</p>   <p>The guidelines were mentioned in a cabinet document that was circulated among local governments, policy banks and state lenders last month, said the two sources with knowledge of the matter. The latest guidelines have not been reported previously.翻译:两位知情人士表示，上个月在地方政府、政策性银行和国有银行之间分发的一份内阁文件中提到了这些指导方针。此前并未报道过最新的指导方针。</p>   <p>The State Council has issued detailed guidelines to reform the public-private partnership (PPP) model for the first time since its launch in 2014, and comes as worries grow about the impact of ballooning local government debt on the economy.翻译:自2014年推出以来，国务院首次发布了政府和社会资本合作（PPP）模式改革的详细指导方针，与此同时，人们越来越担心地方政府债务不断膨胀对经济的影响。</p>   <p>Local government debt reached 92 trillion yuan ($12.6 trillion), or 76% of China's economic output in 2022, up from 62.2% in 2019, according to the latest data from the International Monetary Fund.翻译:根据国际货币基金组织的最新数据，到2022年，地方政府债务将达到92万亿元人民币（12.6万亿美元），占中国经济产出的76%，高于2019年的62.2%。</p>   <p>In an effort to constrain the accumulation of further debt, Beijing will eliminate a regulation allowing local governments to earmark up to 10% of their annual public budget expenditures toward these projects, the sources said.翻译:消息人士称，为了限制债务进一步积累，北京将取消一项允许地方政府将最多 10% 的年度公共预算支出用于这些项目的规定。</p>   <p>The 10% expenditure threshold will now be replaced with government authorities' review of each PPP project, they said. The move comes after numerous local governments' PPP expenditure hit the upper limit of the threshold in recent years.翻译:他们表示，10%的支出门槛现在将由政府当局对每个 PPP 项目的审查所取代。此举是在近年来不少地方政府PPP支出触及门槛上限之后做出的。</p>   <p>The State Council also asked the local governments to halt "problematic projects", identified in inspections conducted by the National Audit Office (NAO) earlier this year, and address the identified issues, said the sources.翻译:消息人士称，国务院还要求地方政府停止审计署今年早些时候检查中发现的“问题项目”，并解决发现的问题。</p>   <p>Projects designated as "problematic" are those riddled with irregularities including in which local government financing vehicles (LGFVs) posed as the "private" partner, spurring excessive debt accumulation, one of the sources said.翻译:其中一位消息人士称，被认定为“有问题”的项目是那些充满违规行为的项目，其中包括地方政府融资平台（LGFV）冒充“私人”合作伙伴，刺激债务过度积累。</p>   <p>In addition to those measures, all PPP projects that have not finished bidding process to find partners by February this year will have to be suspended, said the two sources, who have direct knowledge of the State Council document.翻译:两位直接了解国务院文件的消息人士表示，除了这些措施外，今年 2 月之前尚未完成招标寻找合作伙伴的所有 PPP 项目都将不得不暂停。</p>   <p>Since 2014, Beijing has promoted a PPP model to channel private money into public infrastructure projects, to increase capital investment while easing the burden on heavily-indebted local governments.翻译:2014年以来，北京推广PPP模式，引导民间资金参与公共基础设施项目，增加资本投入，同时减轻负债累累的地方政府负担。</p>   <p>But the PPP boom has alarmed authorities who say some local governments have used public-private partnerships, government investment funds and government procurement services as "disguised channels" for raising debt.翻译:但PPP热潮引起了当局的警惕，他们表示，一些地方政府利用公私合作伙伴关系、政府投资基金和政府采购服务作为筹集债务的“变相渠道”。</p>   <p>Both the sources declined to be named due to sensitivity of the matter.翻译:由于此事的敏感性，两位消息人士均拒绝透露姓名。</p>   <p>The State Council and the NAO did not immediately respond to Reuters requests for comments.</p>    <h 1="">CURBING RISKS</h>  <p>Debt-laden local governments represent a major risk to the Chinese economy and its financial stability, economists say, amid a deepening property crisis, years of over-investment in infrastructure and huge bills to contain the COVID-19 pandemic.翻译:经济学家表示，在房地产危机不断加深、基础设施建设多年过度投资以及遏制新冠肺炎 (COVID-19) 疫情的巨额支出的背景下，负债累累的地方政府对中国经济及其金融稳定构成了重大风险。</p>   <p>A portion of the $12.6 trillion local government debt is linked to the PPP projects, as municipalities used these infrastructure-building initiatives as a conduit to raise capital.翻译:12.6 万亿美元的地方政府债务中有一部分与 PPP 项目相关，因为市政当局利用这些基础设施建设举措作为筹集资金的渠道。</p>   <p>As of the end-2022, China had implemented more than 14,000 PPP projects with the value of investment worth 20.9 trillion yuan ($2.87 trillion), or roughly the size of France's economy, according to a research note by Bank of China.翻译:中国银行的一份研究报告显示，截至2022年底，中国已实施了超过14,000个PPP项目，投资价值达20.9万亿元人民币（2.87万亿美元），大致相当于法国经济规模。</p>   <p>Beijing is now stepping up efforts to minimise the broader economic risk posed by the local government debt.翻译:北京目前正在加紧努力，尽量减少地方政府债务带来的更广泛的经济风险。</p>   <p>Reuters reported last month, citing sources with knowledge of the matter, that China has told state-owned banks to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-instructs-banks-roll-over-local-government-debt-sources-2023-10-17/">roll over existing local government debt</a> with longer-term loans at lower interest rates.翻译:路透社上个月援引知情人士的话报道称，中国已要求国有银行以较低利率以长期贷款<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-instructs-banks-roll-over-local-government-debt-sources-2023-10-17/">展期现有地方政府债务</a>。</p>   <p>The National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC), the top planner, and the finance ministry last week issued rules to encourage private firms to invest in PPP programs and allow them to take controlling stakes in some of those projects.翻译:国家发展和改革委员会（国家发改委）和财政部上周发布了规则，鼓励私营企业投资 PPP 项目，并允许它们在其中一些项目中控股。</p>   <p>The State Council document said that the oversight for PPP projects, such as vetting return-on-investment assessments and fiscal stress testing, will shift from the finance ministry to the NDRC, according to the sources.翻译:消息人士称，国务院文件称，PPP项目的投资回报评估审核和财政压力测试等监管职责将从财政部转移到国家发改委。</p>   <p>The finance ministry and the NDRC also did not respond to Reuters request for comment.翻译:财政部和国家发改委也没有回应路透社的置评请求。</p>   <p>Local governments are required to report all PPP projects to the State Council and the NDRC by November, the first source said, adding the municipalities are encouraged to issue special-purpose or general bonds to repay debt tied to the projects.翻译:第一位消息人士称，地方政府必须在 11 月之前向国务院和国家发改委报告所有 PPP 项目，并鼓励各市发行专项或一般债券来偿还与项目相关的债务。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2927 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2927 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Kevin Yao and Ziyi Tang; Editing by Sumeet Chatterjee and Shri Navaratnam翻译:Kevin Yao 和 Ziyi Tang 报道；编辑：Sumeet Chatterjee 和 Shri Navaratnam</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:06:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">QIKQGMTL2NIM7ENCW2FGPVZRQ4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-orders-local-governments-cut-exposure-public-private-projects-debt-risks-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/DEBT (EXCLUSIVE, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[克林斯曼表示，韩国不会轻视新加坡和中国]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ogJBJfvHxsiEt--E3LQx4-g3DfU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HD4LVAINH5IDRJ75QNI7WSOVH4.jpg" alt="South Korea's new head coach Klinsmann arrives at airport翻译:韩国新任主教练克林斯曼抵达机场" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>South Korean national soccer team's new head coach Juergen Klinsmann speaks upon his arrival at Incheon International Airport in Incheon, South Korea, March 8, 2023.   REUTERS/Kim Soo-hyeon/File Photo翻译:韩国国家足球队新任主教练尤尔根·克林斯曼于 2023 年 3 月 8 日抵达韩国仁川国际机场时发表讲话。路透社/Kim Soo-hyeon/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>South Korea begin their World Cup qualifying campaign against Singapore in Seoul on Thursday followed by a trip to face China, and while Juergen Klinsmann's side are expected to make short work of both opponents the German is taking nothing for granted.翻译:韩国队将于周四在首尔开始与新加坡队的世界杯预选赛，随后将前往中国队，虽然尤尔根·克林斯曼的球队预计将很快击败这两个对手，但德国人并不认为这是理所当然的。</p>   <p>The Koreans, who have appeared at the last 10 World Cups, are heavy favourites to top Group C in the second phase of qualifying for the 2026 tournament, which will be hosted in the U.S., Canada and Mexico and is the first to feature 48 teams.翻译:过去 10 次参加世界杯的韩国队是 2026 年世界杯预选赛第二阶段 C 组头名的热门球队，该赛事将在美国、加拿大和墨西哥举办，是首次有 48 支球队参加的世界杯。</p>   <p>After a rocky start to his tenure, Klinsmann has guided Korea to three straight wins in friendly matches and should make it five victories on the trot against 155th-ranked Singapore and number 79 China.翻译:克林斯曼在经历了上任初期的艰难开局后，带领韩国队在友谊赛中取得了三连胜，并且应该能够在对阵排名第155位的新加坡队和排名第79位的中国队的比赛中取得五场胜利。</p>   <p>"I don't agree with that at all. It will be the wrong way to look at it," Klinsmann said. "All the teams that fight for a spot in the World Cup will fight even harder now. It will be still very difficult.翻译:“我完全不同意这一点。这是错误的看待方式，”克林斯曼说。 “所有争夺世界杯席位的球队现在都会更加努力。这仍然会非常困难。</p>   <p>"You have to have a very professional mindset. We will be very serious in every World Cup qualifying game."翻译:“你必须有非常专业的心态。我们会非常认真地对待每一场世界杯预选赛。”</p>   <p>South Korea, number 24 in the FIFA rankings, have won the Asian Cup twice, but the regional heavyweights have not lifted the trophy since 1960.翻译:国际足联排名第24位的韩国队曾两次夺得亚洲杯冠军，但自1960年以来，该地区的重量级球队就再也没有举起过奖杯。</p>   <p>Klinsmann said winning the next edition in Qatar early next year was their number one target.翻译:克林斯曼表示，赢得明年初在卡塔尔举办的下一届赛事是他们的首要目标。</p>   <p>"We want to go there and win the Asian Cup," he added. "Not say maybe final four. Not maybe. We go there to win it.翻译:“我们想去那里赢得亚洲杯，”他补充道。 “不是说可能进入四强。也不是说可能。我们去那里是为了赢得胜利。</p>   <p>"You have to put this into your mind because a tournament is mainly a mind game. You have to build belief. You have to build credibility within the team that you can win it.翻译:“你必须把这一点牢记在心，因为锦标赛主要是一场智力游戏。你必须建立信念。你必须在团队中建立你可以赢得比赛的信誉。</p>   <p>"We have to aim for the highest goal. If we don't reach it, then it's the fault of the coach. It's no problem."翻译:“我们必须瞄准最高目标。如果我们达不到，那就是教练的错。没问题。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Pearl Josephine Nazare in Bengaluru; Editing by Peter Rutherford 翻译:Pearl Josephine Nazare 在班加罗尔的报道；彼得·卢瑟福编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 07:39:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">V2A5UMQO2NP63KVZMYLIITQAUQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sports/soccer/south-korea-will-not-take-singapore-china-lightly-says-klinsmann-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SOCCER</category>
                
                <category>SOUTHKOREA/KLINSMANN</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[全球电动汽车销量保持强劲，尽管补贴终止，中国仍创历史新高]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Mlhkjk060POe2xAh8Nx9eYXp2ms=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/LRKMPC55XJIMNGXGNI3BPXSWRY.jpg" alt="BYD electric vehicles are displayed at a BYD By 1826 cafe and car dealership in Singapore翻译:比亚迪电动汽车在新加坡 BYD By 1826 咖啡馆和汽车经销店展示" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>BYD electric vehicles are displayed at a BYD By 1826 cafe and car dealership in Singapore翻译:比亚迪电动汽车在新加坡 BYD By 1826 咖啡馆和汽车经销店展示 September 7, 2023. REUTERS/Edgar Su/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/3QTYsV_Jw0lWNd57iTSvybXBU0Q=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PIY5K6PYONPN7FAXNGNEKVKJIQ.jpg" alt="A Be.EV electric vehicle charging bay is seen at a car park in Manchester, Britain翻译:英国曼彻斯特的一个停车场内有一个Be.EV电动汽车充电站" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Be.EV electric vehicle charging bay is seen at a car park in Manchester, Britain翻译:英国曼彻斯特的一个停车场内有一个Be.EV电动汽车充电站, September 8, 2023. REUTERS/Phil Noble/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>Electric-vehicle sales are seeing continued strength globally with China reporting record monthly sales in October despite the end of subsidies, according to market research firm Rho Motion.翻译:市场研究公司 Rho Motion 的数据显示，全球电动汽车销量持续强劲，尽管补贴终止，但中国 10 月份的月度销量仍创历史新高。</p>   <p>China ended an 11-year subsidy scheme for EV purchases in 2022, but some local authorities have continued to offer aid or tax rebates to attract investments as well as subsidies for consumers.翻译:中国于 2022 年结束了为期 11 年的电动汽车购买补贴计划，但一些地方当局继续提供援助或退税以吸引投资以及为消费者提供补贴。</p>   <p>EV sales in China, the world's largest auto market, increased 29% year-to-date in September. The global EV market showed 34% growth in the same period.翻译:中国这个全球最大的汽车市场的电动汽车销量今年 9 月份增长了 29%。同期全球电动汽车市场增长34%。</p>   <p>China is entering the final two months of the year which are seasonally high for vehicle sales, according to Rho Motion.翻译:Rho Motion 表示，中国正进入今年最后两个月，这是汽车销售的季节性高点。</p>   <p>"What's notable about October's figures is that EV demand in China continues to reach record highs even though the subsidies were cut ... 2023 is set to be another banner year for China in terms of EV sales," the market research firm said.翻译:该市场研究公司表示：“10 月份的数据值得注意的是，尽管补贴被削减，中国的电动汽车需求仍继续创下历史新高……就电动汽车销售而言，2023 年将是中国电动汽车销售的又一个标志性年份。”</p>   <p>EV sales grew 26% in European markets, where cutting of subsidies has weighed on demand as seen in Germany where business subsidies were done away with in September, according to Rho Motion.翻译:Rho Motion 表示，欧洲市场的电动汽车销量增长了 26%，补贴的削减对需求造成了压力，就像德国在 9 月份取消了商业补贴一样。</p>   <p>"This (subsidies) is an important factor in the German market as nearly two-thirds of passenger car registrations are commercial," the market research firm said.翻译:该市场研究公司表示：“这（补贴）是德国市场的一个重要因素，因为近三分之二的乘用车注册都是商业性的。”</p>   <p>Tesla <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a>, Mercedes Benz <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MBGn.DE" target="_blank">(MBGn.DE)</a> and Volkswagen <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VOWG_p.DE" target="_blank">(VOWG_p.DE)</a> have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/electric-car-demand-set-stall-europes-valley-death-2023-11-13/">warned</a> high interest rates and a subdued market in the region are putting customers off.翻译:特斯拉<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a> 、梅赛德斯奔驰<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MBGn.DE" target="_blank">(MBGn.DE)</a>和大众汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VOWG_p.DE" target="_blank">(VOWG_p.DE)</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/electric-car-demand-set-stall-europes-valley-death-2023-11-13/">警告称，</a>该地区的高利率和低迷的市场正在让客户望而却步。</p>   <p>EV sales in North America were up 78% so far this year.翻译:今年迄今为止，北美电动汽车销量增长了 78%。</p>   <p>"The North American market continues to have a strong 2023, with Tesla still taking the lion's share of demand as legacy automakers <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/tesla-joins-gm-ford-slowing-ev-factory-ramp-demand-fears-spread-2023-10-19/">temper</a> ambitions of scaling production," Rho Motion said.翻译:Rho Motion 表示：“2023 年北美市场将继续强劲，随着传统汽车制造商<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/tesla-joins-gm-ford-slowing-ev-factory-ramp-demand-fears-spread-2023-10-19/">抑制</a>扩大生产规模的雄心，特斯拉仍占据需求的最大份额。”</p>   <p>Still, Tesla's market share <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/us-electric-vehicle-sales-hit-record-high-tesla-loses-market-share-report-2023-10-12/">slipped</a> to the lowest on record at about 50% during the third quarter despite price cuts, according to a report by dealer services firm Cox Automotive in October.翻译:尽管如此，根据经销商服务公司 Cox Automotive 10 月份的一份报告，尽管降价，特斯拉的市场份额在第三季度<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/us-electric-vehicle-sales-hit-record-high-tesla-loses-market-share-report-2023-10-12/">仍下滑</a>至有记录以来的最低水平，约为 50%。</p>    <span>Reporting by Arsheeya Bajwa in Bengaluru and Paul Lienert in Detroit; Editing by Shounak Dasgupta翻译:Arsheeya Bajwa 在班加罗尔和 Paul Lienert 在底特律的报道；肖纳克·达斯古普塔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 05:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">WDOONQ3IZVMLVKBR6QX7IKWFFM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/global-ev-sales-stay-strong-china-hits-record-despite-end-subsidies-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>EV</category>
                
                <category>GLOBAL SALES/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国毕业生推迟职业梦想，从事临时政府工作]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/sh82Yix3DDrl_QfeMO1S_3RN5vY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XQM3DMCYU5L53LWLPBZXZBANMY.jpg" alt="People attend a job fair in a mall in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家商场参加招聘会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People attend a job fair in a mall in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家商场参加招聘会, China June 30, 2023. REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2023 年 6 月 30 日，人们参加中国北京一家购物中心的招聘会。路透社/Thomas Peter/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0rCCoNzMVortKzoFW-6PrE-EuEU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MJ2TJP5VRVJI7KWCBUAP4UGMHQ.jpg" alt="Job fair in Beijing翻译:北京招聘会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Job seekers attend a job fair in Beijing, China February 16, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo/File Photo翻译:2023 年 2 月 16 日，求职者参加在中国北京举行的招聘会。路透社/Florence Lo/档案照片/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ORWYncqsedvGJIB1jaCATaLF_Tk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/INVO7ONG2VN5TJLUPSEWP6MG2U.jpg" alt="People attend a job fair in a mall in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家商场参加招聘会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People attend a job fair in a mall in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家商场参加招聘会, China June 30, 2023. REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2023 年 6 月 30 日，人们参加中国北京一家购物中心的招聘会。路透社/Thomas Peter/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/z5kD5Wgh5cSoClvs_OtCA4YPdyc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/Q2WVPRMPB5IYDF4LPXZISD2SRY.jpg" alt="People attend a job fair in a mall in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家商场参加招聘会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People attend a job fair in a mall in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家商场参加招聘会, China June 30, 2023. REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2023 年 6 月 30 日，人们参加中国北京一家购物中心的招聘会。路透社/Thomas Peter/资料照片</figcaption></figure>                   <p>Having failed to find his dream job at a Chinese internet company upon graduation, Peter Liu settled for a role in a state library where there is so little need for his participation that he spends his time studying for a change in his career path.翻译:毕业后，彼得·刘(Peter Liu)未能在一家中国互联网公司找到自己梦想的工作，他最终在一家州立图书馆找到了一份工作，那里几乎不需要他参与，所以他把时间花在了学习上，以期改变自己的职业道路。</p>   <p>"It's really hard to get work at big companies," said the 24-year-old who majored in TV production at a Beijing university before moving back home in the central Henan province.翻译:“在大公司找到工作真的很难，”这位 24 岁的年轻人说，他在北京一所大学主修电视制作，后来搬回了位于中部河南省的老家。</p>   <p>Liu got the librarian job after a government-led campaign to secure temporary work for graduates, which analysts describe as a short-term solution to preserve social stability in a slowing economy with little on offer for young Chinese.翻译:刘在政府主导的一场为毕业生争取临时工作的运动后获得了图书馆员的职位，分析人士称，这是在经济放缓、中国年轻人几乎没有什么机会的情况下维护社会稳定的短期解决方案。</p>   <p>Such "welfare jobs," as they are known in China, include roles as receptionists, office administrators, security guards and community workers. Various government institutions offer such jobs every year, but they had usually drawn applications from disadvantaged groups, such as elderly or disabled people.翻译:这些在中国被称为“福利工作”的岗位包括接待员、办公室管理员、保安和社区工作人员。各个政府机构每年都会提供此类工作，但通常都是从弱势群体（例如老年人或残疾人）中吸引申请。</p>      <p>This year, amid a deepening youth joblessness crisis in the world's second-largest economy, even remote rural positions have seen intense competition from young Chinese with diplomas from top universities, graduates and economists say.翻译:毕业生和经济学家表示，今年，在世界第二大经济体青年失业危机日益加深的情况下，即使是偏远的农村职位也面临着来自拥有顶尖大学文凭的中国年轻人的激烈竞争。</p>   <p>The government sees employment as key to pacifying China's most <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-pessimistic-gen-z-poses-challenge-xi-post-covid-2023-01-18/">pessimistic</a> generation in decades, while graduates gaining even limited work experience can also benefit their future employers if the economy recovers, analysts say.翻译:分析人士表示，政府认为就业是安抚中国数十年来最<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-pessimistic-gen-z-poses-challenge-xi-post-covid-2023-01-18/">悲观</a>一代的关键，而如果经济复苏，即使毕业生获得有限的工作经验也能让他们未来的雇主受益。</p>   <p>The one-to-three year contracts pay roughly the minimum wage in the region, typically between 2,000 and 3,000 yuan ($275-$412) per month, sometimes including free meals - much less than their average expectation for a first job salary of 8,033 yuan, according to a survey by Chinese recruitment firm Liepin.翻译:一到三年的合同支付的工资大致相当于该地区的最低工资，通常为每月 2,000 至 3,000 元（275 至 412 美元），有时包括免费餐 - 远低于他们对第一份工作 8,033 元的平均预期工资根据中国招聘公司猎聘的一项调查。</p>   <p>A separate programme aiming for 1 million internships this year has courted state-owned and private firms for participation.翻译:一项旨在今年提供 100 万个实习机会的单独计划吸引了国有和私营公司参与。</p>   <p>The Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security, which did not reply to a request for comment on the government programmes or the job market, told state media last week youth employment was improving.翻译:人力资源和社会保障部没有回复对政府计划或就业市场发表评论的请求，但上周对官方媒体表示，青年就业正在改善。</p>   <p>China has in the past year eased some regulatory burdens on tech, property and finance firms - traditionally large employers of new talent. But state media editorials have also encouraged young graduates to take <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinese-graduates-lower-their-ambitions-moribund-jobs-market-2023-05-31/">lower skilled</a> jobs.翻译:去年，中国减轻了科技、房地产和金融公司的一些监管负担，这些公司历来是新人才的大雇主。但官方媒体的社论也鼓励年轻毕业生从事<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinese-graduates-lower-their-ambitions-moribund-jobs-market-2023-05-31/">技术含量较低的</a>工作。</p>   <p>On Wednesday, the statistics bureau is expected to omit for the fourth consecutive month the release of youth unemployment data, suspended in July after reaching a record 21.3% in June, just as 11.6 million fresh graduates were entering the job market.翻译:周三，预计统计局将连续第四个月省略青年失业率数据的发布，该数据在 6 月份达到创纪录的 21.3% 后于 7 月份暂停发布，当时正值 1,160 万应届毕业生进入就业市场。</p>      <p>The total take-up of short-term jobs and internships remains unknown, but social media posts commenting on the selection process and discussing career options are frequent and analysts expect such roles will be in demand in a slowing economy.翻译:短期工作和实习的总人数仍不得而知，但社交媒体上经常出现评论甄选过程和讨论职业选择的帖子，分析师预计，在经济放缓的情况下，此类职位将会很受欢迎。</p>   <p>Still, the state sector - which provides a fifth of the urban jobs in China - can only temporarily alleviate economic pressure for a portion of university graduates through such campaigns, economists say, warning youth unemployment remains a major long-term headache for Beijing.翻译:尽管如此，经济学家表示，国有部门——提供了中国五分之一的城镇就业机会——只能通过此类运动暂时缓解部分大学毕业生的经济压力，并警告说，青年失业问题仍然是令北京方面长期头疼的一个主要问题。</p>   <p>"Youth unemployment will stay with us for quite a long time, at least for five-to-10 years," said Wang Jun, chief economist at Huatai Asset Management, adding the temporary jobs are "a short-term fix for stability, to relieve social conflicts brought by joblessness."翻译:华泰资产管理公司首席经济学家王军表示：“青年失业问题将在相当长的一段时间内困扰我们，至少会持续五到十年。”他补充说，临时就业岗位是“稳定稳定的短期解决方案”。缓解失业带来的社会矛盾。”</p>   <p>China had witnessed high youth unemployment in the late 1970s and early 1980s as educated youth returned to cities after working the farmlands under Mao Zedong, as well as in the late 1990s when the country began shrinking inefficient state conglomerates.翻译:在20世纪70年代末和1980年代初，随着知青在毛泽东领导下的农田工作后返回城市，以及在90年代末，当中国开始收缩效率低下的国有企业时，中国青年失业率居高不下。</p>   <p>A 23-year-old graduate surnamed Chen said she beat more than a dozen applicants in August to a secretary job at a local agriculture centre in the southwestern city of Chongqing.翻译:一名 23 岁的陈姓毕业生表示，8 月份，她击败了十几名应聘者，在西南部城市重庆的当地农业中心找到了一份秘书工作。</p>   <p>"The gap between my dreams and reality is huge," said Chen, who wanted to become a teacher.翻译:“我的梦想和现实之间的差距很大，”想成为一名教师的陈说。</p>   <p>Chen and Liu are both using the slow days at work to study for the highly-competitive 2024 civil service exam, which drew a record 2.6 million applicants, according to state media. If they pass, they would start on one of the most coveted career paths in China, often referred to as the "iron bowl" of financial stability.翻译:据官方媒体报道，陈和刘都在利用工作中的空闲时间来学习竞争激烈的 2024 年公务员考试，这次考试吸引了创纪录的 260 万人报名。如果通过，他们将开始中国最令人向往的职业道路之一，通常被称为金融稳定的“铁碗”。</p>      <p>Liu never expected to go for a public sector career, but for now he is at least happy that he can take that chance.翻译:刘从未想过会从事公共部门的职业，但现在他至少很高兴自己能抓住这个机会。</p>   <p>"I don't want my parents to see me staying at home all day with nothing to do," said Liu.翻译:“我不想让父母看到我整天呆在家里无所事事，”刘说。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2851 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2851 人民币）</p>    <span>additional reporting by Beijing newsroom; Graphics by Kripa Jayaram and Ellen Zhang
Editing by Shri Navaratnam翻译:北京新闻编辑室的补充报道；制图：Kripa Jayaram 和 Ellen 张 编辑：Shri Navaratnam</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:19:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MVK7JGSBL5KXFPKKLORKHXZV4M</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinese-graduates-hold-off-career-dreams-take-temporary-government-jobs-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ellen Zhang, Marius Zaharia]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/YOUTH (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[拜登和中国习近平将在亚太经合组织峰会上讨论沟通和竞争]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/SFmRtqPmpDU0oQvqzVeyXmjCW8Y=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/RB5ZXO6VRJPJVKYIQJAO7VQMEY.jpg" alt="G20 summit in Bali翻译:G20巴厘岛峰会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of the G20 leaders' summit in Bali, Indonesia, November 14, 2022.  REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque/File Photo翻译:美国总统乔·拜登于 2022 年 11 月 14 日在印度尼西亚巴厘岛举行的 G20 领导人峰会期间会见中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The White House said on Monday President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping will discuss strengthening communication and managing competition when they meet on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit this week.翻译:白宫周一表示，美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平本周将在亚太经合组织（APEC）峰会期间会面，讨论加强沟通和管理竞争的问题。</p>   <p>The face-to-face meeting in the San Francisco Bay Area on Wednesday will be the first between Biden and Xi in a year, with the high-stakes diplomacy aimed at curbing tensions between the two superpowers.翻译:周三在旧金山湾区举行的面对面会晤将是拜登和习近平一年来的首次会面，此次高风险外交旨在遏制两个超级大国之间的紧张关系。</p>   <p>White House national security adviser Jake Sullivan told reporters Biden believes there is no substitute for face-to-face diplomacy to manage the complex relationship.翻译:白宫国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文告诉记者，拜登认为，在处理复杂的关系方面，面对面的外交是无可替代的。</p>   <p>"We anticipate that the leaders will discuss some of the most fundamental elements of the U.S.-PRC bilateral relationship, including the continued importance of strengthening open lines of communication and managing competition responsibly so that it does not veer into conflict," Sullivan said, referring to the People's Republic of China.翻译:沙利文表示：“我们预计领导人将讨论美中双边关系的一些最基本要素，包括加强开放的沟通渠道和负责任地管理竞争以使其不会演变成冲突的持续重要性。”至中华人民共和国。</p>   <p>"The way we achieve that is through intense diplomacy. That's how we clear up misperceptions and avoid surprises."翻译:“我们实现这一目标的方法是通过激烈的外交。这就是我们消除误解并避免意外的方法。”</p>   <p>Sullivan said Biden would go into the summit "on a solid footing," having positioned the United States to be able to compete effectively at home and abroad and with "the strongest recovery and lowest inflation of any leading economy."翻译:沙利文表示，拜登将以“坚实的基础”参加峰会，使美国能够在国内外进行有效竞争，并实现“所有主要经济体中最强劲的复苏和最低的通胀”。</p>   <p>He said Washington is looking for specific outcomes from the meeting and hoped to see progress in reestablishing military-to military ties with China and in combating the trade in fentanyl that has become a scourge in the United States.翻译:他表示，华盛顿正在寻求此次会议的具体成果，并希望看到在与中国重建军事关系以及打击已成为美国祸害的芬太尼贸易方面取得进展。</p>   <p>China cut off military-to-military communications with the United States last year after a visit to Taiwan, a democratically governed island China claims as its own, by then U.S. House speaker Nancy Pelosi. Tense relations soured further when the U.S. shot down U.S. spy balloon In February.翻译:去年，时任美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西访问台湾后，中国切断了与美国的军事联系。台湾是一个民主治理的岛屿，中国声称拥有自己的岛屿。当美国二月份击落美国间谍气球后，紧张关系进一步恶化。</p>   <p>Sullivan said communication between the militaries was the way to ensure competition did not veer into conflict and that China had been "constructive" on the issue in dialogue leading up to the summit.翻译:沙利文表示，军方之间的沟通是确保竞争不会演变成冲突的方式，并且中国在峰会前的对话中对此问题表现出“建设性”态度。</p>   <p>"We will see what happens in San Francisco and the President will be able to report after the meeting, whether in fact, we've made progress on restoring military-to-military links," he said.翻译:他说：“我们将看看旧金山会发生什么，总统将能够在会后报告，我们是否在恢复军事联系方面确实取得了进展。”</p>   <p>Biden and Xi have known each other for more than a decade and have shared hours of conversation over six interactions since Biden's 2021 inauguration.翻译:拜登和习近平已经相识十多年，自拜登 2021 年就职以来，双方已进行了六次互动，进行了数小时的交谈。</p>   <p>However, they have met only once in person since then and Xi has not visited the United States since 2017. Analysts and officials say they will come to the table in an atmosphere of mutual suspicion and garbled impressions of what the other is seeking.翻译:然而，自那以后，他们只见过一次面，而习近平自 2017 年以来就没有访问过美国。分析人士和官员表示，他们将在相互猜疑的气氛中进行会谈，并对对方的追求产生错误的印象。</p>   <p>The meeting is also <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/">expected to cover</a> global issues from the Israel-Hamas war to Russia's invasion of Ukraine, North Korea's ties with Russia, Taiwan, human rights, artificial intelligence, as well as "fair" trade and economic relations, senior Biden administration officials said.翻译:拜登政府高级官员<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/">预计，此次会议还将涵盖</a>以色列与哈马斯战争、俄罗斯入侵乌克兰、朝鲜与俄罗斯的关系、台湾、人权、人工智能以及“公平”贸易和经济关系等全球问题。说。</p>   <p>Sullivan said Biden would raise stability across the Middle East, adding that Beijing should share an interest in de-escalation there.翻译:沙利文表示，拜登将提高整个中东地区的稳定，并补充说，北京应该对缓和那里的局势感兴趣。</p>   <p>Biden would make the point that Iran acting in an "escalatory, destabilizing way" was not in the interests of China, he said. "And the PRC, of course, has a relationship with Iran, and it's capable, if it chooses, to of making those points directly to the Iranian government."翻译:他说，拜登将指出伊朗以“升级、破坏稳定的方式”行事不符合中国的利益。 “当然，中华人民共和国与伊朗有关系，如果它愿意的话，它有能力直接向伊朗政府提出这些观点。”</p>   <p>Leaders from the 21-member APEC forum <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">are due to gather</a> in San Francisco from Wednesday until Friday and the wars in the Middle East and Ukraine have divided opinion among them.翻译:由 21 个成员组成的亚太经合组织论坛的领导人<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">定于周三至周五齐聚</a>旧金山，中东和乌克兰的战争使他们意见分歧。</p>   <p>The senior U.S. official for APEC, Matt Murray, told reporters on Monday that the U.S. was working hard to try to get a strong <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-says-its-working-hard-have-strong-consensus-leaders-declaration-apec-2023-11-13/">consensus statement</a> from the leaders, but analysts say the divisions make drafting this difficult.翻译:美国亚太经合组织高级官员马特·默里周一对记者表示，美国正在努力争取领导人达成强有力的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-says-its-working-hard-have-strong-consensus-leaders-declaration-apec-2023-11-13/">共识声明</a>，但分析人士表示，分歧使得起草过程变得困难。</p>   <p>Sullivan said that at APEC Biden would put forward his economic vision for the region and speak about "how the United States is the preeminent driver of inclusive, sustainable economic growth in the Asia Pacific."翻译:沙利文表示，拜登将在亚太经合组织上提出他对该地区的经济愿景，并谈到“美国如何成为亚太地区包容性、可持续经济增长的卓越推动者”。</p>   <p>(This story has been refiled to remove extraneous words from paragraph 1)翻译:（这个故事已被重新归档，以删除第 1 段中无关的文字）</p>    <span>Reporting by Steve Holland, Nandita Bose in Washington; Additional reporting by David Brunnstrom; Editing by Alistair Bell翻译:史蒂夫·霍兰德 (Steve Holland)、南迪塔·博斯 (Nandita Bose) 驻华盛顿报道；大卫·布伦斯特罗姆 (David Brunnstrom) 的补充报道；阿利斯泰尔·贝尔 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 22:32:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">SS6BME357JKGRHOQDVIUIRZTGE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-chinas-xi-will-discuss-communication-competition-apec-summit-2023-11-13/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Steve Holland, Nandita Bose]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/ (CORRECTED, UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
