<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 07:27:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[拜登和习近平将在受阿片类药物危机困扰的城市讨论芬太尼问题]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/OOzC6ioQ-mgW-8aYP2bkIe3IQFc=/1200x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZCI4IIB2RNMYHP6QARETZE2TBM.jpg" alt="U.S. Customs and Border Protection photo of packets of fentanyl mostly in powder form and methamphetamine which U.S. Customs and Border Protection say they seized from a truck crossing into Arizona from Mexico翻译:美国海关和边境保护局照片，其中大部分是粉末形式的芬太尼和甲基苯丙胺，美国海关和边境保护局表示，他们从一辆从墨西哥进入亚利桑那州的卡车上查获了这些物品" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Packets of fentanyl mostly in powder form and methamphetamine, which U.S. Customs and Border Protection say they seized from a truck crossing into Arizona from Mexico, is on display during a news conference at the Port of Nogales, Arizona, U.S., January 31, 2019.   Courtesy U.S. Customs and Border Protection/Handout via REUTERS /File Photo翻译:2019 年 1 月 31 日，在美国亚利桑那州诺加利斯港举行的新闻发布会上，美国海关和边境保护局表示，他们从一辆从墨西哥进入亚利桑那州的卡车上查获了几包芬太尼和甲基苯丙胺，这些芬太尼主要是粉末形式和甲基苯丙胺。由美国海关和边境保护局提供/来自路透社的讲义/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TG1TEqoix0BmSLzAs_2ZQkKdhx0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XVZII463FBIDNM7WDJMOYPZZ6Q.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden disembarks from Air Force One at San Francisco International Airport, as he arrives to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 14 日，美国总统乔·拜登在旧金山国际机场从空军一号下机，抵达美国加利福尼亚州旧金山参加亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会。 REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lTdjpZN9pb-WDBwFVbkn4Qq-Rig=/1878x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JFCDJ65EHNIW7MVYN3IPSOJ6AQ.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping waves as he arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的APEC（亚太经合组织）峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small/资料照片</figcaption></figure>                 <p>Just blocks from where U.S. President Joe Biden and his Chinese counterpart Xi Jinping will meet other Asia-Pacific leaders this week in San Francisco is a neighborhood where it is commonplace to see people using and selling drugs.翻译:距离美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平本周在旧金山会见其他亚太领导人的地点仅几个街区，在这个街区，人们吸毒和贩卖毒品的现象司空见惯。</p>   <p>While the leaders are unlikely to see the blunt reality of the U.S. opioid crisis as they attend the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum, it will be a topic of discussion when <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">Biden and Xi meet</a> one-on-one on Wednesday.翻译:尽管领导人在出席亚太经合组织（APEC）论坛时不太可能看到美国阿片类药物危机的严峻现实，但这将成为<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">拜登和习近平周三一对一会面</a>时讨论的话题。</p>   <p>The United States wants China's cooperation to stop an illicit flow of "precursor" chemicals that are used to make fentanyl, which is up to 50 times stronger than heroin and is increasingly mixed with other drugs - often with lethal results.翻译:美国希望与中国合作，制止用于制造芬太尼的“前体”化学品的非法流动，芬太尼的浓度比海洛因高出 50 倍，并且越来越多地与其他药物混合 - 往往会造成致命的结果。</p>   <p>In the first nine months of this year, 619 people died of an opioid overdose in San Francisco, most related to the synthetic opioids, compared with 647 such deaths in the whole of 2022, according to the city's Office of the Chief Medical Examiner.翻译:据旧金山首席法医办公室称，今年前 9 个月，旧金山有 619 人死于阿片类药物过量，其中大部分与合成阿片类药物有关，而 2022 年全年此类死亡人数为 647 人。</p>   <p>"It's out of control," said Mike Odeh, 36, a salesperson at a liquor store near where APEC leaders will meet.翻译:“事情已经失控了，”36 岁的迈克·奥德 (Mike Odeh) 说，他是 APEC 领导人会面地点附近一家酒类商店的销售人员。</p>   <p>He said that while the city had been cleaning up the streets ahead of APEC, he normally sees people using fentanyl while walking his son to the park and to school, adding: "You can see it all over. Not this week of course."翻译:他说，虽然该市在亚太经合组织之前一直在清理街道，但他通常会看到人们在送儿子去公园和上学时使用芬太尼，并补充道：“你可以看到这一切。当然不是本周。”</p>   <p>Across the country the rate of drug overdose deaths involving fentanyl more than tripled from 2016 through 2021, according to the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Tens of thousands of people die annually from synthetic opioid overdoses, government statistics show.翻译:根据美国疾病控制与预防中心 (CDC) 的数据，从 2016 年到 2021 年，全国范围内涉及芬太尼的药物过量死亡率增加了两倍多。政府统计数据显示，每年有数万人死于合成阿片类药物过量。</p>   <p>U.S. National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan said on Tuesday that Washington hoped the Biden-Xi summit would result in action to combat the fentanyl trade. A source familiar with plans said the U.S. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-set-take-action-win-chinas-cooperation-fentanyl-2023-11-14/">was ready to remove</a> restrictions on the Institute of Forensic Science, part of China's Ministry of Public Security.翻译:美国国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文周二表示，华盛顿希望拜登与习近平的峰会能够采取行动打击芬太尼贸易。一位熟悉计划的消息人士称，美国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-set-take-action-win-chinas-cooperation-fentanyl-2023-11-14/">准备取消</a>对中国公安部司法鉴定所的限制。</p>   <p>Washington put the institute on the Commerce Department's "entity list" in 2020 over alleged abuses toward Uyghurs and other minority groups - effectively barring it from receiving U.S. exports. China has long questioned why the U.S. would expect cooperation on fentanyl while targeting the institute.</p>    <h 1="">CHINA, MEXICO, US STANCES</h>  <p>China's embassy in Washington declined to comment on the fentanyl issue. Chinese state media has repeatedly said addiction and demand for the drug are U.S. domestic problems.翻译:中国驻华盛顿大使馆拒绝就芬太尼问题发表评论。中国官方媒体多次表示，这种药物的成瘾和需求是美国的国内问题。</p>   <p>U.S. officials say that small chemical businesses in China make precursor chemicals that are shipped to Mexico to produce illicit fentanyl, which is often mixed with other illegal drugs, sold as powders and nasal sprays, and increasingly turned into pills that look like legitimate prescription opioids. These are then smuggled into the United States, the officials say.翻译:美国官员表示，中国的小型化学企业生产前体化学品，然后运往墨西哥生产非法芬太尼，芬太尼通常与其他非法药物混合，以粉末和鼻喷雾剂的形式出售，并越来越多地制成看起来像合法处方阿片类药物的药丸。官员们说，这些东西随后被走私到美国。</p>   <p>Last month, the United States imposed sanctions on 28 people and entities involved with the international proliferation of illicit drugs, including a large China-based network.翻译:上个月，美国对 28 名参与国际非法毒品扩散的个人和实体实施制裁，其中包括一个大型中国网络。</p>   <p>"We know that this global fentanyl supply chain, which ends with the deaths of Americans, often starts with chemical companies in China," said U.S. Attorney General Merrick Garland.翻译:美国司法部长梅里克·加兰表示：“我们知道，这条以美国人死亡为终点的全球芬太尼供应链，往往始于中国的化学公司。”</p>   <p>Advocates have also accused pharmaceutical companies and related businesses of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/rite-aid-joins-companies-going-bankrupt-amid-opioid-litigation-2023-10-16/">fueling the crisis</a> through downplaying the risks of opioids and lack of regulation. Landmark settlements since 2021 have set compensation at a total of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/groups-fighting-us-opioid-crisis-settlement-money-can-be-hard-come-by-2023-06-17/">more than $50 billion nationwide</a>.翻译:支持者还指责制药公司和相关企业淡化阿片类药物的风险和缺乏监管，从而<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/rite-aid-joins-companies-going-bankrupt-amid-opioid-litigation-2023-10-16/">加剧了危机</a>。自 2021 年以来，具有里程碑意义的和解协议已将<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/groups-fighting-us-opioid-crisis-settlement-money-can-be-hard-come-by-2023-06-17/">全国范围内的赔偿总额定为超过 500 亿美元</a>。</p>   <p>Biden is also due to meet with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/mexicos-president-meet-chinese-counterpart-apec-summit-minister-2023-11-14/">Mexican President</a> Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador in San Francisco. Mexican Foreign Minister Alicia Barcena said talks would include how to better control the arrival from Asia of precursors used to make fentanyl.翻译:拜登还将于旧金山会见<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/mexicos-president-meet-chinese-counterpart-apec-summit-minister-2023-11-14/">墨西哥总统</a>安德烈斯·曼努埃尔·洛佩兹·奥夫拉多尔。墨西哥外交部长阿丽西娅·巴尔塞纳表示，会谈将包括如何更好地控制来自亚洲的用于制造芬太尼的前体。</p>   <p>In San Francisco, state and local officials have tried to clean up drugs from the city's streets, with limited success. The crisis has drawn sharp criticism from residents in the city, where drug-fuelled crime has forced some businesses to leave.翻译:在旧金山，州和地方官员试图清除该市街道上的毒品，但收效甚微。这场危机引起了该市居民的尖锐批评，毒品犯罪迫使一些企业离开。</p>   <p>San Francisco's new district attorney, Brooke Jenkins, has made prosecuting drug dealers a cornerstone of her agenda. The city recently formed a law enforcement task force to investigate opioid-linked deaths and poisonings.翻译:旧金山新任地方检察官布鲁克·詹金斯 (Brooke Jenkins) 将起诉毒贩作为她议程的基石。该市最近成立了一个执法工作组，调查与阿片类药物相关的死亡和中毒事件。</p>   <p>The city's Mayor London Breed has pushed to prioritize treatment for drug users, talked of police action as a way to solve the problem, and has called on the federal government to boost its drug trafficking enforcement.翻译:该市市长伦敦·布里德（London Breed）推动优先考虑吸毒者的治疗，谈到警方采取行动作为解决问题的一种方式，并呼吁联邦政府加强对贩毒的执法力度。</p>   <p>"We know San Francisco - and cities across the United States - will benefit from more targeting of the trafficking and production of fentanyl worldwide," a spokesperson for Breed said in a statement.翻译:布里德发言人在一份声明中表示：“我们知道，旧金山以及美国各地的城市将受益于全球范围内更多针对芬太尼贩运和生产的打击。”</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Michael Martina; Writing by Sayantani Ghosh and Michelle Nichols; Editing by Josie Kao翻译:迈克尔·玛蒂娜 (Michael Martina) 的补充报道；由 Sayantani Ghosh 和 Michelle Nichols 撰写；编辑：高乔茜</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 07:03:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">67JHX74B4BIPXL3MEJMYDJ3MRI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Peter Henderson, Anna Tong, Trevor Hunnicutt]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>FENTANYL (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[台湾反对派联合竞选总统挑战领先者]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/xsCPFnftVqP4hDFqbsbVDNoxAPE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/LRBCJKINDZIKLGEC5XZ6772JTY.jpg" alt="Taiwan's Kuomintang Chairman and Taiwan People’s Party Chairman pose for a group photo in Taipei翻译:台湾国民党主席与台湾人民党主席在台北合影" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Taiwan's Kuomintang (KMT) Chairman Eric Chu, Hou Yu-ih candidate for Taiwan's presidency from the main opposition party Kuomintang, former Taiwan president Ma Ying-jeou and Taiwan People’s Party Chairman Ko Wen-je hold hands as they pose for a group photo in Taipei, Taiwan November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Ann Wang翻译:台湾国民党主席朱立伦、台湾主要反对党国民党总统候选人侯裕义、台湾前总统马英九、台湾人民党主席柯文哲手牵手合影。台湾台北，2023 年 11 月 15 日。路透社/Ann Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/97iJ4eGkqx59HgHugX6ymF9Arn8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6DWMM5DN35IDLC67FTGVF25S6U.jpg" alt="Taiwan's Kuomintang Chairman and Taiwan People’s Party Chairman pose for a group photo in Taipei翻译:台湾国民党主席与台湾人民党主席在台北合影" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Taiwan's Kuomintang (KMT) Chairman Eric Chu, Hou Yu-ih candidate for Taiwan's presidency from the main opposition party Kuomintang, former Taiwan president Ma Ying-jeou and Taiwan People’s Party Chairman Ko Wen-je hold hands as they pose for a group photo in Taipei, Taiwan November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Ann Wang翻译:台湾国民党主席朱立伦、台湾主要反对党国民党总统候选人侯裕义、台湾前总统马英九、台湾人民党主席柯文哲手牵手合影。台湾台北，2023 年 11 月 15 日。路透社/Ann Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/E7yevZ7BnPFI-Qnv2zEwWu4TYSU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/LH73IAMKPFNGZLNFRRGGSG4TZU.jpg" alt="Hou Yu-ih, candidate for Taiwan's presidency, surrounded by members of the media as he leaves a press event in Taipei,翻译:台湾总统候选人侯友义在台北举行的新闻发布会上被媒体成员包围，" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Hou Yu-ih, candidate for Taiwan's presidency from the main opposition party Kuomintang (KMT), surrounded by members of the media as he leaves a press event in Taipei, Taiwan November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Ann Wang翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，主要反对党国民党 (KMT) 的台湾总统候选人侯裕义在台湾台北举行的新闻发布会上被媒体成员包围。路透社/Ann Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/VkSjPmEY5FoM_h20qgPn2uFJm-s=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FGFFNNRNWJMZXNYSKDPQAFLCIU.jpg" alt="Taiwan People’s Party Chairman Ko Wen-je speaks to the media in Taipei翻译:台湾人民党主席柯文哲在台北向媒体发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Taiwan People’s Party Chairman Ko Wen-je speaks to the media in Taipei翻译:台湾人民党主席柯文哲在台北向媒体发表讲话, Taiwan November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Ann Wang翻译:台湾人民党主席柯文哲于2023年11月15日在台湾台北向媒体发表讲话。路透社/Ann Wang</figcaption></figure>                   <p>Taiwan's two main opposition parties, which have vowed to renew talks with China, agreed on Wednesday to make a decision on a joint presidential ticket for January's elections, as the front-running ruling party decried interference from Beijing.翻译:台湾两个主要反对党誓言要与中国重启谈判，周三同意就一月选举的联合总统候选人做出决定，领先的执政党谴责北京的干涉。</p>   <p>The issue of China, which views Taiwan as its territory, looms over the Jan. 13 parliamentary and presidential elections. China has stepped up military and political pressure to press the island to accept its sovereignty claim, which Taiwan rejects, including high-profile war games.翻译:将台湾视为其领土的中国问题在 1 月 13 日的议会和总统选举中显得尤为突出。中国加大了军事和政治压力，迫使台湾接受其主权主张，其中包括高调的军事演习，而台湾对此予以拒绝。</p>   <p>Vice President Lai Ching-te, the ruling Democratic Progressive Party's (DPP) presidential candidate, has almost consistently led opinion polls, leaving candidates of the main opposition Kuomintang (KMT), Hou Yu-ih, and the Taiwan People's Party (TPP), Ko Wen-je, to battle it out for second place.翻译:执政党民进党总统候选人、副总统赖清德几乎一直领先民意调查，让主要反对党国民党、侯裕义和台湾人民党的候选人，柯文哲，争夺第二名。</p>   <p>The KMT and TPP have been in acrimonious talks since last month on a united presidential bid, but had failed to agree how to decide who should be the presidential candidate and who should be the running mate.翻译:国民党和跨太平洋党自上个月以来就联合竞选总统进行了激烈的谈判，但未能就如何决定谁应该成为总统候选人以及谁应该成为竞选搭档达成一致。</p>   <p>After talks hosted by former president Ma Ying-jeou, also a senior KMT member, the two parties said they had agreed to use opinion polls conducted between Nov. 7 and this Friday to decide the make-up of the presidential bid with the result to be announced on Saturday.翻译:在前总统、国民党资深委员马英九主持会谈后，两党表示，他们同意利用 11 月 7 日至本周五进行的民意调查来决定总统竞选的组成，结果将于周六公布。</p>   <p>"No matter what, whoever is the lead and whoever is the deputy, everyone will work together," Hou told reporters, referring to who gets the presidential candidate spot and who the gets the vice presidential one.翻译:“不管怎样，无论谁是领导，谁是副总统，大家都会一起努力，”侯告诉记者，他指的是谁获得总统候选人席位，谁获得副总统席位。</p>   <p>"The cooperation isn't only just between the KMT and the TPP. It will unite Taiwan," Hou told business leaders after the talks.翻译:侯先生在会谈后对商界领袖表示：“这种合作不仅仅是国民党和TPP之间的合作。它将团结台湾。”</p>   <p>China cut off routine talks with Taiwan after President Tsai Ing-wen of the DPP took office in 2016. The two opposition parties have vowed to pursue dialogue with China, on an equal and dignified basis, and "restore peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait".</p>    <h 1="">OPPOSITION CHALLENGE</h>  <p>Chen Yi-fan, an assistant professor of diplomacy and international relations at Taiwan's Tamkang University, said if Hou and Kou did not work together then Lai would certainly win.翻译:台湾淡江大学外交与国际关系助理教授陈一凡表示，如果侯和寇不合作，那么赖智肯定会赢。</p>   <p>"The U.S. and China both want stabilised Taiwan Strait relations. Lai may not be the ideal person for this," Chen said.翻译:“美国和中国都希望稳定台海关系。赖清德可能不是这个理想的人选，”陈说。</p>   <p>As the talks got underway, the DPP accused Ma, who last week came out in support of using opinion polls, which the KMT had previously opposed, of taking his instructions from China, given the head of Ma's foundation, Hsiao Hsu-tsen, had visited Beijing this month.翻译:随着会谈的进行，民进党指责马英九听从了中国的指示。马英九上周公开表示支持使用民意调查，而国民党此前曾反对民意调查。本月访问了北京。</p>   <p>"It is not baseless to say, as Vice President Lai has repeatedly done so, that it is China's communist party which most wants to take down the DPP," the party said in a statement.翻译:民进党在一份声明中表示：“正如赖副主席一再说过的那样，中国共产党最想打倒民进党，这并非毫无根据。”</p>   <p>Hsiao rebuffed that, telling reporters he had been in Beijing purely for an academic forum.翻译:萧反驳了这一说法，他告诉记者，他来北京纯粹是为了参加学术论坛。</p>   <p>China detests Lai, believing he is a separatist. Lai says only Taiwan's people can decide their future and has repeatedly offers talks with Beijing, which has rejected the offers.翻译:中国憎恶赖，认为他是分裂分子。黎智英表示，只有台湾人民才能决定自己的未来，并多次提出与北京方面进行会谈，但遭到北京方面的拒绝。</p>   <p>The DPP champions Taiwan's separate identity from China.翻译:民进党主张台湾与中国的独立身份。</p>   <p>Some opinion polls have shown that if Hou and Ko teamed up, in whatever combination, they would beat Lai and his presumptive running mate, Hsiao Bi-khim, Taiwan's envoy to the United States. The DPP has not confirmed Hsiao will join the campaign.翻译:一些民意调查显示，如果侯和柯联手，无论以何种组合，他们都将击败黎智英和他的潜在竞选搭档、台湾驻美国特使萧美琴。民进党尚未确认萧是否会参加竞选。</p>   <p>The KMT has far larger representation than the TPP, controlling 38 of 113 seats in parliament to the TPP's five.翻译:国民党的代表权远大于 TPP，在议会 113 个席位中控制着 38 个席位，而 TPP 控制着 5 个席位。</p>   <p>A fourth candidate is also running for president - Terry Gou, the billionaire founder of major Apple supplier Foxconn <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2317.TW" target="_blank">(2317.TW)</a>.翻译:第四位候选人也在竞选总统，他是苹果主要供应商富士康<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2317.TW" target="_blank">（2317.TW）</a>的亿万富翁创始人郭台铭。</p>   <p>Gou, who has called for the opposition to unite to take on the DPP, has lagged in the polls and the KMT and TPP made no mention of him in announcing their decision to work together.翻译:呼吁反对派联合起来对抗民进党的郭台铭在民意调查中落后，国民党和跨太平洋党在宣布合作的决定时也没有提及他。</p>   <p>Candidates have until Friday of next week to register with the election commission.翻译:候选人必须在下周五之前向选举委员会登记。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ben Blanchard and Yimou Lee; Editing by Muralikumar Anantharaman, Robert Birsel翻译:Ben Blanchard 和 Yimou Lee 报道；编辑：Muralikumar Anantharaman、Robert Birsel</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 06:30:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CXWZYKCKUZLBRLWF6DEDKDR6GE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwans-opposition-parties-decide-joint-presidential-ticket-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ben Blanchard, Yimou Lee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>TAIWAN</category>
                
                <category>ELECTION/ (UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[俄罗斯资源部长在新型导弹研发期间访问朝鲜]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/nQsNJvem-xLt2m4ZdTp5tKvwq7A=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZFPG45UHFVPFNHLPZ7PYLWZDPQ.jpg" alt="A Russian delegation led by Alexander Kozlov, the minister of natural resources, arrives in Pyongyang翻译:自然资源部长亚历山大·科兹洛夫率领的俄罗斯代表团抵达平壤" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Russian delegation led by Alexander Kozlov, the minister of natural resources, presents flower baskets to the statues of North Korea's founder Kim Il Sung and late leader Kim Jong Il at Mansudae Hill, in Pyongyang, North Korea, November 14, 2023.   KCNA via REUTERS    翻译:2023 年 11 月 14 日，朝鲜平壤万寿台山，自然资源部长亚历山大·科兹洛夫率领的俄罗斯代表团向朝鲜创始人金日成和已故领导人金正日的雕像敬献花篮。朝中社路透社</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/KfAZ6Y3lnY0X5qUWFdlwwjX1fEU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SSM2ADTHDRP3HGPBB6FD6W66KQ.jpg" alt="North Korea tested new solid-fuel engine for intermediate ballistic missile翻译:朝鲜测试了用于中型弹道导弹的新型固体燃料发动机" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A test of North Korea's new solid-fuel engines for an intermediate ballistic missile is conducted in this picture released by the Korean Central News Agency on November 15, 2023. KCNA via REUTERS翻译:朝鲜中央通讯社于 2023 年 11 月 15 日发布的这张图片显示，朝鲜正在对用于中型弹道导弹的新型固体燃料发动机进行测试。 朝中社 (KCNA via REUTERS)</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/QvWC0-Ut0lBBRTF3glNxjR_a_ac=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FQFRROQFINIPRJPHY7S7MQETUM.jpg" alt="A Russian delegation led by Alexander Kozlov, the minister of natural resources, arrives in Pyongyang翻译:自然资源部长亚历山大·科兹洛夫率领的俄罗斯代表团抵达平壤" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A performance welcoming a Russian delegation led by Alexander Kozlov, the minister of natural resources is held at the Mansudae Arts Theater, in Pyongyang, North Korea, November 14, 2023.   KCNA via REUTERS 翻译:2023 年 11 月 14 日，朝鲜平壤万寿台艺术剧院举行欢迎自然资源部长亚历山大·科兹洛夫率领的俄罗斯代表团的演出。 朝中社（路透社）</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/iM4kre2eC6JlhDVUhL1VDFLQAAA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BLFZ67TEQJP35HIJSGUFMPTWKU.jpg" alt="A Russian delegation led by Alexander Kozlov, the minister of natural resources, arrives in Pyongyang翻译:自然资源部长亚历山大·科兹洛夫率领的俄罗斯代表团抵达平壤" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Russian delegation led by Alexander Kozlov, the minister of natural resources is welcomed at the Mansudae Arts Theater, in Pyongyang, North Korea, November 14, 2023.   KCNA via REUTERS    翻译:2023 年 11 月 14 日，由自然资源部部长亚历山大·科兹洛夫率领的俄罗斯代表团在朝鲜平壤万寿台艺术剧院受到欢迎。 朝中社（路透社）</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/U6snzGuUlLi9V8Wb5bqcHxVs1Wg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NMBQQ4MF7FMMBNGVWKH4H4CDC4.jpg" alt="A Russian delegation led by Alexander Kozlov, the minister of natural resources, arrives in Pyongyang翻译:自然资源部长亚历山大·科兹洛夫率领的俄罗斯代表团抵达平壤" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Russian delegation led by Alexander Kozlov, the minister of natural resources, arrives in Pyongyang翻译:自然资源部长亚历山大·科兹洛夫率领的俄罗斯代表团抵达平壤 to participate in the 10th meeting of the Trade, Economic and Scientific and Technological Cooperation Committee between the government of the Democratic People's Republic of Korea and the government of the Russia, in North Korea, November 14, 2023.   KCNA via REUTERS 翻译:自然资源部部长亚历山大·科兹洛夫率俄罗斯代表团抵达平壤参加朝俄政府贸易、经济和科技合作委员会第十次会议，2023 年 11 月 14 日，朝鲜。朝中社 (KCNA) 来源：路透社</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/N1gYevT6NnOHUJWh1nh8km5lbfQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/U27BQOQXM5LZPBBPZ3BCPSYOPM.jpg" alt="A Russian delegation led by Alexander Kozlov, the minister of natural resources, arrives in Pyongyang翻译:自然资源部长亚历山大·科兹洛夫率领的俄罗斯代表团抵达平壤" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Russian delegation led by Alexander Kozlov, the minister of natural resources, arrives in Pyongyang翻译:自然资源部长亚历山大·科兹洛夫率领的俄罗斯代表团抵达平壤 to participate in the 10th meeting of the Trade, Economic and Scientific and Technological Cooperation Committee between the government of the Democratic People's Republic of Korea and the government of the Russia, in North Korea, November 14, 2023.   KCNA via REUTERS 翻译:自然资源部部长亚历山大·科兹洛夫率俄罗斯代表团抵达平壤参加朝俄政府贸易、经济和科技合作委员会第十次会议，2023 年 11 月 14 日，朝鲜。朝中社 (KCNA) 来源：路透社 </figcaption></figure>                       <p>A Russian delegation led by natural resources minister Alexander Kozlov is visiting Pyongyang, North Korean state media said on Wednesday, as the politically isolated state announced new progress in its banned ballistic missile programme.翻译:朝鲜官方媒体周三称，由自然资源部长亚历山大·科兹洛夫率领的俄罗斯代表团正在访问平壤，这个政治上孤立的国家宣布其被禁止的弹道导弹计划取得了新进展。</p>   <p>Kozlov arrived on Tuesday, as U.S. Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin met with U.N. member states enforcing the Korean War armistice in Seoul and said they were concerned that China and Russia are helping North Korea expand its military capabilities by enabling Pyongyang to evade U.N. sanctions.翻译:科兹洛夫于周二抵达，当时美国国防部长劳埃德·奥斯汀在首尔会见了执行朝鲜战争停战协定的联合国成员国，并表示他们担心中国和俄罗斯通过让平壤逃避联合国制裁来帮助朝鲜扩大军事能力。</p>   <p>Russia and North Korea were conducting talks on the economy, science and technology, KCNA state media reported, without elaborating.翻译:据朝中社官方媒体报道，俄罗斯和朝鲜正在就经济、科技进行会谈，但没有详细说明。</p>   <p>Kozlov told a reception that Russia wants to develop "substantial cooperation" with North Korea based on the agreements made by Russian President Vladimir Putin and North Korean leader Kim Jong Un <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/nkoreas-kim-meets-putin-missiles-launched-pyongyang-2023-09-13/">when they met</a> in September in Russia's far east, KCNA reported.翻译:据朝中社报道，科兹洛夫在招待会上表示，俄罗斯希望根据俄罗斯总统普京和朝鲜领导人金正恩九月在俄罗斯远东地区<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/nkoreas-kim-meets-putin-missiles-launched-pyongyang-2023-09-13/">会晤时</a>达成的协议，与朝鲜发展“实质性合作”。</p>   <p>He also cited North Korea's "full support" for Russia over regional and international issues, the report said.翻译:报道称，他还提到朝鲜在地区和国际问题上“全力支持”俄罗斯。</p>   <p>A delegation led by the country's culture minister left for St. Petersburg on Tuesday to attend a cultural event, KCNA said in another article.翻译:朝中社在另一篇文章中称，由该国文化部长率领的代表团周二前往圣彼得堡参加文化活动。</p>   <p>North Korea is in its final stages of preparation for the launch of a spy satellite, and appears to have received technical assistance from Russia, South Korea's intelligence agency said this month.</p>    <h 1="">NEW MISSILE ENGINES</h>  <p>North Korean state media also reported on Wednesday that the country had successfully conducted static tests of "new-type high-thrust solid-fuel engines" for intermediate-range ballistic missiles (IRBMs).翻译:朝鲜官方媒体周三还报道称，该国已成功对中程弹道导弹（IRBM）的“新型高推力固体燃料发动机”进行了静态测试。</p>   <p>"The test provided a sure guarantee for reliably accelerating the development of the new-type IRBM system," KCNA said.翻译:朝中社称：“这次测试为可靠地加速新型中程弹道导弹系统的开发提供了可靠的保证。”</p>   <p>The announcement came on the same day South Korea and the U.S. held a joint aerial exercise involving a U.S. B-52 strategic bomber alongside fighter jets as a show of force aimed at Pyongyang, South Korea's defence ministry said.翻译:韩国国防部表示，就在这一消息发布的同一天，韩国和美国举行了联合空中演习，美国一架 B-52 战略轰炸机与战斗机一起，向平壤展示武力。</p>   <p>North Korea's General Missile Bureau attached great significance to the new IRBM, saying the recent tests are essential for enhancing the strategic offensive capabilities of the military in light of "the grave and unstable security environment facing the country" and the "vicious" collusion of its enemies, KCNA added.翻译:朝鲜导弹总局高度重视新型中程弹道导弹，称鉴于“国家面临的严峻且不稳定的安全环境”以及朝鲜半岛核力量的“恶性”勾结，最近的试验对于增强军队的战略进攻能力至关重要。朝中社补充道，“敌人”。</p>   <p>Military analysts say solid-fuel missiles are easier and safer to operate, and require less logistical support, making them harder to detect and more survivable than liquid-fuel weapons.翻译:军事分析人士表示，固体燃料导弹操作起来更容易、更安全，并且需要较少的后勤支持，这使得它们比液体燃料武器更难被发现，生存能力更强。</p>   <p>This year North Korea tested its first solid-fuel intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) - the largest category of ballistic missile - and also uses the technology in a range of smaller weapons.翻译:今年，朝鲜测试了其首枚固体燃料洲际弹道导弹（ICBM）——最大的弹道导弹类别——并且还在一系列小型武器中使用了该技术。</p>   <p>North Korea's missile programme, as well as its nuclear weapons, have been banned by U.N. Security Council resolutions, which imposed sanctions on the country.翻译:联合国安理会决议禁止朝鲜的导弹计划及其核武器，并对朝鲜实施制裁。</p>   <p>Washington has accused North Korea of supplying military equipment to Russia for use in its war with Ukraine, and Moscow of providing technical military support to help North Korea.翻译:华盛顿指责朝鲜向俄罗斯提供军事装备用于其与乌克兰的战争，并指责莫斯科提供技术军事支持来帮助朝鲜。</p>   <p>North Korea and Russia have denied any arms deals, though their leaders pledged closer military cooperation at their September summit.翻译:朝鲜和俄罗斯否认有任何武器交易，尽管两国领导人在九月峰会上承诺加强军事合作。</p>    <span>Reporting by Hyunsu Yim and Josh Smith; Editing by Grant McCool and Gerry Doyle翻译:Hyunsu Yim 和 Josh Smith 报道；格兰特·麦库尔和格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 06:29:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">VSOCHA7HUNMR3D4AWRXQ3ZILPE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/russian-delegation-led-by-natural-resources-minister-arrives-pyongyang-kcna-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Hyunsu Yim, Josh Smith]]></author>
            
                
                <category>NORTHKOREA</category>
                
                <category>RUSSIA/ (UPDATE 3)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[基金经理表示，德国经济和汽车行业面临来自中国的风险]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/DNnIDlUmyXA86759u3om5BfT7sE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WBZV3OSPLJKOZJPN5IS47STJFA.jpg" alt="Auto Shanghai show, in Shanghai翻译:上海车展，上海" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view shows the flags of China and Germany at a booth of a German automaker at the Auto Shanghai show, in Shanghai翻译:上海车展，上海, China, April 19, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/xE7_-K_Ps9aBdSzCaP2wwfO33Lw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6GMJPZHHGVOZ7L6GSNXJKHWUWE.jpg" alt="German Chancellor Scholz visits China翻译:德国总理肖尔茨访华" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>German Chancellor Olaf Scholz meets Chinese Premier Li Keqiang in Beijing, China November 4, 2022. Kay Nietfeld/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:德国总理奥拉夫·肖尔茨于 2022 年 11 月 4 日在中国北京会见中国总理李克强。Kay Nietfeld/Pool via REUTERS/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>Germany's heavy economic exposure to China carries significant risks for Europe's top economy, the country's second-largest fund manager said, singling out the market for electric vehicles as a specific example for how that is likely to pan out.翻译:德国第二大基金经理表示，德国对中国的巨大经济敞口给欧洲最大经济体带来了重大风险，并以电动汽车市场为例，说明了这一情况可能会如何发展。</p>   <p>Union Investment, which has 432 billion euros ($462 billion) in assets under management, looked at nearly 2,000 listed companies globally in a study seen by Reuters, concluding that German companies were particularly vulnerable.翻译:路透社看到，Union Investment管理着4,320亿欧元（合4,620亿美元）的资产，该公司对全球近2,000家上市公司进行了研究，得出的结论是，德国公司尤其容易受到影响。</p>   <p>"No other country, not even China's direct neighbours such as Japan and South Korea, has so many large companies with high exposure to China," the study said, adding this was true for nearly a quarter of all German companies in the focus group.翻译:研究称，“没有其他国家，甚至日本和韩国等中国的直接邻国，拥有如此多对中国有较高敞口的大公司”，并补充说，焦点小组中近四分之一的德国公司都是如此。</p>   <p>China has been Germany's single biggest trade partner since 2016, with bilateral trade of nearly 300 billion euros even surpassing that of the United States. That poses a dilemma for the German government, which is actively trying to get companies to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/derisking-dilemma-how-german-companies-are-tackling-china-risk-2023-10-19/">derisk</a> from China, the world's second-largest economy.翻译:自2016年以来，中国一直是德国最大的贸易伙伴，双边贸易额近3000亿欧元，甚至超过美国。这给德国政府带来了两难的境地，德国政府正在积极努力让企业<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/derisking-dilemma-how-german-companies-are-tackling-china-risk-2023-10-19/">规避</a>来自世界第二大经济体中国的风险。</p>   <p>The fund manager said it was striking that German companies are also increasingly relocating research and development activities to China, while others did the opposite for security reasons.翻译:该基金经理表示，令人惊讶的是，德国公司也越来越多地将研发活动转移到中国，而其他公司则出于安全原因而采取相反的做法。</p>   <p>"This strategy is risky on several levels: Germany suffers as a business location as areas with significant value creation are being moved abroad while the supplier industry is losing orders."翻译:“这一战略在几个层面上都存在风险：德国作为一个商业所在地受到了影响，因为具有重大价值创造的领域正在被转移到国外，而供应商行业正在失去订单。”</p>   <p>Union Investment holds stakes in virtually all German blue-chip companies, including German carmakers Volkswagen <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VOWG_p.DE" target="_blank">(VOWG_p.DE)</a>, BMW <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BMWG.DE" target="_blank">(BMWG.DE)</a> and Mercedes-Benz <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MBGn.DE" target="_blank">(MBGn.DE)</a> as well as BASF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BASFn.DE" target="_blank">(BASFn.DE)</a>, which all have major ties and exposure to the Chinese economy.翻译:Union Investment几乎持有所有德国蓝筹公司的股份，包括德国汽车制造商大众汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VOWG_p.DE" target="_blank">(VOWG_p.DE)</a> 、宝马<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BMWG.DE" target="_blank">(BMWG.DE)</a>和梅赛德斯-奔驰<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MBGn.DE" target="_blank">(MBGn.DE)</a>以及巴斯夫<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BASFn.DE" target="_blank">(BASFn.DE)</a> ，与中国经济有重大联系和接触。</p>   <p>The exposure means that German carmakers are facing risks such as being squeezed out of the Chinese market as well as seeing increased Asian competition in Europe, the fund manager said.翻译:该基金经理表示，这种风险意味着德国汽车制造商面临着被挤出中国市场以及亚洲在欧洲的竞争加剧等风险。</p>   <p>German carmakers could face retaliatory measures in China if Berlin were to protect them from Asian rivals at home, Union Investment said, adding that the technology offered by German car manufacturers can now be replaced, unlike 10 years ago.翻译:联合投资表示，如果柏林要保护德国汽车制造商免受国内亚洲竞争对手的侵害，德国汽车制造商可能会在中国面临报复措施，并补充说，与十年前不同，德国汽车制造商提供的技术现在可以被替换。</p>   <p>"This makes retaliation less painful for China - an important decision-making criterion for Beijing, as we all know."翻译:“这使得报复对中国来说不那么痛苦——众所周知，这是北京的一个重要决策标准。”</p>   <p>($1 = 0.9361 euros)翻译:（1 美元 = 0.9361 欧元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Christoph Steitz; Editing by Paul Simao翻译:克里斯托夫·施泰茨报道；保罗·西毛编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 06:13:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">R26242V4GVKSNBMWQ35AGAFS6M</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/german-economy-auto-sector-face-risks-exposure-china-fund-manager-says-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Christoph Steitz]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GERMANY</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/COMPANIES (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[一些基金经理认为中国大幅折扣股票的优点]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/bZJl2rmWIr6zcaiona84qsrZ0ZY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SZ7JFCQHV5MABK6O752AM24PSA.jpg" alt="Chinese Yuan banknotes are seen behind illuminated stock graph in this illustration翻译:在此插图中，可以在发光股票图后面看到人民币钞票" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Yuan banknotes are seen behind illuminated stock graph in this illustration翻译:在此插图中，可以在发光股票图后面看到人民币钞票 taken February 10, 2020. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张摄于 2020 年 2 月 10 日的插图中，可以在发光的库存图表后面看到人民币纸币。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>After months of steering clear of China, global asset managers and hedge funds say they are seeing tentative signs of a recovery on the mainland and value in the country's depressed stock markets.翻译:在避开中国几个月后，全球资产管理公司和对冲基金表示，他们看到了中国大陆复苏的初步迹象以及该国低迷股市的价值。</p>   <p>While foreign inflows only point to a tepid commitment from these funds so far, the rhetoric is changing as asset managers point to volatility in U.S. stocks and sudden policy impetus in China as reasons to return to the country.翻译:虽然到目前为止，外资流入仅表明这些基金的承诺不温不火，但随着资产管理公司将美国股市的波动和中国突然的政策推动作为重返中国的理由，这种说法正在发生变化。</p>   <p>Asset manager Fidelity International is highlighting China's looser monetary policy and the government's recent 1 trillion yuan ($137.10 billion) borrowing-and-spending sovereign bond plan as a tailwind for the country's stock markets.翻译:资产管理公司富达国际(Fidelity International)强调，中国宽松的货币政策和政府最近1万亿元人民币（合1,371亿美元）的借贷和支出主权债券计划是中国股市的推动力。</p>   <p>“There are mixed pictures if you look globally, depending on your own sort of risk tolerance. Now I think it might be a time to shift from the U.S. into China,” said Marty Dropkin, head of equities, Asia Pacific at Fidelity International.翻译:“如果你放眼全球，情况会是好坏参半，具体取决于你自己的风险承受能力。现在我认为可能是时候从美国转向中国了。”富达国际亚太区股票主管 Marty Dropkin 表示。</p>   <p>London-based £3 billion fund manager Somerset Capital Management likewise finds China exciting. Mark Williams, portfolio manager of its Asia Strategy, says easier monetary and fiscal policies have led to "attractive improvements in company earnings across our portfolio".翻译:总部位于伦敦、价值 30 亿英镑的基金管理公司萨默塞特资本管理公司同样对中国感到兴奋。其亚洲战略投资组合经理马克·威廉姆斯表示，宽松的货币和财政政策导致“我们投资组合中的公司盈利出现了引人注目的改善”。</p>   <p>The fund is increasing exposure to sportswear and electric vehicle companies that will benefit from growing consumer demand.翻译:该基金正在增加对运动服装和电动汽车公司的投资，这些公司将受益于不断增长的消费者需求。</p>   <p>Pessimism on China seems to have peaked this month as authorities in the world's second-largest economy announced bigger stimulus plans and state spending, and even measures to shore up the beleaguered <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-its-indebted-property-sector-2023-11-08/">property</a> sector, though the developers' debt crisis may take years to untangle.翻译:随着世界第二大经济体当局宣布更大规模的刺激计划和国家支出，甚至采取措施支撑陷入困境的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-its-indebted-property-sector-2023-11-08/">房地产</a>行业，对中国的悲观情绪似乎在本月达到顶峰，尽管开发商的债务危机可能需要数年时间才能解决。</p>   <p>The stock market has yet to recover, but has stabilised. The MSCI China index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.dMICN00000PUS" target="_blank">(.dMICN00000PUS)</a> is down 11% so far this year, while U.S. stock indexes S&amp;P 500 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a> and Nasdaq <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.IXIC" target="_blank">(.IXIC)</a> are up 15% and 32%, respectively. Japan’s Nikkei <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a> has gained 25%.翻译:股市尚未复苏，但已趋于稳定。 MSCI 中国指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.dMICN00000PUS" target="_blank">(.dMICN00000PUS)</a>今年迄今已下跌 11%，而美国股指标准普尔 500 指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a>和纳斯达克指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.IXIC" target="_blank">(.IXIC)</a>分别上涨 15% 和 32%。日本日经指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a>上涨 25%。</p>   <p>Morgan Stanley estimates long-only foreign investors now have their deepest underweight positions in China and Hong Kong equities in years. These funds have offloaded nearly $10 billion worth of Chinese equities in the past three months, the largest cumulative outflows since 2018, the bank said.翻译:摩根士丹利估计，只做多的外国投资者目前对中国和香港股市的减持程度是多年来最深的。该行表示，这些基金在过去三个月抛售了价值近100亿美元的中国股票，这是自2018年以来最大的累计流出量。</p>   <p>Chinese stocks have cheapened as a result, to a price-to-earnings ratio of 11%, the lowest among major Asian markets.翻译:中国股市的市盈率因此下跌至 11%，是亚洲主要市场中最低的。</p>   <p>Patrick Ghali, managing partner of Sussex Partners, a London-based hedge fund advisory, says clients who used to say "we don't want any allocation to China" are now thinking of contrarian entry points into the market and of re-engaging.</p>    <h 1="">TURNING POSITIVE</h>  <p>Morgan Stanley data also shows a light turnaround in flows. Foreign investors bought $924 million of China A-shares via the Hong Kong-China Stock Connect link from Nov. 2 to 8, the first week of net inflows since the beginning of August.翻译:摩根士丹利的数据也显示资金流出现轻微好转。 11月2日至8日，外国投资者通过中港通买入9.24亿美元的中国A股，这是自8月初以来的第一周净流入。</p>   <p>The benchmark Hong Kong stock index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a> has risen 1.7% this month after three consecutive months of losses, led by a surge in healthcare and tech shares. And, the Hang Seng Tech Index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSTECH" target="_blank">(.HSTECH)</a> is up 5.1% so far in November.翻译:在医疗保健和科技股飙升的带动下，香港基准股指<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a>在连续三个月下跌后，本月上涨 1.7%。而且，恒生科技指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSTECH" target="_blank">(.HSTECH)</a> 11 月份迄今已上涨 5.1%。</p>   <p>The International Monetary Fund also upgraded its 2023 China economy growth forecast to 5.4% last week.翻译:国际货币基金组织上周也将2023年中国经济增长预期上调至5.4%。</p>   <p>Boston-based investment firm Cambridge Associates says some Middle East investors find China's cheap valuations alluring and are allocating money there.翻译:总部位于波士顿的投资公司Cambridge Associates表示，一些中东投资者发现中国低廉的估值很有吸引力，并正在那里配置资金。</p>   <p>Hong Kong-based hedge fund Triata Capital expects attractive risk-reward in internet and e-commerce giants, saying excess investor pessimism had distorted valuations.翻译:总部位于香港的对冲基金 Triata Capital 预计互联网和电子商务巨头将获得有吸引力的风险回报，称投资者过度悲观情绪扭曲了估值。</p>   <p>“Investors are under-appreciating the substantial upside within (AI-related) software and internet over the long-term,” said Sean Ho, chief investment officer of Triata Capital.翻译:Triata Capital 首席投资官 Sean Ho 表示：“从长远来看，投资者低估了（人工智能相关）软件和互联网的巨大优势。”</p>   <p>Hedge funds typically do not publicly reveal their positions, but disclose them to investors and distributors, through investor letters.翻译:对冲基金通常不会公开披露其头寸，而是通过投资者信函向投资者和分销商披露。</p>   <p>Vivek Tanneeru, portfolio manager at Matthews Asia, a San Francisco-based asset manager, said he maintains an overweight position on China in anticipation of a sentiment boost from improved consumer confidence and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-chinas-xi-will-discuss-communication-competition-apec-summit-2023-11-13/">warmer U.S.-China relations</a>.翻译:总部位于旧金山的资产管理公司Matthews Asia的投资组合经理Vivek Tanneeru表示，他维持对中国的增持立场，因为预计消费者信心改善和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-chinas-xi-will-discuss-communication-competition-apec-summit-2023-11-13/">中美关系回暖将提振市场</a>情绪。</p>   <p>Tanneeru is adding select industrial, travel services, and medical services companies to his portfolio.翻译:Tanneeru 正在将精选的工业、旅游服务和医疗服务公司添加到他的投资组合中。</p>   <p>Some analysts, however, do not expect the feel-good factors will last.翻译:然而，一些分析师预计这种良好的感觉不会持续下去。</p>   <p>Chinese stocks could see a short-term sentiment pick-up given foreign funds have such light positions in the market, said Redmond Wong, Greater China market strategist at Saxo Markets.翻译:盛宝市场(Saxo Markets)大中华区市场策略师雷德蒙德·黄(Redmond Wong)表示，鉴于外国基金在市场上的仓位如此之少，中国股市短期情绪可能会回升。</p>   <p>"But there are rising concerns about China's long-term productivity and growth strategies", he said, referring to the government's often stated priorities around governance and anti-corruption efforts.翻译:“但人们对中国的长期生产力和增长战略的担忧日益增加”，他指的是政府经常提出的围绕治理和反腐败工作的优先事项。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2939 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2939 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Summer Zhen, additional reporting by Xie Yu
Editing by Vidya Ranganathan and Kim Coghill翻译:夏震报道，谢宇补充报道 Vidya Ranganathan 和 Kim Coghill 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 06:09:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">V7KCFZUFD5PZDHB2DDNYKRE5DM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/some-fund-managers-see-merit-chinas-deeply-discounted-stocks-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Summer Zhen]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>FUNDS/ (CORRECTED, ANALYSIS)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[拜登和习近平会面，美中军事和经济紧张局势加剧]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TG1TEqoix0BmSLzAs_2ZQkKdhx0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XVZII463FBIDNM7WDJMOYPZZ6Q.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden disembarks from Air Force One at San Francisco International Airport, as he arrives to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 14 日，美国总统乔·拜登在旧金山国际机场从空军一号下机，抵达美国加利福尼亚州旧金山参加亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会。 REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lTdjpZN9pb-WDBwFVbkn4Qq-Rig=/1878x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JFCDJ65EHNIW7MVYN3IPSOJ6AQ.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping waves as he arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的APEC（亚太经合组织）峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>U.S. President Joe Biden meets Chinese leader Xi Jinping for the first time in a year on Wednesday, for talks that may ease friction between the adversarial superpowers on military conflicts, drug-trafficking and artificial intelligence.翻译:美国总统乔·拜登周三与中国领导人习近平一年来首次会面，会谈可能会缓解敌对超级大国之间在军事冲突、贩毒和人工智能方面的摩擦。</p>   <p>However, deep progress on the vast differences separating the world's economic superpowers may have to wait for another day.翻译:然而，要在世界经济超级大国之间的巨大分歧上取得深入进展，可能还得等到另一天。</p>   <p>Officials on both sides of the Pacific have set expectations low as Biden and Xi are set to discuss Taiwan, the South China Sea, the Israel-Hamas war, Russia's invasion of Ukraine, North Korea, and human rights, each of them areas where the leaders have been unable to resolve long disagreements.翻译:由于拜登和习近平将讨论台湾、南中国海、以色列-哈马斯战争、俄罗斯入侵乌克兰、朝鲜和人权，太平洋两岸的官员都降低了期望，这些领域都涉及到美国的问题。领导人无法解决长期的分歧。</p>   <p>Biden and Xi <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/">arrived in San Francisco</a> on Tuesday, where they were set to hold their meeting on the sidelines the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit.翻译:拜登和习近平周二<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/">抵达旧金山</a>，原定在亚太经合组织（APEC）峰会期间举行会晤。</p>   <p>Leaders from the 21-member country group - and hundreds of CEOs in San Francisco to court them - meet amid <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">Chinese economic weakness</a>, Beijing's simmering territorial feuds with neighbors and a Middle East conflict that is dividing the United States from allies.翻译:这个由 21 个成员国组成的国家集团的领导人以及在旧金山向他们示好的数百名首席执行官在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">中国经济疲软</a>、北京与邻国的领土争端不断升温以及中东冲突导致美国与盟友分裂之际召开会议。</p>   <p>Efforts to carefully choreograph Xi's visit may be upended in the restive Northern California city, despite <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/san-francisco-patches-over-homelessness-drug-abuse-apec-2023-11-15/">efforts to drive homeless people</a> from the streets. The route from the airport to the conference site was lined with demonstrators for and against China's ruling Communist Party, an unusual sight for Xi who last visited the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/cnews-us-usa-china-idCAKBN1792KA-OCATP">United States in 2017</a>.翻译:尽管努力<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/san-francisco-patches-over-homelessness-drug-abuse-apec-2023-11-15/">将无家可归者赶出街头，但在这个动荡不安的北加州城市，精心策划习近平访问的努力</a>可能会被颠覆。从机场到会议地点的路上，挤满了支持和反对中国执政共产党的示威者，这对于<a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/cnews-us-usa-china-idCAKBN1792KA-OCATP">2017 年上次访问美国的</a>习近平来说是不寻常的景象。</p>   <p>Biden has sought direct diplomacy with Xi, betting that a personal relationship he has cultivated for a dozen years with the most powerful Chinese leader since Mao Zedong might salvage bilateral ties that are increasingly turning hostile.翻译:拜登寻求与习近平进行直接外交，押注他与自毛泽东以来最有权势的中国领导人十几年建立的个人关系可能会挽救日益变得敌对的双边关系。</p>   <p>Xi and Biden are expected to meet far from the conference location at a vast estate miles outside of San Francisco carefully chosen for its security, serenity and remoteness.翻译:习近平和拜登预计将在距离会议地点很远的旧金山郊外几英里外的一处巨大庄园会面，该庄园因其安全、宁静和偏远而经过精心挑选。</p>   <p>"The table has been set ... over the course of many weeks for what we hope will be a very productive, candid, constructive conversation," said John Kirby, a White House spokesperson, to reporters traveling aboard Air Force One.</p>    <h 1="">IRAN, ELECTION INTERFERENCE</h>  <p>During the meeting, which could last hours, Biden is expected to press Xi to use China's influence to urge Iran not to take provocative action or encourage its proxies to enter the fray, to avoid regional escalation of the Israel-Hamas conflict.翻译:在可能持续数小时的会议期间，拜登预计将敦促习近平利用中国的影响力敦促伊朗不要采取挑衅行动或鼓励其代理人卷入冲突，以避免以色列与哈马斯冲突的地区升级。</p>   <p>He is also expected to raise Chinese "influence operations" in foreign elections and the status of U.S. citizens that Washington believes are wrongly detained in China.翻译:预计他还将提出中国在外国选举中的“影响力行动”以及华盛顿认为在中国被错误拘留的美国公民的地位。</p>   <p>U.S. officials expected concrete steps to restore staff-level conversations between the two countries on a specific issues from military-to-military communications to reducing the flow of fentanyl, managing the growth of artificial intelligence technologies, managing trade and climate. Many of the chemicals used to make fentanyl come from China, U.S. officials say.翻译:美国官员预计将采取具体措施，恢复两国人员层面的对话，讨论从军事通讯到减少芬太尼流动、管理人工智能技术发展、管理贸易和气候等具体问题。美国官员表示，许多用于制造芬太尼的化学品来自中国。</p>   <p>Biden, 80, presides over an economy that has outperformed expectations and most rich nations after the COVID-19 pandemic. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/biden-approval-falls-lowest-level-since-april-reutersipsos-2023-11-07/">Unpopular with voters at home</a>, he is seeking a second term in office amid concerns about the stability of U.S. democracy.翻译:80 岁的拜登领导的经济在 COVID-19 大流行后的表现超出了预期，也超出了大多数富裕国家的表现。由于对美国民主稳定性的担忧，他<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/biden-approval-falls-lowest-level-since-april-reutersipsos-2023-11-07/">不受国内选民的欢迎</a>，正在寻求连任。</p>   <p>He has corralled the nation's traditional allies from Europe to Asia to confront Russia in Ukraine, although some have differences over the Israel-Hamas conflict.翻译:他召集了该国从欧洲到亚洲的传统盟友，在乌克兰对抗俄罗斯，尽管其中一些盟友在以色列与哈马斯冲突问题上存在分歧。</p>   <p>Xi, a decade Biden's junior, has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/ways-chinas-xi-jinping-amassed-power-over-decade-2022-10-10/">tightened control</a> over policy, state leaders, the media and military and changing the constitution. Recently, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">compounding economic challenges</a> have thrown the country off its three-decade, rocket-propelled growth trajectory.翻译:比拜登小十岁的习近平<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/ways-chinas-xi-jinping-amassed-power-over-decade-2022-10-10/">加强了对政策、国家领导人、媒体和军队的控制</a>，并修改了宪法。最近， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">复杂的经济挑战</a>使该国脱离了三年来高速增长的轨道。</p>   <p>Government officials across the region expect Beijing to test Washington in coming weeks, taking advantage of the United States' perceived shift in focus on Ukraine and Israel, as it pursues its own ambitions in the Indo-Pacific.翻译:该地区的政府官员预计，北京将在未来几周内利用美国在印度太平洋地区追求自己的野心而将重点转向乌克兰和以色列的机会来考验华盛顿。</p>   <p>Biden is expected to tell Xi that U.S. commitments in the Indo-Pacific are unchanged. China has worried its neighbors in recent years with steps in the Taiwan Strait, South China Sea and East China Sea, areas of international dispute. Biden will also express a specific commitment to the security of the Philippines, one of the U.S. officials said.翻译:预计拜登将告诉习近平，美国在印太地区的承诺没有改变。近年来，中国在台湾海峡、南海和东海等国际争议地区采取的行动令邻国感到担忧。一位美国官员表示，拜登还将表达对菲律宾安全的具体承诺。</p>    <span>Reporting by Trevor Hunnicutt; Additional reporting by Steve Holland, Michael Martina and Jeff Mason; Editing by Heather Timmons and Stephen Coates翻译:特雷弗·亨尼卡特报道； Steve Holland、Michael Martina 和 Jeff Mason 的补充报道；希瑟·蒂蒙斯和斯蒂芬·科茨编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 06:08:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZYRPUF6GFRLTHLGM6Y6UA65MXU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Trevor Hunnicutt]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA (PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国工厂产量和消费超出预期，但房地产仍拖累经济]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Industrial output, retail sales growth better than expected</li>  <li>Property sales extend declines, investment slumps</li>  <li>Oct indicators still show significant areas of economic weakness</li>  <li>Economists expect RRR, interest rate cuts</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>工业产出、零售额增速好于预期</li><li>房地产销售延续下滑，投资下滑</li><li>10 月指标仍显示经济显着疲软</li><li>经济学家预计存款准备金率、降息</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/LTq4T77li8f_4bULKrm5bT1ogEs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KIYGJWK6EFJNVKRZ5J5SSLFNOU.jpg" alt="FILE PHOTO: Leapmotor's EV production line in Jinhua翻译:资料图：零跑汽车位于金华的电动汽车生产线" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>FILE PHOTO: Robotic arms assemble cars in the production line for Leapmotor's electric vehicles at a factory in Jinhua, Zhejiang province, China, April 26, 2023. China Daily via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:资料照片：2023 年 4 月 26 日，中国浙江省金华市一家工厂，机械臂在零跑电动汽车生产线上组装汽车。《中国日报》来自路透社/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/L7KVqCa_-hprbq8GJSuMHMR2QR4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/77V6VO752FLN7CTZ4APEUIYDHU.jpg" alt="National Day holiday, in Shanghai翻译:国庆假期，上海" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk along Nanjing Pedestrian Road, a main shopping area, ahead of the National Day holiday, in Shanghai翻译:国庆假期，上海, China September 26, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>China's industrial output and retail sales growth beat expectations in October, but the underlying economic picture highlighted significant pockets of weakness with the crisis-hit property sector continuing to forestall a full-blown revival.翻译:中国10月份的工业产出和零售销售增长超出预期，但基本经济形势凸显了显着的疲软，受危机打击的房地产行业继续阻碍全面复苏。</p>   <p>The world's second-biggest economy has struggled to mount a strong post-COVID recovery as distress in the housing market, local government debt risks, slow global growth and geopolitical tensions have dented momentum. A flurry of policy support measures have proven only modestly beneficial, raising pressure on authorities to roll out more stimulus.翻译:由于房地产市场低迷、地方政府债务风险、全球经济增长缓慢和地缘政治紧张局势削弱了经济增长势头，全球第二大经济体在新冠疫情后一直难以实现强劲复苏。事实证明，一系列政策支持措施的效果有限，这加大了当局推出更多刺激措施的压力。</p>   <p>China's industrial output grew 4.6% in October year-on-year, accelerating from the 4.5% pace seen in September, data from the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) showed on Wednesday, beating expectations for a 4.4% increase in a Reuters poll. It also marked the strongest growth since April.翻译:中国国家统计局(NBS)周三公布的数据显示，中国10月份工业产出同比增长4.6%，较9月份的4.5%有所加快，超过路透调查中4.4%的增长预期。这也标志着自四月份以来最强劲的增长。</p>   <p>Retail sales rose 7.6% in October with improvement in both auto and restaurant sales growth, quickening from a 5.5% gain in September and hitting the fastest pace since May. Analysts had expected retail sales to grow 7.0% due to the low base effect in 2022 when COVID curbs disrupted consumers and businesses.翻译:10 月份零售额增长 7.6%，汽车和餐饮销售增长均有所改善，增速较 9 月份 5.5% 有所加快，达到 5 月份以来的最快增速。分析师此前预计，由于 2022 年新冠疫情遏制扰乱了消费者和企业，基数较低，零售额将增长 7.0%。</p>      <p>Analysts struck a cautious note on the upside data surprise, noting that the property sector remains a weak link for the economy and pointed to the lack of major <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-choose-fiscal-muscle-over-big-reforms-revive-economy-2023-10-24/">reforms</a> as another impediment to sustainable longer term revival in growth.翻译:分析师对意外的上行数据持谨慎态度，指出房地产行业仍然是经济的薄弱环节，并指出缺乏重大<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-choose-fiscal-muscle-over-big-reforms-revive-economy-2023-10-24/">改革</a>是可持续长期增长复苏的另一个障碍。</p>   <p>"Due to the impact of holidays and low base effect in 2022, year-on-year figures cannot reflect the actual momentum of the economy," said Xing Zhaopeng, senior China strategist at ANZ.翻译:澳新银行高级中国策略师邢兆鹏表示，“由于2022年假期影响和低基数效应，同比数据无法反映经济的实际动力。”</p>   <p>He said month-on-month figures suggest economic momentum has further weakened with "increasing deflationary risks".翻译:他表示，环比数据表明，随着“通缩风险增加”，经济势头进一步减弱。</p>   <p>Louise Loo, China economist at Oxford Economics, said prolonged weakness in external demand could hamper industrial production despite strengthening last month as destocking pressures eased further.翻译:牛津经济研究院(Oxford Economics)中国经济学家Louise Loo表示，尽管上个月随着去库存压力进一步缓解，外部需求有所增强，但长期疲软可能会阻碍工业生产。</p>   <p>Consumption didn't make much headway either during the eight-day Golden Week holiday earlier in October. Trips made in that period missed government estimate as economists say consumers are concerned about their jobs and income growth in an uncertain employment market.翻译:十月初的八天黄金周假期期间，消费也没有取得太大进展。经济学家表示，这一时期的旅行人数未达到政府的预期，因为消费者担心就业市场不确定性下的工作和收入增长。</p>   <p>The nationwide survey-based jobless rate stayed at 5.0% in October, unchanged from September, the NBS data showed. Youth unemployment, which hit a record high 21.3% in June, wasn't available after the statistics bureau stopped publishing it since July.翻译:国家统计局数据显示，10月份全国调查失业率保持在5.0%，与9月份持平。统计局自7月起停止发布青年失业率后，6月份青年失业率创下历史新高21.3%。</p>   <p>China has been ramping up efforts to revive its post-COVID economy with a slew of policy support measures in recent months, although the positive effects have been marginal so far.翻译:近几个月来，中国一直在加大力度通过一系列政策支持措施重振后疫情时代的经济，但迄今为止积极效果甚微。</p>   <p>Wednesday's upbeat data comes as a raft of other indicators for October released over recent weeks pointed to muted growth momentum. Imports grew unexpectedly, but exports shrank at a quicker pace, household borrowing remained weak, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">consumer prices</a> swung lower while factory deflation persisted.翻译:周三公布乐观数据之际，近几周发布的 10 月份其他一系列指标均显示增长势头疲弱。进口意外增长，但出口萎缩加快，家庭借贷依然疲软， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">消费者价格</a>下跌，而工厂通货紧缩持续存在。</p>   <p>Authorities are faced with a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/part-chinas-economic-miracle-was-mirage-reality-check-is-next-2023-09-03/">challenging task</a> as any aggressive monetary support would further widen interest rate differentials between China and the West, especially the United States, and dent an already weakened yuan. That could intensify capital outflows, while Beijing is wary of a return to the big-bang fiscal stimulus of the past which created massive debt and hamstrung the economy.翻译:当局面临着一项<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/part-chinas-economic-miracle-was-mirage-reality-check-is-next-2023-09-03/">艰巨的任务</a>，因为任何激进的货币支持都将进一步扩大中国与西方（尤其是美国）之间的利差，并削弱本已疲软的人民币。这可能会加剧资本外流，而北京方面则对回到过去的大规模财政刺激措施持谨慎态度，这种财政刺激措施造成了巨额债务并阻碍了经济。</p>   <p>The economy grew faster-than-expected in the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">third quarter</a>, with analysts generally expecting it to reach the government's full-year growth target of around 5%, though a full-blown recovery is still some time away.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">第三季度</a>经济增长快于预期，分析师普遍预计将达到政府5%左右的全年增长目标，但全面复苏尚需时日。</p>   <p>The yuan held near a more than two-month high after surprisingly softer U.S. inflation reading overnight boosted bets that the Federal Reserve had reached the end of its tightening cycle.</p>    <h 1="">PROPERTY, INVESTMENT DISAPPOINT</h>  <p>The country's central bank, People's Bank of China (PBOC), <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cbank-boosts-liquidity-injection-through-policy-loan-rate-unchanged-2023-11-15/">boosted liquidity injections</a> but kept the interest rate unchanged when rolling over maturing medium-term policy loans on Wednesday.翻译:周三，中国央行中国人民银行在展期到期中期政策贷款时<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cbank-boosts-liquidity-injection-through-policy-loan-rate-unchanged-2023-11-15/">加大了流动性注入力度</a>，但维持利率不变。</p>   <p>In a rare revision last month, the government also lifted its 2023 budget deficit to around 3.8% of gross domestic product from 3% to account for the planned issuance of 1 trillion yuan ($137.10 billion) in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/chinas-new-bonds-help-economic-recovery-official-says-budget-deficit-rises-2023-10-25/">sovereign bonds</a>.翻译:上个月，政府罕见地进行了修订，将2023年预算赤字占国内生产总值的比例从3%提高到3.8%左右，以占计划发行1万亿元人民币（1,371亿美元） <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/chinas-new-bonds-help-economic-recovery-official-says-budget-deficit-rises-2023-10-25/">主权债券</a>的比例。</p>   <p>The PBOC has cut banks' reserve requirement ratio (RRR) twice this year to free up liquidity to aid the economic recovery. Analysts widely expect another RRR cut and an interest rate cut in the final months of this year.翻译:中国人民银行今年已两次下调银行存款准备金率（RRR），以释放流动性以帮助经济复苏。分析师普遍预计今年最后几个月将再次下调存款准备金率和利率。</p>   <p>China's crisis-hit <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/">property sector</a> has yet to see a meaningful rebound despite strengthened <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-its-indebted-property-sector-2023-11-08/">support</a> measures for homebuyers, including relaxing of home purchase restrictions, lowering in borrowing costs and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-is-eyeing-137-bln-new-funding-boost-housing-market-bloomberg-news-2023-11-14/">other programmes.</a>翻译:尽管中国加强了对购房者<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-its-indebted-property-sector-2023-11-08/">的支持</a>措施，包括放宽购房限制、降低借贷成本等，但受危机打击的中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/">房地产行业</a>尚未出现有意义的反弹<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-is-eyeing-137-bln-new-funding-boost-housing-market-bloomberg-news-2023-11-14/">。</a></p>   <p>Property investment fell 9.3% in January-October year-on-year, after a similarly sharp 9.1% drop in January-September.翻译:继1-9月大幅下降9.1%之后，1-10月房地产投资同比下降9.3%。</p>   <p>Fixed asset investment disappointed with a 2.9% expansion year-on-year in the first 10 months, missing expectations for a 3.1% rise. It grew 3.1% in the January-September period.翻译:前10个月固定资产投资同比增长2.9%，低于预期的3.1%。 1-9月增长3.1%。</p>   <p>Confidence among private businesses also remained depressed, with investment in the sector shrinking 0.5% during January-October, narrowing slightly from the 0.6% decline in the first nine months.翻译:私营企业信心依然低迷，1-10月该行业投资下降0.5%，较前9个月0.6%的降幅略有收窄。</p>   <p>"Overall, the data published today suggest that the recovery was struggling to gain a strong footing at the start of Q4, but it was not nearly as weak as some had feared," said Sheana Yue, China economist at Capital Economics.翻译:凯投宏观(Capital Economics)中国经济学家谢娜·岳(Sheana Yue)表示：“总体而言，今天公布的数据表明，第四季度初经济复苏正在努力站稳脚跟，但并不像一些人担心的那么疲弱。”</p>   <p>"Policy looks set to remain supportive, and possibly even stepped up to prevent the economy from backsliding."翻译:“政策看起来将继续保持支持性，甚至可能加强以防止经济倒退。”</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2939 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2939 人民币）</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Albee Zhang and Liangping Gao;
Editing by Shri Navaratnam翻译:Albee 张和亮平高的补充报道；编辑：Shri Navaratnam</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:38:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TPUCTHUAIJI75IGHIQFYSOENNM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ellen Zhang, Kevin Yao]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/ACTIVITY (WRAPUP 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[加州会谈后中美承诺气候合作]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UXrIOsXLuqEBGqgp6K0eh3Y4cXw=/1832x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SSSVDHPBXFOYVATNIL6GPT7QVY.jpg" alt="U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry meets with his Chinese counterpart Xie Zhenhua in Beijing翻译:美国总统气候特使约翰·克里在北京会见中国气候变化特使解振华" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry shakes hands with his Chinese counterpart Xie Zhenhua before a meeting in Beijing, China July 17, 2023. REUTERS/Valerie Volcovici/ File Photo翻译:2023 年 7 月 17 日，美国总统气候特使约翰·克里 (John Kerry) 在中国北京举行会议前与中国气候特使解振华握手。 REUTERS/Valerie Volcovici/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The United States and China will back a new global renewables target and work together on methane and plastic pollution, they said in a joint statement on Wednesday after a meeting to find common ground ahead of COP28 talks in Dubai later this month.翻译:本月晚些时候在迪拜举行的第 28 次缔约方会议 (COP28) 之前，美国和中国举行会议寻找共同点，周三在一份联合声明中表示，美国和中国将支持新的全球可再生能源目标，并在甲烷和塑料污染问题上开展合作。</p>   <p>Climate envoys John Kerry and Xie Zhenhua, meeting in Sunnylands, California on Nov. 4-7, agreed to revive a bilateral climate working group that will discuss areas of cooperation between the two countries, the joint statement said, though differences remain on issues like phasing out fossil fuels.翻译:联合声明称，气候特使约翰·克里和解振华于 11 月 4 日至 7 日在加利福尼亚州桑尼兰兹会面，同意恢复双边气候工作组，该工作组将讨论两国之间的合作领域，尽管在诸如此类的问题上仍然存在分歧。逐步淘汰化石燃料。</p>   <p>"The Sunnylands statement is a timely effort of aligning the United States and China ahead of COP28," said Li Shuo, incoming director of the China Climate Hub at the Asia Society.翻译:即将上任的亚洲协会中国气候中心主任李硕表示：“《阳光之乡》的声明是在 COP28 之前协调美国和中国的及时努力。”</p>   <p>Li described the relationship between the world's two biggest greenhouse gas emitters as "a precondition for meaningful global progress" and said the Sunnylands agreement will help "stabilise the politics" ahead of Dubai talks.翻译:李将世界上两个最大的温室气体排放国之间的关系描述为“有意义的全球进展的先决条件”，并表示《阳光之乡》协议将有助于在迪拜谈判之前“稳定政治”。</p>   <p>The re-launch of the working group marks the normalisation of the climate relationship between the two countries following a hiatus triggered in 2022 by the visit of former House of Representatives speaker Nancy Pelosi to Taiwan, a self-governing island that China claims.翻译:该工作组的重新启动标志着两国气候关系的正常化，此前该关系因前众议院议长南希·佩洛西 (Nancy Pelosi) 访问台湾（中国声称拥有主权）而于 2022 年中断。</p>   <p>It will focus on key areas of cooperation, including abating methane and boosting efficiency and the "circular economy", and exchange information on policies and technologies to reduce emissions. The two sides also promised to work together to curb forest loss and plastic pollution.</p>    <h 1="">"WORK CUT OUT"</h>  <p>China's efforts to cut its own carbon emissions will be in sharp focus at the COP28 talks, with the country still approving new coal-fired power plants in a bid to ensure energy security.翻译:中国削减自身碳排放的努力将成为COP28会议的焦点，中国仍在批准新建燃煤电厂以确保能源安全。</p>   <p>The United States and China said they support a declaration by G20 leaders to triple global renewable energy capacity by 2030, and also agreed to "accelerate the substitution for coal, oil and gas generation".翻译:美国和中国表示，支持二十国集团领导人提出的到2030年将全球可再生能源发电能力增加两倍的宣言，并同意“加速替代煤炭、石油和天然气发电”。</p>   <p>The joint statement said they anticipate "meaningful" reductions in emissions from the power sector this decade, but it fell short of calling for the phasing out of fossil fuels, a goal that China has described as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-climate-envoy-says-phasing-out-fossil-fuels-unrealistic-2023-09-22/">"unrealistic"</a>.翻译:联合声明称，他们预计本十年电力行业的排放量将“有意义”减少，但并未呼吁逐步淘汰化石燃料，中国称这一目标<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-climate-envoy-says-phasing-out-fossil-fuels-unrealistic-2023-09-22/">“不切实际”</a> 。</p>   <p>Both sides also agreed to include methane in their 2035 climate goals - the first time China has made such a pledge - and committed to advancing "at least five" large-scale cooperation projects in carbon capture, utilisation and storage by the end of the decade.翻译:双方还同意将甲烷纳入2035年气候目标，这是中国首次做出此类承诺，并承诺到本十年末推进“至少5个”碳捕集、利用和封存大型合作项目。</p>   <p>Li said COP28 still "has its work cut out", particularly on fossil fuels.翻译:李说，COP28 仍然“有许多工作要做”，特别是在化石燃料方面。</p>   <p>"China also needs to consider what further ambition can be brought to COP," he added. "Stopping the approval of new coal power projects is a good next step."翻译:“中国还需要考虑可以为缔约方大会带来哪些进一步的雄心，”他补充道。 “停止批准新的煤电项目是下一步的好举措。”</p>    <span>Reporting by David Stanway; Editing by Muralikumar Anantharaman and Raju Gopalakrishnan翻译:大卫·斯坦威报道； Muralikumar Anantharaman 和 Raju Gopalakrishnan 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:36:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MMEHXKCLHBMKREBS5CHXKMMOXI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/us-china-pledge-cooperation-climate-following-california-talks-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Stanway, Valerie Volcovici]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CLIMATE CHANGE/USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[欧洲公司敦促中国进一步明确数据传输法]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UH9rid9jkLEt5JsGOJYMoQt30ok=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OOV6PN5M3NOQ3ACUIZ6AADBDYY.jpg" alt="An attendant walks past EU and China flags ahead of the EU-China High-level Economic Dialogue in Beijing翻译:在北京举行的中欧高层经济对话之前，一名与会者走过欧盟和中国国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An attendant walks past EU and China flags ahead of the EU-China High-level Economic Dialogue at Diaoyutai State Guesthouse in Beijing, China June 25, 2018. REUTERS/Jason Lee/File Photo翻译:2018 年 6 月 25 日，在中国北京钓鱼台国宾馆举行的中欧高层经济对话之前，一名与会者走过欧盟和中国国旗。 REUTERS/Jason Lee/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>European firms "urgently" need China to give clearer definitions of key terms in its cross-border data transfer rules, a European business lobby group said on Wednesday, warning firms also stood to waste millions of euros storing non-sensitive data in China.翻译:欧洲商业游说团体周三表示，欧洲企业“迫切”需要中国对其跨境数据传输规则中的关键术语给出更清晰的定义，并警告企业还将浪费数百万欧元在中国存储非敏感数据。</p>   <p>The European Chamber of Commerce in China called on authorities to "provide precise definitions for both 'important data' and 'personal information,'" as outlined in their rules, and also urged that a proposed relaxation of certain aspects of regulations announced in September be finalised as soon as possible.翻译:中国欧盟商会呼吁当局按照其规则中的规定，“为‘重要数据’和‘个人信息’提供准确的定义”，并敦促放宽 9 月份宣布的监管某些方面的提议。尽快敲定。</p>   <p>The world's second-largest economy has in recent years tightened its data laws amid President Xi Jinping's increased focus on national security, and foreign firms fear their lack of clarity could trip them up.翻译:近年来，在习近平主席日益关注国家安全的背景下，全球第二大经济体收紧了数据法，外国公司担心数据法的不明确可能会给他们带来麻烦。</p>   <p>"Ever since the Cybersecurity Law was introduced in 2017, we have gone without a clear definition of 'Important Data.' That's six years," Stefan Bernhart, a chamber vice president, said at the launch of a report based on a member survey on the impact of China's data regulations.翻译:“自2017年《网络安全法》出台以来，我们对‘重要数据’一直没有明确的定义。那是六年，”商会副会长斯特凡·伯恩哈特(Stefan Bernhart)在一份基于对中国数据法规影响的会员调查的报告发布时表示。</p>   <p>BASF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BASFn.DE" target="_blank">(BASFn.DE)</a>, Maersk <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MAERSKb.CO" target="_blank">(MAERSKb.CO)</a>, Siemens <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SIEGn.DE" target="_blank">(SIEGn.DE)</a>, and Volkswagen <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VOWG_p.DE" target="_blank">(VOWG_p.DE)</a> are among the members of the chamber.翻译:巴斯夫<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BASFn.DE" target="_blank">(BASFn.DE)</a> 、马士基<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MAERSKb.CO" target="_blank">(MAERSKb.CO)</a> 、西门子<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SIEGn.DE" target="_blank">(SIEGn.DE)</a>和大众汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VOWG_p.DE" target="_blank">(VOWG_p.DE)</a>都是该商会的成员。</p>   <p>"Many of the laws, guidelines and measures lack specificity, which poses serious operational and compliance challenges to European companies operating in China," the report read, adding requirements like "regulatory security assessment thresholds" were too low, "especially for larger multinational companies."翻译:报告称，“许多法律、指导方针和措施缺乏针对性，这给在华经营的欧洲公司带来了严重的运营和合规挑战”，并补充说，“监管安全评估门槛”等要求太低，“特别是对于大型跨国公司” ”。</p>   <p>Jitters among foreign investors in China have risen over the past year due to a series of corporate raids, predominantly on consultancies and due diligence firms.翻译:过去一年，由于一系列企业搜查行动（主要针对咨询公司和尽职调查公司），中国外国投资者的不安情绪有所加剧。</p>   <p>"Questions about whether or not I am on the right side of the law can be a huge, huge challenge," Bernhart said, adding that it could make smaller firms in particular reconsider investing in China.翻译:伯恩哈特表示：“关于我是否站在法律正确一边的问题可能是一个巨大的挑战。”他补充说，这可能会让规模较小的公司重新考虑在中国的投资。</p>   <p>The chamber's report echoes recent comments from a European Commission official, who said in September that European businesses were <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/eu-says-lack-clarity-chinas-data-laws-is-concerning-2023-09-19/">especially concerned</a> about a lack of clarity in China's data laws.翻译:该商会的报告呼应了欧盟委员会一位官员最近的评论，该官员在 9 月份表示，欧洲企业<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/eu-says-lack-clarity-chinas-data-laws-is-concerning-2023-09-19/">尤其担心</a>中国数据法的不明确性。</p>   <p>China in the same month also said it was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-waive-security-checks-some-data-exports-2023-09-28/">considering waiving</a> data export security assessments for activities such as international trade, academic cooperation, cross-border manufacturing and marketing that do not contain personal information or important data, a move that was welcomed by foreign business chambers and lawyers.翻译:同月，中国还表示<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-waive-security-checks-some-data-exports-2023-09-28/">考虑对国际贸易、学术合作、跨境制造和营销等不包含个人信息或重要数据的活动免除</a>数据出境安全评估，此举受到外国商会的欢迎和律师。</p>   <p>"The release of the draft ... was seen as a signal from the Chinese Government that it is listening to businesses' concerns and is ready to take steps to address them. Companies are waiting eagerly for these positive signals to be translated into action," the chamber said, adding that its members anticipated the draft revisions would be finalised by the end of November.翻译:“草案的发布……被视为中国政府发出的信号，表明它正在倾听企业的担忧，并准备采取措施解决这些问题。企业正在热切地等待这些积极信号转化为行动， ”该商会表示，并补充说，其成员预计修订草案将在 11 月底完成。</p>   <p>The most common type of data European firms transfer abroad is employee's personal information followed by suppliers' and customers' personal information, the survey showed, 96% of which is sent to companies' headquarters and other regional offices.翻译:调查显示，欧洲公司向国外传输的最常见数据类型是员工的个人信息，其次是供应商和客户的个人信息，其中 96% 被发送到公司总部和其他地区办事处。</p>   <p>A third of companies indicated it would cost them "several million euros" to store their data in China if they failed the cross-border transfer security assessment now required by CAC. More than 10 percent of firms said it would cost them "hundreds of millions of euros."翻译:三分之一的公司表示，如果未能通过 CAC 目前要求的跨境传输安全评估，他们将花费“数百万欧元”将数据存储在中国。超过 10% 的公司表示，这将花费他们“数亿欧元”。</p>   <p>Only 6% of respondents indicated that they transferred 'important data' overseas, the chamber said.翻译:该商会表示，只有 6% 的受访者表示他们将“重要数据”转移到海外。</p>   <p>($1 = 0.9322 euros)翻译:（1 美元 = 0.9322 欧元）</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Brenda Goh; Editing by Kim Coghill翻译:Brenda Goh 的补充报道；编辑：金·科吉尔</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:31:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RUZWXP2WQVIZVPMCOEHUIXW4LY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/european-firms-urge-china-give-more-clarity-data-transfer-laws-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Joe Cash]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/DATA</category>
                
                <category>SECURITY</category>
                
                <category>EUROPE (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国经济数据和强劲需求预测推动油价上涨]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/E-8nOFzH4LC_T8_w0JCVItxfEMc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5L7A5E5CCBIGJBV4BXGODRBF3Q.jpg" alt="Oil pump jacks at Vaca Muerta in Argentina翻译:阿根廷 Vaca Muerta 的油泵千斤顶" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Oil pump jacks are seen at the Vaca Muerta shale oil and gas deposit in the Patagonian province of Neuquen, Argentina, January 21, 2019.  REUTERS/Agustin Marcarian/File Photo翻译:2019 年 1 月 21 日，阿根廷内乌肯巴塔哥尼亚省瓦卡穆尔塔页岩油气矿床中的油泵千斤顶。路透社/Agustin Marcarian/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Oil prices rose on Wednesday as China's factory output and retail sales beat expectations, a day after the International Energy Agency (IEA) raised its oil demand growth forecast for this year.翻译:在国际能源署（IEA）上调今年石油需求增长预测的第二天，中国工厂产出和零售额超出预期，油价周三上涨。</p>   <p>Brent futures rose 20 cents, or 0.2%, to $82.67 a barrel by 0427 GMT, while U.S. West Texas Intermediate (WTI) crude rose 15 cents, also 0.2%, to $78.28.翻译:截至 GMT 0427，布伦特原油期货上涨 20 美分，涨幅为 0.2%，至每桶 82.67 美元，而美国西德克萨斯中质原油 (WTI) 则上涨 15 美分，涨幅为 0.2%，至每桶 78.28 美元。</p>   <p>China's October <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/">economic activity perked up</a> as industrial output grew at a faster pace and retail sales growth beat expectations, an encouraging sign for the world's second-largest economy.翻译:中国10月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/">经济活动回暖</a>，工业产出增长加快，零售额增长超出预期，这对世界第二大经济体来说是一个令人鼓舞的迹象。</p>   <p>The IEA joined the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries and its allies (OPEC+) in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/iea-raises-oil-demand-growth-forecasts-despite-economic-gloom-ahead-2023-11-14/">raising oil demand growth forecast</a> for this year, despite projections of slower economic growth in many major countries.翻译:尽管许多主要国家的经济增长放缓，但国际能源署与石油输出国组织及其盟国（OPEC+）一起<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/iea-raises-oil-demand-growth-forecasts-despite-economic-gloom-ahead-2023-11-14/">上调了今年的石油需求增长预测</a>。</p>   <p>"It (IEA) sees oil demand remaining healthy. It raised its forecast due to better-than-expected consumption in China," ANZ Research said in a note on Wednesday.翻译:澳新银行研究部周三在一份报告中表示：“国际能源署认为石油需求依然健康。由于中国的消费好于预期，国际能源署上调了预测。”</p>   <p>Expectations that the U.S. Federal Reserve could cut interest rates next spring sent the U.S. dollar <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DXY" target="_blank">(.DXY)</a> down to a two-and-a-half-month low against a basket of other currencies. A weaker dollar can boost oil demand by making crude cheaper for buyers using other currencies.翻译:对美联储可能在明年春季降息的预期导致美元<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DXY" target="_blank">（.DXY）</a>兑一篮子其他货币跌至两个半月低点。美元疲软可以通过使使用其他货币的买家更便宜的原油价格来提振石油需求。</p>   <p>The U.S. Energy Information Administration (EIA) will release its first oil inventory report in two weeks on Wednesday. EIA did not release a storage report last week due to a systems upgrade.翻译:美国能源信息署（EIA）将于周三发布两周内的首份石油库存报告。由于系统升级，EIA 上周没有发布存储报告。</p>   <p>For the week ended Nov. 10, analysts forecast energy firms added about 1.8 million barrels of crude into U.S. stockpiles, according to a Reuters poll, in line with from the American Petroleum Institute out Tuesday.翻译:路透调查显示，截至 11 月 10 日当周，分析师预测能源公司将向美国库存增加约 180 万桶原油，与美国石油学会周二公布的数据一致。</p>    <span>Reporting by Sudarshan Varadhan and Laura Sanicola; Editing by Miral Fahmy and Raju Gopalakrishnan翻译:Sudarshan Varadhan 和 Laura Sanicola 报道；编辑：Miral Fahmy 和 Raju Gopalakrishnan</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 04:38:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">N3OYCOWULJK5XLQNNUSBJ7FQIQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/oil-gains-middle-east-tensions-stock-data-focus-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Sudarshan Varadhan]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>OIL/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[日本直升机在全国军事演习中训练击退入侵者]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/CDXnCmPW89J210pAIh4yD-d9w8g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/EWM67OJ6I5JD3MJZ5J64PPQ4NQ.jpg" alt="Japanese Ground Self-Defense Force's Amphibious Rapid Deployment Brigade soldiers take part in a military drill at Irisuna island翻译:日本陆上自卫队两栖快速部署旅士兵在入岛岛参加军事演习" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Japanese Ground Self-Defense Force's (JGSDF) AH-64 Apache helicopter flies over JGSDF's Amphibious Rapid Deployment Brigade (ARDB) soldiers and the U.S. Marines during ARDB's military drill at an uninhabited Irisuna island close to Okinawa,  Japan, November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Issei Kato翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，日本陆上自卫队 (JGSDF) 的 AH-64 阿帕奇直升机飞越日本陆上自卫队两栖快速部署旅 (ARDB) 士兵和美国海军陆战队士兵，期间 ARDB 在日本冲绳附近无人居住的 Irisuna 岛上进行军事演习。 路透社/加藤一诚</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/c9Cc1aC0RHP3eGYZk8xt6uLr9sk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WKHJ5XCN25IHLKJS2YBMWEBTMM.jpg" alt="Japanese Ground Self-Defense Force's Amphibious Rapid Deployment Brigade soldiers take part in a military drill at Irisuna island翻译:日本陆上自卫队两栖快速部署旅士兵在入岛岛参加军事演习" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Commander Shingo Nashinoki and soldiers of Japanese Ground Self-Defense Force's (JGSDF) Amphibious Rapid Deployment Brigade (ARDB), Japan's first marine unit since World War Two, take part in a military drill as the U.S. Marines observe, at an uninhabited Irisuna island closed to Okinawa, Japan, November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Issei Kato翻译:日本陆上自卫队 (JGSDF) 两栖快速部署旅 (ARDB) 司令员梨木真吾 (Shingo Nashinoki) 和士兵们在无人居住的入里苏纳岛 (Irisuna) 参加美国海军陆战队观察的军事演习，这是日本自第二次世界大战以来的第一支海军陆战队2023 年 11 月 15 日飞往日本冲绳。REUTERS/Issei Kato</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/3zaeNgZ7CK0dwu7b1Aw8WxGSFTs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/QBC2U3ELBNPONKJ6U762NR3AXU.jpg" alt="Japanese Ground Self-Defense Force's Amphibious Rapid Deployment Brigade soldiers take part in a military drill at Irisuna island翻译:日本陆上自卫队两栖快速部署旅士兵在入岛岛参加军事演习" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An aerial view taken from Japanese Ground Self-Defense Force's (JGSDF) CH-47 Chinook helicopter shows uninhabited Irisuna island close to Okinawa before a military drill by JGSDF's Amphibious Rapid Deployment Brigade (ARDB), Japan's first marine unit since World War Two, Japan, November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Issei Kato翻译:日本陆上自卫队 (JGSDF) CH-47 支努干直升机拍摄的鸟瞰图显示，在日本陆上自卫队两栖快速部署旅 (ARDB) 进行军事演习之前，冲绳附近无人居住的 Irisuna 岛，这是日本自第二次世界大战以来的第一支海军陆战队，2023 年 11 月 15 日。路透社/Issei Kato</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/1R6Zi3s4kjeGmby_ex-XDD4fECg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VY4MJSRYQVKSNN6Z4NUYLEJB3M.jpg" alt="Japanese Ground Self-Defense Force's Amphibious Rapid Deployment Brigade soldiers take part in a military drill at Irisuna island翻译:日本陆上自卫队两栖快速部署旅士兵在入岛岛参加军事演习" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Soldiers of Japanese Ground Self-Defense Force's (JGSDF) Amphibious Rapid Deployment Brigade (ARDB), Japan's first marine unit since World War Two, take part in a military drill as a U.S. Marine personnel looks on, at an uninhabited Irisuna island close to Okinawa, Japan, November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Issei Kato翻译:日本陆上自卫队 (JGSDF) 两栖快速部署旅 (ARDB) 的士兵在冲绳附近无人居住的入里砂岛参加军事演习，美国海军陆战队人员在旁观看，这是第二次世界大战以来日本的第一支海军陆战队部队，日本，2023 年 11 月 15 日。路透社/Issei Kato</figcaption></figure>                   <p>A Japanese Apache helicopter on Wednesday flew low over an uninhabited island in Okinawa in a simulated attack on invading forces, part of exercises under way in Japan to prepare its air, sea and land forces for a potential conflict in East Asia.翻译:周三，一架日本阿帕奇直升机低空飞越冲绳一座无人居住的岛屿，模拟攻击入侵部队，这是日本正在进行的演习的一部分，旨在为东亚潜在的冲突做好准备，其空中、海上和陆地部队。</p>   <p>The flight over Irisuna, about 70 kilometres (43.5 miles) from the main Okinawa island, was part of the country's 11-day nationwide 05JX. The drills, which end Monday, also include an air defence exercise in Japan’s north and simulated attacks on five nuclear reactors including the Fukushima plant.翻译:这次飞越距离冲绳主岛约 70 公里（43.5 英里）的伊里斯纳 (Irisuna) 航班是该国为期 11 天的全国 05JX 计划的一部分。演习将于周一结束，还包括在日本北部进行防空演习，以及对包括福岛核电站在内的五个核反应堆进行模拟攻击。</p>   <p>Such military exercises are set to expand in scope and become more frequent after Prime Minister Fumio Kishida in December unveiled a military build-up that will double defence spending over the next five years to bolster Japan's Self Defence Forces against possible adversaries, including China.翻译:日本首相岸田文雄去年 12 月公布了一项军力建设计划，该计划将在未来五年内将国防开支增加一倍，以增强日本自卫队对抗包括中国在内的潜在对手，此类军事演习的范围将扩大，也将变得更加频繁。</p>   <p>"The national security environment around Japan has become harsher, particularly with the growing military activities by China and Russia in the East China Sea, South China Sea and western Pacific," Shingo Nashinoki, commander of Japan's Amphibious Rapid Deployment Brigade, (ARDB) said on Irisuna.翻译:日本两栖快速部署旅（ARDB）指挥官梨木真吾（Shingo Nashinoki）表示：“日本周边的国家安全环境变得更加严峻，特别是随着中国和俄罗斯在东海、南海和西太平洋的军事活动不断增加。”关于伊莉苏娜。</p>   <p>Trained to conduct operations from the sea, his unit was established in 2018 to help Japan defend the Okinawa islands, which stretch from the main Japanese islands to close to Taiwan.翻译:他的部队成立于 2018 年，接受过海上行动训练，旨在帮助日本保卫冲绳群岛，冲绳群岛从日本主要岛屿一直延伸到台湾附近。</p>   <p>Japan's increasing defence budget will allow the ARDB to add a third regiment, Nashinoki said.翻译:Nashinoki 表示，日本不断增加的国防预算将使 ARDB 能够增加第三个团。</p>    <span>Reporting by Tim Kelly. Editing by Gerry Doyle翻译:蒂姆·凯利报道。格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:47:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">B6PPRNEWBROL3MWWESTSNZCSUY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japanese-helicopters-train-repel-invaders-amid-nationwide-military-drills-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Tim Kelly]]></author>
            
                
                <category>JAPAN</category>
                
                <category>DEFENCE/IRISUNA (TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国习近平在美国参加高风险的拜登峰会和亚太经合组织]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/p6qfrGq_KnFImjes-E8-skVpo7s=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/G3OUQNJDMBPYVDLRYOE6AHE4EQ.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/y2h857HMko9po5X5eBS1uFQPfvo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ICBJHPVSKNLPFMHZY23C7Q2JUE.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A motorcade transporting China's President Xi Jinping arrives at a hotel where the Chinese delegation will stay during the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:2023 年 11 月 14 日，中国国家主席习近平的车队抵达美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的 APEC（亚太经合组织）峰会期间中国代表团下榻的酒店。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/wUwIReGdJLNC-uUymBbSJs2ahuI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZV25UQ5GSZIJPLXDTWJWHNI6I4.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping waves as he arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/JPgeh28fhc5-XGizfDmKoe3_mVU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/EDABMKLXARKULGZ7QBNBLGKRTU.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/1ULQEt5sTvuCu6kPSYAuW0bVAUE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FPUKURKYKVLCFCT2TWQF57BHYI.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small  翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/nTTy9R4o0xvH8z5i5l9UgcP0kio=/1756x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OC6EUZFDFNNEFG7E6SN7ZX77WU.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken holds an APEC Ministerial Meeting (AMM) Opening Session in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯于 2023 年 11 月 14 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行亚太经合组织部长级会议 (AMM) 开幕会议。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/QwRI1qNoHW9vcw7Wj3S8tVMkeDI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/LUSFUFQ2JNMPTPWYK3DCLLVWRY.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken attends an APEC Ministerial Meeting (AMM) Opening Session in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯出席 2023 年 11 月 14 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织部长级会议 (AMM) 开幕会议。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria</figcaption></figure>                         <p>Chinese President Xi Jinping began his first visit to the United States in six years on Tuesday, after President Joe Biden said he aimed to restore normal communications with Beijing and his top diplomat stressed the need for freedoms that Washington says Beijing is undermining in the Asia-Pacific region.翻译:周二，中国国家主席习近平开始六年来首次访问美国，此前美国总统乔·拜登表示，他的目标是恢复与北京的正常沟通，他的高级外交官强调了华盛顿称北京正在破坏亚洲自由的必要性。太平洋地区。</p>   <p>Xi is on his first visit to the U.S. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/cnews-us-usa-china-idCAKBN1792KA-OCATP">since 2017</a>. He is due to meet Biden at an undisclosed location in the San Francisco Bay Area on Wednesday morning and then attend the annual summit of the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/tricky-politics-menu-chinas-xi-us-business-dinner-2023-11-14/">(APEC) forum.</a>翻译:这是习近平<a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/cnews-us-usa-china-idCAKBN1792KA-OCATP">自2017年以来</a>首次访问美国。他将于周三上午在旧金山湾区的一个秘密地点与拜登会面，然后出席亚太经济合作组织<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/tricky-politics-menu-chinas-xi-us-business-dinner-2023-11-14/">（APEC）论坛年度峰会。</a></p>   <p>Xi's summit with Biden will be the first<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">face-to-face</a> meeting between the U.S. and Chinese leaders in a year and has been billed by U.S. officials as an opportunity to reduce friction in what many see as the world's most dangerous rivalry.翻译:习近平与拜登的峰会将是美国和中国领导人一年来的首次<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">面对面</a>会晤，美国官员称这是减少摩擦的一个机会，这场许多人认为这是世界上最危险的竞争。</p>   <p>Xi waved from the steps of his Air China plane upon arrival and descended to meet U.S. officials on the tarmac, including Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen and U.S. Ambassador to China Nicholas Burns.翻译:习近平抵达国航飞机后，在飞机台阶上挥手致意，然后降落在停机坪上会见美国官员，其中包括财政部长珍妮特·耶伦和美国驻华大使尼古拉斯·伯恩斯。</p>   <p>He then got into his Chinese Hongqi, or "Red Flag," limousine and departed the airport into San Francisco, where demonstrations are expected both for and against his visit.翻译:随后，他乘坐他的中国红旗豪华轿车离开机场前往旧金山，预计那里将举行支持和反对他访问的示威活动。</p>   <p>Less than two hours earlier, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken addressed ministers of the 21-member APEC and stressed the U.S. believed in "a region where economies are free to choose their own path ... where goods, ideas, people flow lawfully and freely."翻译:不到两个小时前，美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯向亚太经合组织 21 个成员国的部长们发表讲话，强调美国相信“一个经济体可以自由选择自己道路的地区……在这里，货物、思想和人员可以合法且自由地流动”。自由。”</p>   <p>Blinken did not mention China by name, but his language echoed U.S. rhetoric in recent years in which Washington has accused China of bullying smaller countries in the Indo-Pacific and trying to undermine what the U.S. and its allies call the "rules-based" order.翻译:布林肯没有提到中国的名字，但他的语言呼应了美国近年来的言论，华盛顿指责中国欺凌印太地区的小国，并试图破坏美国及其盟友所谓的“基于规则”的秩序。</p>   <p>U.S. Trade Representative Katherine Tai, who with Blinken opened the APEC ministerial session, said the San Francisco meeting came at a time of "great uncertainty and challenges" for the region. She noted increasing geopolitical tensions, fragile supply chains and a worsening climate crisis.翻译:美国贸易代表戴凯瑟琳·戴 (Katherine Tai) 与布林肯一起宣布亚太经合组织部长级会议开幕，她表示，旧金山会议召开之际，该地区正面临“巨大的不确定性和挑战”。她指出，地缘政治紧张局势日益加剧，供应链脆弱，气候危机日益恶化。</p>   <p>Earlier, Biden said he aimed to improve the relationship with China after a period of strained ties and would seek to resume normal communications between the two superpowers, including <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-says-goal-xi-meeting-is-resume-us-china-military-communications-2023-11-14/">military-to-military contacts</a>.翻译:此前，拜登表示，他的目标是在一段紧张时期后改善与中国的关系，并将寻求恢复两个超级大国之间的正常沟通，包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-says-goal-xi-meeting-is-resume-us-china-military-communications-2023-11-14/">军事接触</a>。</p>   <p>White House national security spokesperson John Kirby told reporters that Biden and Xi would also talk about the Israel-Hamas conflict in Gaza as well as U.S. efforts to support Ukraine in its fight against the Russian military.翻译:白宫国家安全发言人约翰·柯比告诉记者，拜登和习近平还将讨论以色列与哈马斯在加沙的冲突，以及美国支持乌克兰对抗俄罗斯军队的努力。</p>   <p>Economic issues will be high on the agenda.翻译:经济问题将成为议程的重点。</p>   <p>Biden said the U.S. does not want to decouple from China, but wants to change the economic relationship for the better. His administration has made a push to "de-risk" some critical U.S. supply chains from China as the two countries’ economic and military competition has grown.翻译:拜登表示，美国不想与中国脱钩，而是希望改善经济关系。随着两国经济和军事竞争的加剧，他的政府已努力推动美国一些关键供应链从中国“消除风险”。</p>   <p>Xi, who is seeking to entice foreign investment during the APEC to counter his country's recent struggles, is expected to dine with top U.S. business executives on Wednesday.翻译:习近平正在亚太经合组织会议期间寻求吸引外国投资，以应对中国最近的困境。预计他将于周三与美国企业高管共进晚餐。</p>   <p>For American businesses, it will be a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/tricky-politics-menu-chinas-xi-us-business-dinner-2023-11-14/">chance to hear</a> directly from China's leader as they search for ways to navigate that country's economic slowdown and uncertainty caused by expanding Chinese security rules.</p>    <h 1="">CONCERNS ABOUT A SHOWDOWN</h>  <p>Biden has been careful to assure countries in the region, including China, that the U.S. does not seek complete economic separation, a notion that has fueled concerns among Washington's partners and allies of a superpower showdown that would upend the global economy.翻译:拜登一直小心翼翼地向包括中国在内的该地区国家保证，美国不会寻求完全的经济分离，这一想法加剧了华盛顿的合作伙伴和盟友对超级大国摊牌的担忧，这将颠覆全球经济。</p>   <p>China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-premier-evil-neighbour-next-door-is-showing-off-her-power-our-door-2022-08-05/">severed</a> military-to-military contacts with the U.S. after then-House of Representatives Speaker Nancy Pelosi visited democratically governed but Chinese-claimed Taiwan in August 2022.翻译:2022 年 8 月，时任众议院议长南希·佩洛西访问民主治理但中国声称拥有主权的台湾后，中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-premier-evil-neighbour-next-door-is-showing-off-her-power-our-door-2022-08-05/">切断了</a>与美国的军事接触。</p>   <p>Restoring the contacts is a top U.S. goal to avoid miscalculations between the two militaries.翻译:恢复接触是美国的首要目标，以避免两军之间出现误判。</p>   <p>Washington also hopes for more cooperation from Beijing in combating production of the potent synthetic opioid drug <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-set-take-action-win-chinas-cooperation-fentanyl-2023-11-14/">fentanyl</a>, which has become a scourge in the United States and particularly in San Francisco.翻译:华盛顿还希望与北京加强合作，打击强效合成阿片类药物<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-set-take-action-win-chinas-cooperation-fentanyl-2023-11-14/">芬太尼</a>的生产，芬太尼已成为美国尤其是旧金山的祸害。</p>   <p>Sino-U.S. relations worsened after Biden ordered the shooting down in February of a suspected Chinese <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-announce-successful-conclusion-chinese-balloon-recovery-sources-2023-02-17/">spy balloon</a> that flew over the United States.翻译:拜登2月份下令击落飞越美国上空的疑似中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-announce-successful-conclusion-chinese-balloon-recovery-sources-2023-02-17/">间谍气球</a>后，中美关系恶化。</p>   <p>Top Biden administration officials have since visited Beijing and met with their counterparts in an effort to rebuild communications and trust.翻译:此后，拜登政府高级官员访问了北京并会见了同行，以努力重建沟通和信任。</p>   <p>Several hundred mostly pro-China demonstrators carrying Chinese flags gathered outside the Chinese delegation's hotel ahead of Xi's arrival in the U.S.翻译:在习近平抵达美国之前，数百名手持中国国旗的示威者聚集在中国代表团下榻的酒店外，其中大部分是亲中国的</p>   <p>Larger protests, including by rights groups critical of Xi's policies in Tibet, Hong Kong and toward Muslim Uyghurs, are expected near the summit venue on Wednesday.翻译:预计周三峰会会场附近将举行更大规模的抗议活动，其中包括批评习近平在西藏、香港和穆斯林维吾尔人政策的人权组织。</p>   <p>As Biden arrived in San Francisco, shortly before Xi was due to land, dueling demonstrators greeted the U.S. president's motorcade from the airport. Some waved Chinese flags and held banners calling for "kindly" and "warm" U.S.-Sino ties. Others held signs condemning the Chinese Communist Party.翻译:当拜登抵达旧金山时，就在习近平即将抵达之前不久，示威者在机场迎接美国总统的车队。一些人挥舞着中国国旗，举着呼吁“友好”和“温暖”的美中关系的横幅。其他人则举着谴责中国共产党的标语。</p>   <p>Earlier on Tuesday, a small aircraft flew circles over the APEC summit venue in downtown San Francisco, trailing a banner that read, "END CCP FREE CHINA FREE HK FREE TIBET FREE UIGHUR," referring to China's treatment of Uyghurs, which the Biden administration calls "genocide."翻译:周二早些时候，一架小型飞机在旧金山市中心的亚太经合组织峰会会场上空盘旋，机上悬挂着一条横幅，上面写着“结束中共、自由中国、自由香港、自由西藏、自由维吾尔人”，指的是中国对待维吾尔人的方式，拜登政府称这是中国对待维吾尔人的方式。 “种族灭绝。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Michael Martina, Ann Saphir, David Brunnstrom, Trevor Hunnicutt, David Lawder, Sayantani Ghosh and Peter Henderson; Editing by Leslie Adler, Chris Reese, Josie Kao, Don Durfee and Lincoln Feast.翻译:Michael Martina、Ann Saphir、David Brunnstrom、Trevor Hunnicutt、David Lawder、Sayantani Ghosh 和 Peter Henderson 报道；由莱斯利·阿德勒、克里斯·里斯、乔西·高、唐·德菲和林肯·盛宴编辑。</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:43:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">UHP6R2QSRZPV5EGYYV7EDHAK4A</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Michael Martina, David Brunnstrom]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/MINISTERIAL (UPDATE 5, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国商务部长表示印太谈判的三大“支柱”已结束]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/id2c8QkQ1liVs-zbTsW7UD2vCnk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/UO5FM7JNZZOAVDMBEH3DE5MXNQ.jpg" alt="Indo-Pacific Economic Framework meeting in Detroit翻译:印度-太平洋经济框架会议在底特律举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo addresses the media during the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework meeting in Detroit翻译:印度-太平洋经济框架会议在底特律举行, Michigan U.S. May 27, 2023. REUTERS/Rebecca Cook/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S. Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo said a ministers meeting on Tuesday had completed three of four "pillars" in the Biden administration's Indo-Pacific Economic Framework talks on the sidelines of a Pacific Rim leaders summit.翻译:美国商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多表示，周二的部长级会议已经完成了拜登政府在环太平洋地区领导人峰会期间举行的印度-太平洋经济框架谈判的四个“支柱”中的三个。</p>   <p>Raimondo, made the remark at a bilateral meeting with Japan, one of the 14 IPEF countries in the U.S.-led talks.翻译:雷蒙多是在与日本举行的双边会议上发表上述言论的。日本是参加美国主导的谈判的 14 个 IPEF 国家之一。</p>   <p>She did not specify any details of the agreements, but the Commerce Department has led the negotiations on pillars covering supply chains, cooperation on clean energy on fighting corruption and tax evasion.翻译:她没有具体说明协议的任何细节，但商务部主导了供应链、清洁能源合作、反腐败和逃税等支柱的谈判。</p>   <p>Addressing Japan's trade, economy and industry minister, Yasutoshi Nishimura and foreign minister, Yoko Kamikawa, Raimondo said: "I want to thank both of you for your strong support of the IPEF. We had an excellent ministerial earlier today, closing out the three pillars of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework."翻译:雷蒙多在向日本经济产业大臣西村康稔和外务大臣上川洋子致辞时表示：“我要感谢你们两位对 IPEF 的大力支持。今天早些时候，我们举行了一次出色的部长级会议，结束了三大支柱印度-太平洋经济框架”。</p>   <p>Her remarks revealed IPEF member countries have agreed on terms of the clean energy pillar, which aims to boost cooperation on <a href="https://www.commerce.gov/sites/default/files/2023-03/IPEF-Pillar-III-Clean-Economy-Public-Summary.pdf" target="_blank">de-carbonization efforts</a> and on the anti-corruption chapter, which aims also aims to curb <a href="https://www.commerce.gov/sites/default/files/2023-03/IPEF-Pillar-IV-Fair-Economy-Public-Summary.pdf" target="_blank">tax evasion</a> and help countries build stronger institutions and laws.翻译:她的讲话透露，IPEF成员国已就清洁能源支柱的条款达成一致，该支柱旨在加强<a href="https://www.commerce.gov/sites/default/files/2023-03/IPEF-Pillar-III-Clean-Economy-Public-Summary.pdf" target="_blank">脱碳努力</a>和反腐败章节的合作，该章节还旨在遏制<a href="https://www.commerce.gov/sites/default/files/2023-03/IPEF-Pillar-IV-Fair-Economy-Public-Summary.pdf" target="_blank">逃税</a>并帮助各国建立更强有力的机构和法律。</p>   <p>Raimondo last May had announced the completion of the supply chains pillar, which set up an early warning and consultation system for supply chain disruptions due to natural disasters and other factors. A <a href="https://www.ups.com/WebTracking/processInputRequest?tracknum=1ZU0B01T0327140038&amp;loc=en_US" target="_blank">text was completed</a> in September.翻译:雷蒙多去年5月宣布完成供应链支柱，为因自然灾害等因素造成的供应链中断建立预警和咨询系统。 9 月<a href="https://www.ups.com/WebTracking/processInputRequest?tracknum=1ZU0B01T0327140038&amp;loc=en_US" target="_blank">完成了案文</a>。</p>   <p>The fourth pillar, on trade, is not close to agreement, a major setback to the Biden administration, which had hoped to announce substantial completion this week during the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation summit as a symbol of deeper U.S. economic integration with the region and a counterweight alternative to China.翻译:第四个支柱——贸易——尚未接近达成协议，这对拜登政府来说是一个重大挫折，拜登政府原本希望在本周的亚太经合组织峰会上宣布实质性完成协议，以此作为美国与该地区经济深度融合的象征。中国的制衡替代品。</p>   <p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen said on Monday the trade pillar negotiations will <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/yellen-indo-pacific-trade-talks-need-further-work-2023-11-14/">"require further work"</a>.翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦周一表示，贸易支柱谈判将<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/yellen-indo-pacific-trade-talks-need-further-work-2023-11-14/">“需要进一步开展工作”</a> 。</p>   <p>The difficulties on trade come as Biden prepares to meet with Chinese President Xi Jinping on Wednesday in a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/">high-stakes discussion</a> aimed at easing tense relations between the world's two largest economies.翻译:贸易方面的困难出现之际，拜登准备周三与中国国家主席习近平会面，进行一场旨在缓解世界最大两个经济体之间紧张关系的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/">高风险讨论</a>。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Lawder; Editing by Christian Schmollinger and Lincoln Feast.翻译:大卫·劳德报道；克里斯蒂安·施莫林格和林肯·费斯特编辑。</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:30:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CMEHU2H6IRPOTATAGOMGHJ7N3M</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/us-commerce-secretary-says-closed-three-pillars-indo-pacific-talks-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Lawder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/TRADE</category>
                
                <category>IPEF (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国房地产销售延续下滑，前景承压]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ZK7QFM-uFu1AqxVmYfclsK8eU-g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/K7JAUPVPWJLGZFL45JNDNQEUR4.jpg" alt="A man rides a scooter past apartment highrises that are under construction near the new stadium in Zhengzhou翻译:一名男子骑着摩托车经过郑州新体育场附近正在建设的高层公寓" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A man rides a scooter past apartment highrises that are under construction near the new stadium in Zhengzhou翻译:一名男子骑着摩托车经过郑州新体育场附近正在建设的高层公寓, Henan province, China, January 19, 2019.  Picture taken January 19, 2019.  REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's property sales fell at a faster pace in October and investment in real estate slumped, official data showed on Wednesday, suggesting the crisis-hit sector is yet to emerge from its decline despite Beijing's recent support efforts.翻译:周三官方数据显示，中国10月份房地产销售下降速度加快，房地产投资大幅下滑，这表明尽管北京方面最近采取了支持措施，但受危机打击的行业尚未摆脱衰退。</p>   <p>Property sales by floor area fell 20.33% year-on-year against a 19.77% fall in September, according to Reuters calculations based on data released by the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS).翻译:路透社根据国家统计局公布的数据计算，房屋销售面积同比下降20.33%，而9月份则下降19.77%。</p>   <p>Sales fell 7.8% year-on-year in January-October, compared with a 7.5% slide in the first nine months of 2023.翻译:1-10月销售额同比下降7.8%，而2023年前9个月则下滑7.5%。</p>   <p>Authorities have been ramping up measures to support real estate, including relaxing home purchase restrictions and lowering borrowing costs, although these have failed to shore up a meaningful recovery in major cities.翻译:当局一直在加大支持房地产的措施，包括放宽购房限制和降低借贷成本，尽管这些措施未能支撑主要城市的有意义的复苏。</p>   <p>Recent economic data has been mixed with industrial output and retail sales both <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/">beating expectations</a> in October although other indicators such as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-imports-unexpectedly-grow-oct-exports-extend-declines-2023-11-07/">exports</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">consumer prices</a> point to persistent drags on growth.翻译:最近的经济数据好坏参半，10 月份工业产出和零售销售均<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/">超出预期</a>，尽管<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-imports-unexpectedly-grow-oct-exports-extend-declines-2023-11-07/">出口</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">消费者价格</a>等其他指标表明经济增长持续受到拖累。</p>   <p>While a twice-a-decade financial policy meeting last month offered few surprises for the property market, authorities remain concerned about risks that could spill into other industries, threatening financial stability.翻译:尽管上个月举行的十年两次的金融政策会议没有给房地产市场带来什么惊喜，但当局仍然担心风险可能蔓延到其他行业，威胁金融稳定。</p>   <p>China plans to provide at least 1 trillion yuan ($137 billion) of low-cost financing to the urban village renovations and affordable housing programs, Bloomberg News reported on Tuesday, citing people familiar with the matter.翻译:彭博新闻社周二援引知情人士的话报道称，中国计划为城中村改造和保障性住房项目提供至少 1 万亿元人民币（合 1,370 亿美元）的低成本融资。</p>   <p>Reuters previously reported a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">state-engineered rescue</a> of Country Garden <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">(2007.HK)</a> by Ping An Insurance Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601318.SS" target="_blank">(601318.SS)</a>, which would be one of the most significant interventions to date by China to support the sector, though Ping An has repeatedly denied the rescue plan.翻译:路透社此前报道称，平安保险集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601318.SS" target="_blank">（601318.SS）</a>对碧桂园<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">（2007.HK）</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">进行了国家设计的救助</a>，这将是迄今为止中国支持该行业的最重大干预措施之一，尽管平安一再表示否认了救援计划。</p>   <p>Property investment fell 16.7% from a year earlier after an 18.7% slide in September, according to Reuters calculations.翻译:据路透社计算，房地产投资继 9 月份下降 18.7% 后，同比下降 16.7%。</p>   <p>New construction starts measured by floor area fell 23.2% year-on-year, after a 23.4% slump in the first nine months.翻译:按建筑面积计算的新开工面积同比下降 23.2%，前 9 个月下降 23.4%。</p>   <p>Funds raised by China's property developers were down 13.8% year-on-year after a 13.5% fall in January-September.翻译:继1-9月下降13.5%之后，中国房地产开发商募集资金同比下降13.8%。</p>    <span>Reporting by Liangping Gao, Ella Cao and Ryan Woo; Editing by Sam Holmes翻译:高亮平、曹艾拉、吴瑞安报道；山姆·霍姆斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:13:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FRN3TIHRYNMKPIIVX77TKE57ZU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/PROPERTY</category>
                
                <category>INVESTMENT (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1-10月房地产销售同比下降7.8%，投资下降9.3%]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ZK7QFM-uFu1AqxVmYfclsK8eU-g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/K7JAUPVPWJLGZFL45JNDNQEUR4.jpg" alt="A man rides a scooter past apartment highrises that are under construction near the new stadium in Zhengzhou翻译:一名男子骑着摩托车经过郑州新体育场附近正在建设的高层公寓" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A man rides a scooter past apartment highrises that are under construction near the new stadium in Zhengzhou翻译:一名男子骑着摩托车经过郑州新体育场附近正在建设的高层公寓, Henan province, China, January 19, 2019.  Picture taken January 19, 2019.  REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Property sales by floor area in China fell 7.8% year-on-year in January-October, compared with a 7.5% slide in the first nine months of 2023, suggesting China's property sector is yet to emerge from its slump.翻译:1-10月中国房地产销售面积同比下降7.8%，而2023年前9个月的下滑幅度为7.5%，这表明中国房地产行业尚未走出低迷状态。</p>   <p>Property investment in the first 10 months of 2023 fell 9.3% from a year earlier, after dropping 9.1% in January-September, according to data from the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) released on Wednesday.翻译:国家统计局周三发布的数据显示，继1-9月下降9.1%之后，2023年前10个月房地产投资同比下降9.3%。</p>   <p>New construction starts measured by floor area fell 23.2% year-on-year, after a 23.4% slump in the first nine months.翻译:按建筑面积计算的新开工面积同比下降 23.2%，前 9 个月下降 23.4%。</p>   <p>Funds raised by China's property developers were down 13.8% year-on-year after a 13.5% fall in January-September.翻译:继1-9月下降13.5%之后，中国房地产开发商募集资金同比下降13.8%。</p>   <p>(This story has been corrected to change sales fall percentage to 7.8%, from 6.8%, in the headline and paragraph 1)翻译:（这个故事已被更正，将标题和第 1 段中的销售额下降百分比从 6.8% 更改为 7.8%）</p>    <span>Reporting by Liangping Gao, Ella Cao and Ryan Woo; Editing by Sam Holmes翻译:高亮平、曹艾拉、吴瑞安报道；山姆·霍姆斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:08:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">JHOILHZI3BOZZIKDLUIQDGZB3U</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-78-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/PROPERTY</category>
                
                <category>INVESTMENT (URGENT, CORRECTION)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国银行通过政策性贷款加大流动性注入，利率不变]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/5WpBhmWCsz2HDENvuzwOegpnOyA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YFL7JVKIYBLCNORUY7KN3GS4TA.jpg" alt="A gardener works outside the headquarters of the central bank of the People's Republic of China in Beijing翻译:一名园丁在北京中央银行总部外工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A gardener works outside the headquarters of the central bank of the People's Republic of China in Beijing翻译:一名园丁在北京中央银行总部外工作 October 8, 2008. External and internal conditions are ripe for China to cut interest rates soon to give the economy a lift, an official newspaper said in a front-page commentary on Wednesday. REUTERS/Jason Lee (CHINA)翻译:2008年10月8日，北京，一名园丁在中华人民共和国央行总部外工作。一份官方报纸在头条新闻中称，中国近期降息提振经济的内外条件已经成熟。周三的版面评论。路透社/Jason Lee（中国）</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's central bank ramped up liquidity injection but kept the interest rate unchanged when rolling over maturing medium-term policy loans on Wednesday, matching market expectations.翻译:中国央行周三加大流动性注入力度，但在到期中期政策贷款展期时保持利率不变，符合市场预期。</p>   <p>Market participants believe that a weakening Chinese yuan has constrained the central bank's efforts to aggressively lower interest rates even though the recovery of the world's second-largest economy remains uneven and requires further stimulus.翻译:市场人士认为，尽管世界第二大经济体的复苏仍不平衡，需要进一步刺激，但人民币贬值限制了央行大幅降息的努力。</p>   <p>The People's Bank of China (PBOC) said it was keeping the rate on 1.45 trillion yuan ($199.92 billion) worth of one-year medium-term lending facility (MLF) loans to some financial institutions unchanged at 2.50% from the previous operation.翻译:中国人民银行（PBOC）表示，将向部分金融机构发放的 1.45 万亿元人民币（合 1,999.2 亿美元）的一年期中期借贷便利（MLF）贷款利率维持在 2.50% 不变。</p>   <p>The central bank said the loan operation was meant to maintain banking system liquidity reasonably ample to counteract short-term factors including tax payments and government bond issuance.翻译:央行表示，此次贷款操作旨在保持银行体系流动性合理充裕，以应对纳税、国债发行等短期因素。</p>   <p>"At the same time, it will appropriately provide mid- and long-term base money," the PBOC said in an online statement.翻译:“同时，适当提供中长期基础货币，”中国人民银行在网上发布的声明中表示。</p>   <p>All 31 market watchers polled by Reuters this week had expected the central bank to inject fresh funds to exceed the maturity.翻译:路透社本周调查的 31 名市场观察人士均预计央行将注入新资金以超过到期期限。</p>   <p>With 850 billion yuan worth of MLF loans set to expire this month, the operation resulted a net 600 billion yuan of fresh fund injection into the banking system.翻译:本月8500亿元MLF贷款即将到期，此次操作为银行体系净注入资金6000亿元。</p>   <p>"Weak inflation and the recent liquidity squeeze call for stronger policy support this week," Carlos Casanova, senior economist for Asia at UBP, said in a note this week.翻译:UBP 亚洲高级经济学家卡洛斯·卡萨诺瓦 (Carlos Casanova) 在本周的一份报告中表示，“疲软的通胀和近期的流动性紧缩要求本周采取更强有力的政策支持。”</p>   <p>"Liquidity conditions tightened in October, as a deluge of bond issuance to fund fiscal stimulus and quarter-end cash demand from corporates drove up interbank rates. The most likely outcome is for PBOC to inject more support through open market operations, while leaving the MLF rate unchanged."翻译:“10月份流动性状况收紧，因为为财政刺激提供资金的大量债券发行以及企业季末现金需求推高了银行间利率。最可能的结果是中国人民银行通过公开市场操作注入更多支持，同时退出MLF率不变。”</p>   <p>He added that authorities will remain on alert and continue to support the recovery, expecting another 10-basis-point interest rate cut and an additional RRR cut in December, if not sooner.翻译:他补充说，当局将保持警惕并继续支持经济复苏，预计 12 月份（甚至更早）将再次降息 10 个基点并进一步下调存款准备金率。</p>   <p>The interest rate on one-year AAA-rated negotiable certificates of deposit (NCDs) , which measure short-term inter-bank borrowing costs, is hovering at a six-month high of 2.5653%, about 7 bps higher than the MLF rate the central bank charges financial institutions.翻译:衡量短期银行间借贷成本的一年期AAA级可转让存款证（NCD）利率徘徊在六个月高点2.5653%，比MLF利率高出约7个基点。中央银行向金融机构收取费用。</p>   <p>Wednesday's liquidity support for the nascent economic recovery through the medium-term policy loans has, however, reduced necessity for more imminent monetary stimulus, some traders and analysts said.翻译:然而，一些交易员和分析师表示，周三通过中期政策贷款为新生经济复苏提供的流动性支持降低了迫在眉睫的货币刺激措施的必要性。</p>   <p>"But MLF loans is rather expensive, and we still expect additional reserve requirement ratio (RRR) cuts in the future to reduce (banks) debt costs," said Xing Zhaopeng, senior China strategist at ANZ.翻译:澳新银行高级中国策略师邢兆鹏表示：“但MLF贷款相当昂贵，我们仍然预计未来会进一步下调存款准备金率（RRR），以降低（银行）债务成本。”</p>   <p>China has reported a slew of mixed October economic data, as industrial output and retail sales growth data surprised on the upside, while factory activity unexpectedly contracted and consumer prices continued to fall.翻译:中国公布的10月份经济数据好坏参半，工业产出和零售销售增长数据意外上行，而工厂活动意外收缩，消费者价格继续下跌。</p>   <p>Still, market watchers said the currency remained as a key constraint for the authorities to ease monetary policy. China's yuan has lost about 5% to the dollar so far this year to become one of the worst performing Asian currencies.翻译:尽管如此，市场观察人士表示，人民币汇率仍然是当局放松货币政策的主要制约因素。今年迄今为止，人民币兑美元汇率已下跌约5%，成为表现最差的亚洲货币之一。</p>   <p>The sizable depreciation has prompted authorities to step up efforts to support the currency, with many analysts believing policymakers may view yuan stability as a prerequisite for restoring confidence in yuan assets.翻译:大幅贬值促使当局加大支持人民币的力度，许多分析师认为，政策制定者可能将人民币稳定视为恢复人民币资产信心的先决条件。</p>   <p>China remains an outlier among global central banks as it has loosened monetary policy to shore up a stalling recovery but further rate cuts will widen the yield gap with the United States, putting more pressure on the yuan and risking outflows.翻译:中国在全球央行中仍然是一个异类，因为它已经放松了货币政策以支撑停滞的复苏，但进一步降息将扩大与美国的收益率差距，给人民币带来更大的压力，并带来资金外流的风险。</p>   <p>The central bank also injected 495 billion yuan through seven-day reverse repos while keeping borrowing cost unchanged at 1.80%, it said in the statement.翻译:央行在声明中表示，还通过7天逆回购注入4950亿元人民币，维持借贷成本在1.80%不变。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2530 yuan)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2530 元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Winni Zhou and Tom Westbrook; Editing by Christian Schmollinger, Stephen Coates &amp; Shri Navaratnam翻译:Winni Zhou 和 Tom Westbrook 报道；编辑：Christian Schmollinger、Stephen Coates 和 Shri Navaratnam</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 02:42:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">GXDDW2AWXZJSDPGIR6SLALRZD4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cbank-boosts-liquidity-injection-through-policy-loan-rate-unchanged-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/RATES (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MSCI公布季度指数审核结果]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TNQyfi6slRuYp7evKx7UG96jJgc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/AIEKY4OEORN2XOBEYMXT7VAOQQ.jpg" alt="Illustration photo of the MSCI logo翻译:MSCI 标志的插图照片" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The MSCI logo is seen in this June 20, 2017 illustration photo.  REUTERS/Thomas White/Illustration/File Photo翻译:MSCI 标志见这张 2017 年 6 月 20 日的插图照片。路透社/托马斯·怀特/插图/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Index provider MSCI <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSCI.N" target="_blank">(MSCI.N)</a> said on Tuesday that 46 securities will be added to and 69 deleted from its widely-followed MSCI ACWI stock index, while 14 will be added and two deleted from its frontier markets stock index.翻译:指数提供商 MSCI <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSCI.N" target="_blank">(MSCI.N)</a>周二表示，其广受关注的 MSCI ACWI 股票指数将增加 46 只股票，删除 69 只股票，而其前沿市场股票指数将增加 14 只股票，删除 2 只股票。</p>   <p>Changes will be implemented as of the market close on Nov. 30, MSCI announced in its quarterly index review.翻译:MSCI 在其季度指数审查中宣布，这些变化将于 11 月 30 日收盘时实施。</p>   <p>The three largest additions to the MSCI ACWI from developed markets will be Vertiv Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VRT.N" target="_blank">(VRT.N)</a> and Celsius Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/CELH.O" target="_blank">(CELH.O)</a> from the United States, and Italy’s Leonardo <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LDOF.MI" target="_blank">(LDOF.MI)</a>.翻译:发达市场中加入 MSCI ACWI 的前三名将是美国的 Vertiv Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VRT.N" target="_blank">(VRT.N)</a>和摄氏度控股<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/CELH.O" target="_blank">(CELH.O)</a> ，以及意大利的 Leonardo <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LDOF.MI" target="_blank">(LDOF.MI)</a> 。</p>   <p>The three largest additions from emerging markets will be India’s Tata Motors <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TAMO.NS" target="_blank">(TAMO.NS)</a>, Indonesia’s Amman Mineral International <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AMMN.JK" target="_blank">(AMMN.JK)</a> and CGN Power Co <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/003816.SZ" target="_blank">(003816.SZ)</a> from China.翻译:来自新兴市场的三大新增企业将是印度塔塔汽车公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TAMO.NS" target="_blank">(TAMO.NS)</a> 、印度尼西亚安曼矿业国际公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AMMN.JK" target="_blank">(AMMN.JK)</a>和中国中广核电力有限公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/003816.SZ" target="_blank">(003816.SZ)</a> 。</p>   <p>The three largest additions to the Frontier Markets Index will be Vietnam Prosperity Joint Stock Commercial Bank <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VPB.HM" target="_blank">(VPB.HM)</a>, Oman International Development &amp; Investment Company <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/OMVS.OM" target="_blank">(OMVS.OM)</a> and Banque Marocaine pour le Commerce et l'Industrie <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BCI.CS" target="_blank">(BCI.CS)</a>.翻译:前沿市场指数中新增的三大银行将是越南繁荣股份商业银行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VPB.HM" target="_blank">(VPB.HM)</a> 、阿曼国际开发投资公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/OMVS.OM" target="_blank">(OMVS.OM)</a>和摩洛哥商业工业银行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BCI.CS" target="_blank">(BCI.CS)</a> 。</p>   <p>MSCI said it will add 10 and delete 45 securities to its China A Onshore indexes, with CGN Power Co, Shanghai United Imaging Healthcare <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/688271.SS" target="_blank">(688271.SS)</a> and Empyrean Technology Co <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/301269.SZ" target="_blank">(301269.SZ)</a> the largest by market capitalization. It will also add 16 and delete 25 securities from the MSCI China All Shares Index. The largest additions will be these same companies.翻译:MSCI表示，将在其中国A股在岸指数中增加10只股票，删除45只股票，其中中广核电力、上海联影医疗<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/688271.SS" target="_blank">（688271.SS）</a>和九重天科技股份有限公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/301269.SZ" target="_blank">（301269.SZ）</a>市值最大。它还将从 MSCI 中国全股指数中添加 16 只股票和删除 25 只股票。最大的新增成员将是这些公司。</p>    <span>Reporting by Rodrigo Campos
Editing by Chris Reese翻译:罗德里戈·坎波斯报道 克里斯·里斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 23:30:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">P4QCMK53DFOYJGILKI5WSW46JY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/msci-announces-results-quarterly-index-review-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>MSCI</category>
                
                <category>REVIEW/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国高级议员在习近平会面前向拜登施压囚犯问题信函]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/adNPz0m4tNc4EXUbDpfWkYGbYqs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/C2YUZ5N23ZOMRGIZHE5BECJASY.jpg" alt="U.S. Senator Ben Cardin (D-MD) speaks at a committee meeting after assuming the chairmanship of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee at the U.S. Capitol on Capitol Hill in Washington翻译:美国参议员本·卡丁（D-MD）在华盛顿国会山美国国会担任参议院外交关系委员会主席后在委员会会议上发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Senator Ben Cardin (D-MD) speaks at a committee meeting after assuming the chairmanship of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee at the U.S. Capitol on Capitol Hill in Washington翻译:美国参议员本·卡丁（D-MD）在华盛顿国会山美国国会担任参议院外交关系委员会主席后在委员会会议上发表讲话, U.S., September 28, 2023. REUTERS/Craig Hudson/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>The chairman of the U.S. Senate Foreign Relations Committee urged President Joe Biden to use his upcoming meeting with Chinese President Xi Jinping to push for the release of Americans detained for years in China, according to a letter seen by Reuters on Tuesday.翻译:路透社周二看到的一封信显示，美国参议院外交关系委员会主席敦促总统乔·拜登利用即将与中国国家主席习近平举行的会晤，推动释放在中国被拘留多年的美国人。</p>   <p>Democratic Senator Ben Cardin wrote to Biden to push for immediate freedom for Mark Swidan, Kai Li and David Lin, whom the U.S. government has classified as wrongfully detained in China. Republicans and other Democrats have also called for their release.翻译:民主党参议员本·卡丁写信给拜登，敦促立即释放被美国政府列为在中国错误拘留的马克·斯维丹、李凯和林大卫。共和党人和其他民主党人也呼吁释放他们。</p>   <p>Biden and Xi are holding talks around events at the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation forum in San Francisco, as the United States seeks to recover from a diplomatic crisis over its downing of a suspected Chinese spy balloon over the United States in February.翻译:拜登和习近平正在旧金山亚太经济合作论坛上就有关活动举行会谈，此时美国正寻求从二月份在美国上空击落疑似中国间谍气球引发的外交危机中恢复过来。</p>   <p>"With the holiday season approaching, and the opportunity to start the New Year on a more positive note in bilateral U.S.-China relationships, I implore you to secure commitments from president Xi to release these Americans immediately," Cardin wrote.翻译:卡丁写道：“随着假期的临近，以及美中双边关系以更积极的方式开始新年的机会，我恳请您确保习主席承诺立即释放这些美国人。”</p>   <p>Cardin also asked for the release and safety of U.S.-based journalists' family members whom he said are missing, jailed or detained in China due to their connection to the journalists.翻译:卡丁还要求释放驻美国记者的家人并确保他们的安全，他说这些家人因与记者有联系而在中国失踪、被监禁或拘留。</p>   <p>Families of Americans the U.S. government has classified as wrongfully detained in China have also repeatedly urged the government to prioritize the release of their loved ones in talks with Chinese officials.翻译:被美国政府列为在中国错误拘留的美国人的家属也一再敦促政府在与中国官员的会谈中优先释放他们的亲人。</p>   <p>Katherine Swidan said she spoke to U.S. Ambassador to China Nicholas Burns about her son Mark over the weekend, but called the conversation "disappointing" because Burns would not say whether Biden would raise Mark’s name with Xi.翻译:凯瑟琳·斯维丹(Katherine Swidan)表示，她周末与美国驻华大使尼古拉斯·伯恩斯(Nicholas Burns)谈论了她的儿子马克(Mark)，但称这次谈话“令人失望”，因为伯恩斯不愿透露拜登是否会向习近平提及马克的名字。</p>   <p>"China only respects strength," she said, adding that she was frustrated because the Biden administration did not appear to have a plan to get U.S. detainees out of China.翻译:“中国只尊重实力，”她说，并补充说，她感到沮丧，因为拜登政府似乎没有计划将美国在押人员带出中国。</p>   <p>A State Department spokesperson commented that the department has no greater priority than the safety and security of U.S. citizens and noted that it continually raises wrongfully detained U.S. nationals during engagements with senior Chinese officials.翻译:美国国务院发言人评论说，该部门最优先考虑的莫过于美国公民的安全和保障，并指出，该部门在与中国高级官员接触时不断提及被错误拘留的美国公民。</p>   <p>China says such cases are handled according to law.翻译:中方表示，此类案件将依法处理。</p>    <span>Reporting by Patricia Zengerle and Michael Martina; Editing by Stephen Coates翻译:帕特里夏·曾格尔 (Patricia Zengerle) 和迈克尔·马丁纳 (Michael Martina) 报道；斯蒂芬·科茨编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 22:56:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZDHUMWNM4BKE7DQHESLVYQ4JHM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/senior-us-lawmaker-pushes-biden-prisoners-ahead-xi-meeting-letter-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Patricia Zengerle, Michael Martina]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CONGRESS</category>
                
                <category>CHINA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[澳大利亚相信中国下个月将解除所有贸易封锁]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tlOCbhf4AQTSfnCSNLqE0rVmYmo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4FPO6VW3GNJQLEKJUSM3NPT7O4.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of Australian and Chinese flags翻译:澳大利亚和中国国旗插画图片" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Flags of Australia and China are displayed in this illustration picture taken May 11, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration翻译:这张摄于 2023 年 5 月 11 日的插图照片中展示了澳大利亚和中国的国旗。REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration</figcaption></figure>       <p>Australia said on Wednesday China could lift all its remaining trade blocks by next month as relations between the commodity trade partners stabilise and after Prime Minister Anthony Albanese's visit to Beijing earlier this month.翻译:澳大利亚周三表示，随着大宗商品贸易伙伴之间的关系稳定以及总理安东尼·阿尔巴内斯本月早些时候访问北京之后，中国可能会在下个月解除所有剩余的贸易封锁。</p>   <p>Albanese's government has taken credit for patching up ties with China since coming to office last year. China has lifted most trade blocks imposed amid a 2020 diplomatic dispute after Australia called for an inquiry into the origins of COVID-19.翻译:自去年上任以来，阿尔巴尼斯政府因修复与中国的关系而受到赞誉。在澳大利亚呼吁对 COVID-19 的起源进行调查后，中国取消了在 2020 年外交争端中施加的大部分贸易封锁。</p>   <p>"I remain very confident ... that by Christmas all of these trade impediments will be removed," trade minister Don Farrell told ABC Radio from San Francisco, where he is attending Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) meetings.翻译:“我仍然非常有信心……到圣诞节，所有这些贸易障碍都将被消除，”贸易部长唐·法雷尔在旧金山出席亚太经合组织（APEC）会议时告诉美国广播公司广播电台。</p>   <p>"And we will have restored that stable relationship that we want with our largest trading partner."翻译:“我们将与我们最大的贸易伙伴恢复我们想要的稳定关系。”</p>   <p>Farrell said he hoped to resolve the issues over lobster and beef, which related to bio-security rules, ahead of a meeting with Chinese counterpart Wang Wentao in San Francisco.翻译:法雷尔表示，他希望在旧金山与中国外长王文涛会面之前解决涉及生物安全规则的龙虾和牛肉问题。</p>    <span>Reporting by Renju Jose in Sydney. Editing by Sam Holmes.翻译:Renju Jose 悉尼报道。山姆·霍姆斯编辑。</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 22:53:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">XQQB2LJGGVPONCFWDIWUXHPQFA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australia-confident-china-will-lift-all-trade-blocks-next-month-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/TRADE</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早间竞标：在美国软着陆希望的推动下登上月球]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ATcJg9p9txuNGT_jE7iAFeQTFag=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SOYPWW527ZKYHKNPZB2O6HCXAI.jpg" alt="Pedestrians walk past an electronic board displaying Nikkei share average, outside a brokerage in Tokyo翻译:东京一家经纪公司外，行人走过显示日经平均股价的电子板" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Pedestrians walk past an electronic board displaying Nikkei share average, outside a brokerage in Tokyo翻译:东京一家经纪公司外，行人走过显示日经平均股价的电子板, Japan, October 31, 2023. REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>A look at the day ahead in Asian markets from Jamie McGeever, financial markets columnist.翻译:金融市场专栏作家杰米·麦克吉弗 (Jamie McGeever) 对亚洲市场未来一天的展望。</p>   <p>Asian markets open on Wednesday with stocks, risk assets and investor sentiment around the world soaring after <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-consumer-prices-unchanged-october-2023-11-14/">cooling U.S. inflation data</a> on Tuesday looked to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/traders-see-no-more-fed-rate-increases-cuts-start-may-2023-11-14/">close the door</a> on more rate hikes and pave the way for the fabled economic 'soft landing'.翻译:亚洲市场周三开盘，全球股市、风险资产和投资者情绪飙升，周二<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-consumer-prices-unchanged-october-2023-11-14/">美国通胀数据降温，</a>似乎<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/traders-see-no-more-fed-rate-increases-cuts-start-may-2023-11-14/">关闭了进一步加息的大门</a>，并为传说中的经济“软着陆”铺平了道路。</p>   <p>Some of Tuesday's U.S. market moves were eye-popping - two- and five-year bond yields plunged more than 20 basis points; the Nasdaq rose more than 2%; the Russell 2000 index rose 5% for its best day in a year; <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/yens-slide-multi-decade-lows-keeps-markets-intervention-alert-2023-11-14/">the dollar</a> fell 1.5% for its worst day in a year; and the Aussie and New Zealand dollars both leaped 2%.翻译:周二美国市场的一些走势令人瞠目结舌——两年期和五年期债券收益率暴跌超过20个基点；纳斯达克指数上涨超过2%；罗素 2000 指数上涨 5%，创一年来最好单日涨幅； <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/yens-slide-multi-decade-lows-keeps-markets-intervention-alert-2023-11-14/">美元</a>下跌1.5%，创下一年来最糟糕的一天；澳元和新西兰元均上涨 2%。</p>   <p>This should be rocket fuel for Asia on Wednesday, although there is no shortage of event risk.翻译:尽管不乏事件风险，但这应该是周三亚洲的火箭燃料。</p>   <p>Top-tier data releases include third quarter Japanese GDP and Chinese retail sales, industrial output, investment and unemployment figures for October, while U.S. and Chinese Presidents <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">Joe Biden and Xi Jinping</a> meet at the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation forum in San Francisco.翻译:顶级数据发布包括日本第三季度GDP和中国10月份零售额、工业产出、投资和失业数据，同时美国和中国国家主席<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">乔·拜登和习近平</a>在旧金山举行的亚太经济合作论坛上会面。</p>   <p>Biden and Xi have only met once before, and this is Xi's first visit to the U.S. since 2017. Xi is hoping to persuade Biden to ease up on tariffs and export controls aimed at keeping the most advanced semiconductors from being sent to China.翻译:拜登和习近平此前只见过一次面，这是习近平自2017年以来首次访问美国。习近平希望说服拜登放松关税和出口管制，以阻止最先进的半导体输往中国。</p>   <p>In a separate dinner with business leaders, he will also be looking to boost flagging investment by U.S. firms in China. Foreign investors have pulled huge sums out of China this year as the economy has faltered and tensions with the West have deepened.翻译:在与商界领袖举行的另一场晚宴上，他还将寻求提振美国公司在中国萎靡不振的投资。今年，随着中国经济步履蹒跚、与西方的紧张关系加剧，外国投资者已从中国撤出巨额资金。</p>   <p>Ahead of their talks, China's yuan climbed to a three-month high of 7.25 per dollar on Tuesday, rising around 0.5% for its biggest one-day gain in two months.翻译:在会谈之前，人民币兑美元汇率周二攀升至三个月高位7.25，上涨约0.5%，创两个月来最大单日涨幅。</p>   <p>The latest retail sales, industrial output, investment and unemployment figures for October will give an insight into whether China's economy is maintaining the surprisingly strong momentum it showed in the third quarter.翻译:10月份最新的零售销售、工业产出、投资和失业数据将让我们了解中国经济是否保持了第三季度令人惊讶的强劲势头。</p>   <p>Citi's China economic surprises index has been in positive territory for almost a month, suggesting activity is strengthening or analysts are lowering their expectations. Or a bit of both.翻译:花旗中国经济意外指数近一个月来一直处于正值区间，表明经济活动正在加强，或者分析师正在降低预期。或者两者兼而有之。</p>   <p>Japan's economic surprises index, on the other hand, just slumped into negative territory and is the lowest since June. The first reading of third quarter GDP on Wednesday could lift it again - the bar would appear low enough.翻译:另一方面，日本经济意外指数刚刚跌至负值，为 6 月以来的最低水平。周三公布的第三季度 GDP 初值可能会再次提升——这个标准似乎足够低。</p>   <p>Economists reckon the economy contracted 0.1% from the April-June period and shrank 0.6% on an annualized basis. That would represent a significant slowdown from growth rates of 1.2% and 4.8%, respectively, in the previous quarter.翻译:经济学家估计，经济较 4 月至 6 月期间收缩 0.1%，年化收缩 0.6%。这将比上一季度分别 1.2% 和 4.8% 的增长率显着放缓。</p>   <p>The corporate focus in Asia on Wednesday turns to the third quarter earnings reports from China's JD.Com and Tencent Holdings. JD.Com is expected to report a 2.3% increase in revenue to CNY249.258 billion and CNY5.77 earnings per share.翻译:周三亚洲企业的焦点转向中国京东和腾讯控股的第三季度收益报告。京东预计营收增长 2.3%，至 2,492.58 亿元人民币，每股收益 5.77 元人民币。</p>   <p>Here are key developments that could provide more direction to markets on Wednesday:翻译:以下是周三可能为市场提供更多方向的关键进展：</p>   <p>- Japan GDP (Q3, preliminary)翻译:- 日本 GDP（第三季度，初步）</p>   <p>- China retail sales, industrial output, investment, unemployment (October)翻译:- 中国零售额、工业产出、投资、失业率（10月）</p>   <p>- Presidents Joe Biden and Xi Jinping meet翻译:- 乔·拜登总统和习近平会面</p>    <span>By Jamie McGeever; Editing by翻译:作者：杰米·麦克吉弗；编辑者</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 21:56:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">DMDP4OFDONMNZLWSDAO6UEDHXA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/global-markets-view-asia-graphics-pix-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jamie McGeever]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>ASIA (GRAPHICS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
