<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 23:27:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[乔·拜登与习近平在军事、经济问题上发生分歧]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/FvilMKflkrYZQdGP7GSAh5f5V5c=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/47OZBB6DJZPCBBXDPLRZ52XHGM.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden shakes hands with Chinese President Xi Jinping at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登在菲洛丽庄园与中国国家主席习近平握手。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/uJlbUuBKlrkFU-CkBFWK1pCOyn8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4LSUN2CXHZKPXNOXEZKFD47QI4.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping attend a bilateral meeting at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经济合作组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平出席在菲洛丽庄园举行的双边会议。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/1aQy68ht2GBcwt8yS92TftHRBS0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/IXQBFFPVX5NWBIPIGGTFBAM2GE.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden welcomes Chinese President Xi Jinping at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登在菲洛丽庄园欢迎中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tqs78ae9Y1UTE522yIVIOzSVmBI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/P3ULMM4OFBJNRKE5X3M2YDA7FQ.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登在菲洛丽庄园会见中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TG1TEqoix0BmSLzAs_2ZQkKdhx0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XVZII463FBIDNM7WDJMOYPZZ6Q.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden disembarks from Air Force One at San Francisco International Airport, as he arrives to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 14 日，美国总统乔·拜登在旧金山国际机场从空军一号下机，抵达美国加利福尼亚州旧金山参加亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会。 REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lTdjpZN9pb-WDBwFVbkn4Qq-Rig=/1878x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JFCDJ65EHNIW7MVYN3IPSOJ6AQ.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping waves as he arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的APEC（亚太经合组织）峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small/资料照片</figcaption></figure>                       <p>U.S. President Joe Biden met Chinese leader Xi Jinping for the first time in a year on Wednesday for talks aimed at easing<a href="https://www.reuters.com/podcasts/biden-meet-xi-san-francisco-2023-11-12/?%24web_only=true&amp;_branch_match_id=1161293349163474432&amp;utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_medium=marketing&amp;_branch_referrer=H4sIAAAAAAAAA8soKSkottLXz8nMy9YrSi0tSS0q1kvOz9VP1Q9wSwzOLi7O8XZNAgBzJOFkJgAAAA%3D%3D">friction</a> between the two superpowers over military conflicts, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">drug-trafficking</a> and artificial intelligence, and said they had made "real progress."翻译:美国总统乔·拜登周三与中国领导人习近平一年来首次会面，会谈旨在缓解两个超级大国之间在军事冲突、 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">贩毒</a>和人工智能方面的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/podcasts/biden-meet-xi-san-francisco-2023-11-12/?%24web_only=true&amp;_branch_match_id=1161293349163474432&amp;utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_medium=marketing&amp;_branch_referrer=H4sIAAAAAAAAA8soKSkottLXz8nMy9YrSi0tSS0q1kvOz9VP1Q9wSwzOLi7O8XZNAgBzJOFkJgAAAA%3D%3D">摩擦</a>，并表示双方已取得“真正进展”。</p>   <p>Biden welcomed the Chinese leader at the Filoli estate, a country house and gardens about 30 miles (48 km) south of San Francisco, where they will move later for a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/">summit of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation</a> (APEC) forum.翻译:拜登在位于旧金山以南约 30 英里（48 公里）的菲洛丽庄园（Filoli Estate）欢迎了中国领导人，这是一座乡村别墅和花园，他们稍后将前往那里参加<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/">亚太经济合作组织（APEC）论坛峰会</a>。</p>   <p>Biden said the U.S. and China had to ensure that competition between them "does not veer into conflict" and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-objects-us-proposal-apec-trade-investment-policies-source-2023-11-15/">manage their relationship</a> "responsibly." He said issues such as climate change, counter-narcotics and AI demanded their joint attention.翻译:拜登表示，美国和中国必须确保两国之间的竞争“不会演变成冲突”，并“负责任地” <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-objects-us-proposal-apec-trade-investment-policies-source-2023-11-15/">管理两国关系</a>。他表示，气候变化、禁毒和人工智能等问题需要他们共同关注。</p>   <p>After a morning session of talks and before heading into lunch with Xi, Biden said on social media platform X, it was vital they understood each other "leader to leader."翻译:经过上午的会谈后，在与习近平共进午餐之前，拜登在社交媒体平台 X 上表示，他们“领导人之间”的相互理解至关重要。</p>   <p>"There are critical global challenges that demand our joint leadership. And today, we made real progress," he said.翻译:“全球面临着严峻的挑战，需要我们共同领导。今天，我们取得了真正的进展，”他说。</p>   <p>A White House statement said the leaders "held a candid and constructive discussion on a range of bilateral and global issues and exchanged views on areas of difference."翻译:白宫声明称，两国领导人“就一系列双边和全球问题进行了坦诚和建设性的讨论，并就分歧领域交换了意见”。</p>   <p>Xi told Biden as they began their talks a lot had happened since their last meeting <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/top-takeaways-biden-xi-meeting-bali-2022-11-14/">a year ago in Bali</a>. "The world has emerged from the COVID pandemic, but is still under its tremendous impacts. The global economy is recovering, but its momentum remains sluggish."翻译:习近平在会谈开始时告诉拜登<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/top-takeaways-biden-xi-meeting-bali-2022-11-14/">，自一年前巴厘岛</a>上次会面以来发生了很多事情。 “世界已经摆脱了新冠肺炎疫情的影响，但仍受到巨大影响。全球经济正在复苏，但动能依然低迷。”</p>   <p>He called the U.S.-China relationship "the most important bilateral relationship in the world," and said he and Biden "shoulder heavy responsibilities for the two peoples, for the world, and for history."翻译:他称美中关系是“世界上最重要的双边关系”，并表示他和拜登“对两国人民、对世界、对历史肩负着沉重的责任”。</p>   <p>"For two large countries like China and the United States, turning their back on each other is not an option," he said. "It is unrealistic for one side to remodel the other, and conflict and confrontation has unbearable consequences for both sides."翻译:“对于中国和美国这样的两个大国来说，互相背弃不是一个选择，”他说。 “一方改造另一方是不现实的，冲突对抗会给双方带来难以承受的后果。”</p>   <p>The leaders will be seeking to reduce friction but deep progress on the vast differences separating them may have to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">wait for another day</a>.翻译:领导人将寻求减少摩擦，但要在解决他们之间的巨大分歧方面取得深入进展可能要<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">等到另一天</a>。</p>   <p>Biden and Xi will discuss a host of issues where the countries are on opposing sides including Taiwan, the South China Sea, the Israel-Hamas war, Russia's invasion of Ukraine, North Korea and human rights.翻译:拜登和习近平将讨论一系列两国对立的问题，包括台湾、南海、以色列-哈马斯战争、俄罗斯入侵乌克兰、朝鲜和人权。</p>   <p>Leaders from the 21-country group APEC - and hundreds of CEOs in San Francisco to court them - are meeting amid relative <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">Chinese economic weakness</a>, Beijing's territorial feuds with neighbors and a Middle East conflict that is dividing the United States from allies.</p>    <h 1="">DIRECT DIPLOMACY</h>  <p>Experts say Xi will be looking for a smooth summit with Biden to show those at home concerned about the economy and dwindling foreign investment that he can successfully handle relations between the world's two largest economies.翻译:专家表示，习近平将寻求与拜登举行顺利的峰会，向那些担心经济和外国投资减少的国内人士表明，他能够成功处理世界两大经济体之间的关系。</p>   <p>Efforts to carefully choreograph his visit may be upended in San Francisco despite <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/san-francisco-patches-over-homelessness-drug-abuse-apec-2023-11-15/">efforts to drive homeless people</a> from the streets. Xi's route from the airport to the conference site on Tuesday was lined with demonstrators for and against China's ruling Communist Party, an unusual sight for the leader, who last visited the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/cnews-us-usa-china-idCAKBN1792KA-OCATP">United States in 2017</a>.翻译:尽管旧金山努力<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/san-francisco-patches-over-homelessness-drug-abuse-apec-2023-11-15/">将无家可归者赶出街头，但精心安排他的访问的努力</a>可能会被颠覆。周二，习近平从机场前往会议地点的路上，两旁都是支持和反对中国执政共产党的示威者，这对于这位<a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/cnews-us-usa-china-idCAKBN1792KA-OCATP">2017年最后一次访问美国的</a>领导人来说是不寻常的景象。</p>   <p>Biden has sought direct diplomacy with Xi, betting that a personal relationship he has cultivated for a dozen years with the most powerful Chinese leader since Mao Zedong might salvage ties that have turned increasingly hostile.翻译:拜登寻求与习近平进行直接外交，押注他与自毛泽东以来最强大的中国领导人十几年来建立的个人关系可能会挽救日益敌对的关系。</p>   <p>Chong Ja Ian, a political science professor at the National University of Singapore, said the two sides are engaged in what Mao referred to during China's civil war as "talk and fight, fight and talk".翻译:新加坡国立大学政治学教授庄嘉欣表示，两国正在进行毛泽东在中国内战期间所说的“谈打仗、打打谈”。</p>   <p>"That is, to talk while building up forces," Chong said.翻译:“就是一边说话一边积蓄力量，”冲说。</p>   <p>Biden is expected to press Xi to use his influence to urge Iran to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/irans-axis-resistance-against-israel-faces-trial-by-fire-2023-11-15/">avoid action</a> that could spread the Israel-Hamas conflict across the Middle East.翻译:预计拜登将敦促习近平利用自己的影响力敦促伊朗避免采取可能将以色列与哈马斯冲突蔓延到整个中东地区的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/irans-axis-resistance-against-israel-faces-trial-by-fire-2023-11-15/">行动</a>。</p>   <p>He is also expected to raise alleged Chinese operations to influence foreign elections and human rights, including U.S. citizens Washington believes are wrongly detained in China.翻译:预计他还将提出涉嫌中国影响外国选举和人权的行动，其中包括华盛顿认为在中国被错误拘留的美国公民。</p>   <p>U.S. officials expect concrete steps to restore staff-level conversations between the countries on issues from military-to-military communications, to reducing the flow of fentanyl, managing artificial intelligence, and on trade and climate.翻译:美国官员预计将采取具体措施，恢复两国之间的参谋级对话，讨论的问题包括军方间的沟通、减少芬太尼的流动、管理人工智能以及贸易和气候等问题。</p>   <p>Many of the chemicals used to make fentanyl, a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">scourge</a> in the U.S., come from China, U.S. officials say.</p>    <h 1="">RENEWABLE ENERGY TARGET</h>  <p>Before the meeting, both countries <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/us-china-pledge-cooperation-climate-following-california-talks-2023-11-15/">backed a new renewable energy target</a> and said they would work to reduce methane and plastic pollution, renewing climate cooperation suspended after former U.S. Speaker of the House <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-premier-evil-neighbour-next-door-is-showing-off-her-power-our-door-2022-08-05/">Nancy Pelosi visited Taiwan</a> in 2022.翻译:会前，两国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/us-china-pledge-cooperation-climate-following-california-talks-2023-11-15/">支持新的可再生能源目标</a>，并表示将努力减少甲烷和塑料污染，延续美国前众议院议长<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-premier-evil-neighbour-next-door-is-showing-off-her-power-our-door-2022-08-05/">南希·佩洛西 2022 年访问台湾</a>后暂停的气候合作。</p>   <p>However, on Wednesday, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-objects-us-proposal-apec-trade-investment-policies-source-2023-11-15/">China objected</a> to a U.S. proposal for APEC members to incorporate sustainability and inclusivity into trade and investment policies, a source briefed on the negotiations said.翻译:然而，一位了解谈判情况的消息人士称，周三， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-objects-us-proposal-apec-trade-investment-policies-source-2023-11-15/">中国反对</a>美国提出的亚太经合组织成员将可持续性和包容性纳入贸易和投资政策的提议。</p>   <p>Biden, 80, presides over an economy that has outperformed expectations and most rich nations after the COVID-19 pandemic. He is seeking a second term in office.翻译:80 岁的拜登领导的经济在 COVID-19 大流行后的表现超出了预期，也超出了大多数富裕国家的表现。他正在寻求连任。</p>   <p>He has corralled the nation's traditional allies from Europe to Asia to confront Russia in Ukraine and stand up to China, although some have differences over the Israel-Hamas conflict.翻译:他召集了该国从欧洲到亚洲的传统盟友，在乌克兰与俄罗斯对抗，并与中国对抗，尽管其中一些盟友在以色列与哈马斯冲突问题上存在分歧。</p>   <p>Xi, a decade Biden's junior, has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/ways-chinas-xi-jinping-amassed-power-over-decade-2022-10-10/">tightened control</a> over policy, state leaders, the media and military and changing the constitution. Recently, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">economic challenges</a> have thrown the country off its three-decade growth trajectory.翻译:比拜登小十岁的习近平<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/ways-chinas-xi-jinping-amassed-power-over-decade-2022-10-10/">加强了对政策、国家领导人、媒体和军队的控制</a>，并修改了宪法。最近， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">经济挑战</a>使该国脱离了三年的增长轨迹。</p>   <p>Analysts say Xi's position may be tempered by concern about the November 2024 U.S. presidential election and the potential for a less friendly U.S. president in Donald Trump.翻译:分析人士表示，习近平的立场可能会因为对 2024 年 11 月美国总统大选的担忧以及唐纳德·特朗普可能出现一位不太友好的美国总统而受到影响。</p>   <p>"Beijing stands to gain more from collaborating with, rather than boycotting, the Biden administration during its remaining tenure," said Tong Zhao of the Carnegie China think tank.翻译:卡内基中国智库的赵童表示：“在拜登政府剩余任期内，北京将通过与拜登政府合作而不是抵制拜登政府而获得更多利益。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Trevor Hunnicutt; Additional reporting by Steve Holland, Michael Martina, Martin Pollard, Jeff Mason, David Lawder and David Brunnstrom; Editing by Heather Timmons, Angus MacSwan, Don Durfee and Josie Kao翻译:特雷弗·亨尼卡特报道； Steve Holland、Michael Martina、Martin Pollard、Jeff Mason、David Lawder 和 David Brunnstrom 的补充报道；编辑：Heather Timmons、Angus MacSwan、Don Durfee 和 Josie Kao</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 22:51:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZYRPUF6GFRLTHLGM6Y6UA65MXU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Trevor Hunnicutt, David Brunnstrom]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA (UPDATE 6, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[习近平与乔·拜登会面当天，亚太经合组织抗议者提前出现]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ioXuZqhxYGYc2GOYADPy544yDoM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/Z4LLU5H5DNLMFDHBKUZJ5S46HA.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>California Highway Patrol officers stand guard, as people protest against Chinese President Xi Jinping on the day of Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经济合作组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会当天，加州公路巡警在人们抗议中国国家主席习近平时站岗。 REUTERS/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/F_tW6fZ96mf3HNkf0uVnvf9ye2U=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7OYSA5RH3FOYPICFAF4HDGQ4YA.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People protest against Chinese President Xi Jinping on the day of Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行亚太经合组织 (APEC) 工商领导人峰会，人们抗议中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/qmhC-Xn20p4QuviULa_0PYiYrIo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JORQORFKYVJ5RBXI6HSC7PZCUA.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People protest against Chinese President Xi Jinping on the day of Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行亚太经合组织 (APEC) 工商领导人峰会，人们抗议中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/mHzw_v1AemJoPfV5IzGGk_F8yI0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/EA2DFZKAJ5NW7FGUCLYMYGR7QI.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Protesters taunt people in suit, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会集会上，抗议者嘲笑着西装革履的人。 REUTERS/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/z_I3LF5Q1LNzOdklTyr6xuQ5wgs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3S4NBLOQOBPZ3OXOGNPCWH4CXE.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Supporters of Chinese President Xi Jinping wave a flag at people protesting against Chinese President Xi Jinping on the day of Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 工商领导人峰会当天，中国国家主席习近平的支持者向抗议中国国家主席习近平的人们挥舞旗帜。 REUTERS/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UMFDwww_h47JGqvWkeFsnZ0rKXs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TJQXEP2ANVJMXD47UT2A2VOM4M.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Protesters scuffle with police, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，美国加利福尼亚州旧金山，抗议者在反对亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会的集会上与警察发生扭打。 REUTERS/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TSIg-P9NS4Ne-gHbR_bIxWnkapM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZFDYBYLUE5PSZDJXXFR7OL545Y.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Protesters demonstrate on the ground, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，抗议者在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的反对亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会的集会上进行示威。路透社/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/FbCF-nFb9S5t9yAyO4QUZLIXcKE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TZPHLS7UGRM7RKWTRGW23AQOGQ.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A protester confronts with a person, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，美国加利福尼亚州旧金山，在反对亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会的集会上，一名抗议者与一人对峙。路透社/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/yC244DtSNHKhuneBU8iUTECU2kw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/K5Q3RI6BG5LGHOUNEPPJRQU3DM.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Police get through the line of protesters to reinforce, as protesters block, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的一场反对亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会的集会上，警方冲破抗议者的队伍进行增援。路透社/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>                             <p>Protesters took to the streets of San Francisco on Wednesday <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">as a meeting</a> between U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping took place, obstructing some entrances to the APEC conference and blocking downtown streets.翻译:周三，在美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平举行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">会晤之际</a>，抗议者走上旧金山街头，堵塞了亚太经合组织会议的一些入口，并封锁了市中心的街道。</p>   <p>Global leaders and CEOs of major U.S. corporations will all be at the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation</a> (APEC) forum in San Francisco, offering tempting targets to protest.翻译:全球领导人和美国大公司的首席执行官都将出席在旧金山举行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">的亚太经济合作组织</a>（APEC）论坛，提出诱人的抗议目标。</p>   <p>Opponents of Xi and China marched through downtown around noon. Hundreds moved through the city's center near the San Francisco convention center, chanting "free Tibet" and "free Hong Kong."翻译:中午时分，习近平和中国的反对者在市中心游行。数百人穿过旧金山会议中心附近的市中心，高呼“自由西藏”和“自由香港”。</p>   <p>Headed by a police escort, the peaceful group - which stretched for multiple city blocks - blocked one of the main downtown thoroughfares, as it moved in a slow circle around the convention center's perimeter.翻译:在警察护送的带领下，这群和平的团体绵延多个街区，封锁了市中心的一条主干道，并绕着会议中心周边缓慢移动。</p>   <p>“We can say beyond a reasonable doubt that this will be the largest anti-Xi protest during the bilateral talks hosted here in the United States in the history of Xi Jinping’s time as a dictator of China,” Pema Doma, executive director of Students for a Free Tibet, said early in the day.翻译:“我们可以毫无疑问地说，这将是习近平作为中国独裁者时期历史上在美国举行的双边会谈期间最大规模的反习近平抗议活动，”学生组织执行主任佩玛·多马(Pema Doma)说。当天早些时候就说过“自由西藏”。</p>   <p>A smaller group of Xi supporters gave thumbs-down gestures to protesters downtown, and local television showed crowds welcoming Xi, waving huge Chinese and American flags, as well as posters of the two flags together, along a highway south of San Francisco where the presidents were scheduled to meet. Some protesters also lined that route.翻译:一小群习近平的支持者向市中心的抗议者做出了大拇指朝下的手势，当地电视台显示，在旧金山以南的一条高速公路上，人群挥舞着巨大的中国和美国国旗，以及两国国旗在一起的海报，欢迎习近平。已安排见面。一些抗议者也在这条路线上排队。</p>   <p>People also are using the meeting as a forum for global issues such as the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-public-support-israel-drops-majority-backs-ceasefire-reutersipsos-2023-11-15/">Israel-Hamas war</a> and responding to climate change.翻译:人们还利用这次会议作为讨论<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-public-support-israel-drops-majority-backs-ceasefire-reutersipsos-2023-11-15/">以色列-哈马斯战争</a>和应对气候变化等全球问题的论坛。</p>   <p>Early on Wednesday, about 150 people gathered at an intersection outside a security zone at the city's convention center. The group formed a human chain that prevented conference attendees from walking through the intersection, diverting some commuters and delegates onto nearby streets.翻译:周三早些时候，约 150 人聚集在该市会议中心安全区外的十字路口。该组织形成了一条人链，阻止与会者穿过十字路口，将一些通勤者和代表转移到附近的街道上。</p>   <p>"I'm actually kind of impressed by the fact that there's so few people here and they've actually kind of gummed up the works a little bit," said Gary Hughes from the advocacy group Biofuelwatch.翻译:“事实上，这里的人很少，而且他们实际上有点搞砸了，这一事实给我留下了深刻的印象，”倡导组织生物燃料观察的加里·休斯说。</p>   <p>Protesters held signs that said "War criminals out of SF" and "From Palestine to the Philippines stop the US war machine."翻译:抗议者举着标语，上面写着“战犯滚出旧金山”和“从巴勒斯坦到菲律宾，阻止美国战争机器”。</p>   <p>Police donned protective helmets and formed a line about 50 feet (15 meters) from a speaker and microphone for speeches, but there were no major clashes before the non-Chinese protests ended, around midday.翻译:警察戴上防护头盔，在距离扬声器和麦克风约 50 英尺（15 米）的地方排成一队进行演讲，但在中午左右非华人抗议活动结束之前没有发生重大冲突。</p>   <p>Thousands of police lined streets near the convention center, and protests in the days before Biden and Xi's meeting had been relatively peaceful, with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/apec-san-francisco-protesters-span-gamut-political-issues-2023-11-13/">some crowds stretching for blocks</a>, including a march uniting several interest groups on Sunday.翻译:会议中心附近的街道上排列着数千名警察，拜登和习近平会面前几天的抗议活动相对和平， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/apec-san-francisco-protesters-span-gamut-political-issues-2023-11-13/">一些人群延伸了几个街区</a>，包括周日联合多个利益团体举行的游行。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/san-francisco-patches-over-homelessness-drug-abuse-apec-2023-11-15/">San Francisco has cleaned up downtown streets</a> for the meeting, and it had prepared for potential confrontation with demonstrators: eight-foot-high (2.4-meter-high) metal mesh barriers have been erected to keep people on sidewalks from interfering with vehicle traffic near the convention center.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/san-francisco-patches-over-homelessness-drug-abuse-apec-2023-11-15/">旧金山已经为会议清理了市中心街道</a>，并为可能与示威者发生对抗做好了准备：已经竖起八英尺高（2.4米高）的金属网屏障，以防止人行道上的人们干扰附近的车辆交通会议中心。</p>   <p>The potential for disruptions around the summit site, portions of which were shut to vehicles and foot traffic, led the U.S. Department of Homeland Security to designate the meeting a national special security event, putting the U.S. Secret Service in charge of coordination of policing agencies.翻译:由于峰会地点周围可能出现干扰，其中部分地点禁止车辆和行人通行，美国国土安全部将此次会议指定为国家特别安全活动，并由美国特勤局负责协调警务机构。</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Ann Saphir; Writing By Peter Henderson; Editing by Josie Kao and Jonathan Oatis翻译:Ann Saphir 的补充报道；作者：彼得·亨德森；编辑：Josie Kao 和 Jonathan Oatis</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 22:49:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">V5Z5PTD2ABL6LAMVFZUIDWAYCM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/apec-protesters-turn-out-early-xi-jinping-joe-biden-meeting-day-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Max Cherney, Loren Elliot]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/PROTEST (UPDATE 1, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[欧洲公司敦促中国进一步明确数据传输法]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UH9rid9jkLEt5JsGOJYMoQt30ok=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OOV6PN5M3NOQ3ACUIZ6AADBDYY.jpg" alt="An attendant walks past EU and China flags ahead of the EU-China High-level Economic Dialogue in Beijing翻译:在北京举行的中欧高层经济对话之前，一名与会者走过欧盟和中国国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An attendant walks past EU and China flags ahead of the EU-China High-level Economic Dialogue at Diaoyutai State Guesthouse in Beijing, China June 25, 2018. REUTERS/Jason Lee/File Photo翻译:2018 年 6 月 25 日，在中国北京钓鱼台国宾馆举行的中欧高层经济对话之前，一名与会者走过欧盟和中国国旗。 REUTERS/Jason Lee/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>European firms "urgently" need China to give clearer definitions of key terms in its cross-border data transfer rules, a European business lobby group said on Wednesday, warning firms also stood to waste millions of euros storing non-sensitive data in China.翻译:欧洲商业游说团体周三表示，欧洲企业“迫切”需要中国对其跨境数据传输规则中的关键术语给出更清晰的定义，并警告企业还将浪费数百万欧元在中国存储非敏感数据。</p>   <p>The European Chamber of Commerce in China called on authorities to "provide precise definitions for both 'important data' and 'personal information,'" as outlined in their rules, and also urged that a proposed relaxation of certain aspects of regulations announced in September be finalised as soon as possible.翻译:中国欧盟商会呼吁当局按照其规则中的规定，“为‘重要数据’和‘个人信息’提供准确的定义”，并敦促放宽 9 月份宣布的监管某些方面的提议。尽快敲定。</p>   <p>The world's second-largest economy has in recent years tightened its data laws amid President Xi Jinping's increased focus on national security, and foreign firms fear their lack of clarity could trip them up.翻译:近年来，在习近平主席日益关注国家安全的背景下，全球第二大经济体收紧了数据法，外国公司担心数据法的不明确可能会给他们带来麻烦。</p>   <p>"Ever since the Cybersecurity Law was introduced in 2017, we have gone without a clear definition of 'Important Data.' That's six years," Stefan Bernhart, a chamber vice president, said at the launch of a report based on a member survey on the impact of China's data regulations.翻译:“自2017年《网络安全法》出台以来，我们对‘重要数据’一直没有明确的定义。那是六年，”商会副会长斯特凡·伯恩哈特(Stefan Bernhart)在一份基于对中国数据法规影响的会员调查的报告发布时表示。</p>   <p>BASF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BASFn.DE" target="_blank">(BASFn.DE)</a>, Maersk <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MAERSKb.CO" target="_blank">(MAERSKb.CO)</a>, Siemens <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SIEGn.DE" target="_blank">(SIEGn.DE)</a>, and Volkswagen <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VOWG_p.DE" target="_blank">(VOWG_p.DE)</a> are among the members of the chamber.翻译:巴斯夫<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BASFn.DE" target="_blank">(BASFn.DE)</a> 、马士基<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MAERSKb.CO" target="_blank">(MAERSKb.CO)</a> 、西门子<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SIEGn.DE" target="_blank">(SIEGn.DE)</a>和大众汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VOWG_p.DE" target="_blank">(VOWG_p.DE)</a>都是该商会的成员。</p>   <p>"Many of the laws, guidelines and measures lack specificity, which poses serious operational and compliance challenges to European companies operating in China," the report read, adding requirements like "regulatory security assessment thresholds" were too low, "especially for larger multinational companies."翻译:报告称，“许多法律、指导方针和措施缺乏针对性，这给在华经营的欧洲公司带来了严重的运营和合规挑战”，并补充说，“监管安全评估门槛”等要求太低，“特别是对于大型跨国公司” ”。</p>   <p>Jitters among foreign investors in China have risen over the past year due to a series of corporate raids, predominantly on consultancies and due diligence firms.翻译:过去一年，由于一系列企业搜查行动（主要针对咨询公司和尽职调查公司），中国外国投资者的不安情绪有所加剧。</p>   <p>"Questions about whether or not I am on the right side of the law can be a huge, huge challenge," Bernhart said, adding that it could make smaller firms in particular reconsider investing in China.翻译:伯恩哈特表示：“关于我是否站在法律正确一边的问题可能是一个巨大的挑战。”他补充说，这可能会让规模较小的公司重新考虑在中国的投资。</p>   <p>The chamber's report echoes recent comments from a European Commission official, who said in September that European businesses were <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/eu-says-lack-clarity-chinas-data-laws-is-concerning-2023-09-19/">especially concerned</a> about a lack of clarity in China's data laws.翻译:该商会的报告呼应了欧盟委员会一位官员最近的评论，该官员在 9 月份表示，欧洲企业<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/eu-says-lack-clarity-chinas-data-laws-is-concerning-2023-09-19/">尤其担心</a>中国数据法的不明确性。</p>   <p>China in the same month also said it was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-waive-security-checks-some-data-exports-2023-09-28/">considering waiving</a> data export security assessments for activities such as international trade, academic cooperation, cross-border manufacturing and marketing that do not contain personal information or important data, a move that was welcomed by foreign business chambers and lawyers.翻译:同月，中国还表示<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-waive-security-checks-some-data-exports-2023-09-28/">考虑对国际贸易、学术合作、跨境制造和营销等不包含个人信息或重要数据的活动免除</a>数据出境安全评估，此举受到外国商会的欢迎和律师。</p>   <p>"The release of the draft ... was seen as a signal from the Chinese Government that it is listening to businesses' concerns and is ready to take steps to address them. Companies are waiting eagerly for these positive signals to be translated into action," the chamber said, adding that its members anticipated the draft revisions would be finalised by the end of November.翻译:“草案的发布……被视为中国政府发出的信号，表明它正在倾听企业的担忧，并准备采取措施解决这些问题。企业正在热切地等待这些积极信号转化为行动， ”该商会表示，并补充说，其成员预计修订草案将在 11 月底完成。</p>   <p>The most common type of data European firms transfer abroad is employee's personal information followed by suppliers' and customers' personal information, the survey showed, 96% of which is sent to companies' headquarters and other regional offices.翻译:调查显示，欧洲公司向国外传输的最常见数据类型是员工的个人信息，其次是供应商和客户的个人信息，其中 96% 被发送到公司总部和其他地区办事处。</p>   <p>A third of companies indicated it would cost them "several million euros" to store their data in China if they failed the cross-border transfer security assessment now required by CAC. More than 10 percent of firms said it would cost them "hundreds of millions of euros."翻译:三分之一的公司表示，如果未能通过 CAC 目前要求的跨境传输安全评估，他们将花费“数百万欧元”将数据存储在中国。超过 10% 的公司表示，这将花费他们“数亿欧元”。</p>   <p>Only 6% of respondents indicated that they transferred 'important data' overseas, the chamber said.翻译:该商会表示，只有 6% 的受访者表示他们将“重要数据”转移到海外。</p>   <p>($1 = 0.9322 euros)翻译:（1 美元 = 0.9322 欧元）</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Brenda Goh; Editing by Kim Coghill翻译:Brenda Goh 的补充报道；编辑：金·科吉尔</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 21:55:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RUZWXP2WQVIZVPMCOEHUIXW4LY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/european-firms-urge-china-give-more-clarity-data-transfer-laws-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Joe Cash]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/DATA</category>
                
                <category>SECURITY</category>
                
                <category>EUROPE (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早盘出价：盘整，处于鸽派拐点]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/RSchSP1fRGGb9GXdNBcmijBcrTc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZM2C2CYXWJMGXODF32YXPBSJ74.jpg" alt="An investor looks at an electronic board showing stock information at a brokerage house in Shanghai翻译:一位投资者在上海一家券商内查看显示股票信息的电子板" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An investor looks at an electronic board showing stock information at a brokerage house in Shanghai翻译:一位投资者在上海一家券商内查看显示股票信息的电子板, China July 6, 2018. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2018 年 7 月 6 日，中国上海一家券商，一位投资者正在查看显示股票信息的电子板。REUTERS/Aly Song/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A look at the day ahead in Asian markets from Jamie McGeever, financial markets columnist.翻译:金融市场专栏作家杰米·麦克吉弗 (Jamie McGeever) 对亚洲市场未来一天的展望。</p>   <p>A bout of consolidation across Asian markets on Thursday is likely after the previous day's stellar gains, as investors adjust to what appears to be a decisive moment in the global interest rate and inflation cycle.翻译:在前一天的大幅上涨之后，周四亚洲市场可能会出现一轮盘整，因为投资者正在适应全球利率和通胀周期的决定性时刻。</p>   <p>There is a growing consensus forming that major central banks' interest rate-raising cycle is over, a conviction strengthened by a series of inflation reports and other indicators from major economies.翻译:人们日益形成共识，认为主要央行的加息周期已经结束，主要经济体的一系列通胀报告和其他指标强化了这一信念。</p>   <p>Figures on Wednesday showed that <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-retail-sales-fall-slightly-october-2023-11-15/">U.S. producer prices</a> fell at their fastest pace since April 2020, and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/uk-inflation-rate-falls-lower-than-expected-46-october-2023-11-15/">UK consumer inflation</a> undershot all forecasts. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/oil-gains-middle-east-tensions-stock-data-focus-2023-11-15/">Oil</a> prices fell again on Wednesday, and are now down more than 10% year-on-year.翻译:周三的数据显示，<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-retail-sales-fall-slightly-october-2023-11-15/">美国生产者价格</a>指数以 2020 年 4 月以来的最快速度下跌， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/uk-inflation-rate-falls-lower-than-expected-46-october-2023-11-15/">英国消费者通胀</a>低于所有预测。周三<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/oil-gains-middle-east-tensions-stock-data-focus-2023-11-15/">油价</a>再次下跌，目前同比跌幅超过10%。</p>   <p>Investors are increasingly pricing in more rate cuts next year, bond yields and the dollar are coming under downward pressure, and stocks and risk assets are buoyant. All in, financial conditions in most countries are loosening.翻译:投资者越来越多地预计明年将进一步降息，债券收益率和美元面临下行压力，而股票和风险资产则表现强劲。总而言之，大多数国家的金融状况正在放松。</p>   <p>Some of that reversed on Wednesday - Treasury yields and the dollar rebounded a bit from the previous day's slump - which may keep a lid on Asian markets on Thursday, even though <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-signal-more-gains-wall-street-eyes-data-biden-xi-meeting-2023-11-15/">Wall Street</a> held onto its gains and closed higher.翻译:其中一些情况在周三发生了逆转——美国国债收益率和美元从前一天的暴跌中小幅反弹——这可能会限制周四亚洲市场的表现，尽管<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-signal-more-gains-wall-street-eyes-data-biden-xi-meeting-2023-11-15/">华尔街</a>守住了涨幅并收高。</p>   <p>Investors could be forgiven for taking a breather on Thursday after such as huge rally on Wednesday that saw the MSCI Asia ex-Japan, MSCI Emerging Market index and Japan's Nikkei 225 all post their biggest gains in a year, of 2.5% or more.翻译:在周三MSCI亚洲（日本除外）、MSCI新兴市场指数和日本日经225指数均录得一年来最大涨幅（2.5%或以上）后，投资者在周四稍事休息也是情有可原的。</p>   <p>But they also have other major economic and corporate news to digest, which will inject an extra dose of caution into the trading session.翻译:但他们还有其他重大经济和企业新闻需要消化，这将为交易时段注入额外的谨慎情绪。</p>   <p>The economic calendar sees the release of Japanese trade data, machinery orders and the closely-watched 'tertiary activity index', as well as Australian unemployment and Chinese house prices.翻译:经济日历将发布日本贸易数据、机械订单和备受关注的“第三产业指数”，以及澳大利亚失业率和中国房价。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/japans-economy-contracts-demand-wanes-2023-11-15/">Japan's GDP</a> figures on Wednesday were much weaker than expected, leading economists at Barclays and elsewhere to cut their 2023 and 2024 growth forecasts.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/japans-economy-contracts-demand-wanes-2023-11-15/">日本周三公布的 GDP</a>数据远弱于预期，导致巴克莱银行和其他机构的经济学家下调了 2023 年和 2024 年的增长预测。</p>   <p>But financial conditions in Japan are the loosest since 1990, according to Goldman Sachs, which is partly why the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/bojs-hawkish-rhetoric-signals-chance-negative-rates-may-end-soon-2023-11-15/">Bank of Japan</a> has stepped up its hawkish rhetoric and may end its negative interest rate policy early next year.翻译:但据高盛称，日本的金融状况是自 1990 年以来最宽松的，这也是<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/bojs-hawkish-rhetoric-signals-chance-negative-rates-may-end-soon-2023-11-15/">日本央行</a>加强鹰派言论并可能于明年初结束负利率政策的部分原因。</p>   <p>Laying that ground at a time when the economy is shrinking, however, is not ideal.翻译:然而，在经济萎缩之际奠定基础并不理想。</p>   <p>China's house price data will be closely watched for signs that the property sector is beginning to stabilize. There are signs of stabilization elsewhere in Chinese markets - the yuan is its strongest in three months against the dollar, and foreigners are increasing their holdings of China's onshore yuan bonds.翻译:人们将密切关注中国的房价数据，寻找房地产行业开始企稳的迹象。中国市场其他地方也出现了企稳的迹象——人民币兑美元汇率创三个月来最高水平，外国人正在增持中国在岸人民币债券。</p>   <p>On the policy front, the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/philippine-cbank-likely-hold-rates-65-thurs-may-hike-again-dec-2023-11-14/">Philippine central bank</a> is expected to keep its key interest rate unchanged at 6.50% on Thursday, although there's an outside chance it might hike to 6.75%.翻译:政策方面，预计<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/philippine-cbank-likely-hold-rates-65-thurs-may-hike-again-dec-2023-11-14/">菲律宾央行</a>周四将维持关键利率在 6.50% 不变，但外部可能性有可能升至 6.75%。</p>   <p>On the corporate front, China's Alibaba and Lenovo release their latest earnings reports.翻译:企业方面，中国的阿里巴巴和联想发布了最新的财报。</p>   <p>Here are key developments that could provide more direction to markets on Thursday:翻译:以下是周四可能为市场提供更多方向的关键进展：</p>   <p>- Japan trade (October)翻译:- 日本贸易（十月）</p>   <p>- China house prices (October)翻译:- 中国房价（10月）</p>   <p>- Philippines interest rate decision翻译:- 菲律宾利率决定</p>    <span>By Jamie McGeever;翻译:作者：杰米·麦克吉弗；</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 21:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">GNGNTBFREFJP7CKMO37IHU6OXU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/global-markets-view-asia-graphics-pix-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jamie McGeever]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>ASIA (GRAPHICS, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国反对美国提出的亚太经合组织贸易和投资政策提案——消息来源]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Nbtv42O59Qi_sPwyiwKH2llQlxE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6ZP2QU2TIFNV3CPJ3JD4JVXRPI.jpg" alt="APEC summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Trade Representative Ambassador Katherine Tai speaks during an APEC Ministerial Meeting (AMM) Opening Session in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small翻译:美国贸易代表大使戴凯瑟琳于 2023 年 11 月 15 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织部长级会议 (AMM) 开幕式上发表讲话。 REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/aT13ys4kLYZPJd6mmW-pR6MWjQ4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/H3H5626AX5LVNKQH6NFFPVWDKU.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping attend a bilateral meeting at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经济合作组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平出席在菲洛丽庄园举行的双边会议。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>               <p>China is objecting to a U.S. proposal for Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation members to incorporate sustainability and inclusivity into their trade and investment policies, a source briefed on the negotiations said on Wednesday.翻译:一位了解谈判情况的消息人士周三表示，中国反对美国提出的亚太经合组织成员国将可持续性和包容性纳入其贸易和投资政策的提议。</p>   <p>Talks on the issue were continuing at the APEC summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行 to try to find language that the group's 21 member states could agree on, the source said.</p>   <p>U.S. Trade Representative Katherine Tai told a trade-focused plenary meeting she hoped the proposal, dubbed by the Biden administration as the "San Francisco Principles for Integrating Inclusivity and Sustainability into Trade and Investment Policy" could be still be finalized.翻译:美国贸易代表凯瑟琳·戴在一次以贸易为重点的全体会议上表示，她希望这项被拜登政府称为“将包容性和可持续性纳入贸易和投资政策的旧金山原则”的提案仍能最终确定。</p>   <p>Tai said the U.S.-led effort was "supported by all economies but one and, as such, it is unclear if APEC will fulfill that mandate. Nonetheless, I remain optimistic that economies will finalize the San Francisco Principles soon."翻译:戴表示，美国主导的努力“得到了除一个经济体之外的所有经济体的支持，因此，目前尚不清楚亚太经合组织是否会履行这一使命。尽管如此，我仍然乐观地认为各经济体将很快敲定《旧金山原则》。”</p>   <p>Few details of the U.S. proposal were available, but the Biden administration is promoting the idea that APEC economies increase opportunities for more people, particularly disadvantaged populations, and to incorporate clean energy and carbon emissions reductions goals into their development, growth and trade policies.翻译:美国提案的细节很少，但拜登政府正在宣扬这样的想法：APEC经济体为更多人，特别是弱势群体增加机会，并将清洁能源和碳减排目标纳入其发展、增长和贸易政策。</p>   <p>Tai is separately seeking to negotiate a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/eu-seeks-ease-us-tariff-green-subsidy-threats-2023-10-16/">green steel arrangement</a> with the European Union that aims to disadvantage Chinese steelmakers on the basis of their higher carbon emissions.翻译:戴秉国正在单独寻求与欧盟谈判一项<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/eu-seeks-ease-us-tariff-green-subsidy-threats-2023-10-16/">绿色钢铁安排</a>，旨在使中国钢铁制造商因碳排放量较高而处于不利地位。</p>   <p>News of China's objections at the APEC summit come as U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">met south of San Francisco</a> for high-stakes talks that <a href="https://www.reuters.com/podcasts/biden-meet-xi-san-francisco-2023-11-12/?%24web_only=true&amp;_branch_match_id=1161293349163474432&amp;utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_medium=marketing&amp;_branch_referrer=H4sIAAAAAAAAA8soKSkottLXz8nMy9YrSi0tSS0q1kvOz9VP1Q9wSwzOLi7O8XZNAgBzJOFkJgAAAA%3D%3D">may ease friction</a> between the superpowers over military conflicts, drug trafficking and artificial intelligence.翻译:中国反对亚太经合组织峰会的消息传出之际，美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">在旧金山以南举行</a>高风险会谈，会谈<a href="https://www.reuters.com/podcasts/biden-meet-xi-san-francisco-2023-11-12/?%24web_only=true&amp;_branch_match_id=1161293349163474432&amp;utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_medium=marketing&amp;_branch_referrer=H4sIAAAAAAAAA8soKSkottLXz8nMy9YrSi0tSS0q1kvOz9VP1Q9wSwzOLi7O8XZNAgBzJOFkJgAAAA%3D%3D">可能会缓解超级大国之间在军事冲突、贩毒和人工智能方面的摩擦</a>。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Lawder; editing by Jonathan Oatis翻译:大卫·劳德报道；乔纳森·奥蒂斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 20:43:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">IKKK7IPQ65MQHAG55ARUJB4XJY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-objects-us-proposal-apec-trade-investment-policies-source-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Lawder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/TRADE</category>
                
                <category>CHINA (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国议员就乔恩·斯图尔特 (Jon Stewart) 的中国内容质疑苹果]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ihlwvgzsGnBRqDzxZ30h6kE-pl0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3MDUJ3B26FNB5MS7MYOFDRNI5Q.jpg" alt="People arrive on the red carpet before comedian and talk show host Jon Stewart receives the Mark Twain Prize For American Humor at The Kennedy Center翻译:人们在喜剧演员兼脱口秀主持人乔恩·斯图尔特在肯尼迪中心接受马克·吐温美国幽默奖之前走上红地毯" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Comedian and talk show host Jon Stewart arrives on the red carpet before receiving the Mark Twain Prize For American Humor, at The Kennedy Center in Washington, U.S.,&nbsp;April 24 2022. &nbsp;REUTERS/Cheriss May/File Photo翻译:喜剧演员兼脱口秀主持人乔恩·斯图尔特于 2022 年 4 月 24 日在美国华盛顿肯尼迪中心登上红地毯，然后接受马克·吐温美国幽默奖。路透社/Cheriss May/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S. lawmakers asked Apple Inc to explain the abrupt end of political comedian Jon Stewart's television show on its streaming service, according to a letter made public on Wednesday, citing concerns that content related to China was behind the cancellation.翻译:根据周三公开的一封信，美国立法者要求苹果公司解释政治喜剧演员乔恩·斯图尔特在其流媒体服务上的电视节目突然结束的原因，理由是担心取消节目背后涉及与中国有关的内容。</p>   <p>The New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/19/business/media/jon-stewart-the-problem-ends.html" target="_blank">reported last month</a> that Stewart's show on Apple's streaming service was ending, the result of creative differences. The newspaper said Stewart told members of his staff that potential show topics related to China and artificial intelligence were causing concern to Apple executives.翻译:《纽约时报》 <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/19/business/media/jon-stewart-the-problem-ends.html" target="_blank">上个月报道</a>称，由于创意分歧，斯图尔特在苹果流媒体服务上的节目即将结束。该报称，斯图尔特告诉他的员工，与中国和人工智能相关的潜在展会主题引起了苹果高管的担忧。</p>   <p>Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a> declined comment to the Times.翻译:苹果公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a>拒绝向《纽约时报》发表评论。</p>   <p>"While companies have the right to determine what content is appropriate for their streaming service, the coercive tactics of a foreign power should not be directly or indirectly influencing these determinations," the Republican and Democratic leaders of the House of Representatives' Select Committee on Competition with the Chinese Communist Party said in the letter to Apple Chief Executive Tim Cook.翻译:众议院竞争特别委员会的共和党和民主党领导人表示：“虽然公司有权决定哪些内容适合其流媒体服务，但外国势力的胁迫策略不应直接或间接影响这些决定。”与中国共产党在给苹果首席执行官蒂姆·库克的信中说。</p>   <p>The letter asked representatives of Apple for a briefing on its concerns by Dec. 15, 2023. It said the committee also expected to speak with representatives of Stewart.翻译:这封信要求苹果代表在 2023 年 12 月 15 日之前就其担忧进行简报。信中称，委员会还希望与斯图尔特的代表进行交谈。</p>   <p>"To reassure the creative community in light of these reports, we also respectfully request that Apple publicly commit that content that could be perceived as critical of the CCP or the PRC is welcome on Apple TV+ and other Apple services," said the letter, signed by the panel's Republican chairperson, Representative Michael Gallagher, and Representative Raja Krishnamoorthi, the panel's ranking Democrat.翻译:信中写道：“为了根据这些报告让创意界放心，我们还诚挚地要求苹果公司公开承诺，Apple TV+ 和其他苹果服务上欢迎可能被视为批评中共或中华人民共和国的内容。”由该小组的共和党主席、众议员迈克尔·加拉格尔（Michael Gallagher）和该小组的民主党众议员拉贾·克里希纳莫蒂（Raja Krishnamoorthi）组成。</p>   <p>Representatives for Stewart and Apple did not respond to Reuters' requests for comment.翻译:斯图尔特和苹果的代表没有回应路透社的置评请求。</p>   <p>The letter was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/tricky-politics-menu-chinas-xi-us-business-dinner-2023-11-14/">released ahead of a dinner</a> expected on Wednesday night at which top U.S. business leaders were to dine with Chinese President Xi Jinping in San Francisco as he seeks to court American companies and counter his country's recent struggles to entice foreign investment.翻译:这封信是在周三晚上举行的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/tricky-politics-menu-chinas-xi-us-business-dinner-2023-11-14/">晚宴之前发布的</a>，届时美国高层商界领袖将在旧金山与中国国家主席习近平共进晚餐，习近平寻求讨好美国公司，并应对中国最近在吸引外国投资方面的困难。</p>   <p>The dinner on the margins of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum would follow a day of talks between Xi and U.S. President Joe Biden, aimed at stabilizing fraught ties between the world's two largest economies.翻译:在亚太经合组织（APEC）论坛间隙举行的晚宴之前，习近平和美国总统乔·拜登进行了一天的会谈，旨在稳定世界最大两个经济体之间紧张的关系。</p>   <p>The House committee has made China's controls on media a focus of its work.翻译:众议院委员会已将中国对媒体的控制作为其工作重点。</p>   <p>U.S. lawmakers have long expressed concerns about potential Chinese government censorship given the ruling Communist Party’s strict media controls. The concern is particularly acute for Hollywood films, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/china-film/">as some studios have altered</a> or self-censored scripts to appease Chinese government minders and gain access to the country’s market.翻译:鉴于执政的共产党对媒体的严格控制，美国立法者长期以来一直对中国政府可能进行的审查表示担忧。对于好莱坞电影来说，这种担忧尤其严重，<a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/china-film/">因为一些电影公司已经改变</a>或自我审查剧本，以安抚中国政府监管人员并进入该国市场。</p>    <span>Reporting by Patricia Zengerle and Michael Martina; Additional reporting by Stephen Nellis and Dawn Chmielewski; Editing by Stephen Coates翻译:帕特里夏·曾格尔 (Patricia Zengerle) 和迈克尔·马丁纳 (Michael Martina) 报道； Stephen Nellis 和 Dawn Chmielewski 的补充报道；斯蒂芬·科茨编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 19:25:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6KO56ZNXIFLGJPAQSQP23VJLFM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/media-telecom/us-lawmakers-question-apple-over-jon-stewarts-china-content-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Patricia Zengerle, Michael Martina]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CONGRESS</category>
                
                <category>APPLE (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[意大利打击从中国走私芬太尼至美国逮捕六人]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/q17ApiU0bqq2v3yh5BrAc_xeQ4M=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DQ57AQMHKVMXTBZWJYS4QT6WGM.jpg" alt="Italy arrests six in crackdown on fentanyl smuggling from China to U.S翻译:意大利打击从中国走私芬太尼至美国逮捕六人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An undated handout picture released by Guardia di Finanza shows banknotes that were seized as a part of an operation against fentanyl trafficking from China to U.S., in Piacenza, Italy. Guardia di Finanza Press Office/Handout via REUTERS 翻译:金融卫报发布的一张未注明日期的讲义图片显示，意大利皮亚琴察在打击从中国向美国贩运芬太尼的行动中查获的钞票。 Guardia di Finanza 新闻办公室/路透社讲义</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/3hXmboWQLjwkfzJtjCmE7ixe-hM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CFCW4ALHFJMSXPUISTX34FUEHI.jpg" alt="Italy arrests six in crackdown on fentanyl smuggling from China to U.S翻译:意大利打击从中国走私芬太尼至美国逮捕六人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An undated handout picture released by Guardia di Finanza shows tools that were seized as a part of an operation against fentanyl trafficking from China to U.S., in Piacenza, Italy. Guardia di Finanza Press Office/Handout via REUTERS 翻译:Guardia di Finanza 发布的一张未注明日期的讲义图片显示，在意大利皮亚琴察打击从中国向美国贩运芬太尼的行动中查获的工具。 Guardia di Finanza 新闻办公室/路透社的讲义</figcaption></figure>               <p>Italian police have arrested six people in a crackdown on a network that allegedly played go-between for fentanyl trafficking from China to the United States, Guardia di Finanza police and prosecutors in the northern city of Piacenza said on Wednesday.翻译:北部城市皮亚琴察的金融警卫队警方和检察官周三表示，意大利警方在打击一个涉嫌从中国向美国贩运芬太尼的网络中逮捕了六人。</p>   <p>"It was really good work, achieved through direct cooperation with investigators from the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA)," Piacenza chief prosecutor Grazia Pradella told Reuters, adding that U.S police arrested 11 other people and seized 2 kg of the synthetic drug.翻译:皮亚琴察首席检察官格拉齐亚·普拉德拉 (Grazia Pradella) 告诉路透社：“这确实是一项出色的工作，是通过与美国缉毒局 (DEA) 调查人员的直接合作完成的。”他补充说，美国警方逮捕了另外 11 人，并缴获了 2 公斤合成毒品。</p>   <p>Washington is hoping to secure more cooperation from Beijing in combating production of the potent synthetic opioid fentanyl, a scourge in the United States, when President Joe Biden meets <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">Chinese President Xi Jinping</a> on Wednesday.翻译:当乔·拜登总统周三会见<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">中国国家主席习近平</a>时，华盛顿希望获得北京方面的更多合作，打击强效合成阿片类药物芬太尼的生产，芬太尼在美国是一个祸害。</p>   <p>The rate of drug overdose deaths involving fentanyl more than tripled from 2016 through 2021 in the U.S, according to the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).翻译:根据美国疾病控制与预防中心 (CDC) 的数据，从 2016 年到 2021 年，美国涉及芬太尼的药物过量死亡率增加了两倍多。</p>   <p>Among those arrested in Italy is the alleged head of the network, a 51-year-old Italian man suspected of buying fentanyl from China over the past three years. He sold it on to buyers in the United States, and in one case in Mexico, the chief prosecutor said.翻译:在意大利被捕的人中有一名被指控为该网络负责人的人，他是一名 51 岁的意大利男子，涉嫌在过去三年从中国购买芬太尼。首席检察官表示，他将其卖给了美国的买家，其中还包括墨西哥的买家。</p>   <p>The investigation began in April after a report sent by the DEA liaison officer at the U.S. embassy in Rome, Guardia di Finanza police said in a statement, adding the fentanyl arrived in Piacenza inside packages sent from China and labelled as containing electronics or books.翻译:Guardia di Finanza警方在一份声明中表示，美国驻罗马大使馆缉毒局联络官发出报告后，调查于四月开始，并补充说，芬太尼装在从中国寄出的包裹中抵达皮亚琴察，并贴有电子产品或书籍的标签。</p>   <p>Police said they were able to trace 100,000 packaged doses and that related economic transactions amounting to more than 250,000 euros ($275,000) took place through untraceable payment instruments using cryptocurrency.翻译:警方表示，他们能够追踪到 100,000 个包装剂量，并且通过使用加密货币的无法追踪的支付工具进行了价值超过 250,000 欧元（275,000 美元）的相关经济交易。</p>   <p>The judge in Piacenza had ordered seven arrests but a Ukrainian national is a fugitive and international law enforcement agencies have been alerted to track him down, police said.翻译:警方表示，皮亚琴察的法官已下令逮捕七人，但一名乌克兰国民是逃犯，国际执法机构已接到通知追查他。</p>   <p>Italian police also found that the group had minted near-perfect fake Swiss coins, smuggled them across the border to Switzerland where they laundered them through automated sports betting machines and bitcoin ATMs.翻译:意大利警方还发现，该团伙铸造了近乎完美的假瑞士硬币，并将其偷运至瑞士，并通过自动体育博彩机和比特币 ATM 机进行洗钱。</p>   <p>The conversion of bitcoins back into euros was then entrusted to people in Eastern Europe who would return the "cleaned" sum minus 7% commission to the counterfeiter in Piacenza.翻译:然后，将比特币兑换回欧元的工作委托给东欧的人，他们将“干净”的金额减去 7% 的佣金返还给皮亚琴察的造假者。</p>   <p>Police said they seized 300,000 euros in cash, about 26,000 euros in bitcoin, 70 computer devices and three valuable watches, as well as a property and the equipment for counterfeiting currency.
($1 = 0.9207 euros)翻译:警方称，他们查获了 30 万欧元现金、约 2.6 万欧元比特币、70 台电脑设备和三块贵重手表，以及一处财产和用于伪造货币的设备。 （1 美元 = 0.9207 欧元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Emilio Parodi
Editing by Keith Weir翻译:埃米利奥·帕罗迪 (Emilio Parodi) 报道 基思·威尔 (Keith Weir) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 19:00:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZGCKWXSDZJMMDO2M7QZBA3HYGA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/italy-arrests-six-crackdown-fentanyl-smuggling-china-us-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Emilio Parodi]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ITALY</category>
                
                <category>FENTANYL/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>USA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[在拜登与习近平会面之前，与中国相关的 ETF 吸引了看涨期权押注]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/phtpuAUxstUjXz0AIES4Vnt1wPw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PBUKQQHJBFJV5FEUJSN5OL5XGM.jpg" alt="Traders work on the floor of the NYSE in New York翻译:交易员在纽约证券交易所工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Traders work on the floor at the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) in New York City, U.S., November 15, 2023.  REUTERS/Brendan McDermid/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，交易员在美国纽约市纽约证券交易所 (NYSE) 的交易大厅工作。REUTERS/Brendan McDermid/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S.-listed exchange traded funds focused on China are seeing bullish options activity as investors await U.S. President Joe Biden's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">meeting</a> with Chinese leader Xi Jinping on Wednesday for signs of easing friction between the two superpowers.翻译:随着投资者等待美国总统乔·拜登周三与中国领导人习近平<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">会面</a>，以寻找两个超级大国之间摩擦缓和的迹象，专注于中国的美国上市交易所交易基金看到了看涨的期权活动。</p>   <p>Some of the bullish positions included call options on the Xtrackers Harvest CSI 300 China A-Shares ETF with a $27 strike price - some 6% higher than where the fund trades today - set to expire Friday.翻译:部分看涨头寸包括 Xtrackers Harvest CSI 300 China A-Shares ETF 的看涨期权，执行价为 27 美元，比该基金今天的交易价格高出约 6%，将于周五到期。</p>   <p>The iShares Trust-China Large-Cap ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FXI.P" target="_blank">(FXI.P)</a> also sport multiple lines of at-money and upside calls with sizeable open interest, including almost 100,000 contracts at the 29.85 strike. The ETF was trading at $27.28 on Wednesday.翻译:iShares Trust-China Large-Cap ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FXI.P" target="_blank">(FXI.P)</a>还拥有多条平价和上行看涨期权，持仓量相当大，其中包括近 100,000 份合约，执行价为 29.85。该 ETF 周三交易价格为 27.28 美元。</p>   <p>Other large China-focused ETFs, including the iShares MSCI China ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MCHI.O" target="_blank">(MCHI.O)</a>, KraneShares CSI China Internet ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/KWEB.P" target="_blank">(KWEB.P)</a>, also showed upbeat options activity, according to Trade Alert data.翻译:根据 Trade Alert 数据，其他专注于中国的大型 ETF，包括 iShares MSCI 中国 ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MCHI.O" target="_blank">(MCHI.O)</a> 、KraneShares CSI China Internet ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/KWEB.P" target="_blank">(KWEB.P)</a> ，也显示出乐观的期权活动。</p>   <p>"It certainly seems that there is generally bullish positioning ahead of the meeting," said Steve Sosnick, chief strategist at Interactive Brokers, noting that the positions had been built up over several days. "The open interest in options expiring Friday is heavily skewed to the upside."翻译:盈透证券（Interactive Brokers）首席策略师史蒂夫·索斯尼克（Steve Sosnick）表示：“在会议之前，似乎普遍存在看涨头寸。”他指出，这些头寸是在几天内建立起来的。 “周五到期的期权的未平仓合约严重偏向上行。”</p>   <p>While some of the upside positioning may be tied to a rally in the broader equity market - including a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/goldilocks-hopes-return-wall-st-after-benign-inflation-report-2023-11-14/">Tuesday surge</a> that saw the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/goldilocks-hopes-return-wall-st-after-benign-inflation-report-2023-11-14/">S&amp;P 500 rise 1.9%</a> on bets that the Federal Reserve is done hiking interest rates - investors are also likely speculating on a positive outcome from the meeting between Biden and Xi, Sosnick said.翻译:虽然部分上行定位可能与更广泛的股市反弹有关——包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/goldilocks-hopes-return-wall-st-after-benign-inflation-report-2023-11-14/">周二的飙升</a>， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/goldilocks-hopes-return-wall-st-after-benign-inflation-report-2023-11-14/">标普 500 指数因押注美联储不再加息而上涨 1.9%</a> ——但投资者也可能对利好进行投机。索斯尼克表示，拜登和习近平的会晤成果。</p>   <p>"The bullish positioning in ASHR and FXI is almost certainly the result of pre-meeting enthusiasm since it is highly biased to near-term upside calls and the positioning occurred prior to yesterday's run-up," Sosnick said.翻译:Sosnick 表示：“ASHR 和 FXI 的看涨定位几乎肯定是会议前热情的结果，因为它高度偏向于近期上涨的呼声，并且定位发生在昨天的上涨之前。”</p>   <p>Biden and Xi arrived in San Francisco on Tuesday, where they were set to hold their meeting on the sidelines the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit. The meeting is set for 2 p.m. ET (1900 GMT).翻译:拜登和习近平周二抵达旧金山，原定在亚太经合组织（APEC）峰会期间举行会晤。会议定于美国东部时间下午 2 点（格林尼治标准时间 1900）。</p>      <p>Investors' nascent enthusiasm for Chinese stocks is at odds with how these ETF's have performed this year. The largest China-linked ETFs are down anywhere between 3% to 9% for the year. Meanwhile the S&amp;P 500 is up nearly 18%.翻译:投资者对中国股票的热情与这些 ETF 今年的表现不一致。最大的中国相关 ETF 今年下跌了 3% 至 9%。与此同时，标准普尔 500 指数上涨近 18%。</p>   <p>Fund managers in the November BofA Global Research survey named shorting China equities as the market's second "most crowded" trade.翻译:基金经理在 11 月份美国银行全球研究调查中将做空中国股票列为市场第二“最拥挤”的交易。</p>   <p>Daniel Kirsch, head of options at Piper Sandler, said recent bullish options flows into KWEB may be to do with a combination of enthusiasm ahead of the Biden-Xi meeting as well as results from Chinese e-commerce companies JD.com and Alibaba . On Wednesday, JD.com reported a surge in third-quarter profit, while Alibaba results are expected after the close of trading.翻译:Piper Sandler 期权主管 Daniel Kirsch 表示，最近看涨期权流入 KWEB 可能与拜登与习主席会面前的热情以及中国电子商务公司京东和阿里巴巴的业绩有关。周三，京东公布第三季度利润大幅增长，而阿里巴巴的业绩预计将在收盘后公布。</p>   <p>"People are looking for areas that could be catching up (to the rally in broader markets)," Kirsch said.翻译:基尔希表示：“人们正在寻找可能追赶（追赶更广泛市场反弹）的领域。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Saqib Iqbal Ahmed; Additional reporting by Suzanne McGee; Editing by Ira Iosebashvili and Jonathan Oatis翻译:萨奇布·伊克巴尔·艾哈迈德报道；苏珊·麦吉 (Suzanne McGee) 的补充报道；编辑：Ira Iosebashvili 和 Jonathan Oatis</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 18:28:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">NPASMWJJYNLH5A2UTAHMGDIDTY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/china-linked-etfs-draw-bullish-options-bets-ahead-biden-xi-meet-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Saqib Ahmed]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>STOCKS/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ETFS</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[加州会谈后中美推进气候合作]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UXrIOsXLuqEBGqgp6K0eh3Y4cXw=/1832x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SSSVDHPBXFOYVATNIL6GPT7QVY.jpg" alt="U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry meets with his Chinese counterpart Xie Zhenhua in Beijing翻译:美国总统气候特使约翰·克里在北京会见中国气候变化特使解振华" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry shakes hands with his Chinese counterpart Xie Zhenhua before a meeting in Beijing, China July 17, 2023. REUTERS/Valerie Volcovici/ File Photo翻译:2023 年 7 月 17 日，美国总统气候特使约翰·克里 (John Kerry) 在中国北京举行会议前与中国气候特使解振华握手。 REUTERS/Valerie Volcovici/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The United States and China will back a new global renewables target and work together on methane and plastic pollution, they said in a joint statement on Wednesday after a meeting to find common ground ahead of COP28 talks in Dubai later this month.翻译:本月晚些时候在迪拜举行的第 28 次缔约方会议 (COP28) 之前，美国和中国举行会议寻找共同点，周三在一份联合声明中表示，美国和中国将支持新的全球可再生能源目标，并在甲烷和塑料污染问题上开展合作。</p>   <p>Climate envoys John Kerry and Xie Zhenhua, meeting in Sunnylands, California, from Nov. 4-8, agreed to revive a bilateral climate working group that will discuss areas of cooperation, the joint statement said, though differences remain on issues like phasing out fossil fuels.翻译:联合声明称，气候特使约翰·克里和解振华于 11 月 4 日至 8 日在加利福尼亚州桑尼兰兹举行会议，同意恢复双边气候工作组，讨论合作领域，尽管在逐步淘汰化石燃料等问题上仍存在分歧燃料。</p>   <p>"The Sunnylands statement is a timely effort of aligning the United States and China ahead of COP28," said Li Shuo, incoming director of the China Climate Hub at the Asia Society.翻译:即将上任的亚洲协会中国气候中心主任李硕表示：“《阳光之乡》的声明是在 COP28 之前协调美国和中国的及时努力。”</p>   <p>Li described the relationship between the world's two biggest greenhouse gas emitters as "a precondition for meaningful global progress" and said the Sunnylands agreement would help "stabilise the politics" ahead of the Dubai talks.翻译:李将世界上最大的两个温室气体排放国之间的关系描述为“全球取得有意义进展的先决条件”，并表示《阳光之乡》协议将有助于在迪拜会谈之前“稳定政治”。</p>   <p>The re-launch of the working group marks the normalisation of the climate relationship between the two countries following a hiatus triggered in 2022 by the visit of former House of Representatives speaker Nancy Pelosi to Taiwan, a self-governing island that China claims as its own.翻译:该工作组的重新启动标志着两国气候关系的正常化，该关系因前众议院议长南希·佩洛西 (Nancy Pelosi) 2022 年访问台湾而中断。台湾是一个中国声称拥有主权的岛屿。 。</p>   <p>Partnership between the world's two biggest emitting countries is seen as a crucial element to securing a consensus agreement at COP28.翻译:世界上两个最大排放国之间的伙伴关系被视为在 COP28 上达成共识协议的关键因素。</p>   <p>For the first time, China - the world's biggest emitter of greenhouse gas emissions - will include non-carbon dioxide greenhouse gases like nitrogen oxide in its 2035 national climate plan as well as specific actions to curb methane emissions, major sources of global emissions.翻译:作为全球最大的温室气体排放国，中国首次将氮氧化物等非二氧化碳温室气体纳入其2035年国家气候计划以及遏制全球主要排放源甲烷排放的具体行动。</p>   <p>"This implies that China needs to do a lot more to be in line with ambitious global goals," said Joanna Lewis, a professor at Georgetown University's School of Foreign Service.翻译:乔治城大学外交学院教授乔安娜·刘易斯表示：“这意味着中国需要做更多的事情来实现雄心勃勃的全球目标。”</p>   <p>It also focuses on key areas of cooperation, including abating methane and boosting efficiency and the "circular economy", and exchanging information on policies and technologies to reduce emissions. The two sides also promised to work together to curb forest loss and plastic pollution.</p>    <h 1="">"WORK CUT OUT"</h>  <p>China's efforts to cut its own carbon emissions will be in sharp focus at COP28, with the country still approving new coal-fired power plants in a bid to ensure energy security.翻译:中国削减自身碳排放的努力将成为COP28的焦点，中国仍在批准新的燃煤电厂以确保能源安全。</p>   <p>The United States and China said they support a declaration by G20 leaders to triple global renewable energy capacity by 2030, and also agreed to "accelerate the substitution for coal, oil and gas generation," which would result in "meaningful absolute power sector emission reductions" this decade.翻译:美国和中国表示，他们支持二十国集团领导人的宣言，即到2030年将全球可再生能源发电能力增加两倍，并同意“加速替代煤炭、石油和天然气发电”，这将导致“电力行业绝对排放量大幅减少” “这十年。</p>   <p>That falls short of calling for the phasing out of fossil fuels, a goal that China has described as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-climate-envoy-says-phasing-out-fossil-fuels-unrealistic-2023-09-22/">"unrealistic"</a>. However, a report released earlier this week said that record levels of new <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-emissions-could-go-into-structural-decline-next-year-research-2023-11-14/">renewable installations</a> in China may help "all but guarantee" a decline in China's CO2 emissions next year.翻译:这还不足以呼吁逐步淘汰化石燃料，中国称这一目标<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-climate-envoy-says-phasing-out-fossil-fuels-unrealistic-2023-09-22/">“不切实际”</a> 。然而，本周早些时候发布的一份报告称，中国新增<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-emissions-could-go-into-structural-decline-next-year-research-2023-11-14/">可再生能源装机</a>量创历史新高，可能有助于“几乎保证”中国明年二氧化碳排放量的下降。</p>   <p>Both sides also agreed to include methane in their 2035 climate goals - the first time China has made such a pledge - and committed to advancing "at least five" large-scale cooperation projects in carbon capture, utilisation and storage by the end of the decade.翻译:双方还同意将甲烷纳入2035年气候目标，这是中国首次做出此类承诺，并承诺到本十年末推进“至少5个”碳捕集、利用和封存大型合作项目。</p>   <p>The joint statement said that the United States, China and COP28 host the United Arab Emirates will hold a Methane and Non-CO2 Greenhouse Gases Summit at COP28.翻译:联合声明称，美国、中国和COP28主办国阿联酋将在COP28期间举行甲烷和非二氧化碳温室气体峰会。</p>   <p>Li said COP28 still "has its work cut out", particularly on fossil fuels.翻译:李说，COP28 仍然“有许多工作要做”，特别是在化石燃料方面。</p>   <p>"China also needs to consider what further ambition can be brought to COP," he added. "Stopping the approval of new coal power projects is a good next step."翻译:“中国还需要考虑可以为缔约方大会带来哪些进一步的雄心，”他补充道。 “停止批准新的煤电项目是下一步的好举措。”</p>    <span>Reporting by David Stanway; Editing by Muralikumar Anantharaman, Raju Gopalakrishnan and Nick Macfie翻译:大卫·斯坦威报道；编辑：Muralikumar Anantharaman、Raju Gopalakrishnan 和 Nick Macfie</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 17:13:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MMEHXKCLHBMKREBS5CHXKMMOXI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/us-china-pledge-cooperation-climate-following-california-talks-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Stanway, Valerie Volcovici]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CLIMATE CHANGE</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA (UPDATE 3)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[拜登和习近平：对旧金山会晤有何期待]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UHEC4c6uyZunk1-qtxZN3LKzl_E=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WX4TAZDGPRLJNKFZWMZOEV7DVE.jpg" alt="G20 summit in Bali翻译:G20巴厘岛峰会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of the G20 leaders' summit in Bali, Indonesia, November 14, 2022.  REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque//File Photo翻译:美国总统乔·拜登于 2022 年 11 月 14 日在印度尼西亚巴厘岛举行的 G20 领导人峰会期间会见中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque//档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/McUPwAozX1sxXZ0g2DpxCwoYiDU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NELW4O3BFFO3ZEIJZK2X52VEYM.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A woman holds a Chinese flag while a man holds a placard outside a hotel where the Chinese delegation is staying during the APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:2023 年 11 月 14 日，美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行 APEC 峰会，中国代表团下榻的酒店外，一名女子举着中国国旗，一名男子举着标语牌。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/XX9y9gx2FOh0__Js0ue_Z9COELc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WQIVN6LOWZNE5GEYLOKXFAAB2E.jpg" alt="G20 summit in Bali翻译:G20巴厘岛峰会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of the G20 leaders' summit in Bali, Indonesia, November 14, 2022.  REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque/File Photo翻译:美国总统乔·拜登于 2022 年 11 月 14 日在印度尼西亚巴厘岛举行的 G20 领导人峰会期间会见中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque/档案照片</figcaption></figure>                 <p>U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping will meet on Wednesday before a summit of the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum</a> in San Francisco, seeking to reduce friction in what many see as the world's most dangerous rivalry.翻译:美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平将于周三在旧金山<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">举行的亚太经济合作组织（APEC）论坛</a>峰会之前会面，寻求减少许多人认为世界上最危险的竞争中的摩擦。</p>   <p>The leaders of the world's two largest economies have known each other for over a decade and have shared hours of conversation in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/top-us-china-exchanges-since-biden-took-office-2023-06-12/">six interactions</a> since Biden's January 2021 inauguration. But they have met only <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/ahead-tense-g20-summit-biden-xi-meet-talks-2022-11-14/">once in person</a> since then, and Xi, who <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/">arrived</a> in San Francisco on Tuesday evening, had not visited the United States <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/cnews-us-usa-china-idCAKBN1792KA-OCATP">since 2017</a> when Donald Trump was president.</p>    <h 1="">WHAT ISSUES ARE THEY LIKELY TO DISCUSS?</h>  <p>The White House says the aim of the summit, expected to be held at the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">Filoli Estate</a>, about 30 miles (48 km) south of San Francisco, is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-chinas-xi-will-discuss-communication-competition-apec-summit-2023-11-13/">to boost communication</a> to prevent an intense rivalry from veering into conflict. The meeting is expected to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/">cover global issues</a> from the conflict in the Middle East to Russia's invasion of Ukraine, North Korea's ties with Russia, Taiwan, human rights, artificial intelligence, as well as "fair" trade and economic relations.翻译:白宫表示，峰会预计将在旧金山以南约 30 英里（48 公里）的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">菲洛丽庄园</a>举行，其目的是<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-chinas-xi-will-discuss-communication-competition-apec-summit-2023-11-13/">加强沟通</a>，防止激烈的竞争演变成冲突。会议预计将<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/">涵盖从中东冲突到俄罗斯入侵乌克兰、朝鲜与俄罗斯、台湾、人权、人工智能以及“公平”贸易和经济关系等全球问题</a>。</p>   <p>Biden is expected to tell Xi that the U.S. remains committed to standing with its allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific, in the face of Chinese pressure against democratically governed Taiwan, which China claims as its own, and in the South and East China Seas. He will also express a specific commitment to the security of the Philippines, U.S. officials said.</p>    <h 1="">WHAT DEALS CAN WE EXPECT?</h>  <p>The White House says Washington is looking for specific outcomes and hopes to see progress in reestablishing military-to military ties with China and in combating trade in the potent synthetic opioid drug fentanyl, which has become a scourge in the United States, and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">especially in San Francisco</a>. Any deal on fentanyl would likely mean Washington's having to lift human rights sanctions on China's police forensic institute in return.翻译:白宫表示，华盛顿正在寻求具体成果，并希望在与中国重建军事关系以及打击强效合成阿片类药物芬太尼贸易方面取得进展，芬太尼已成为美国的祸害，尤其<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">是在圣保罗。弗朗西斯科</a>.任何有关芬太尼的协议都可能意味着华盛顿必须取消对中国警察法医研究所的人权制裁作为回报。</p>   <p>Biden said on Tuesday his goal would be to resume normal communications with China, including <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-says-goal-xi-meeting-is-resume-normal-communications-2023-11-14/">military-to-military contacts</a>.翻译:拜登周二表示，他的目标是恢复与中国的正常沟通，包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-says-goal-xi-meeting-is-resume-normal-communications-2023-11-14/">军事接触</a>。</p>   <p>With elections in Taiwan in early 2024, political analysts expect China to seek U.S. assurances that it will do nothing to encourage pro-independence elements, while Xi will also be hoping to persuade Biden to ease up on tariffs and the export controls that aim to keep the most advanced semiconductors from being sent to China. In a separate <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/tricky-politics-menu-chinas-xi-us-business-dinner-2023-11-14/">dinner with business leaders</a>, the Chinese president will be looking to boost flagging investment by U.S. firms in China.翻译:随着 2024 年初台湾大选，政治分析人士预计，中国将寻求美国保证，不会采取任何措施鼓励台独分子，而习近平也希望说服拜登放松关税和出口管制，以保持台湾的独立。最先进的半导体被运往中国。在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/tricky-politics-menu-chinas-xi-us-business-dinner-2023-11-14/">与商界领袖举行的另一场晚宴</a>上，中国国家主席将寻求提振美国公司在中国萎靡不振的投资。</p>   <p>The leaders may highlight plans to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/us-china-plan-increase-commercial-flights-between-countries-us-official-2023-06-28/">increase commercial flights</a> between the two countries, and policy experts said they could move to ease restrictions on journalist visas, which would be to the benefit of both sides.翻译:领导人可能会强调<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/us-china-plan-increase-commercial-flights-between-countries-us-official-2023-06-28/">增加两国之间商业航班</a>的计划，政策专家表示，他们可能会采取措施放松对记者签证的限制，这对双方都有利。</p>   <p>Biden is also expected to urge China to use its <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-chinas-xi-will-discuss-communication-competition-apec-summit-2023-11-13/">influence with Iran</a> to not broaden the conflict in the Middle East.翻译:预计拜登还将敦促中国利用其<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-chinas-xi-will-discuss-communication-competition-apec-summit-2023-11-13/">对伊朗的影响力</a>，不要扩大中东冲突。</p>   <p>But no one is expecting a reset of the relationship or any grand bargain that will dramatically alter how the countries see each other. "We remain in an enduring period of competition and tension," said Richard Fontaine of Washington's Center for a New American Security. "There's not going to be any big breakthroughs, there won't be any real change in substance."</p>    <h 1="">HOW WILL THE MEETING IMPACT MARKETS?</h>  <p>Market participants will keep a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-signal-more-gains-wall-street-eyes-data-biden-xi-meeting-2023-11-15/">keen focus</a> on the talks to gauge sentiment between the two governments.翻译:市场参与者将<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-signal-more-gains-wall-street-eyes-data-biden-xi-meeting-2023-11-15/">密切关注</a>会谈，以衡量两国政府之间的情绪。</p>   <p>The 21 APEC members and the world beyond hope for an easing of U.S.-China tensions, and progress on that score would be viewed positively, but political analysts said any improvement in the mood could be only temporary. Elections in Taiwan early next year and the November 2024 U.S. presidential vote that could bring a return of Trump to the White House promise a year fraught with uncertainty.翻译:亚太经合组织 21 个成员和全世界都对美中紧张局势的缓和以及在这方面取得的进展抱有积极的看法，但政治分析人士表示，情绪的任何改善都可能只是暂时的。明年初的台湾选举和 2024 年 11 月的美国总统大选可能会让特朗普重返白宫，这将是充满不确定性的一年。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Brunnstrom and Michael Martina; Editing by Don Durfee, Grant McCool and Leslie Adler翻译:大卫·布伦斯特罗姆和迈克尔·玛蒂娜报道；唐·杜菲 (Don Durfee)、格兰特·麦库尔 (Grant McCool) 和莱斯利·阿德勒 (Leslie Adler) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 15:14:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">GAIBRZFRQRJ6PILJ2R75SXIOYI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Michael Martina, David Brunnstrom]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/BIDEN</category>
                
                <category>XI</category>
                
                <category>EXPECTATIONS (EXPLAINER, UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[日本和中国将就贸易问题举行定期会谈 - 媒体]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ou9Sk6ccXVlkLm_qd6XsyX4MZRo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TD3VAGTBZVJJ5EH53YM4EBOJHU.jpg" alt="Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida reshuffles his cabinet翻译:日本首相岸田文雄改组内阁" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Japan's Minister of Economy, Trade and Industry Yasutoshi Nishimura walks on the day of the cabinet reshuffle, at the Prime Minister's office in Tokyo, Japan September 13, 2023. REUTERS/Issei Kato/File photo翻译:2023年9月13日，日本经济产业大臣西村康稔在内阁改组当天在日本东京首相办公室散步。路透社/Issei Kato/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Japanese and Chinese trade ministers have agreed to establish a framework to discuss export controls, Japanese media reported on Wednesday, indicating steps on economic cooperation after a period of strained ties between the neighbours.翻译:据日本媒体周三报道，日本和中国贸易部长已同意建立一个讨论出口管制的框架，这表明在邻国关系紧张一段时间后将采取经济合作措施。</p>   <p>Japanese Trade Minister Yasutoshi Nishimura said the talks could help stabilise relations.翻译:日本经济产业大臣西村康稔表示，会谈有助于稳定关系。</p>   <p>"We will hold firm discussions with Chinese officials to build constructive and stable Japan-China relations," Nishimura was quoted as saying after talks with his counterpart, Wang Wentao, on the sidelines of an Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation meeting in San Francisco.翻译:“我们将与中国官员进行坚定的讨论，以建立建设性和稳定的日中关系，”西村在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织会议期间与外长王文涛会谈后表示。</p>   <p>The dialogue is expected to be held by officials at the level of director-general and section chief, who are in charge of export controls, the Yomiuri newspaper reported.翻译:据《读卖新闻》报道，此次对话预计将由负责出口管制的总干事和科长级别的官员举行。</p>   <p>China has recently imposed curbs on the exports of some materials, including chipmaking metals like <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-export-curbs-choke-off-shipments-gallium-germanium-second-month-2023-10-20/">gallium</a>, and is expected to restrict exports of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-ups-critical-minerals-heat-with-graphite-controls-2023-10-24/">graphite</a>, used in batteries, in December.翻译:中国最近对一些材料的出口实施了限制，包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-export-curbs-choke-off-shipments-gallium-germanium-second-month-2023-10-20/">镓</a>等芯片制造金属，并预计将于 12 月限制用于电池的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-ups-critical-minerals-heat-with-graphite-controls-2023-10-24/">石墨</a>的出口。</p>   <p>The talks are aimed at preventing an escalation of retaliatory trade disputes with China, the Yomiuri reported.翻译:据《读卖新闻》报道，此次会谈旨在防止与中国的报复性贸易争端升级。</p>   <p>Before heading to the U.S. to attend the APEC meeting, Kishida told reporters nothing has been decided regarding a meeting with China's leader Xi Jinping on the sidelines.翻译:在前往美国参加亚太经合组织会议之前，岸田告诉记者，关于与中国领导人习近平会面的事宜尚未做出任何决定。</p>   <p>"There is no change in our basic stance that both sides must make the effort to maintain stable and constructive relations," Kishida said. "We would like to continue communicating (with China) in various forms."翻译:岸田说：“我们的基本立场没有改变，即双方必须努力维持稳定和建设性的关系。” “我们愿意继续以各种形式（与中国）进行沟通。”</p>   <p>Relations between China and Japan, rarely smooth, have been particularly strained over recent months.翻译:中国和日本之间的关系绝非一帆风顺，近几个月来尤其紧张。</p>   <p>Japan <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japan-says-harassment-calls-china-regarding-fukushima-water-release-extremely-2023-08-28/">infuriated </a>China when it began releasing treated radioactive water from its wrecked Fukushima nuclear plant into the ocean in August.翻译:日本八月开始将受损福岛核电站处理过的放射性水排入海洋， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japan-says-harassment-calls-china-regarding-fukushima-water-release-extremely-2023-08-28/">激怒了</a>中国。</p>   <p>China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-formally-arrests-astellas-employee-suspected-spying-japan-urges-release-2023-10-19/">last month</a> formally arrested a Japanese executive, an employee of Japanese drugmaker Astellas Pharma <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/4503.T" target="_blank">(4503.T)</a>, on suspicion of espionage. The arrest has had a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/how-an-executives-arrest-struck-blow-japan-china-business-2023-11-14/">chilling effect</a> on business, Japanese officials said.翻译:中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-formally-arrests-astellas-employee-suspected-spying-japan-urges-release-2023-10-19/">上个月</a>以涉嫌间谍罪正式逮捕了一名日本制药商安斯泰来制药公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/4503.T" target="_blank">（Astellas Pharma，4503.T）</a>员工的日本高管。日本官员表示，这次逮捕对商业产生了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/how-an-executives-arrest-struck-blow-japan-china-business-2023-11-14/">寒蝉效应</a>。</p>    <span>Reporting by Satoshi Sugiyama and Sakura Murakami; Editing by Jan Harvey and Robert Birsel翻译:杉山聪和村上樱的报道；扬·哈维和罗伯特·伯塞尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 11:20:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6C2CTCIDOBI3NKAZFZDKRPRQBE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japan-china-hold-regular-talks-trade-issues-media-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>JAPAN</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/TRADE (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[拜登和习近平将在受阿片类药物危机困扰的城市讨论芬太尼]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/OOzC6ioQ-mgW-8aYP2bkIe3IQFc=/1200x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZCI4IIB2RNMYHP6QARETZE2TBM.jpg" alt="U.S. Customs and Border Protection photo of packets of fentanyl mostly in powder form and methamphetamine which U.S. Customs and Border Protection say they seized from a truck crossing into Arizona from Mexico翻译:美国海关和边境保护局照片，其中大部分是粉末形式的芬太尼和甲基苯丙胺，美国海关和边境保护局表示，他们从一辆从墨西哥进入亚利桑那州的卡车上查获了这些物品" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Packets of fentanyl mostly in powder form and methamphetamine, which U.S. Customs and Border Protection say they seized from a truck crossing into Arizona from Mexico, is on display during a news conference at the Port of Nogales, Arizona, U.S., January 31, 2019.   Courtesy U.S. Customs and Border Protection/Handout via REUTERS /File Photo翻译:2019 年 1 月 31 日，在美国亚利桑那州诺加利斯港举行的新闻发布会上，美国海关和边境保护局表示，他们从一辆从墨西哥进入亚利桑那州的卡车上查获了几包芬太尼和甲基苯丙胺，这些芬太尼主要是粉末形式和甲基苯丙胺。由美国海关和边境保护局提供/来自路透社的讲义/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TG1TEqoix0BmSLzAs_2ZQkKdhx0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XVZII463FBIDNM7WDJMOYPZZ6Q.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden disembarks from Air Force One at San Francisco International Airport, as he arrives to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 14 日，美国总统乔·拜登在旧金山国际机场从空军一号下机，抵达美国加利福尼亚州旧金山参加亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会。 REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lTdjpZN9pb-WDBwFVbkn4Qq-Rig=/1878x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JFCDJ65EHNIW7MVYN3IPSOJ6AQ.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping waves as he arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的APEC（亚太经合组织）峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small/资料照片</figcaption></figure>                 <p>Just blocks from where U.S. President Joe Biden and his Chinese counterpart Xi Jinping will meet other Asia-Pacific leaders this week in San Francisco is a neighborhood where it is commonplace to see people using and selling drugs.翻译:距离美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平本周在旧金山会见其他亚太领导人的地点仅几个街区，在这个街区，人们吸毒和贩卖毒品的现象司空见惯。</p>   <p>While the leaders are unlikely to see the blunt reality of the U.S. opioid crisis as they attend the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum, it will be a topic of discussion when <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">Biden and Xi meet</a> one-on-one on Wednesday.翻译:尽管领导人在出席亚太经合组织（APEC）论坛时不太可能看到美国阿片类药物危机的严峻现实，但这将成为<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">拜登和习近平周三一对一会面</a>时讨论的话题。</p>   <p>The United States wants China's cooperation to stop an illicit flow of "precursor" chemicals that are used to make fentanyl, which is up to 50 times stronger than heroin and is increasingly mixed with other drugs - often with lethal results.翻译:美国希望与中国合作，制止用于制造芬太尼的“前体”化学品的非法流动，芬太尼的浓度比海洛因高出 50 倍，并且越来越多地与其他药物混合 - 往往会造成致命的后果。</p>   <p>In the first nine months of this year, 619 people died of an opioid overdose in San Francisco, most related to the synthetic opioids, compared with 647 such deaths in the whole of 2022, according to the city's Office of the Chief Medical Examiner.翻译:据旧金山首席法医办公室称，今年前 9 个月，旧金山有 619 人死于阿片类药物过量，其中大部分与合成阿片类药物有关，而 2022 年全年此类死亡人数为 647 人。</p>   <p>"It's out of control," said Mike Odeh, 36, a salesperson at a liquor store near where APEC leaders will meet.翻译:“事情已经失控了，”36 岁的迈克·奥德 (Mike Odeh) 说，他是 APEC 领导人会面地点附近一家酒类商店的销售人员。</p>   <p>He said that while the city had been cleaning up the streets ahead of APEC, he normally sees people using fentanyl while walking his son to the park and to school, adding: "You can see it all over. Not this week of course."翻译:他说，虽然该市在亚太经合组织之前一直在清理街道，但他通常会看到人们在送儿子去公园和上学时使用芬太尼，并补充道：“你可以看到这一切。当然不是本周。”</p>   <p>Across the country the rate of drug overdose deaths involving fentanyl more than tripled from 2016 through 2021, according to the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Tens of thousands of people die annually from synthetic opioid overdoses, government statistics show.翻译:根据美国疾病控制与预防中心 (CDC) 的数据，从 2016 年到 2021 年，全国范围内涉及芬太尼的药物过量死亡率增加了两倍多。政府统计数据显示，每年有数万人死于合成阿片类药物过量。</p>   <p>U.S. National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan said on Tuesday that Washington hoped the Biden-Xi summit would result in action to combat the fentanyl trade. A source familiar with plans said the U.S. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-set-take-action-win-chinas-cooperation-fentanyl-2023-11-14/">was ready to remove</a> restrictions on the Institute of Forensic Science, part of China's Ministry of Public Security.翻译:美国国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文周二表示，华盛顿希望拜登与习近平的峰会能够采取行动打击芬太尼贸易。一位熟悉计划的消息人士称，美国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-set-take-action-win-chinas-cooperation-fentanyl-2023-11-14/">准备取消</a>对中国公安部司法鉴定所的限制。</p>   <p>Washington put the institute on the Commerce Department's "entity list" in 2020 over alleged abuses toward Uyghurs and other minority groups - effectively barring it from receiving U.S. exports. China has long questioned why the U.S. would expect cooperation on fentanyl while targeting the institute.</p>    <h 1="">CHINA, MEXICO, US STANCES</h>  <p>China's embassy in Washington declined to comment on the fentanyl issue. Chinese state media has repeatedly said addiction and demand for the drug are U.S. domestic problems.翻译:中国驻华盛顿大使馆拒绝就芬太尼问题发表评论。中国官方媒体多次表示，这种药物的成瘾和需求是美国的国内问题。</p>   <p>U.S. officials say that small chemical businesses in China make precursor chemicals that are shipped to Mexico to produce illicit fentanyl, which is often mixed with other illegal drugs, sold as powders and nasal sprays, and increasingly turned into pills that look like legitimate prescription opioids. These are then smuggled into the United States, the officials say.翻译:美国官员表示，中国的小型化学企业生产前体化学品，然后运往墨西哥生产非法芬太尼，芬太尼通常与其他非法药物混合，以粉末和鼻喷雾剂的形式出售，并越来越多地制成看起来像合法处方阿片类药物的药丸。官员们说，这些东西随后被走私到美国。</p>   <p>Last month, the United States imposed sanctions on 28 people and entities involved with the international proliferation of illicit drugs, including a large China-based network.翻译:上个月，美国对 28 名参与国际非法毒品扩散的个人和实体实施制裁，其中包括一个大型中国网络。</p>   <p>"We know that this global fentanyl supply chain, which ends with the deaths of Americans, often starts with chemical companies in China," said U.S. Attorney General Merrick Garland.翻译:美国司法部长梅里克·加兰表示：“我们知道，这条以美国人死亡为终点的全球芬太尼供应链，往往始于中国的化学公司。”</p>   <p>Advocates have also accused pharmaceutical companies and related businesses of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/rite-aid-joins-companies-going-bankrupt-amid-opioid-litigation-2023-10-16/">fueling the crisis</a> through downplaying the risks of opioids and lack of regulation. Landmark settlements since 2021 have set compensation at a total of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/groups-fighting-us-opioid-crisis-settlement-money-can-be-hard-come-by-2023-06-17/">more than $50 billion nationwide</a>.翻译:支持者还指责制药公司和相关企业淡化阿片类药物的风险和缺乏监管，从而<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/rite-aid-joins-companies-going-bankrupt-amid-opioid-litigation-2023-10-16/">加剧了危机</a>。自 2021 年以来，具有里程碑意义的和解协议已将<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/groups-fighting-us-opioid-crisis-settlement-money-can-be-hard-come-by-2023-06-17/">全国范围内的赔偿总额定为超过 500 亿美元</a>。</p>   <p>Biden is also due to meet with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/mexicos-president-meet-chinese-counterpart-apec-summit-minister-2023-11-14/">Mexican President</a> Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador in San Francisco. Mexican Foreign Minister Alicia Barcena said talks would include how to better control the arrival from Asia of precursors used to make fentanyl.翻译:拜登还将于旧金山会见<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/mexicos-president-meet-chinese-counterpart-apec-summit-minister-2023-11-14/">墨西哥总统</a>安德烈斯·曼努埃尔·洛佩兹·奥夫拉多尔。墨西哥外交部长阿丽西娅·巴尔塞纳表示，会谈将包括如何更好地控制来自亚洲的用于制造芬太尼的前体。</p>   <p>In San Francisco, state and local officials have tried to clean up drugs from the city's streets, with limited success. The crisis has drawn sharp criticism from residents in the city, where drug-fuelled crime has forced some businesses to leave.翻译:在旧金山，州和地方官员试图清除该市街道上的毒品，但收效甚微。这场危机引起了该市居民的尖锐批评，毒品犯罪迫使一些企业离开。</p>   <p>San Francisco's new district attorney, Brooke Jenkins, has made prosecuting drug dealers a cornerstone of her agenda. The city recently formed a law enforcement task force to investigate opioid-linked deaths and poisonings.翻译:旧金山新任地方检察官布鲁克·詹金斯 (Brooke Jenkins) 将起诉毒贩作为她议程的基石。该市最近成立了一个执法工作组，调查与阿片类药物相关的死亡和中毒事件。</p>   <p>The city's Mayor London Breed has pushed to prioritize treatment for drug users, talked of police action as a way to solve the problem, and has called on the federal government to boost its drug trafficking enforcement.翻译:该市市长伦敦·布里德（London Breed）推动优先考虑吸毒者的治疗，谈到警方采取行动作为解决问题的一种方式，并呼吁联邦政府加强对贩毒的执法力度。</p>   <p>"We know San Francisco - and cities across the United States - will benefit from more targeting of the trafficking and production of fentanyl worldwide," a spokesperson for Breed said in a statement.翻译:布里德发言人在一份声明中表示：“我们知道，旧金山以及美国各地的城市将受益于全球范围内更多针对芬太尼贩运和生产的打击。”</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Michael Martina; Writing by Sayantani Ghosh and Michelle Nichols; Editing by Josie Kao翻译:迈克尔·玛蒂娜 (Michael Martina) 的补充报道；由 Sayantani Ghosh 和 Michelle Nichols 撰写；编辑：高乔茜</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 07:03:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">67JHX74B4BIPXL3MEJMYDJ3MRI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Peter Henderson, Anna Tong, Trevor Hunnicutt]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>FENTANYL (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[一些基金经理认为中国大幅折扣股票的优点]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/bZJl2rmWIr6zcaiona84qsrZ0ZY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SZ7JFCQHV5MABK6O752AM24PSA.jpg" alt="Chinese Yuan banknotes are seen behind illuminated stock graph in this illustration翻译:在此插图中，可以在发光股票图后面看到人民币钞票" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Yuan banknotes are seen behind illuminated stock graph in this illustration翻译:在此插图中，可以在发光股票图后面看到人民币钞票 taken February 10, 2020. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张摄于 2020 年 2 月 10 日的插图中，可以在发光的库存图表后面看到人民币纸币。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>After months of steering clear of China, global asset managers and hedge funds say they are seeing tentative signs of a recovery on the mainland and value in the country's depressed stock markets.翻译:在避开中国几个月后，全球资产管理公司和对冲基金表示，他们看到了中国大陆复苏的初步迹象以及该国低迷股市的价值。</p>   <p>While foreign inflows only point to a tepid commitment from these funds so far, the rhetoric is changing as asset managers point to volatility in U.S. stocks and sudden policy impetus in China as reasons to return to the country.翻译:虽然到目前为止，外资流入仅表明这些基金的承诺不温不火，但随着资产管理公司将美国股市的波动和中国突然的政策推动作为重返中国的理由，这种说法正在发生变化。</p>   <p>Asset manager Fidelity International is highlighting China's looser monetary policy and the government's recent 1 trillion yuan ($137.10 billion) borrowing-and-spending sovereign bond plan as a tailwind for the country's stock markets.翻译:资产管理公司富达国际(Fidelity International)强调，中国宽松的货币政策和政府最近的1万亿元人民币（合1,371亿美元）的借贷和支出主权债券计划是中国股市的推动力。</p>   <p>“There are mixed pictures if you look globally, depending on your own sort of risk tolerance. Now I think it might be a time to shift from the U.S. into China,” said Marty Dropkin, head of equities, Asia Pacific at Fidelity International.翻译:“如果你放眼全球，情况会是好坏参半，具体取决于你自己的风险承受能力。现在我认为可能是时候从美国转向中国了。”富达国际亚太区股票主管 Marty Dropkin 表示。</p>   <p>London-based £3 billion fund manager Somerset Capital Management likewise finds China exciting. Mark Williams, portfolio manager of its Asia Strategy, says easier monetary and fiscal policies have led to "attractive improvements in company earnings across our portfolio".翻译:总部位于伦敦、价值 30 亿英镑的基金管理公司萨默塞特资本管理公司同样对中国感到兴奋。其亚洲战略投资组合经理马克·威廉姆斯表示，宽松的货币和财政政策导致“我们投资组合中的公司盈利出现了引人注目的改善”。</p>   <p>The fund is increasing exposure to sportswear and electric vehicle companies that will benefit from growing consumer demand.翻译:该基金正在增加对运动服装和电动汽车公司的投资，这些公司将受益于不断增长的消费者需求。</p>   <p>Pessimism on China seems to have peaked this month as authorities in the world's second-largest economy announced bigger stimulus plans and state spending, and even measures to shore up the beleaguered <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-its-indebted-property-sector-2023-11-08/">property</a> sector, though the developers' debt crisis may take years to untangle.翻译:随着世界第二大经济体当局宣布更大规模的刺激计划和国家支出，甚至采取措施支撑陷入困境的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-its-indebted-property-sector-2023-11-08/">房地产</a>行业，对中国的悲观情绪似乎在本月达到顶峰，尽管开发商的债务危机可能需要数年时间才能解决。</p>   <p>The stock market has yet to recover, but has stabilised. The MSCI China index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.dMICN00000PUS" target="_blank">(.dMICN00000PUS)</a> is down 11% so far this year, while U.S. stock indexes S&amp;P 500 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a> and Nasdaq <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.IXIC" target="_blank">(.IXIC)</a> are up 15% and 32%, respectively. Japan’s Nikkei <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a> has gained 25%.翻译:股市尚未复苏，但已趋于稳定。 MSCI 中国指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.dMICN00000PUS" target="_blank">(.dMICN00000PUS)</a>今年迄今已下跌 11%，而美国股指标准普尔 500 指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a>和纳斯达克指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.IXIC" target="_blank">(.IXIC)</a>分别上涨 15% 和 32%。日本日经指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a>上涨 25%。</p>   <p>Morgan Stanley estimates long-only foreign investors now have their deepest underweight positions in China and Hong Kong equities in years. These funds have offloaded nearly $10 billion worth of Chinese equities in the past three months, the largest cumulative outflows since 2018, the bank said.翻译:摩根士丹利估计，只做多的外国投资者目前对中国和香港股市的减持程度是多年来最深的。该行表示，这些基金在过去三个月抛售了价值近100亿美元的中国股票，这是自2018年以来最大的累计流出量。</p>   <p>Chinese stocks have cheapened as a result, to a price-to-earnings ratio of 11%, the lowest among major Asian markets.翻译:中国股市的市盈率因此下跌至 11%，是亚洲主要市场中最低的。</p>   <p>Patrick Ghali, managing partner of Sussex Partners, a London-based hedge fund advisory, says clients who used to say "we don't want any allocation to China" are now thinking of contrarian entry points into the market and of re-engaging.</p>    <h 1="">TURNING POSITIVE</h>  <p>Morgan Stanley data also shows a light turnaround in flows. Foreign investors bought $924 million of China A-shares via the Hong Kong-China Stock Connect link from Nov. 2 to 8, the first week of net inflows since the beginning of August.翻译:摩根士丹利的数据也显示资金流出现轻微好转。 11月2日至8日，外国投资者通过中港通买入9.24亿美元的中国A股，这是自8月初以来的第一周净流入。</p>   <p>The benchmark Hong Kong stock index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a> has risen 1.7% this month after three consecutive months of losses, led by a surge in healthcare and tech shares. And, the Hang Seng Tech Index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSTECH" target="_blank">(.HSTECH)</a> is up 5.1% so far in November.翻译:在医疗保健和科技股飙升的带动下，香港基准股指<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a>在连续三个月下跌后，本月上涨 1.7%。而且，恒生科技指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSTECH" target="_blank">(.HSTECH)</a> 11 月份迄今已上涨 5.1%。</p>   <p>The International Monetary Fund also upgraded its 2023 China economy growth forecast to 5.4% last week.翻译:国际货币基金组织上周也将2023年中国经济增长预期上调至5.4%。</p>   <p>Boston-based investment firm Cambridge Associates says some Middle East investors find China's cheap valuations alluring and are allocating money there.翻译:总部位于波士顿的投资公司Cambridge Associates表示，一些中东投资者发现中国低廉的估值很有吸引力，并正在那里配置资金。</p>   <p>Hong Kong-based hedge fund Triata Capital expects attractive risk-reward in internet and e-commerce giants, saying excess investor pessimism had distorted valuations.翻译:总部位于香港的对冲基金 Triata Capital 预计互联网和电子商务巨头将获得有吸引力的风险回报，称投资者过度悲观情绪扭曲了估值。</p>   <p>“Investors are under-appreciating the substantial upside within (AI-related) software and internet over the long-term,” said Sean Ho, chief investment officer of Triata Capital.翻译:Triata Capital 首席投资官 Sean Ho 表示：“从长远来看，投资者低估了（人工智能相关）软件和互联网的巨大优势。”</p>   <p>Hedge funds typically do not publicly reveal their positions, but disclose them to investors and distributors, through investor letters.翻译:对冲基金通常不会公开披露其头寸，而是通过投资者信函向投资者和分销商披露。</p>   <p>Vivek Tanneeru, portfolio manager at Matthews Asia, a San Francisco-based asset manager, said he maintains an overweight position on China in anticipation of a sentiment boost from improved consumer confidence and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-chinas-xi-will-discuss-communication-competition-apec-summit-2023-11-13/">warmer U.S.-China relations</a>.翻译:总部位于旧金山的资产管理公司Matthews Asia的投资组合经理Vivek Tanneeru表示，他维持对中国的增持立场，因为预计消费者信心改善和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-chinas-xi-will-discuss-communication-competition-apec-summit-2023-11-13/">中美关系回暖将提振市场</a>情绪。</p>   <p>Tanneeru is adding select industrial, travel services, and medical services companies to his portfolio.翻译:Tanneeru 正在将精选的工业、旅游服务和医疗服务公司添加到他的投资组合中。</p>   <p>Some analysts, however, do not expect the feel-good factors will last.翻译:然而，一些分析师预计这种良好的感觉不会持续下去。</p>   <p>Chinese stocks could see a short-term sentiment pick-up given foreign funds have such light positions in the market, said Redmond Wong, Greater China market strategist at Saxo Markets.翻译:盛宝市场(Saxo Markets)大中华区市场策略师雷德蒙德·黄(Redmond Wong)表示，鉴于外国基金在市场上的仓位如此之少，中国股市短期情绪可能会回升。</p>   <p>"But there are rising concerns about China's long-term productivity and growth strategies", he said, referring to the government's often stated priorities around governance and anti-corruption efforts.翻译:“但人们对中国的长期生产力和增长战略的担忧日益增加”，他指的是政府经常提出的围绕治理和反腐败工作的优先事项。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2939 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2939 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Summer Zhen, additional reporting by Xie Yu
Editing by Vidya Ranganathan and Kim Coghill翻译:夏震报道，谢宇补充报道 Vidya Ranganathan 和 Kim Coghill 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 06:09:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">V7KCFZUFD5PZDHB2DDNYKRE5DM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/some-fund-managers-see-merit-chinas-deeply-discounted-stocks-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Summer Zhen]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>FUNDS/ (CORRECTED, ANALYSIS)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国工厂产量和消费超出预期，但房地产仍拖累经济]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Industrial output, retail sales growth better than expected</li>  <li>Property sales extend declines, investment slumps</li>  <li>Oct indicators still show significant areas of economic weakness</li>  <li>Economists expect RRR, interest rate cuts</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>工业产出、零售额增速好于预期</li><li>房地产销售延续下滑，投资下滑</li><li>10 月指标仍显示经济显着疲软</li><li>经济学家预计存款准备金率、降息</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/LTq4T77li8f_4bULKrm5bT1ogEs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KIYGJWK6EFJNVKRZ5J5SSLFNOU.jpg" alt="FILE PHOTO: Leapmotor's EV production line in Jinhua翻译:资料图：零跑汽车位于金华的电动汽车生产线" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>FILE PHOTO: Robotic arms assemble cars in the production line for Leapmotor's electric vehicles at a factory in Jinhua, Zhejiang province, China, April 26, 2023. China Daily via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:资料照片：2023 年 4 月 26 日，中国浙江省金华市一家工厂，机械臂在零跑电动汽车生产线上组装汽车。《中国日报》来自路透社/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/L7KVqCa_-hprbq8GJSuMHMR2QR4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/77V6VO752FLN7CTZ4APEUIYDHU.jpg" alt="National Day holiday, in Shanghai翻译:国庆假期，上海" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk along Nanjing Pedestrian Road, a main shopping area, ahead of the National Day holiday, in Shanghai翻译:国庆假期，上海, China September 26, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>China's industrial output and retail sales growth beat expectations in October, but the underlying economic picture highlighted significant pockets of weakness with the crisis-hit property sector continuing to forestall a full-blown revival.翻译:中国10月份的工业产出和零售销售增长超出预期，但基本经济形势凸显了显着的疲软，受危机打击的房地产行业继续阻碍全面复苏。</p>   <p>The world's second-biggest economy has struggled to mount a strong post-COVID recovery as distress in the housing market, local government debt risks, slow global growth and geopolitical tensions have dented momentum. A flurry of policy support measures have proven only modestly beneficial, raising pressure on authorities to roll out more stimulus.翻译:由于房地产市场低迷、地方政府债务风险、全球经济增长缓慢和地缘政治紧张局势削弱了经济增长势头，全球第二大经济体在新冠疫情后一直难以实现强劲复苏。事实证明，一系列政策支持措施的效果有限，这加大了当局推出更多刺激措施的压力。</p>   <p>China's industrial output grew 4.6% in October year-on-year, accelerating from the 4.5% pace seen in September, data from the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) showed on Wednesday, beating expectations for a 4.4% increase in a Reuters poll. It also marked the strongest growth since April.翻译:中国国家统计局(NBS)周三公布的数据显示，中国10月份工业产出同比增长4.6%，较9月份的4.5%有所加快，超过路透调查中4.4%的增长预期。这也标志着自四月份以来最强劲的增长。</p>   <p>Retail sales rose 7.6% in October with improvement in both auto and restaurant sales growth, quickening from a 5.5% gain in September and hitting the fastest pace since May. Analysts had expected retail sales to grow 7.0% due to the low base effect in 2022 when COVID curbs disrupted consumers and businesses.翻译:10 月份零售额增长 7.6%，汽车和餐饮销售增长均有所改善，增速较 9 月份 5.5% 有所加快，达到 5 月份以来的最快增速。分析师此前预计，由于 2022 年新冠疫情遏制扰乱了消费者和企业，基数较低，零售额将增长 7.0%。</p>      <p>Analysts struck a cautious note on the upside data surprise, noting that the property sector remains a weak link for the economy and pointed to the lack of major <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-choose-fiscal-muscle-over-big-reforms-revive-economy-2023-10-24/">reforms</a> as another impediment to sustainable longer term revival in growth.翻译:分析师对意外的上行数据持谨慎态度，指出房地产行业仍然是经济的薄弱环节，并指出缺乏重大<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-choose-fiscal-muscle-over-big-reforms-revive-economy-2023-10-24/">改革</a>是可持续长期增长复苏的另一个障碍。</p>   <p>"Due to the impact of holidays and low base effect in 2022, year-on-year figures cannot reflect the actual momentum of the economy," said Xing Zhaopeng, senior China strategist at ANZ.翻译:澳新银行高级中国策略师邢兆鹏表示，“由于2022年假期影响和低基数效应，同比数据无法反映经济的实际动力。”</p>   <p>He said month-on-month figures suggest economic momentum has further weakened with "increasing deflationary risks".翻译:他表示，环比数据表明，随着“通缩风险增加”，经济势头进一步减弱。</p>   <p>Louise Loo, China economist at Oxford Economics, said prolonged weakness in external demand could hamper industrial production despite strengthening last month as destocking pressures eased further.翻译:牛津经济研究院(Oxford Economics)中国经济学家Louise Loo表示，尽管上个月随着去库存压力进一步缓解，外部需求有所增强，但长期疲软可能会阻碍工业生产。</p>   <p>Consumption didn't make much headway either during the eight-day Golden Week holiday earlier in October. Trips made in that period missed government estimate as economists say consumers are concerned about their jobs and income growth in an uncertain employment market.翻译:十月初的八天黄金周假期期间，消费也没有取得太大进展。经济学家表示，这一时期的旅行人数未达到政府的预期，因为消费者担心就业市场不确定性下的工作和收入增长。</p>   <p>The nationwide survey-based jobless rate stayed at 5.0% in October, unchanged from September, the NBS data showed. Youth unemployment, which hit a record high 21.3% in June, wasn't available after the statistics bureau stopped publishing it since July.翻译:国家统计局数据显示，10月份全国调查失业率保持在5.0%，与9月份持平。统计局自7月起停止发布青年失业率后，6月份青年失业率创下历史新高21.3%。</p>   <p>China has been ramping up efforts to revive its post-COVID economy with a slew of policy support measures in recent months, although the positive effects have been marginal so far.翻译:近几个月来，中国一直在加大力度通过一系列政策支持措施重振后疫情时代的经济，但迄今为止积极效果甚微。</p>   <p>Wednesday's upbeat data comes as a raft of other indicators for October released over recent weeks pointed to muted growth momentum. Imports grew unexpectedly, but exports shrank at a quicker pace, household borrowing remained weak, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">consumer prices</a> swung lower while factory deflation persisted.翻译:周三公布乐观数据之际，近几周发布的 10 月份其他一系列指标均显示增长势头疲弱。进口意外增长，但出口萎缩加快，家庭借贷依然疲弱， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">消费者价格</a>下跌，而工厂通货紧缩持续存在。</p>   <p>Authorities are faced with a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/part-chinas-economic-miracle-was-mirage-reality-check-is-next-2023-09-03/">challenging task</a> as any aggressive monetary support would further widen interest rate differentials between China and the West, especially the United States, and dent an already weakened yuan. That could intensify capital outflows, while Beijing is wary of a return to the big-bang fiscal stimulus of the past which created massive debt and hamstrung the economy.翻译:当局面临着一项<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/part-chinas-economic-miracle-was-mirage-reality-check-is-next-2023-09-03/">艰巨的任务</a>，因为任何激进的货币支持都将进一步扩大中国与西方（尤其是美国）之间的利差，并削弱本已疲软的人民币。这可能会加剧资本外流，而北京方面则对回到过去的大规模财政刺激措施持谨慎态度，这种财政刺激措施造成了巨额债务并阻碍了经济。</p>   <p>The economy grew faster-than-expected in the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">third quarter</a>, with analysts generally expecting it to reach the government's full-year growth target of around 5%, though a full-blown recovery is still some time away.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">第三季度</a>经济增长快于预期，分析师普遍预计将达到政府5%左右的全年增长目标，但全面复苏尚需时日。</p>   <p>The yuan held near a more than two-month high after surprisingly softer U.S. inflation reading overnight boosted bets that the Federal Reserve had reached the end of its tightening cycle.</p>    <h 1="">PROPERTY, INVESTMENT DISAPPOINT</h>  <p>The country's central bank, People's Bank of China (PBOC), <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cbank-boosts-liquidity-injection-through-policy-loan-rate-unchanged-2023-11-15/">boosted liquidity injections</a> but kept the interest rate unchanged when rolling over maturing medium-term policy loans on Wednesday.翻译:周三，中国央行中国人民银行在展期到期中期政策贷款时<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cbank-boosts-liquidity-injection-through-policy-loan-rate-unchanged-2023-11-15/">加大了流动性注入力度</a>，但维持利率不变。</p>   <p>In a rare revision last month, the government also lifted its 2023 budget deficit to around 3.8% of gross domestic product from 3% to account for the planned issuance of 1 trillion yuan ($137.10 billion) in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/chinas-new-bonds-help-economic-recovery-official-says-budget-deficit-rises-2023-10-25/">sovereign bonds</a>.翻译:上个月，政府罕见地进行了修订，将2023年预算赤字占国内生产总值的比例从3%提高到3.8%左右，以占计划发行1万亿元人民币（1,371亿美元） <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/chinas-new-bonds-help-economic-recovery-official-says-budget-deficit-rises-2023-10-25/">主权债券</a>的比例。</p>   <p>The PBOC has cut banks' reserve requirement ratio (RRR) twice this year to free up liquidity to aid the economic recovery. Analysts widely expect another RRR cut and an interest rate cut in the final months of this year.翻译:中国人民银行今年已两次下调银行存款准备金率（RRR），以释放流动性以帮助经济复苏。分析师普遍预计今年最后几个月将再次下调存款准备金率和利率。</p>   <p>China's crisis-hit <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/">property sector</a> has yet to see a meaningful rebound despite strengthened <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-its-indebted-property-sector-2023-11-08/">support</a> measures for homebuyers, including relaxing of home purchase restrictions, lowering in borrowing costs and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-is-eyeing-137-bln-new-funding-boost-housing-market-bloomberg-news-2023-11-14/">other programmes.</a>翻译:尽管中国加强了对购房者<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-its-indebted-property-sector-2023-11-08/">的支持</a>措施，包括放宽购房限制、降低借贷成本等，但受危机打击的中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/">房地产行业</a>尚未出现有意义的反弹<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-is-eyeing-137-bln-new-funding-boost-housing-market-bloomberg-news-2023-11-14/">。</a></p>   <p>Property investment fell 9.3% in January-October year-on-year, after a similarly sharp 9.1% drop in January-September.翻译:继1-9月大幅下降9.1%之后，1-10月房地产投资同比下降9.3%。</p>   <p>Fixed asset investment disappointed with a 2.9% expansion year-on-year in the first 10 months, missing expectations for a 3.1% rise. It grew 3.1% in the January-September period.翻译:前10个月固定资产投资同比增长2.9%，低于预期的3.1%。 1-9月增长3.1%。</p>   <p>Confidence among private businesses also remained depressed, with investment in the sector shrinking 0.5% during January-October, narrowing slightly from the 0.6% decline in the first nine months.翻译:私营企业信心依然低迷，1-10月该行业投资下降0.5%，较前9个月0.6%的降幅略有收窄。</p>   <p>"Overall, the data published today suggest that the recovery was struggling to gain a strong footing at the start of Q4, but it was not nearly as weak as some had feared," said Sheana Yue, China economist at Capital Economics.翻译:凯投宏观(Capital Economics)中国经济学家谢娜·岳(Sheana Yue)表示：“总体而言，今天公布的数据表明，第四季度初经济复苏正在努力站稳脚跟，但并不像一些人担心的那么疲软。”</p>   <p>"Policy looks set to remain supportive, and possibly even stepped up to prevent the economy from backsliding."翻译:“政策看起来将继续保持支持性，甚至可能加强以防止经济倒退。”</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2939 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2939 人民币）</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Albee Zhang and Liangping Gao;
Editing by Shri Navaratnam翻译:Albee 张和亮平高的补充报道；编辑：Shri Navaratnam</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:38:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TPUCTHUAIJI75IGHIQFYSOENNM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ellen Zhang, Kevin Yao]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/ACTIVITY (WRAPUP 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国习近平在美国参加高风险的拜登峰会和亚太经合组织]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/p6qfrGq_KnFImjes-E8-skVpo7s=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/G3OUQNJDMBPYVDLRYOE6AHE4EQ.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/y2h857HMko9po5X5eBS1uFQPfvo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ICBJHPVSKNLPFMHZY23C7Q2JUE.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A motorcade transporting China's President Xi Jinping arrives at a hotel where the Chinese delegation will stay during the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:2023 年 11 月 14 日，中国国家主席习近平的车队抵达美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的 APEC（亚太经合组织）峰会期间中国代表团下榻的酒店。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/wUwIReGdJLNC-uUymBbSJs2ahuI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZV25UQ5GSZIJPLXDTWJWHNI6I4.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping waves as he arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/JPgeh28fhc5-XGizfDmKoe3_mVU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/EDABMKLXARKULGZ7QBNBLGKRTU.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/1ULQEt5sTvuCu6kPSYAuW0bVAUE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FPUKURKYKVLCFCT2TWQF57BHYI.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small翻译:中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会。路透社/布列塔尼·霍西阿-斯莫尔</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/nTTy9R4o0xvH8z5i5l9UgcP0kio=/1756x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OC6EUZFDFNNEFG7E6SN7ZX77WU.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken holds an APEC Ministerial Meeting (AMM) Opening Session in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯于 2023 年 11 月 14 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行亚太经合组织部长级会议 (AMM) 开幕会议。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/QwRI1qNoHW9vcw7Wj3S8tVMkeDI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/LUSFUFQ2JNMPTPWYK3DCLLVWRY.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken attends an APEC Ministerial Meeting (AMM) Opening Session in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯出席 2023 年 11 月 14 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织部长级会议 (AMM) 开幕会议。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria</figcaption></figure>                         <p>Chinese President Xi Jinping began his first visit to the United States in six years on Tuesday, after President Joe Biden said he aimed to restore normal communications with Beijing and his top diplomat stressed the need for freedoms that Washington says Beijing is undermining in the Asia-Pacific region.翻译:周二，中国国家主席习近平开始六年来首次访问美国，此前美国总统乔·拜登表示，他的目标是恢复与北京的正常沟通，他的高级外交官强调了华盛顿称北京正在破坏亚洲自由的必要性。太平洋地区。</p>   <p>Xi is on his first visit to the U.S. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/cnews-us-usa-china-idCAKBN1792KA-OCATP">since 2017</a>. He is due to meet Biden at an undisclosed location in the San Francisco Bay Area on Wednesday morning and then attend the annual summit of the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/tricky-politics-menu-chinas-xi-us-business-dinner-2023-11-14/">(APEC) forum.</a>翻译:这是习近平<a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/cnews-us-usa-china-idCAKBN1792KA-OCATP">自2017年以来</a>首次访问美国。他将于周三上午在旧金山湾区的一个秘密地点与拜登会面，然后出席亚太经济合作组织<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/tricky-politics-menu-chinas-xi-us-business-dinner-2023-11-14/">（APEC）论坛年度峰会。</a></p>   <p>Xi's summit with Biden will be the first<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">face-to-face</a> meeting between the U.S. and Chinese leaders in a year and has been billed by U.S. officials as an opportunity to reduce friction in what many see as the world's most dangerous rivalry.翻译:习近平与拜登的峰会将是美国和中国领导人一年来的首次<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">面对面</a>会晤，美国官员称这是减少摩擦的一个机会，这场许多人认为这是世界上最危险的竞争。</p>   <p>Xi waved from the steps of his Air China plane upon arrival and descended to meet U.S. officials on the tarmac, including Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen and U.S. Ambassador to China Nicholas Burns.翻译:习近平抵达国航飞机后，在飞机台阶上挥手致意，然后降落在停机坪上会见美国官员，其中包括财政部长珍妮特·耶伦和美国驻华大使尼古拉斯·伯恩斯。</p>   <p>He then got into his Chinese Hongqi, or "Red Flag," limousine and departed the airport into San Francisco, where demonstrations are expected both for and against his visit.翻译:随后，他乘坐他的中国红旗豪华轿车离开机场前往旧金山，预计那里将举行支持和反对他访问的示威活动。</p>   <p>Less than two hours earlier, U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken addressed ministers of the 21-member APEC and stressed the U.S. believed in "a region where economies are free to choose their own path ... where goods, ideas, people flow lawfully and freely."翻译:不到两个小时前，美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯向亚太经合组织 21 个成员国的部长们发表讲话，强调美国相信“一个经济体可以自由选择自己道路的地区……在这里，货物、思想和人员可以合法且自由地流动”。自由。”</p>   <p>Blinken did not mention China by name, but his language echoed U.S. rhetoric in recent years in which Washington has accused China of bullying smaller countries in the Indo-Pacific and trying to undermine what the U.S. and its allies call the "rules-based" order.翻译:布林肯没有提到中国的名字，但他的语言呼应了美国近年来的言论，华盛顿指责中国欺凌印太地区的小国，并试图破坏美国及其盟友所谓的“基于规则”的秩序。</p>   <p>U.S. Trade Representative Katherine Tai, who with Blinken opened the APEC ministerial session, said the San Francisco meeting came at a time of "great uncertainty and challenges" for the region. She noted increasing geopolitical tensions, fragile supply chains and a worsening climate crisis.翻译:美国贸易代表戴凯瑟琳·戴 (Katherine Tai) 与布林肯一起宣布亚太经合组织部长级会议开幕，她表示，旧金山会议召开之际，该地区正面临“巨大的不确定性和挑战”。她指出，地缘政治紧张局势日益加剧，供应链脆弱，气候危机日益恶化。</p>   <p>Earlier, Biden said he aimed to improve the relationship with China after a period of strained ties and would seek to resume normal communications between the two superpowers, including <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-says-goal-xi-meeting-is-resume-us-china-military-communications-2023-11-14/">military-to-military contacts</a>.翻译:此前，拜登表示，他的目标是在一段紧张时期后改善与中国的关系，并将寻求恢复两个超级大国之间的正常沟通，包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-says-goal-xi-meeting-is-resume-us-china-military-communications-2023-11-14/">军事接触</a>。</p>   <p>White House national security spokesperson John Kirby told reporters that Biden and Xi would also talk about the Israel-Hamas conflict in Gaza as well as U.S. efforts to support Ukraine in its fight against the Russian military.翻译:白宫国家安全发言人约翰·柯比告诉记者，拜登和习近平还将讨论以色列与哈马斯在加沙的冲突，以及美国支持乌克兰对抗俄罗斯军队的努力。</p>   <p>Economic issues will be high on the agenda.翻译:经济问题将成为议程的重点。</p>   <p>Biden said the U.S. does not want to decouple from China, but wants to change the economic relationship for the better. His administration has made a push to "de-risk" some critical U.S. supply chains from China as the two countries’ economic and military competition has grown.翻译:拜登表示，美国不想与中国脱钩，而是希望改善经济关系。随着两国经济和军事竞争的加剧，他的政府已努力推动美国一些关键供应链从中国“消除风险”。</p>   <p>Xi, who is seeking to entice foreign investment during the APEC to counter his country's recent struggles, is expected to dine with top U.S. business executives on Wednesday.翻译:习近平正在亚太经合组织会议期间寻求吸引外国投资，以应对中国最近的困境。预计他将于周三与美国企业高管共进晚餐。</p>   <p>For American businesses, it will be a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/tricky-politics-menu-chinas-xi-us-business-dinner-2023-11-14/">chance to hear</a> directly from China's leader as they search for ways to navigate that country's economic slowdown and uncertainty caused by expanding Chinese security rules.</p>    <h 1="">CONCERNS ABOUT A SHOWDOWN</h>  <p>Biden has been careful to assure countries in the region, including China, that the U.S. does not seek complete economic separation, a notion that has fueled concerns among Washington's partners and allies of a superpower showdown that would upend the global economy.翻译:拜登一直小心翼翼地向包括中国在内的该地区国家保证，美国不会寻求完全的经济分离，这一想法加剧了华盛顿的合作伙伴和盟友对超级大国摊牌的担忧，这将颠覆全球经济。</p>   <p>China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-premier-evil-neighbour-next-door-is-showing-off-her-power-our-door-2022-08-05/">severed</a> military-to-military contacts with the U.S. after then-House of Representatives Speaker Nancy Pelosi visited democratically governed but Chinese-claimed Taiwan in August 2022.翻译:2022 年 8 月，时任众议院议长南希·佩洛西访问民主治理但中国声称拥有主权的台湾后，中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-premier-evil-neighbour-next-door-is-showing-off-her-power-our-door-2022-08-05/">切断了</a>与美国的军事接触。</p>   <p>Restoring the contacts is a top U.S. goal to avoid miscalculations between the two militaries.翻译:恢复接触是美国的首要目标，以避免两军之间出现误判。</p>   <p>Washington also hopes for more cooperation from Beijing in combating production of the potent synthetic opioid drug <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-set-take-action-win-chinas-cooperation-fentanyl-2023-11-14/">fentanyl</a>, which has become a scourge in the United States and particularly in San Francisco.翻译:华盛顿还希望与北京加强合作，打击强效合成阿片类药物<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-set-take-action-win-chinas-cooperation-fentanyl-2023-11-14/">芬太尼</a>的生产，芬太尼已成为美国尤其是旧金山的祸害。</p>   <p>Sino-U.S. relations worsened after Biden ordered the shooting down in February of a suspected Chinese <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-announce-successful-conclusion-chinese-balloon-recovery-sources-2023-02-17/">spy balloon</a> that flew over the United States.翻译:拜登2月份下令击落飞越美国上空的疑似中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-announce-successful-conclusion-chinese-balloon-recovery-sources-2023-02-17/">间谍气球</a>后，中美关系恶化。</p>   <p>Top Biden administration officials have since visited Beijing and met with their counterparts in an effort to rebuild communications and trust.翻译:此后，拜登政府高级官员访问了北京并会见了同行，以努力重建沟通和信任。</p>   <p>Several hundred mostly pro-China demonstrators carrying Chinese flags gathered outside the Chinese delegation's hotel ahead of Xi's arrival in the U.S.翻译:在习近平抵达美国之前，数百名手持中国国旗的示威者聚集在中国代表团下榻的酒店外，其中大部分是亲中国的</p>   <p>Larger protests, including by rights groups critical of Xi's policies in Tibet, Hong Kong and toward Muslim Uyghurs, are expected near the summit venue on Wednesday.翻译:预计周三峰会会场附近将举行更大规模的抗议活动，其中包括批评习近平在西藏、香港和穆斯林维吾尔人政策的人权组织。</p>   <p>As Biden arrived in San Francisco, shortly before Xi was due to land, dueling demonstrators greeted the U.S. president's motorcade from the airport. Some waved Chinese flags and held banners calling for "kindly" and "warm" U.S.-Sino ties. Others held signs condemning the Chinese Communist Party.翻译:当拜登抵达旧金山时，就在习近平即将抵达之前不久，示威者在机场迎接美国总统的车队。一些人挥舞着中国国旗，举着呼吁“友好”和“温暖”的美中关系的横幅。其他人则举着谴责中国共产党的标语。</p>   <p>Earlier on Tuesday, a small aircraft flew circles over the APEC summit venue in downtown San Francisco, trailing a banner that read, "END CCP FREE CHINA FREE HK FREE TIBET FREE UIGHUR," referring to China's treatment of Uyghurs, which the Biden administration calls "genocide."翻译:周二早些时候，一架小型飞机在旧金山市中心的亚太经合组织峰会会场上空盘旋，机上悬挂着一条横幅，上面写着“结束中共、自由中国、自由香港、自由西藏、自由维吾尔人”，指的是中国对待维吾尔人的方式，拜登政府称这是中国对待维吾尔人的方式。 “种族灭绝。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Michael Martina, Ann Saphir, David Brunnstrom, Trevor Hunnicutt, David Lawder, Sayantani Ghosh and Peter Henderson; Editing by Leslie Adler, Chris Reese, Josie Kao, Don Durfee and Lincoln Feast.翻译:Michael Martina、Ann Saphir、David Brunnstrom、Trevor Hunnicutt、David Lawder、Sayantani Ghosh 和 Peter Henderson 报道；由莱斯利·阿德勒、克里斯·里斯、乔西·高、唐·德菲和林肯·盛宴编辑。</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:43:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">UHP6R2QSRZPV5EGYYV7EDHAK4A</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Michael Martina, David Brunnstrom]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/MINISTERIAL (UPDATE 5, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国房地产销售延续下滑，前景承压]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ZK7QFM-uFu1AqxVmYfclsK8eU-g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/K7JAUPVPWJLGZFL45JNDNQEUR4.jpg" alt="A man rides a scooter past apartment highrises that are under construction near the new stadium in Zhengzhou翻译:一名男子骑着摩托车经过郑州新体育场附近正在建设的高层公寓" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A man rides a scooter past apartment highrises that are under construction near the new stadium in Zhengzhou翻译:一名男子骑着摩托车经过郑州新体育场附近正在建设的高层公寓, Henan province, China, January 19, 2019.  Picture taken January 19, 2019.  REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2019年1月19日，一名男子骑着摩托车经过中国河南省郑州新体育场附近正在建设的公寓高层建筑。照片拍摄于2019年1月19日。路透社/Thomas Peter/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's property sales fell at a faster pace in October and investment in real estate slumped, official data showed on Wednesday, suggesting the crisis-hit sector is yet to emerge from its decline despite Beijing's recent support efforts.翻译:周三官方数据显示，中国10月份房地产销售下降速度加快，房地产投资大幅下滑，这表明尽管北京方面最近采取了支持措施，但受危机打击的行业尚未摆脱衰退。</p>   <p>Property sales by floor area fell 20.33% year-on-year against a 19.77% fall in September, according to Reuters calculations based on data released by the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS).翻译:路透社根据国家统计局公布的数据计算，房屋销售面积同比下降20.33%，而9月份则下降19.77%。</p>   <p>Sales fell 7.8% year-on-year in January-October, compared with a 7.5% slide in the first nine months of 2023.翻译:1-10月销售额同比下降7.8%，而2023年前9个月则下滑7.5%。</p>   <p>Authorities have been ramping up measures to support real estate, including relaxing home purchase restrictions and lowering borrowing costs, although these have failed to shore up a meaningful recovery in major cities.翻译:当局一直在加大支持房地产的措施，包括放宽购房限制和降低借贷成本，尽管这些措施未能支撑主要城市的有意义的复苏。</p>   <p>Recent economic data has been mixed with industrial output and retail sales both <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/">beating expectations</a> in October although other indicators such as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-imports-unexpectedly-grow-oct-exports-extend-declines-2023-11-07/">exports</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">consumer prices</a> point to persistent drags on growth.翻译:最近的经济数据好坏参半，10 月份工业产出和零售销售均<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/">超出预期</a>，尽管<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-imports-unexpectedly-grow-oct-exports-extend-declines-2023-11-07/">出口</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">消费者价格</a>等其他指标表明经济增长持续受到拖累。</p>   <p>While a twice-a-decade financial policy meeting last month offered few surprises for the property market, authorities remain concerned about risks that could spill into other industries, threatening financial stability.翻译:尽管上个月举行的十年两次的金融政策会议没有给房地产市场带来什么惊喜，但当局仍然担心风险可能蔓延到其他行业，威胁金融稳定。</p>   <p>China plans to provide at least 1 trillion yuan ($137 billion) of low-cost financing to the urban village renovations and affordable housing programs, Bloomberg News reported on Tuesday, citing people familiar with the matter.翻译:彭博新闻社周二援引知情人士的话报道称，中国计划为城中村改造和保障性住房项目提供至少 1 万亿元人民币（合 1,370 亿美元）的低成本融资。</p>   <p>Reuters previously reported a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">state-engineered rescue</a> of Country Garden <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">(2007.HK)</a> by Ping An Insurance Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601318.SS" target="_blank">(601318.SS)</a>, which would be one of the most significant interventions to date by China to support the sector, though Ping An has repeatedly denied the rescue plan.翻译:路透社此前报道称，平安保险集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601318.SS" target="_blank">（601318.SS）</a>对碧桂园<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">（2007.HK）</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">进行了国家设计的救助</a>，这将是迄今为止中国支持该行业的最重大干预措施之一，尽管平安一再表示否认了救援计划。</p>   <p>Property investment fell 16.7% from a year earlier after an 18.7% slide in September, according to Reuters calculations.翻译:据路透社计算，房地产投资继 9 月份下降 18.7% 后，同比下降 16.7%。</p>   <p>New construction starts measured by floor area fell 23.2% year-on-year, after a 23.4% slump in the first nine months.翻译:按建筑面积计算的新开工面积同比下降 23.2%，前 9 个月下降 23.4%。</p>   <p>Funds raised by China's property developers were down 13.8% year-on-year after a 13.5% fall in January-September.翻译:继1-9月下降13.5%之后，中国房地产开发商募集资金同比下降13.8%。</p>    <span>Reporting by Liangping Gao, Ella Cao and Ryan Woo; Editing by Sam Holmes翻译:高亮平、曹艾拉、吴瑞安报道；山姆·霍姆斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:13:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FRN3TIHRYNMKPIIVX77TKE57ZU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/PROPERTY</category>
                
                <category>INVESTMENT (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1-10月房地产销售同比下降7.8%，投资下降9.3%]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ZK7QFM-uFu1AqxVmYfclsK8eU-g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/K7JAUPVPWJLGZFL45JNDNQEUR4.jpg" alt="A man rides a scooter past apartment highrises that are under construction near the new stadium in Zhengzhou翻译:一名男子骑着摩托车经过郑州新体育场附近正在建设的高层公寓" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A man rides a scooter past apartment highrises that are under construction near the new stadium in Zhengzhou翻译:一名男子骑着摩托车经过郑州新体育场附近正在建设的高层公寓, Henan province, China, January 19, 2019.  Picture taken January 19, 2019.  REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2019年1月19日，一名男子骑着摩托车经过中国河南省郑州新体育场附近正在建设的公寓高层建筑。照片拍摄于2019年1月19日。路透社/Thomas Peter/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Property sales by floor area in China fell 7.8% year-on-year in January-October, compared with a 7.5% slide in the first nine months of 2023, suggesting China's property sector is yet to emerge from its slump.翻译:1-10月中国房地产销售面积同比下降7.8%，而2023年前9个月的下滑幅度为7.5%，这表明中国房地产行业尚未走出低迷状态。</p>   <p>Property investment in the first 10 months of 2023 fell 9.3% from a year earlier, after dropping 9.1% in January-September, according to data from the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) released on Wednesday.翻译:国家统计局周三发布的数据显示，继1-9月下降9.1%之后，2023年前10个月房地产投资同比下降9.3%。</p>   <p>New construction starts measured by floor area fell 23.2% year-on-year, after a 23.4% slump in the first nine months.翻译:按建筑面积计算的新开工面积同比下降 23.2%，前 9 个月下降 23.4%。</p>   <p>Funds raised by China's property developers were down 13.8% year-on-year after a 13.5% fall in January-September.翻译:继1-9月下降13.5%之后，中国房地产开发商募集资金同比下降13.8%。</p>   <p>(This story has been corrected to change sales fall percentage to 7.8%, from 6.8%, in the headline and paragraph 1)翻译:（这个故事已被更正，将标题和第 1 段中的销售额下降百分比从 6.8% 更改为 7.8%）</p>    <span>Reporting by Liangping Gao, Ella Cao and Ryan Woo; Editing by Sam Holmes翻译:高亮平、曹艾拉、吴瑞安报道；山姆·霍姆斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:08:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">JHOILHZI3BOZZIKDLUIQDGZB3U</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-78-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/PROPERTY</category>
                
                <category>INVESTMENT (URGENT, CORRECTION)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国银行通过政策性贷款加大流动性注入，利率不变]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/5WpBhmWCsz2HDENvuzwOegpnOyA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YFL7JVKIYBLCNORUY7KN3GS4TA.jpg" alt="A gardener works outside the headquarters of the central bank of the People's Republic of China in Beijing翻译:一名园丁在北京中央银行总部外工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A gardener works outside the headquarters of the central bank of the People's Republic of China in Beijing翻译:一名园丁在北京中央银行总部外工作 October 8, 2008. External and internal conditions are ripe for China to cut interest rates soon to give the economy a lift, an official newspaper said in a front-page commentary on Wednesday. REUTERS/Jason Lee (CHINA)</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's central bank ramped up liquidity injection but kept the interest rate unchanged when rolling over maturing medium-term policy loans on Wednesday, matching market expectations.翻译:中国央行周三加大流动性注入力度，但在到期中期政策贷款展期时保持利率不变，符合市场预期。</p>   <p>Market participants believe that a weakening Chinese yuan has constrained the central bank's efforts to aggressively lower interest rates even though the recovery of the world's second-largest economy remains uneven and requires further stimulus.翻译:市场人士认为，尽管世界第二大经济体的复苏仍不平衡，需要进一步刺激，但人民币贬值限制了央行大幅降息的努力。</p>   <p>The People's Bank of China (PBOC) said it was keeping the rate on 1.45 trillion yuan ($199.92 billion) worth of one-year medium-term lending facility (MLF) loans to some financial institutions unchanged at 2.50% from the previous operation.翻译:中国人民银行（PBOC）表示，将向部分金融机构发放的 1.45 万亿元人民币（合 1,999.2 亿美元）的一年期中期借贷便利（MLF）贷款利率维持在 2.50% 不变。</p>   <p>The central bank said the loan operation was meant to maintain banking system liquidity reasonably ample to counteract short-term factors including tax payments and government bond issuance.翻译:央行表示，此次贷款操作旨在保持银行体系流动性合理充裕，以应对纳税、国债发行等短期因素。</p>   <p>"At the same time, it will appropriately provide mid- and long-term base money," the PBOC said in an online statement.翻译:“同时，适当提供中长期基础货币，”中国人民银行在网上发布的声明中表示。</p>   <p>All 31 market watchers polled by Reuters this week had expected the central bank to inject fresh funds to exceed the maturity.翻译:路透社本周调查的 31 名市场观察人士均预计央行将注入新资金以超过到期期限。</p>   <p>With 850 billion yuan worth of MLF loans set to expire this month, the operation resulted a net 600 billion yuan of fresh fund injection into the banking system.翻译:本月8500亿元MLF贷款即将到期，此次操作为银行体系净注入资金6000亿元。</p>   <p>"Weak inflation and the recent liquidity squeeze call for stronger policy support this week," Carlos Casanova, senior economist for Asia at UBP, said in a note this week.翻译:UBP 亚洲高级经济学家卡洛斯·卡萨诺瓦 (Carlos Casanova) 在本周的一份报告中表示，“疲软的通胀和近期的流动性紧缩要求本周采取更强有力的政策支持。”</p>   <p>"Liquidity conditions tightened in October, as a deluge of bond issuance to fund fiscal stimulus and quarter-end cash demand from corporates drove up interbank rates. The most likely outcome is for PBOC to inject more support through open market operations, while leaving the MLF rate unchanged."翻译:“10月份流动性状况收紧，因为为财政刺激提供资金的大量债券发行以及企业季末现金需求推高了银行间利率。最可能的结果是中国人民银行通过公开市场操作注入更多支持，同时退出MLF率不变。”</p>   <p>He added that authorities will remain on alert and continue to support the recovery, expecting another 10-basis-point interest rate cut and an additional RRR cut in December, if not sooner.翻译:他补充说，当局将保持警惕并继续支持经济复苏，预计 12 月份（甚至更早）将再次降息 10 个基点并进一步下调存款准备金率。</p>   <p>The interest rate on one-year AAA-rated negotiable certificates of deposit (NCDs) , which measure short-term inter-bank borrowing costs, is hovering at a six-month high of 2.5653%, about 7 bps higher than the MLF rate the central bank charges financial institutions.翻译:衡量短期银行间借贷成本的一年期AAA级可转让存款证（NCD）利率徘徊在六个月高点2.5653%，比MLF利率高出约7个基点。中央银行向金融机构收取费用。</p>   <p>Wednesday's liquidity support for the nascent economic recovery through the medium-term policy loans has, however, reduced necessity for more imminent monetary stimulus, some traders and analysts said.翻译:然而，一些交易员和分析师表示，周三通过中期政策贷款为新生经济复苏提供的流动性支持降低了迫在眉睫的货币刺激措施的必要性。</p>   <p>"But MLF loans is rather expensive, and we still expect additional reserve requirement ratio (RRR) cuts in the future to reduce (banks) debt costs," said Xing Zhaopeng, senior China strategist at ANZ.翻译:澳新银行高级中国策略师邢兆鹏表示：“但MLF贷款相当昂贵，我们仍然预计未来会进一步下调存款准备金率（RRR），以降低（银行）债务成本。”</p>   <p>China has reported a slew of mixed October economic data, as industrial output and retail sales growth data surprised on the upside, while factory activity unexpectedly contracted and consumer prices continued to fall.翻译:中国公布的10月份经济数据好坏参半，工业产出和零售销售增长数据意外上行，而工厂活动意外收缩，消费者价格继续下跌。</p>   <p>Still, market watchers said the currency remained as a key constraint for the authorities to ease monetary policy. China's yuan has lost about 5% to the dollar so far this year to become one of the worst performing Asian currencies.翻译:尽管如此，市场观察人士表示，人民币汇率仍然是当局放松货币政策的主要制约因素。今年迄今为止，人民币兑美元汇率已下跌约5%，成为表现最差的亚洲货币之一。</p>   <p>The sizable depreciation has prompted authorities to step up efforts to support the currency, with many analysts believing policymakers may view yuan stability as a prerequisite for restoring confidence in yuan assets.翻译:大幅贬值促使当局加大支持人民币的力度，许多分析师认为，政策制定者可能将人民币稳定视为恢复人民币资产信心的先决条件。</p>   <p>China remains an outlier among global central banks as it has loosened monetary policy to shore up a stalling recovery but further rate cuts will widen the yield gap with the United States, putting more pressure on the yuan and risking outflows.翻译:中国在全球央行中仍然是一个异类，因为它已经放松了货币政策以支撑停滞的复苏，但进一步降息将扩大与美国的收益率差距，给人民币带来更大的压力，并带来资金外流的风险。</p>   <p>The central bank also injected 495 billion yuan through seven-day reverse repos while keeping borrowing cost unchanged at 1.80%, it said in the statement.翻译:央行在声明中表示，还通过7天逆回购注入4950亿元人民币，维持借贷成本在1.80%不变。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2530 yuan)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2530 元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Winni Zhou and Tom Westbrook; Editing by Christian Schmollinger, Stephen Coates &amp; Shri Navaratnam翻译:Winni Zhou 和 Tom Westbrook 报道；编辑：Christian Schmollinger、Stephen Coates 和 Shri Navaratnam</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 02:42:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">GXDDW2AWXZJSDPGIR6SLALRZD4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cbank-boosts-liquidity-injection-through-policy-loan-rate-unchanged-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/RATES (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国高级议员在习近平会面前向拜登施压囚犯问题信函]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/adNPz0m4tNc4EXUbDpfWkYGbYqs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/C2YUZ5N23ZOMRGIZHE5BECJASY.jpg" alt="U.S. Senator Ben Cardin (D-MD) speaks at a committee meeting after assuming the chairmanship of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee at the U.S. Capitol on Capitol Hill in Washington翻译:美国参议员本·卡丁（D-MD）在华盛顿国会山美国国会担任参议院外交关系委员会主席后在委员会会议上发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Senator Ben Cardin (D-MD) speaks at a committee meeting after assuming the chairmanship of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee at the U.S. Capitol on Capitol Hill in Washington翻译:美国参议员本·卡丁（D-MD）在华盛顿国会山美国国会担任参议院外交关系委员会主席后在委员会会议上发表讲话, U.S., September 28, 2023. REUTERS/Craig Hudson/File Photo翻译:美国参议员本·卡丁 (D-MD) 于 2023 年 9 月 28 日在美国华盛顿国会山担任参议院外交关系委员会主席后在委员会会议上发表讲话。 REUTERS/Craig Hudson/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The chairman of the U.S. Senate Foreign Relations Committee urged President Joe Biden to use his upcoming meeting with Chinese President Xi Jinping to push for the release of Americans detained for years in China, according to a letter seen by Reuters on Tuesday.翻译:路透社周二看到的一封信显示，美国参议院外交关系委员会主席敦促总统乔·拜登利用即将与中国国家主席习近平举行的会晤，推动释放在中国被拘留多年的美国人。</p>   <p>Democratic Senator Ben Cardin wrote to Biden to push for immediate freedom for Mark Swidan, Kai Li and David Lin, whom the U.S. government has classified as wrongfully detained in China. Republicans and other Democrats have also called for their release.翻译:民主党参议员本·卡丁写信给拜登，敦促立即释放被美国政府列为在中国错误拘留的马克·斯维丹、李凯和林大卫。共和党人和其他民主党人也呼吁释放他们。</p>   <p>Biden and Xi are holding talks around events at the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation forum in San Francisco, as the United States seeks to recover from a diplomatic crisis over its downing of a suspected Chinese spy balloon over the United States in February.翻译:拜登和习近平正在旧金山亚太经济合作论坛上就有关活动举行会谈，此时美国正寻求从二月份在美国上空击落疑似中国间谍气球引发的外交危机中恢复过来。</p>   <p>"With the holiday season approaching, and the opportunity to start the New Year on a more positive note in bilateral U.S.-China relationships, I implore you to secure commitments from president Xi to release these Americans immediately," Cardin wrote.翻译:卡丁写道：“随着假期的临近，以及美中双边关系以更积极的方式开始新年的机会，我恳请您确保习主席承诺立即释放这些美国人。”</p>   <p>Cardin also asked for the release and safety of U.S.-based journalists' family members whom he said are missing, jailed or detained in China due to their connection to the journalists.翻译:卡丁还要求释放驻美国记者的家人并确保他们的安全，他说这些家人因与记者有联系而在中国失踪、被监禁或拘留。</p>   <p>Families of Americans the U.S. government has classified as wrongfully detained in China have also repeatedly urged the government to prioritize the release of their loved ones in talks with Chinese officials.翻译:被美国政府列为在中国错误拘留的美国人的家属也一再敦促政府在与中国官员的会谈中优先释放他们的亲人。</p>   <p>Katherine Swidan said she spoke to U.S. Ambassador to China Nicholas Burns about her son Mark over the weekend, but called the conversation "disappointing" because Burns would not say whether Biden would raise Mark’s name with Xi.翻译:凯瑟琳·斯维丹(Katherine Swidan)表示，她周末与美国驻华大使尼古拉斯·伯恩斯(Nicholas Burns)谈论了她的儿子马克(Mark)，但称这次谈话“令人失望”，因为伯恩斯不愿透露拜登是否会向习近平提及马克的名字。</p>   <p>"China only respects strength," she said, adding that she was frustrated because the Biden administration did not appear to have a plan to get U.S. detainees out of China.翻译:“中国只尊重实力，”她说，并补充说，她感到沮丧，因为拜登政府似乎没有计划将美国在押人员带出中国。</p>   <p>A State Department spokesperson commented that the department has no greater priority than the safety and security of U.S. citizens and noted that it continually raises wrongfully detained U.S. nationals during engagements with senior Chinese officials.翻译:美国国务院发言人评论说，该部门最优先考虑的莫过于美国公民的安全和保障，并指出，该部门在与中国高级官员接触时不断提及被错误拘留的美国公民。</p>   <p>China says such cases are handled according to law.翻译:中方表示，此类案件将依法处理。</p>    <span>Reporting by Patricia Zengerle and Michael Martina; Editing by Stephen Coates翻译:帕特里夏·曾格尔 (Patricia Zengerle) 和迈克尔·马丁纳 (Michael Martina) 报道；斯蒂芬·科茨编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 22:56:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZDHUMWNM4BKE7DQHESLVYQ4JHM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/senior-us-lawmaker-pushes-biden-prisoners-ahead-xi-meeting-letter-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Patricia Zengerle, Michael Martina]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CONGRESS</category>
                
                <category>CHINA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[澳大利亚相信中国下个月将解除所有贸易封锁]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tlOCbhf4AQTSfnCSNLqE0rVmYmo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4FPO6VW3GNJQLEKJUSM3NPT7O4.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of Australian and Chinese flags翻译:澳大利亚和中国国旗插画图片" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Flags of Australia and China are displayed in this illustration picture taken May 11, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration翻译:这张摄于 2023 年 5 月 11 日的插图照片中展示了澳大利亚和中国的国旗。REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration</figcaption></figure>       <p>Australia said on Wednesday China could lift all its remaining trade blocks by next month as relations between the commodity trade partners stabilise and after Prime Minister Anthony Albanese's visit to Beijing earlier this month.翻译:澳大利亚周三表示，随着大宗商品贸易伙伴之间的关系稳定以及总理安东尼·阿尔巴内斯本月早些时候访问北京之后，中国可能会在下个月解除所有剩余的贸易封锁。</p>   <p>Albanese's government has taken credit for patching up ties with China since coming to office last year. China has lifted most trade blocks imposed amid a 2020 diplomatic dispute after Australia called for an inquiry into the origins of COVID-19.翻译:自去年上任以来，阿尔巴尼斯政府因修复与中国的关系而受到赞誉。在澳大利亚呼吁对 COVID-19 的起源进行调查后，中国取消了在 2020 年外交争端中施加的大部分贸易封锁。</p>   <p>"I remain very confident ... that by Christmas all of these trade impediments will be removed," trade minister Don Farrell told ABC Radio from San Francisco, where he is attending Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) meetings.翻译:“我仍然非常有信心……到圣诞节，所有这些贸易障碍都将被消除，”贸易部长唐·法雷尔在旧金山出席亚太经合组织（APEC）会议时告诉美国广播公司广播电台。</p>   <p>"And we will have restored that stable relationship that we want with our largest trading partner."翻译:“我们将与我们最大的贸易伙伴恢复我们想要的稳定关系。”</p>   <p>Farrell said he hoped to resolve the issues over lobster and beef, which related to bio-security rules, ahead of a meeting with Chinese counterpart Wang Wentao in San Francisco.翻译:法雷尔表示，他希望在旧金山与中国外长王文涛会面之前解决涉及生物安全规则的龙虾和牛肉问题。</p>    <span>Reporting by Renju Jose in Sydney. Editing by Sam Holmes.翻译:Renju Jose 悉尼报道。山姆·霍姆斯编辑。</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 22:53:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">XQQB2LJGGVPONCFWDIWUXHPQFA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australia-confident-china-will-lift-all-trade-blocks-next-month-2023-11-14/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/TRADE</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
