<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 18:29:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[石油高管表示，中石油将取代埃克森美孚成为伊拉克西库尔纳1号油田的主要承包商]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/l16ZkP6Mx5ca3G9bmIhceXYy5cU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/H3JWVVNKGNKSPJS2KH4L54PUPE.jpg" alt="PetroChina's petrol station is pictured in Beijing翻译:图为北京的中石油加油站" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>PetroChina's petrol station is pictured in Beijing翻译:图为北京的中石油加油站, China, March 21, 2016. REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Iraq has signed a settlement agreement with U.S. energy giant Exxon Mobil Corp <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/XOM.N" target="_blank">(XOM.N)</a> to finalise its exit from the West Qurna 1 oilfield and allow PetroChina to become the field's lead contractor, a senior Iraqi oil executive said on Saturday.翻译:伊拉克一位高级石油高管周六表示，伊拉克已与美国能源巨头埃克森美孚公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/XOM.N" target="_blank">（XOM.N）</a>签署了一项和解协议，以最终退出西库尔纳1号油田，并允许中石油成为该油田的主要承包商。</p>   <p>"We studied the settlement agreement and the oil ministry with the Basra Oil Company believe that the best option is for Petrochina to become the lead contractor of West Qurna 1," Hassan Mohammed, deputy Basra Oil Co. manager in charge of oilfields and licensing rounds affairs, told Reuters.翻译:巴士拉石油公司负责油田和许可轮次的副经理哈桑·穆罕默德表示：“我们研究了和解协议，石油部与巴士拉石油公司认为，最好的选择是中石油成为西库尔纳 1 号油田的主承包商。”事务，告诉路透社。</p>   <p>PetroChina will hold the largest stake in the field after the departure of Exxon.翻译:埃克森美孚退出后，中石油将持有该油田最大股份。</p>   <p>Iraq has also signed a "sale agreement" arranging the financial issues to finalise the process of acquiring Exxon Mobil Corp's (XOM.N) stake in West Qurna 1 oilfield by Iraq's state-run Basra Oil Co. (BOC), said Mohammed.翻译:穆罕默德表示，伊拉克还签署了一份“销售协议”，安排财务问题，以最终完成伊拉克国营巴士拉石油公司（BOC）收购埃克森美孚公司（XOM.N）在西库尔纳1号油田的股份的过程。</p>   <p>The sale agreement includes a commitment to resolve in further talks the tax value that Exxon must pay for selling its stake in the field, he said.翻译:他说，销售协议包括承诺在进一步谈判中解决埃克森美孚出售其在该油田的股份必须支付的税收价值。</p>   <p>"Tax issue is not resolved yet and according to the sale agreement we have two options, either to reach a tax settlement or we resort to arbitration," said the BOC executive.翻译:“税务问题尚未解决，根据销售协议，我们有两种选择，要么达成税务和解，要么诉诸仲裁，”该行高管表示。</p>   <p>Exxon and PetroChina were not immediately available for comment, but two oil managers at the West Qurna 1 field confirmed the details of the settlement and sale agreement signed with Exxon.翻译:埃克森美孚和中石油并未立即发表评论，但西库尔纳1号油田的两名石油管理人员证实了与埃克森美孚签署的和解和销售协议的细节。</p>   <p>Last year, Indonesia’s state-owned oil and gas firm Pertamina bought 10% of Exxon Mobil’s stake in Iraq’s West Qurna 1 oilfield, increasing its share to 20%, while BOC bought 22.7% of the field.翻译:去年，印尼国有油气公司Pertamina购买了埃克森美孚在伊拉克West Qurna 1油田10%的股份，将其股份增加至20%，而中国银行则购买了该油田22.7%的股份。</p>   <p>Basra Oil Company director Khalid Hamza told Reuters in an interview in 2021 that Exxon was seeking to sell the share for $350 million.翻译:巴士拉石油公司董事哈立德·哈姆扎 (Khalid Hamza) 在 2021 年接受路透社采访时表示，埃克森美孚正寻求以 3.5 亿美元的价格出售该股份。</p>   <p>West Qurna 1, in southern Iraq, is one of the world’s largest oilfields with recoverable reserves estimated at more than 20 billion barrels. It currently produces around 560,000 barrels per day, said the field officials.翻译:West Qurna 1 位于伊拉克南部，是世界上最大的油田之一，可采储量估计超过 200 亿桶。油田官员表示，目前该厂日产量约为 560,000 桶。</p>   <p>Following its exit from West Qurna 1, Exxon will have no presence in Iraq's energy sectory, said BOC officials.翻译:中行官员表示，退出西古尔纳一号油田后，埃克森美孚将不再涉足伊拉克能源行业。</p>    <span>Reporting by Aref Mohammed in Basra; Additional reporting by Hadeel Al Sayegh in Dubai; Writing by Ahmed Rasheed; Editing by Kirsten Donovan and Giles Elgood翻译:阿里夫·穆罕默德在巴士拉的报道； Hadeel Al Sayegh 在迪拜的补充报道；艾哈迈德·拉希德 (Ahmed Rasheed) 撰写；克尔斯滕·多诺万和贾尔斯·埃尔古德编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 14:20:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">WFFAUMVDZZJ3RETMCI5GZOQODU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/petrochina-replace-exxon-lead-contractor-iraqs-west-qurna-1-oilfield-oil-2023-11-11/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Aref Mohammed]]></author>
            
                
                <category>IRAQ</category>
                
                <category>ENERGY/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[尽管有中国船只，菲律宾仍将继续南海补给任务]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0Vaj6Omj4LXphIa6NLnoI9_kKGE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZBTMXWFEJRJZZJU7WFRIQCJ2WQ.jpg" alt="Philippines resupply mission in the South China Sea翻译:菲律宾在南海执行补给任务" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Philippine supply boat sails near a Chinese Coast Guard ship during a resupply mission for Filipino troops stationed at a grounded warship in the South China Sea, October 4, 2023. REUTERS/Adrian Portugal/File Photo翻译:2023 年 10 月 4 日，一艘菲律宾补给船在为驻扎在南海搁浅军舰上的菲律宾部队执行补给任务时，在一艘中国海岸警卫队船只附近航行。路透社/阿德里安·葡萄牙/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Philippines' coast guard said on Saturday it would maintain its regular supply missions to troops stationed on a disputed atoll in the South China Sea even though it expects more Chinese vessels to be sent to the area.翻译:菲律宾海岸警卫队周六表示，尽管预计将派遣更多中国船只前往该地区，但仍将维持对驻扎在南海争议环礁上的部队的定期补给任务。</p>   <p>The Philippines regularly sends supplies to a handful of troops living aboard an aging warship that was deliberately run aground on the Second Thomas Shoal in 1999 to assert Manila's sovereignty claims over the atoll.翻译:菲律宾定期向居住在一艘老化军舰上的少数部队运送物资，这艘军舰于 1999 年故意搁浅在仁爱礁，以维护马尼拉对该环礁的主权主张。</p>   <p>China claims almost the entire South China Sea, including the Second Thomas Shoal, and has deployed hundreds of vessels to patrol there.翻译:中国对包括仁爱礁在内的几乎整个南海拥有主权，并部署了数百艘船只在那里巡逻。</p>   <p>"We are still going to carry out these dangerous missions despite our limited number of vessels and despite the increasing number of Chinese vessels they are going to deploy," Philippine coast guard spokesperson Jay Tarriela told a press conference.翻译:菲律宾海岸警卫队发言人杰伊·塔里拉在新闻发布会上表示：“尽管我们的船只数量有限，而且他们将部署越来越多的中国船只，但我们仍将执行这些危险的任务。”</p>   <p>"We have to make sure the supplies will still reach our troops," Tarriela said, adding that China's coast guard is deploying smaller vessels to try to outmanoeuvre its Philippine counterpart.翻译:塔里埃拉说：“我们必须确保补给品仍能送达我们的部队。”他补充说，中国海警正在部署较小的船只，试图智取菲律宾海警。</p>   <p>He spoke a day after the Philippines <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-coast-guard-urges-philippines-stop-infringing-sovereignty-2023-11-10/">condemned</a> the Chinese coast guard for "unprovoked acts of coercion and dangerous manoeuvres," including using a water cannon against one of its boats in an attempt to disrupt a resupply mission.翻译:一天前，菲律宾<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-coast-guard-urges-philippines-stop-infringing-sovereignty-2023-11-10/">谴责</a>中国海警“无端胁迫和危险举动”，包括使用高压水枪攻击其一艘船只，试图扰乱补给任务。</p>   <p>China's Embassy in Manila said on Saturday its coast guard had taken necessary enforcement measures against Philippine ships after the vessels infringed on Beijing's sovereignty.翻译:中国驻马尼拉大使馆周六表示，在菲律宾船只侵犯北京主权后，中国海警已对这些船只采取了必要的执法措施。</p>   <p>The U.S. State Department said on Saturday it stands with the Philippines, with which it has signed a defence treaty.翻译:美国国务院周六表示，它与菲律宾站在一起，并与菲律宾签署了一项防御条约。</p>   <p>"We urge the PRC (People's Republic of China) to respect the high seas freedoms of navigation guaranteed to all states under international law," it said in a statement, reaffirming its commitment to the defence treaty.翻译:它在一份声明中表示：“我们敦促中华人民共和国尊重国际法保障所有国家的公海航行自由。”并重申其对防卫条约的承诺。</p>   <p>Philippine President Ferdinand Marcos has pursued warmer ties with Washington, reversing the pro-China stance of his predecessor and leading to a rise in tension in the South China Sea.翻译:菲律宾总统费迪南德·马科斯寻求与华盛顿改善关系，扭转了其前任的亲华立场，导致南海紧张局势升级。</p>    <span>Reporting by Neil Jerome Morales
Editing by Helen Popper翻译:尼尔·杰罗姆·莫拉莱斯报道 海伦·波普尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 10:57:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">AOZTKKWXVJNBRLWONLOSNXBDZY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-continue-south-china-sea-supply-missions-despite-chinese-boats-2023-11-11/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SOUTHCHINASEA</category>
                
                <category>PHILIPPINES/ (TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[耶伦将与中国领导人“加强沟通”，警告俄罗斯的支持]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/xIO9IvH7625evaLFQkaeoBMogwo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WZMI4SNF3VIU5MGMENBXYSYXW4.jpg" alt="U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen meets with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng during a bilateral meeting in San Francisco翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦在旧金山举行双边会议期间会见中国国务院副总理何立峰" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen meets with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng during a bilateral meeting ahead of a U.S.-hosted APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 10, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria/ File photo翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦于 2023 年 11 月 10 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的 APEC（亚太经合组织）峰会之前的双边会议上会见中国副总理何立峰。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria/File照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen said on Friday that she agreed with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng to "intensify communication" on economic issues but warned him to crack down on Chinese companies that give material support to Russia for its war in Ukraine.翻译:美国财长耶伦周五表示，她同意中国国务院副总理何立峰就经济问题“加强沟通”，但警告他要打击为俄罗斯乌克兰战争提供物质支持的中国公司。</p>   <p>The two "had candid, direct, and productive discussions" on issues from U.S export controls to possible areas of cooperation, including climate change and debt relief for low-income countries, Yellen told a press conference after two days of meetings in San Francisco.翻译:耶伦在旧金山举行两天会议后在新闻发布会上表示，两人就从美国出口管制到可能的合作领域（包括气候变化和低收入国家债务减免）等问题“进行了坦诚、直接和富有成效的讨论”。</p>   <p>The two held talks before the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">Nov. 15-17 Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC)</a> gathering of leaders in San Francisco, which will feature a planned meeting between U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping.翻译:两人在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">11 月 15 日至 17 日在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC)</a>领导人会议之前举行了会谈，美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平计划在此次会议上举行会晤。</p>   <p>Yellen said she accepted an invitation from He, referred to by China's state media as the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-new-economic-tsar-faces-challenges-emulating-his-predecessor-2023-11-01/">director of a powerful Communist Party economic body</a>, to return to China next year as part of a "regular cadence of contact" between the economic leaders.翻译:耶伦表示，她接受了贺建奎的邀请，作为经济领导人之间“定期接触”的一部分，贺建奎明年将返回中国。贺建奎被中国官方媒体称为<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-new-economic-tsar-faces-challenges-emulating-his-predecessor-2023-11-01/">一个强大的共产党经济机构的负责人</a>。</p>   <p>She emphasized that the U.S. has no desire to decouple its economy from China, but wanted a level playing field for U.S. companies and workers.翻译:她强调，美国无意将经济与中国脱钩，而是希望为美国企业和工人提供公平的竞争环境。</p>   <p>"During our discussions, we agreed that in-depth and frank discussions matter, particularly when we disagree," Yellen said. "And I emphasized that the current uncertain global landscape makes it particularly crucial that we maintain resilient lines of communication going forward."</p>    <h 1="">RUSSIA WAR AID</h>  <p>Yellen said that the Treasury has seen evidence that Chinese companies and banks may be aiding in the flow of equipment for use in Russia's war in Ukraine despite Western sanctions, and warned He that these firms <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/yellen-warns-beijing-chinese-firms-aiding-russia-face-significant-consequences-2023-11-10/">"will face significant consequences"</a> if they do.翻译:耶伦表示，财政部已经看到证据表明，尽管受到西方制裁，中国公司和银行可能仍在为俄罗斯在乌克兰战争中使用的设备流动提供援助，并警告贺称，如果这样做，这些公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/yellen-warns-beijing-chinese-firms-aiding-russia-face-significant-consequences-2023-11-10/">“将面临严重后果”</a> 。</p>   <p>"We would like to see China crack down on this, especially when we're able to provide information," Yellen said. She gave no further details on the names of the companies involved or on He's reaction.翻译:耶伦表示：“我们希望看到中国对此进行打击，特别是当我们能够提供信息时。”她没有透露所涉及公司的名称或贺建奎的反应的更多细节。</p>   <p>Discussing the Israel-Hamas war, Yellen spoke of the need "to prevent escalation and expansion of the conflict in the Middle East," the Treasury said in a statement.翻译:美国财政部在一份声明中表示，在讨论以色列与哈马斯战争时，耶伦谈到需要“防止中东冲突升级和扩大”。</p>   <p>Regarding the U.S. Treasury debt market, Yellen said it would be unsurprising to see China reducing holdings of U.S. Treasury debt to support its currency, but China does not publish information about its foreign exchange practices.翻译:关于美国国债市场，耶伦表示，看到中国减持美国国债以支持人民币汇率并不令人意外，但中国并未公布有关其外汇行为的信息。</p>   <p>She said a ransomware attack on China's largest lender, the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/yellen-no-impact-us-treasury-market-icbc-hack-2023-11-10/">was not interfering</a> with the market for U.S. Treasury debt.</p>    <h 1="">COMMON LANGUAGE</h>  <p>Until earlier this year there had been very little contact between Washington and Beijing on economic issues as relations had become fractured during the previous five years, starting with former President Donald Trump's tariff war with Beijing and more recently the increasing U.S. national security restrictions on U.S. technologies.翻译:直到今年早些时候，华盛顿和北京之间在经济问题上的接触还很少，因为从前总统唐纳德·特朗普与北京的关税战开始，到最近美国对美国技术的国家安全限制不断增加，两国关系在过去五年中已经破裂。 。</p>   <p>A change in China's economic leadership had meant that the Treasury needed to build up new contacts in Beijing from scratch, starting with Yellen's trip to Beijing in July, where she first met with He, a senior Treasury official said on Friday.翻译:一位财政部高级官员周五表示，中国经济领导层的变化意味着财政部需要从头开始在北京建立新的联系，从耶伦7月份访问北京开始，她在那里首次会见了贺建奎。</p>   <p>Yellen and He's meetings on Thursday and Friday did not produce any specific actions, but the two sides did agree on some common language to describe the engagement, an unusual step in recent U.S.-China interactions.翻译:耶伦和贺建奎周四和周五的会面没有采取任何具体行动，但双方确实就一些共同语言来描述此次接触达成了一致，这是近期美中互动中不同寻常的一步。</p>   <p>Under the jointly negotiated language, they agreed to "work toward common solutions, address disagreements where possible and avoid misperceptions contributing to unintended escalations."翻译:根据共同谈判的措辞，他们同意“努力寻求共同解决方案，尽可能解决分歧，并避免导致意外升级的误解”。</p>   <p>The two sides agreed to seek "a healthy economic relationship that provides a level playing field for companies and workers in both countries and benefits the two peoples."翻译:双方同意寻求“健康的经济关系，为两国企业和工人提供公平的竞争环境，造福两国人民”。</p>   <p>"Sino-U.S. economic relations are rooted in the common interests of both countries in the economic field, which objectively benefits each other and their people," said Liao Min, Chinese vice Finance Minister.翻译:中国财政部副部长廖敏表示：“中美经济关系植根于两国在经济领域的共同利益，客观上造福于彼此和两国人民。”</p>   <p>"Mutually beneficial cooperation between China and the United States has strong momentum, a solid foundation and broad space, but the pre-requisite is equality and mutual respect."翻译:中美互利合作势头强劲、基础坚实、空间广阔，但前提是平等和相互尊重。</p>   <p>Liao added that he hoped the two countries will work in the same direction and take practical actions to "create the necessary conditions for the maintenance and development of economic relations between the two countries," according to a statement published on the Ministry of Finance website.翻译:根据财政部网站发布的声明，廖补充说，希望两国相向而行，采取实际行动，“为两国经济关系的维护和发展创造必要条件”。</p>   <p>The senior Treasury official acknowledged that the U.S. and China may perceive what constitutes a level playing field differently, but the U.S. side can now point out policies that are inconsistent with that.翻译:这位财政部高级官员承认，美国和中国对公平竞争环境的看法可能不同，但美方现在可以指出与此不一致的政策。</p>   <p>They also committed to strengthen the global financial architecture, including through a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/imf-board-approves-plan-boost-lending-resources-without-shareholding-changes-2023-11-07/">recently approved</a> International Monetary Fund quota funding increase and plans to "increase the voice of under-represented members/regions," a reference to a bigger shareholding for China.翻译:他们还承诺加强全球金融架构，包括通过<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/imf-board-approves-plan-boost-lending-resources-without-shareholding-changes-2023-11-07/">最近批准的</a>国际货币基金组织配额资金增加和计划“增加代表性不足的成员国/地区的发言权”，即中国增加股份。</p>    <span>Reporting by Eric Beech, David Lawder, Ann Saphir, additional reporting and writing by Andrea Shalal and David Ljunggren: Editing by Chizu Nomiyama, Andrea Ricci, Grant McCool, Christian Schmollinger and Simon Cameron-Moore翻译:Eric Beech、David Lawder、Ann Saphir 报道，Andrea Shalal 和 David Ljunggren 补充报道和撰写：Chizu Nomiyama、Andrea Ricci、Grant McCool、Christian Schmollinger 和 Simon Cameron-Moore 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 05:05:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">PKEGR33CWZLXDIRN4ODWGY37SA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/yellen-chinas-he-intensify-communication-after-pre-apec-meetings-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Lawder, Ann Saphir]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA (UPDATE 5, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[官方控制的中国报纸称，美国与英伟达在规则上“抓到我”]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/3ksn8bZ4Jjnq_sFqRCUMT66h7Uk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BJPLE6VYKJMHRL3FU4FCDUP3CI.jpg" alt="U.S. in game of &quot;catch me if you can&quot; with Nvidia on rules - China media翻译:美国与英伟达就规则展开“能追我”的游戏 - 中国媒体" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A smartphone with a displayed NVIDIA logo is placed on a computer motherboard in this illustration taken March 6, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张 2023 年 3 月 6 日拍摄的插图中，一台显示 NVIDIA 徽标的智能手机被放置在计算机主板上。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S. curbs on China have created a game of "catch me if you can" with U.S. chip giant Nvidia and other companies, which affect the interests of both countries and will accelerate Chinese innovation, the Global Times newspaper said on Saturday.翻译:《环球时报》周六称，美国对中国的限制与美国芯片巨头英伟达等公司形成了一场“能抓我”的博弈，这影响到两国利益，也将加速中国的创新。</p>   <p>The chip industry newsletter SemiAnalysisas <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/nvidia-plans-release-three-new-chips-china-local-media-2023-11-09/">reported</a> earlier that Nvidia plans to release new artificial intelligence chips aimed at the Chinese market less than a month after the U.S. tightened rules on selling high-end AI chips to China.翻译:芯片行业时事通讯SemiAnalysisas早些时候<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/nvidia-plans-release-three-new-chips-china-local-media-2023-11-09/">报道</a>称，在美国收紧向中国出售高端人工智能芯片的规定不到一个月后，英伟达计划针对中国市场发布新的人工智能芯片。</p>   <p>"The several rounds between Nvidia and the U.S. government are the story of a high-tech enterprise that does legitimate business but encounters strong political interference in free trade, and tries every means to ensure its own survival and development," the state-controlled newspaper said in a commentary.翻译:《英伟达与美国政府的几轮交锋，是一家从事合法经营的高科技企业在自由贸易方面遭遇强烈政治干预，千方百计确保自身生存和发展的故事》，在评论中说道。</p>   <p>"For commercial companies, this is not funny at all, and even a bit sad."翻译:“对于商业公司来说，这一点都不好笑，甚至有点可悲。”</p>   <p>The U.S. restrictions on chips, which seek to stop China from getting cutting-edge U.S. technologies to strengthen its military, were "not only harmful to China's interests, but also to the U.S.", the newspaper said.翻译:该报称，美国对芯片的限制旨在阻止中国获得美国尖端技术来增强其军事实力，“不仅损害中国的利益，也损害美国”。</p>   <p>"What the U.S. government has done makes normal and legitimate transactions tremble with fear, creating an intense atmosphere in the market," it said.翻译:“美国政府的做法让正常合法的交易都人心惶惶，市场气氛紧张。”</p>   <p>Last month, Nvidia, whose graphics processing units (GPUs) dominate the AI market, said new U.S. export restrictions would <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/nvidia-may-be-forced-shift-out-some-countries-after-new-us-export-curbs-2023-10-17/">block sales</a> of two high-end AI chips, the A800 and H800, that it created for the Chinese market last year to comply with previous export rules.翻译:上个月，图形处理单元（GPU）在人工智能市场占据主导地位的英伟达表示，美国新的出口限制将<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/nvidia-may-be-forced-shift-out-some-countries-after-new-us-export-curbs-2023-10-17/">阻碍其去年为中国市场开发的两款高端人工智能芯片 A800 和 H800 的销售。</a>以前的出口规则。</p>   <p>The new rules put a cap on how much computing power a chip can pack into a small size. They include what analysts call a "grey zone" in which chips might still be allowed to ship to China but will require a license.翻译:新规则对小尺寸芯片所能容纳的计算能力设置了上限。其中包括分析师所说的“灰色地带”，其中芯片可能仍被允许运往中国，但需要许可证。</p>   <p>SemiAnalysis said the new Nvidia chips are called the HGX H20, L20 PCIe and L2 PCIe and the company could announce them on Nov. 16. The chips include most of Nvidia's newest features for but have had some computing power measures cut back, according to the newsletter. Nvidia declined to comment.翻译:SemiAnalysis 表示，新的 Nvidia 芯片被称为 HGX H20、L20 PCIe 和 L2 PCIe，该公司可能会在 11 月 16 日发布。通讯。英伟达拒绝置评。</p>   <p>The Global Times said U.S. companies had been looking for "workarounds" to comply with the regulations.翻译:《环球时报》表示，美国公司一直在寻找“变通办法”以遵守这些规定。</p>   <p>"It is not difficult to imagine that as long as Washington remains committed to 'choking' China, the game of 'catch me if you can' will continue indefinitely," the newspaper said.翻译:该报称，“不难想象，只要华盛顿继续致力于‘扼杀’中国，‘能抓我’的游戏就会无限期地持续下去。”</p>   <p>"In this sense, the 'loopholes' that the U.S. is trying to close will never be completely fixed, and they will only find themselves in an awkward situation of pressing one end of the gourd only to make the other end float up."翻译:从这个意义上说，美国试图堵上的‘漏洞’永远不会被彻底堵住，只会陷入葫芦一头压下去另一头浮上来的尴尬境地。”</p>   <p>"This will inevitably force and accelerate the process of independent innovation in high-tech industries in China."翻译:“这必然倒逼和加速我国高新技术产业自主创新的进程。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Shanghai Newsroom; editing by Robert Birsel翻译:上海新闻编辑室报道；罗伯特·伯塞尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 03:11:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">GFJLVPET6VPONNRYEDQQNYVHZQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-game-catch-me-if-you-can-with-nvidia-rules-china-media-2023-11-11/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>NVIDIA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/COMMENTARY (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[捷克与台湾合作重建乌克兰]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Vi9xu8sTyJpkqACjgR1UfGA0Cs0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/Y7BLUGBGV5JXLM7BNV7GMTKOMU.jpg" alt="Tomas Kopecny, the Czech government envoy for Ukraine, Taiwan deputy foreign minister Roy Lee and David Steinke pose for a group photo after an event in Taipei翻译:捷克政府乌克兰特使托马斯·科佩奇尼、台湾外交部副部长李罗伊和大卫·斯坦克在台北举行的活动后合影" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Tomas Kopecny, the Czech government envoy for Ukraine, Taiwan deputy foreign minister Roy Lee and David Steinke, the Czech representative in Taiwan pose for a group photo after an event in Taipei, Taiwan, November 10, 2023. REUTERS/Ben Blanchard翻译:捷克政府乌克兰问题特使托马斯·科佩奇尼、台湾外交部副部长李罗伊和捷克驻台湾代表大卫·斯坦克于2023年11月10日在台湾台北举行的一次活动后合影。路透社/Ben Blanchard</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Czech and Taiwanese governments signed an agreement on Friday to work together to help reconstruction work in Ukraine, with a senior Czech envoy praising Taipei as a "great ally" despite the absence of formal diplomatic ties.翻译:捷克和台湾政府周五签署了一项协议，共同帮助乌克兰的重建工作，捷克高级特使称赞台北是“伟大的盟友”，尽管没有正式的外交关系。</p>   <p>Ukraine has won broad sympathy in Taiwan after Russia's invasion, with many Taiwanese seeing parallels between Ukraine's situation and the threat Taipei's government says it faces from China, which claims the island as its own territory.翻译:俄罗斯入侵后，乌克兰在台湾赢得了广泛同情，许多台湾人认为乌克兰的局势与台北政府所说的来自中国的威胁有相似之处，中国声称该岛是自己的领土。</p>   <p>Taiwan has donated more than $100 million for humanitarian relief, and joined in Western-led sanctions against Russia. Moscow calls its actions in Ukraine "a special military operation".翻译:台湾已捐赠超过1亿美元用于人道主义救援，并加入西方主导的针对俄罗斯的制裁。莫斯科称其在乌克兰的行动是“一次特别军事行动”。</p>   <p>The agreement between Taiwan and the Czech Republic, signed by the de facto ambassadors in each other's capitals, will see the two working together on rebuilding water and energy systems.翻译:台湾和捷克共和国之间的协议由事实上的驻对方首都大使签署，两国将共同努力重建供水和能源系统。</p>   <p>Visiting Taipei for the signing ceremony, Tomas Kopecny, the Czech government envoy for Ukraine reconstruction, said his country had "such a strong connection with Taiwan".翻译:前往台北参加签字仪式的捷克政府乌克兰重建特使托马斯·科佩奇尼表示，捷克“与台湾有着紧密的联系”。</p>   <p>"We are very happy that the country that is defending us on our behalf, Ukraine, is being supported by our great ally and friend, Taiwan, together with us," Kopecny said at the ceremony at Taiwan's foreign ministry.翻译:科佩奇尼在台湾外交部举行的仪式上表示：“我们非常高兴，代表我们保卫我们的国家乌克兰得到了我们伟大盟友和朋友台湾的支持。”</p>   <p>Taiwan has no formal diplomatic ties with any European country except the Vatican.翻译:除梵蒂冈外，台湾与任何欧洲国家都没有正式外交关系。</p>   <p>But Central and Eastern European countries have been particularly keen to show support for Taiwan - especially following Russia's attack of Ukraine - defying Beijing's anger about such contacts and lessening Taiwan's international diplomatic isolation.翻译:但中欧和东欧国家特别热衷于表达对台湾的支持——尤其是在俄罗斯袭击乌克兰之后——无视北京对此类接触的愤怒，并减轻台湾的国际外交孤立。</p>   <p>China has declined to condemn Russia for the invasion of Ukraine it launched in February 2022 and has maintained close ties, though it has also sent envoys to help peace efforts.翻译:中国拒绝谴责俄罗斯于 2022 年 2 月入侵乌克兰，并与俄罗斯保持着密切关系，但也派出特使帮助和平努力。</p>   <p>Deputy Taiwan Foreign Minister Roy Lee said aid would expand into other areas to assist resume normal life "when Ukraine is approaching final victory".翻译:台湾外交部副部长李在镕表示，援助将扩大到其他领域，以帮助“当乌克兰接近最终胜利时”恢复正常生活。</p>   <p>"It is only the unity of democratic countries that will be able to punish and deter authoritarian countries to make the same wrong decision again," Lee said.翻译:李说：“只有民主国家团结起来，才能惩罚和阻止专制国家再次做出同样的错误决定。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Ben Blanchard; Editing by Angus MacSwan翻译:本·布兰查德报道；安格斯·麦克斯旺编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 01:11:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">CAFMSYZUKRJJ5AI7NOTWNADTG4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/czechs-team-up-with-taiwan-ukraine-reconstruction-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>UKRAINE</category>
                
                <category>CRISIS/CZECH</category>
                
                <category>TAIWAN (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国称拜登将于周三在旧金山湾区会见习近平]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lmawNusCncKAbnw-ni3KMo9Wgcc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/LKENZOOLMZOXFAZTQTIBPFCUBY.jpg" alt="G20 summit in Bali翻译:G20巴厘岛峰会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden shakes hands with Chinese President Xi Jinping as they meet on the sidelines of the G20 leaders' summit in Bali, Indonesia, November 14, 2022.  REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque/File Photo翻译:2022 年 11 月 14 日，美国总统乔·拜登在印度尼西亚巴厘岛举行的二十国集团领导人峰会期间与中国国家主席习近平握手。路透社/凯文·拉马克/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>President Joe Biden will meet Chinese President Xi Jinping face-to-face for the first time in a year on Wednesday, the White House said, in high-stakes diplomacy aimed at curbing tensions between the world's two superpowers.翻译:白宫表示，美国总统乔·拜登将于周三与中国国家主席习近平一年来首次面对面会面，这是旨在遏制世界两个超级大国之间紧张关系的高风险外交。</p>   <p>The closely watched interaction, on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit in the San Francisco Bay area, could last hours and involve teams of officials from Beijing and Washington.翻译:在旧金山湾区举行的亚太经济合作组织（APEC）峰会期间，这场受到密切关注的互动可能会持续几个小时，并有来自北京和华盛顿的官员团队参与。</p>   <p>It is expected to cover global issues from the Israel-Hamas war to Russia's invasion of Ukraine, North Korea's ties with Russia, Taiwan, the Indo-Pacific, human rights, fentanyl, artificial intelligence, as well as "fair" trade and economic relations, senior Biden administration officials said.翻译:预计将涵盖从以色列与哈马斯战争到俄罗斯入侵乌克兰、朝鲜与俄罗斯的关系、台湾、印太、人权、芬太尼、人工智能以及“公平”贸易和经济关系等全球问题。拜登政府高级官员表示。</p>   <p>"Nothing will be held back; everything is on the table," according to one U.S. official, who declined to be named, in a briefing with reporters.翻译:一位不愿透露姓名的美国官员在向记者通报情况时表示，“没有什么会被阻止；一切都摆在桌面上”。</p>   <p>"We're clear-eyed about this. We know efforts to shape or reform China over several decades have failed. But we expect China to be around and to be a major player on the world stage for the rest of our lifetimes."翻译:“我们对此很清楚。我们知道几十年来塑造或改革中国的努力都失败了。但我们预计中国将在我们的有生之年继续存在并成为世界舞台上的主要参与者。”</p>   <p>U.S. officials, who have been pushing for the meeting for the better part of a year, believe Beijing has actively been working to undermine U.S. policy around the world.翻译:美国官员一年多来一直在推动这次会议，他们认为北京一直在积极努力破坏美国的全球政策。</p>   <p>The White House confirmed the day of the meeting in a statement on Friday. The Chinese foreign ministry said on Friday that Xi would visit the United States Nov. 14-17, attend the APEC summit and meet with Biden.翻译:白宫在周五的一份声明中确认了会议的日期。中国外交部周五表示，习近平将于11月14日至17日访问美国，出席亚太经合组织峰会并会见拜登。</p>   <p>Biden and Xi will speak across oceans of ideological difference for the first time since November 2022. The U.S. president's team engineered a diplomatic blitz to repair hostile relations after Biden ordered the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/biden-says-us-is-going-take-care-of-chinese-balloon-2023-02-04/">shooting down of a suspected Chinese spy balloon</a> that transited U.S. skies in February.翻译:拜登和习近平将自 2022 年 11 月以来首次跨越意识形态差异发表讲话。2 月份，拜登下令<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/biden-says-us-is-going-take-care-of-chinese-balloon-2023-02-04/">击落飞越美国上空的疑似中国间谍气球</a>后，美国总统团队发起了一场外交闪电战，以修复敌对关系。</p>   <p>A main result is expected to be greater diplomacy - promises to talk more on key issues, including on climate, global health, economic stability, counter-narcotic efforts and potentially the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-us-military-chill-do-they-talk-all-2023-06-27/">resumption of some</a> military-to-military channels after a high-level freeze.翻译:预计主要结果将是加强外交——承诺就关键问题进行更多对话，包括气候、全球健康、经济稳定、禁毒工作，以及可能在高层冻结后<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-us-military-chill-do-they-talk-all-2023-06-27/">恢复一些</a>军事渠道。</p>   <p>Both sides may make modest gestures of goodwill to ease talks, according to two other people briefed on the discussions.翻译:另两位了解讨论情况的人士表示，双方可能会做出温和的善意姿态，以缓和谈判。</p>   <p>But deep progress will be hard. Both countries increasingly regard themselves as locked in a direct competition to secure a military edge, corner the 21st-century economy and win the affections of second-tier countries, U.S. and Chinese officials say.翻译:但取得深入进展将是困难的。美国和中国官员表示，两国越来越认为自己陷入了直接竞争，以确保军事优势、垄断21世纪经济并赢得二流国家的青睐。</p>   <p>Efforts to carefully choreograph Xi's visit may be upended in the restive Northern California city, which has a long history of left-wing protest and agitation.翻译:在这座躁动不安的北加州城市，精心策划习近平访问的努力可能会被颠覆，这座城市有着悠久的左翼抗议和煽动历史。</p>   <p>Biden and Xi have known each other for more than a decade and shared hours of conversation over six interactions since Biden's 2021 inauguration. But both men come to the table with mutual suspicion, grievances and garbled impressions of what the other is seeking, analysts say.翻译:拜登和习近平已经相识十多年，自拜登 2021 年就职以来，双方进行了六次互动，进行了数小时的交谈。但分析人士称，两人来到谈判桌前时都互相猜疑、不满，并对对方的追求抱有错误的印象。</p>   <p>Among other sensitive topics, Biden is expected to raise Chinese "influence operations" in foreign elections and the status of U.S. citizens that Washington believes are wrongly detained in China.翻译:除其他敏感话题外，预计拜登将提出中国在外国选举中的“影响力行动”，以及华盛顿认为在中国被错误拘留的美国公民的地位。</p>   <p>Biden, 80, presides over an economy that has outperformed expectations and most rich nations after the COVID-19 pandemic. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/biden-approval-falls-lowest-level-since-april-reutersipsos-2023-11-07/">Unpopular with voters at home</a>, he is seeking a second term in office amid concerns about the stability of U.S. democracy.翻译:80 岁的拜登领导的经济在 COVID-19 大流行后的表现超出了预期，也超出了大多数富裕国家的表现。由于对美国民主稳定性的担忧，他<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/biden-approval-falls-lowest-level-since-april-reutersipsos-2023-11-07/">不受国内选民的欢迎</a>，正在寻求连任。</p>   <p>Nonetheless, Biden has corralled the nation's traditional allies from Europe to Asia to confront Russia in Ukraine, although some have differences over the Israel-Hamas conflict.翻译:尽管如此，拜登还是聚集了从欧洲到亚洲的美国传统盟友，在乌克兰对抗俄罗斯，尽管其中一些盟友在以色列与哈马斯冲突问题上存在分歧。</p>   <p>Washington's long alliances, from NATO to the defense treaties in the Pacific, are not-so-quietly being <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/japan-nato-agree-new-partnership-programme-nato-vilnius-summit-2023-07-12/">summoned in Asia</a> to deter a conflict with China.翻译:华盛顿的长期联盟，从北约到太平洋防务条约，正在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/japan-nato-agree-new-partnership-programme-nato-vilnius-summit-2023-07-12/">亚洲不那么悄然地被召唤</a>来阻止与中国的冲突。</p>   <p>Xi, a decade Biden's junior, has become the most powerful Chinese leader since Mao Zedong, after <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/ways-chinas-xi-jinping-amassed-power-over-decade-2022-10-10/">tightening control</a> over policy, state leaders, the media and military and changing the constitution. Recently, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">compounding economic challenges</a> have thrown the country off its three-decade, rocket-propelled growth trajectory.翻译:习近平比拜登小十岁，在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/ways-chinas-xi-jinping-amassed-power-over-decade-2022-10-10/">加强对政策、国家领导人、媒体和军队的控制</a>并修改宪法后，他已成为自毛泽东以来最强大的中国领导人。最近， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">复杂的经济挑战</a>使该国脱离了三年来高速增长的轨道。</p>   <p>Diplomats in Washington expect Beijing to test the United States in coming weeks, taking advantage of the U.S.'s perceived shift in focus on Ukraine and Israel, as it pursues its own ambitions in the Indo-Pacific.翻译:华盛顿的外交官预计，北京将在未来几周内试探美国，利用美国在印度太平洋地区追求自己的野心时将重点转移到乌克兰和以色列的机会。</p>   <p>Biden is expected to tell Xi that U.S. commitments in the Indo-Pacific are unchanged. China has worried its neighbors in recent years with steps in the Taiwan Strait, South China Sea and East China Sea, areas of international dispute. Biden will also express a specific commitment to the security of the Philippines, one of the U.S. officials said.翻译:预计拜登将告诉习近平，美国在印太地区的承诺没有改变。近年来，中国在台湾海峡、南海和东海等国际争议地区采取的行动令邻国感到担忧。一位美国官员表示，拜登还将表达对菲律宾安全的具体承诺。</p>   <p>Biden is also expected to press Xi to impress on Iran that it would be unwise to try to expand the conflict in the Middle East, the official said.翻译:这位官员表示，预计拜登还将向习近平施压，让伊朗明白，试图扩大中东冲突是不明智的。</p>    <span>Reporting by Trevor Hunnicutt; Editing by Heather Timmons, Stephen Coates and Chizu Nomiyiama翻译:特雷弗·亨尼卡特报道；编辑：Heather Timmons、Stephen Coates 和 Chizu Nomiyiama</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 23:51:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MD447PWFBBNODJJN4EJRMWA4RY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-meet-xi-wednesday-san-francisco-bay-area-us-officials-say-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Trevor Hunnicutt]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[耶伦警告北京：中国企业援助俄罗斯面临“重大后果”]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/whNpjXiePujy46LXCmtHVrK1ScE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SFJOCRNJ5BIXXKJO7XN2POKXW4.jpg" alt="U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen arrives for a bilateral meeting with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng in San Francisco翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦抵达旧金山与中国国务院副总理何立峰举行双边会晤" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen attends a press conference after a meeting with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng, ahead of a U.S.-hosted APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 10, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦于 2023 年 11 月 10 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会之前与中国国务院副总理何立峰会面后出席新闻发布会。 REUTERS/Carlos巴里亚</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/sW0XdcgTbck3WX4wDvQJumH80Q8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2MJOMVQXBFOK7ELSKF4TS2DI5M.jpg" alt="U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen arrives for a bilateral meeting with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng in San Francisco翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦抵达旧金山与中国国务院副总理何立峰举行双边会晤" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen attends a press conference after a meeting with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng, ahead of a U.S.-hosted APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 10, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦于 2023 年 11 月 10 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会之前与中国国务院副总理何立峰会面后出席新闻发布会。 REUTERS/Carlos巴里亚</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/0vZdSpJoHT6JwyO3E9UoYkpBmw8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HFKRZWBPVNLB3JIPQHSGRRDRKQ.jpg" alt="U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen arrives for a bilateral meeting with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng in San Francisco翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦抵达旧金山与中国国务院副总理何立峰举行双边会晤" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen attends a press conference after a meeting with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng, ahead of a U.S.-hosted APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 10, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦于 2023 年 11 月 10 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会之前与中国国务院副总理何立峰会面后出席新闻发布会。 REUTERS/Carlos巴里亚</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ros5KW8HeM9vkbt479h2ig80gvU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WIVDNHBEORI7ZJP5XLOMWLBKOY.jpg" alt="U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen arrives for a bilateral meeting with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng in San Francisco翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦抵达旧金山与中国国务院副总理何立峰举行双边会晤" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen attends a press conference after a meeting with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng, ahead of a U.S.-hosted APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 10, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦于 2023 年 11 月 10 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会之前与中国国务院副总理何立峰会面后出席新闻发布会。 REUTERS/Carlos巴里亚</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/D4xBMfJNY-naZ3gsphhDN_drx2Y=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VA5KK4UZ7JL7FIAUOBV5QCM62M.jpg" alt="The United States hosts leaders from APEC nations in San Francisco翻译:美国在旧金山接待亚太经合组织国家领导人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen shakes hands with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng during a bilateral meeting ahead of a U.S.-hosted APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 9, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:2023 年 11 月 9 日，在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会之前，美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦 (Janet Yellen) 在双边会议上与中国国务院副总理何立峰握手。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria</figcaption></figure>                     <p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen on Friday said the U.S. government had seen evidence that Chinese firms may be aiding in the flow of equipment to Russia's war effort despite Western sanctions, and said she had urged China to crack down.翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦周五表示，美国政府已经看到证据表明，尽管受到西方制裁，中国公司可能仍在协助向俄罗斯战争提供设备，并表示她已敦促中国予以打击。</p>   <p>Yellen said she raised the issue during two days of meetings with Chinese Vice Premier He Lifeng, expressing concern that equipment "helpful to Russia's military" was evading sanctions and getting to Moscow to aid its war against Ukraine.翻译:耶伦表示，她在与中国国务院副总理何立峰两天的会晤中提出了这个问题，并对“对俄罗斯军方有帮助”的设备正在逃避制裁并前往莫斯科协助其对乌克兰的战争表示担忧。</p>   <p>"I stressed that companies must not provide material support to Russia's defense industrial sector and that they will face significant consequences if they do," Yellen told reporters at a news conference in San Francisco.翻译:耶伦在旧金山举行的新闻发布会上对记者表示：“我强调，企业不得向俄罗斯国防工业部门提供物质支持，如果这样做，他们将面临严重后果。”</p>   <p>"We are determined to do all that we can to stem this flow of material that aids Russia in conducting this brutal and illegal war," Yellen said, warning that any companies aiding Moscow's war effort could face sanctions.翻译:耶伦表示：“我们决心尽一切努力阻止帮助俄罗斯进行这场残酷和非法战争的物资流动。”他警告说，任何帮助莫斯科战争的公司都可能面临制裁。</p>   <p>She said the U.S. government had already imposed sanctions against a number of private firms, including some in China, that were helping Russia get equipment, along with some financial institutions that could be aiding that effort.翻译:她表示，美国政府已经对一些帮助俄罗斯获取设备的私营企业（包括中国的一些企业）以及一些可能协助这一努力的金融机构实施了制裁。</p>   <p>"We would like to see China crack down on this, especially when we're able to provide information," she said. She gave no further details on the names of the companies involved or He's reaction.翻译:“我们希望看到中国严厉打击这一行为，特别是当我们能够提供信息时，”她说。她没有透露所涉及公司的名称或贺建奎的反应的更多细节。</p>   <p>Yellen stressed the Chinese firms in question were private and said she was not suggesting that this was occurring with knowledge of the Chinese government.翻译:耶伦强调，相关中国公司是私营企业，并表示她并不是说这种情况是在中国政府知情的情况下发生的。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Lawder and Ann Saphir, writing by Andrea Shalal and Alistair Bell翻译:David Lawder 和 Ann Saphir 报道，Andrea Shalal 和 Alistair Bell 撰稿</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 22:00:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">PCZZ3JRTQJLEFFX2GWYOKXQO5M</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/yellen-warns-beijing-chinese-firms-aiding-russia-face-significant-consequences-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Lawder, Ann Saphir]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>YELLEN (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国最大的银行中国工商银行遭受勒索软件攻击]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/-H8rgHIF0Z3r-2YqMnYRluFplH4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4TDXCPGCFVIONOBSA7IY45TYRA.jpg" alt="Industrial and Commercial Bank of China Ltd (ICBC)'s logo is seen at its branch in Beijing翻译:中国工商银行（ICBC）北京分行的标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Industrial and Commercial Bank of China Ltd (ICBC)'s logo is seen at its branch in Beijing翻译:中国工商银行（ICBC）北京分行的标志, China, March 30, 2016. REUTERS/Kim Kyung-Hoon/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Industrial and Commercial Bank of China's (ICBC) U.S. arm was hit by a ransomware attack that disrupted trades in the U.S. Treasury market on Thursday, the latest in a string of victims ransom-demanding hackers have claimed this year.翻译:周四，中国工商银行（ICBC）美国分行遭受勒索软件攻击，扰乱了美国国债市场的交易，这是今年黑客索要赎金的一系列受害者中的最新一起。</p>   <p>ICBC Financial Services, the U.S. unit of China's largest commercial lender by assets, said it was investigating the attack that disrupted some of its systems, and making progress toward recovering from it.翻译:中国资产规模最大的商业银行的美国子公司工银金融服务公司表示，正在调查这起破坏其部分系统的攻击事件，并在恢复方面取得进展。</p>   <p>China's foreign ministry said on Friday the lender is striving to minimise risk impact and losses after the attack.翻译:中国外交部周五表示，该行正在努力将袭击发生后的风险影响和损失降到最低。</p>   <p>"ICBC has been closely monitoring the matter and has done its best in emergency response and supervisory communication," ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin told a regular news conference.翻译:工行新闻发言人汪文斌在例行新闻发布会上表示，工行一直密切关注此事，并尽最大努力做好应急处置和监管沟通。</p>   <p>Wang added businesses remained normal at ICBC head office and other branches and subsidiaries across the globe.翻译:王补充说，工商银行总行及全球其他分支机构的业务保持正常。</p>   <p>Hackers lock up a victim organisation's systems in such attacks and demand ransom for unlocking it, often also stealing sensitive data for extortion.翻译:黑客在此类攻击中锁定受害组织的系统，并索要赎金来解锁系统，通常还窃取敏感数据以进行勒索。</p>   <p>Several ransomware experts and analysts said an aggressive cybercrime gang named Lockbit was believed to be behind the hack, although the gang's dark web site where it typically posts names of its victims did not mention ICBC as a victim as of Thursday evening. Lockbit did not respond to a request for comment sent via a contact address posted on its site.翻译:几位勒索软件专家和分析师表示，据信一个名为 Lockbit 的激进网络犯罪团伙是此次黑客攻击的幕后黑手，尽管该团伙通常在其暗网网站上发布受害者姓名，但截至周四晚间并未提及 ICBC 是受害者。 Lockbit 没有回复通过其网站上发布的联系地址发送的置评请求。</p>   <p>"We don't often see a bank this large get hit with this disruptive of a ransomware attack," said Allan Liska, a ransomware expert at the cybersecurity firm Recorded Future.翻译:网络安全公司 Recorded Future 的勒索软件专家艾伦·利斯卡 (Allan Liska) 表示：“我们很少看到这么大的银行受到如此破坏性的勒索软件攻击。”</p>   <p>Liska, who also believes Lockbit was behind the hack, said ransomware gangs may not name and shame their victims when they are negotiating with them.翻译:利斯卡也认为 Lockbit 是此次黑客攻击的幕后黑手，他表示，勒索软件团伙在与受害者谈判时可能不会点名或羞辱受害者。</p>   <p>"This attack continues a trend of increasing brazenness by ransomware groups," he said. "With no fear of repercussions, ransomware groups feel no target is off limits."翻译:他说：“这次攻击延续了勒索软件组织日益肆无忌惮的趋势。” “由于不担心后果，勒索软件组织认为没有任何目标是不受限制的。”</p>   <p>U.S. authorities have struggled to curb a rash of cybercrime, chiefly ransomware attacks, which hit hundreds of companies in nearly every industry each year. Just last week <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/alliance-40-countries-vow-not-pay-ransom-cybercriminals-us-says-2023-10-31/">U.S. officials said</a> they were working on curtailing the funding routes of ransomware gangs by improving information-sharing on such criminals across a 40-country alliance.翻译:美国当局一直在努力遏制一系列网络犯罪，主要是勒索软件攻击，这些攻击每年都会袭击几乎每个行业的数百家公司。就在上周， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/alliance-40-countries-vow-not-pay-ransom-cybercriminals-us-says-2023-10-31/">美国官员表示，</a>他们正在通过 40 个国家联盟改善有关此类犯罪分子的信息共享，努力减少勒索软件团伙的资金来源。</p>   <p>The ICBC did not comment on whether Lockbit was behind the hack. It is common for targets to refrain from publicly disclosing the names of cybercrime gangs.翻译:ICBC 没有评论 Lockbit 是否是此次黑客攻击的幕后黑手。目标通常不会公开披露网络犯罪团伙的名称。</p>   <p>Since Lockbit was discovered in 2020, the group has hit 1,700 U.S. organizations, according to the U.S. Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA). Last month it <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/boeing-assessing-lockbit-hacking-gang-threat-sensitive-data-leak-2023-10-27/">threatened Boeing with a leak</a> of sensitive data.翻译:据美国网络安全和基础设施安全局 (CISA) 称，自 2020 年 Lockbit 被发现以来，该组织已攻击 1,700 个美国组织。上个月，它<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/boeing-assessing-lockbit-hacking-gang-threat-sensitive-data-leak-2023-10-27/">威胁波音公司泄露</a>敏感数据。</p>   <p>A CISA spokesperson referred questions about the ICBC hack to the U.S. Treasury Department.翻译:CISA 发言人将有关 ICBC 黑客攻击的问题转交给了美国财政部。</p>   <p>While market sources said the impact of the hack appeared limited, it signalled how vulnerable systems at large organizations such as the bank continue to be. Thursday's incident is likely to raise questions over market participants' cybersecurity controls and draw regulatory scrutiny.</p>    <h 1="">TRADES CLEARED</h>  <p>ICBC said it had successfully cleared Treasury trades executed on Wednesday and repurchase agreements (repo) financing trades done on Thursday.翻译:中国工商银行表示，已成功清算周三执行的国债交易和周四执行的回购协议融资交易。</p>   <p>"In general, the event had a limited impact on the market," said Scott Skyrm, executive vice president for fixed income and repo at broker-dealer Curvature Securities.翻译:经纪交易商 Curvature Securities 负责固定收益和回购的执行副总裁 Scott Skyrm 表示：“总的来说，该事件对市场的影响有限。”</p>   <p>Some market participants said trades going through ICBC were not settled due to the attack and affected market liquidity. It was not clear whether this contributed to the weak outcome of a 30-year bond auction on Thursday.翻译:一些市场人士表示，由于袭击事件，通过工行进行的交易未能结算，影响了市场流动性。目前尚不清楚这是否导致了周四 30 年期债券拍卖的疲弱结果。</p>   <p>"There could have been maybe some technical issues with some participants not being able to access the market fully on the day," said Michael Gladchun, associate portfolio manager, core plus fixed income, at Loomis Sayles.翻译:Loomis Sayles 核心+固定收益副投资组合经理 Michael Gladchun 表示：“可能存在一些技术问题，部分参与者当天无法完全进入市场。”</p>   <p>The Financial Times reported earlier on Thursday that the U.S. Securities Industry and Financial Markets Association (SIFMA) told members that ICBC <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601398.SS" target="_blank">(601398.SS)</a> had been hit by ransomware that disrupted the U.S. Treasury market by preventing it from settling trades on behalf of other market players.翻译:英国《金融时报》周四早些时候报道称，美国证券业和金融市场协会（SIFMA）告诉会员，中国工商银行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601398.SS" target="_blank">（601398.SS）</a>遭到勒索软件攻击，勒索软件阻止其代表其他市场结算交易，扰乱了美国国债市场玩家。</p>   <p>"We are aware of the cybersecurity issue and are in regular contact with key financial sector participants, in addition to federal regulators. We continue to monitor the situation," a Treasury spokesperson said in a response to a question about the FT report. SIFMA declined to comment.翻译:“我们意识到了网络安全问题，除了联邦监管机构之外，我们还与主要金融部门参与者保持定期联系。我们将继续关注事态发展，”财政部发言人在回答有关《金融时报》报告的问题时表示。 SIFMA拒绝发表评论。</p>   <p>The Treasury market appeared to be functioning normally on Thursday, according to LSEG data.翻译:根据伦敦证券交易所数据，周四国债市场似乎运行正常。</p>   <p>(This story has been refiled to fix the spelling of analyst's name in paragraph 17)翻译:（这篇报道已重新归档，以修正第 17 段中分析师姓名的拼写）</p>    <span>Reporting by Urvi Dugar in Bengaluru and Pete Schroder in Washington; Additional reporting by Gertrude Chavez-Dreyfuss, Davide Barbuscia, Carolina Mandl, Paritosh Bansal and Joe Cash; Editing by Stephen Coates and Tomasz Janowski翻译:Urvi Dugar 在班加罗尔和 Pete Schroder 在华盛顿的报道； Gertrude Chavez-Dreyfuss、Davide Barbuscia、Carolina Mandl、Paritosh Bansal 和 Joe Cash 的补充报道；斯蒂芬·科茨和托马斯·雅诺夫斯基编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 17:14:24 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">VBXWF64MS5LINE3N466YFWUWHY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-largest-bank-icbc-hit-by-ransomware-software-ft-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Pete Schroeder, Zeba Siddiqui]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ICBC</category>
                
                <category>HACK/ (CORRECTED, UPDATE 9, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[菲律宾谴责中国“无端胁迫行为”阻止补给任务]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tsU7yVP9535QCIzldv4Bbub1lvo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HIV2JPEUHJPYHNYM64VVRTCLTM.jpg" alt="National flags are placed outside a room where Philippine Finance Secretary Carlos Dominguez and China's Commerce Minister Gao Hucheng address reporters after their meeting in Beijing翻译:菲律宾财政部长卡洛斯·多明计斯和中国商务部部长高虎城在北京会晤后向记者发表讲话的房间外悬挂着国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>National flags are placed outside a room where Philippine Finance Secretary Carlos Dominguez and China's Commerce Minister Gao Hucheng address reporters after their meeting in Beijing翻译:菲律宾财政部长卡洛斯·多明计斯和中国商务部部长高虎城在北京会晤后向记者发表讲话的房间外悬挂着国旗, China, January 23, 2017. REUTERS/Damir Sagolj/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Philippines on Friday condemned China's coast guard for "unprovoked acts of coercion and dangerous manoeuvres," including its use of a water cannon against one of its boats in an attempt to disrupt a resupply mission in the South China Sea.翻译:菲律宾周五谴责中国海警“无端胁迫和危险举动”，包括对一艘船只使用高压水枪，试图扰乱在南海的补给任务。</p>   <p>China's actions, the Philippines said, have not only "put the lives of our people at risk," but have "put into question and significant doubt the sincerity of its calls for peaceful dialogue".翻译:菲律宾表示，中国的行为不仅“将我国人民的生命置于危险之中”，而且“让人对其呼吁和平对话的诚意产生质疑和严重怀疑”。</p>   <p>The regular resupply missions support the Philippines' troops stationed in an intentionally grounded dilapidated warship on Second Thomas Shoal, a hotly disputed atoll in the South China Sea that Manila calls Ayungin and is known as Renai Reef in China.翻译:这些定期补给任务为驻扎在仁爱礁的一艘故意搁浅的破旧军舰上的菲律宾军队提供支持。仁爱礁是南海有争议的一个环礁，马尼拉称之为阿云金岛，在中国被称为仁爱礁。</p>   <p>China claims almost the entire South China Sea, including the Second Thomas Shoal, and has deployed hundreds of vessels to patrol there.翻译:中国对包括仁爱礁在内的几乎整个南海拥有主权，并部署了数百艘船只在那里巡逻。 These include what Manila refers to as "Chinese maritime militia", which it said were involved in the latest attempt to obstruct the resupply mission.翻译:中国对包括仁爱礁在内的几乎整个南海拥有主权，并部署了数百艘船只在那里巡逻。其中包括马尼拉所说的“中国海上民兵”，菲律宾称这些民兵参与了最近一次阻挠补给任务的企图。</p>   <p>Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin said on Friday at a regular press conference that Beijing opposes actions that undermine China's sovereignty and interests and has lodged solemn representations with the Philippine embassy.翻译:中国外交部发言人汪文斌周五在例行记者会上表示，中方反对损害中国主权和利益的行为，已向菲律宾驻华使馆提出严正交涉。</p>   <p>China's coast guard said two small Philippine transport ships and three coast guard ships entered the waters without the permission of the Chinese government and urged the Philippines to stop infringing on Beijing's sovereignty.翻译:中国海警表示，两艘菲律宾小型运输船和三艘海警船未经中国政府许可进入该海域，并敦促菲律宾停止侵犯北京主权。</p>   <p>It said in a statement its actions were lawful and it has and made temporary special arrangements for the Philippine side to transport food and other necessary daily necessities翻译:声明称，其行为合法，已为菲方运输食品等必要生活物资作出临时特别安排。</p>   <p>In a second statement late on Friday, the coast guard said that the Philippine vessels had insisted on "rushing into" the area in an "unsafe and unprofessional" manner, and that it approached the vessels for verification purposes.翻译:在周五晚些时候的第二份声明中，海岸警卫队表示，菲律宾船只坚持以“不安全和不专业”的方式“冲入”该地区，并称其接近这些船只是为了核实情况。</p>   <p>The Philippines' government said the resupply mission was completed, even as its boats were "subjected to extremely reckless and dangerous harassment at close proximity" by the Chinese coast guard's inflatable boats inside the shoal.翻译:菲律宾政府表示，补给任务已经完成，尽管其船只在浅滩内“受到了中国海警充气艇极其鲁莽和危险的近距离骚扰”。</p>   <p>For years, Manila and Beijing have been embroiled in on-off confrontations at the Second Thomas Shoal as China has become more assertive in pressing its maritime claims, alarming rival claimants and other states operating in the South China Sea, including the United States and Japan.翻译:多年来，马尼拉和北京在仁爱礁陷入断断续续的对抗，因为中国在提出海洋主张方面变得更加自信，这令其他声索国和包括美国和日本在内的在南海活动的其他国家感到震惊。 。</p>   <p>Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida said during his visit to Manila on Saturday that his country, the Philippines and the United States were <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/japan-pm-kishida-cooperating-with-philippines-us-protect-south-china-sea-2023-11-04/">cooperating</a> to protect the freedom of the South China Sea.翻译:日本首相岸田文雄周六访问马尼拉时表示，日本、菲律宾和美国正在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/japan-pm-kishida-cooperating-with-philippines-us-protect-south-china-sea-2023-11-04/">合作</a>保护南海的自由。</p>   <p>On Thursday, the Philippines said it was acquiring five 97-metre (318-ft) multi-role response vessels to strengthen the capabilities of its coast guard and the 29.3 billion pesos ($524 million) project would be funded by Official Development Assistance loans from Japan.翻译:周四，菲律宾表示将采购五艘 97 米（318 英尺）多用途响应船，以加强其海岸警卫队的能力，该耗资 293 亿比索（5.24 亿美元）的项目将由来自菲律宾的官方发展援助贷款提供资金。日本。</p>   <p>Both Japan and Washington have their support behind a 2016 ruling by the Permanent Court of Arbitration in the Hague, that said Beijing's expansive claims had no legal basis, delivering a historic legal victory for the Philippines. Under the ruling, the shoal is inside the Philippines' exclusive economic zone.翻译:日本和华盛顿都支持海牙常设仲裁法院 2016 年的一项裁决，该裁决称北京的广泛主张没有法律依据，为菲律宾带来了历史性的法律胜利。根据裁决，该浅滩位于菲律宾专属经济区内。</p>   <p>China's use of water cannons followed a series of incidents in the South China Sea, including the collisions between China's vessels and two Manila ships on Oct. 22. The Philippines accused China coastguard of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-tells-china-stop-provocative-actions-south-china-sea-2023-10-23/">"intentionally"</a> colliding with its vessels.翻译:中国在南海发生一系列事件后使用了高压水枪，其中包括10月22日中国船只与马尼拉两艘船只相撞。菲律宾指责中国海警<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/philippines-tells-china-stop-provocative-actions-south-china-sea-2023-10-23/">“故意”</a>与其船只相撞。</p>   <p>($1 = 55.9200 Philippine pesos)翻译:（1 美元 = 55.9200 菲律宾比索）</p>    <span>Reporting by Beijing newsroom, and Neil Jerome Morales in Manila; Writing by Bernard Orr; Editing by Christopher Cushing, Gerry Doyle, Christina Fincher and Hugh Lawson翻译:北京新闻编辑室和马尼拉尼尔·杰罗姆·莫拉莱斯的报道；伯纳德·奥尔撰写；编辑：克里斯托弗·库欣、格里·多伊尔、克里斯蒂娜·芬奇和休·劳森</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 14:28:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MEV2HDONWJPK7OF2LYBQDX5K6M</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-coast-guard-urges-philippines-stop-infringing-sovereignty-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PHILIPPINES/ (UPDATE 4)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国的光棍节是什么？如何庆祝？]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/VkvrXmdXWcirVHKKUbx-d425s0Y=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2ZAYINITJRIBZPAYBX53Z2I25A.jpg" alt="People walk past an Alibaba's advertisement promoting Singles Day shopping festival, in Beijing翻译:北京，人们走过阿里巴巴宣传双十一购物节的广告" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk past Alibaba's advertisements promoting Singles Day shopping festival, at a subway station in Beijing, China October 26, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年10月26日，中国北京的一个地铁站，人们走过阿里巴巴宣传双十一购物节的广告。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tQpvMgT9JpSZraUytdfg8wES3jo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TYTWYBCEBVOOXHD66PISCVTSSI.jpg" alt="Woman stands near an Alibaba's advertisement promoting Singles Day shopping festival in Beijing翻译:北京，一位女士站在阿里巴巴宣传双十一购物节的广告附近" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A woman stands near an Alibaba's advertisement promoting Singles Day shopping festival, at a bus stop in Beijing, China October 26, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023 年 10 月 26 日，中国北京的一个公交车站，一名妇女站在阿里巴巴宣传双十一购物节的广告附近。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>               <p>Black Friday? No. Cyber Monday? Nope. Prime Day? Absolutely not. The world's biggest shopping event happens in China each year - and it's called Singles Day.翻译:黑色星期五？不。网络星期一？没有。黄金日？绝对不。世界上最大的购物活动每年都会在中国举行，这天被称为“光棍节”。</p>   <p>Originally a holiday to celebrate being single, as a counter to Valentine's Day, the event has grown into a weeks-long online shopping festival that peaks on Nov. 11.</p>    <h 1="">WHEN DID THE IDEA OF SINGLES DAY ORIGINATE?</h>  <p>The idea for Singles Day had originated at China's Nanjing University back in 1993 and was originally called "Bachelor's Day." On the day, single people treat themselves with gifts and presents, while also organizing social gatherings and parties.</p>    <h 1="">HOW MUCH DO CONSUMERS SPEND?</h>  <p>Last year, the total value of goods sold during the shopping bonanza - also known as "Double 11" - totaled 1.15 trillion yuan ($157.97 billion), according to data from consultancy firm Bain.翻译:根据咨询公司贝恩的数据，去年购物热潮（又称“双11”）期间销售的商品总价值达1.15万亿元人民币（1579.7亿美元）。</p>   <p>That is more than four times the $35.3 billion U.S. shoppers spent last year during Cyber Week, the period from Black Friday to Cyber Monday, per data from Adobe Analytics.翻译:根据 Adob​​e Analytics 的数据，这是去年美国购物者在网络周（即黑色星期五到网络星期一期间）花费的 353 亿美元的四倍多。</p>   <p>Cyber Monday immediately follows Black Friday, which falls on the day after the U.S. Thanksgiving Day holiday, the busiest shopping day of the year in the United States.翻译:网络星期一紧随黑色星期五之后，黑色星期五恰逢美国感恩节假期后的第二天，这是美国一年中最繁忙的购物日。</p>   <p>But growth has been slowing even as overall sales for Singles Day hit record highs, with last year's 3% rise marking the slowest increase ever. The event has in recent years lost some of its novelty with the rise of other shopping festivals in China, including the midyear "618" sales that are the country's second largest.翻译:但尽管双十一的整体销售额创下历史新高，增长速度却一直在放缓，去年的增长 3%，创下有史以来最慢的增幅。近年来，随着中国其他购物节的兴起，其中包括中国第二大购物节“618”，该活动失去了一些新鲜感。</p>      <p>Strict COVID-19 curbs in China impacted sales last year, but several industry experts are expecting a rebound, as the economy improves and livestream sales remain robust.翻译:中国对 COVID-19 的严格限制影响了去年的销售，但几位行业专家预计，随着经济好转和直播销售保持强劲，销量将会反弹。</p>   <p>"We're optimistic about growth this year because the recovery seems to be stabilizing and consumption is on a more clear upward trend," said Jacob Cooke, co-founder and CEO of Beijing-based WPIC Marketing + Technologies.翻译:总部位于北京的 WPIC Marketing + Technologies 联合创始人兼首席执行官雅各布·库克 (Jacob Cooke) 表示：“我们对今年的增长持乐观态度，因为复苏似乎正在趋于稳定，消费呈现出更加明显的上升趋势。”</p>   <p>His e-commerce consultancy firm expects sales for the Chinese shopping event to rise in the range between 14% and 18% from last year, which is higher than Adobe's projection for a 5.4% rise in Cyber Week sales.</p>    <h 1="">WHAT MAJOR BRANDS AND PRODUCTS ARE SHOPPERS BUYING?</h>  <p>While <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/alibaba-banks-aggressive-singles-day-pricing-recoup-sales-mojo-2023-10-31/">Alibaba 9988.HK started "Double 11"</a> in 2009 to win over online shoppers with discounts and promotions, China's major e-commerce platforms now all take part in it.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/alibaba-banks-aggressive-singles-day-pricing-recoup-sales-mojo-2023-10-31/">阿里巴巴9988.HK于2009年启动“双11”，</a>以打折促销的方式吸引网购消费者，如今中国各大电商平台都参与其中。</p>   <p>JD.com <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9618.HK" target="_blank">(9618.HK)</a> joined in 2012 and PDD Holdings-owned <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PDD.O" target="_blank">(PDD.O)</a> Pinduoduo has also become a significant player, offering low cost products in competition with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/alibaba-promises-major-discounts-ahead-chinas-singles-day-shopping-event-2023-10-23/">Alibaba-owned Tmall and Taobao platforms</a>.翻译:京东<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9618.HK" target="_blank">（9618.HK）</a>于2012年加入，拼多多控股<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PDD.O" target="_blank">（PDD.O）</a>拼多多也成为重要参与者，提供低成本产品，与<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/alibaba-promises-major-discounts-ahead-chinas-singles-day-shopping-event-2023-10-23/">阿里巴巴旗下的天猫和淘宝平台</a>竞争。</p>   <p>Last year, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/pickup-us-cyber-week-sales-beat-chinas-singles-day-gain-2022-11-29/">Chinese shoppers spent more on essentials</a>, supplements, vitamins and pet-care products. Those products are expected to stay in demand this year, along with more lifestyle-focused products such as athletic wear and sports equipment.翻译:去年， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/pickup-us-cyber-week-sales-beat-chinas-singles-day-gain-2022-11-29/">中国消费者在必需品、补充剂、维生素和宠物护理产品上的支出增加</a>。这些产品以及运动服装和运动器材等更多注重生活方式的产品预计今年将保持需求。</p>   <p>"There is enormous demand among Chinese consumers for products and services that improve their lifestyles and facilitate self-expression," Cooke said.</p>    <h 1="">HOW DOES SINGLES DAY COMPARE TO BLACK FRIDAY?</h>  <p>In comparison, U.S. shoppers last year had bought more Pokemon toys, Hot Wheels, TVs, footwear and air fryers during the key Black Friday and Cyber Monday shopping periods, according to Adobe.翻译:据 Adob​​e 称，相比之下，去年美国消费者在黑色星期五和网络星期一的关键购物时段购买了更多的口袋妖怪玩具、风火轮、电视、鞋类和空气炸锅。</p>   <p>From 2014 until 2021, Singles Day had <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/pickup-us-cyber-week-sales-beat-chinas-singles-day-gain-2022-11-29/">posted growth rates of about 34% annually</a> on average, versus Cyber Week's 17% average gain, according to data from consultancy Bain and from Adobe Analytics.</p>    <h 1="">WHAT OTHER COMPANIES HOPE TO BENEFIT?</h>  <p>Several American companies from apparel makers Nike <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NKE.N" target="_blank">(NKE.N)</a> and Lululemon <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LULU.O" target="_blank">(LULU.O)</a> to cosmetics firm Estee Lauder <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/EL.N" target="_blank">(EL.N)</a> and consumer goods giant Procter &amp; Gamble <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PG.N" target="_blank">(PG.N)</a> have a big presence on the Tmall marketplace and stand to benefit from the event.翻译:从服装制造商耐克<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NKE.N" target="_blank">(NKE.N)</a>和 Lululemon <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LULU.O" target="_blank">(LULU.O)</a>到化妆品公司雅诗兰黛<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/EL.N" target="_blank">(EL.N)</a>和消费品巨头宝洁公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PG.N" target="_blank">(PG.N) 等</a>多家美国公司在天猫市场上占有重要地位，并能从此次活动中获益。</p>   <p>Last year, Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a>, Nike and L'Oreal <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/OREP.PA" target="_blank">(OREP.PA)</a> were also among the biggest winners from the event, along with Chinese home appliance makers such as Haier and Midea and sportswear brand Anta.翻译:去年，苹果<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a> 、耐克和欧莱雅<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/OREP.PA" target="_blank">(OREP.PA)</a>也是该活动的最大赢家，此外还有海尔、美的等中国家电制造商以及运动服装品牌安踏。</p>   <p>Nike said in December "Double 11" demand in Greater China grew by mid-teens, outpacing the broader sports industry, with demand from Gen Z consumers for the brand growing by 45% during the shopping period in China on Tmall.翻译:耐克表示，去年 12 月“双 11”期间，大中华区的需求增长了 15%，超过了整个体育行业的增速，Z 世代消费者在中国天猫购物期间对该品牌的需求增长了 45%。</p>   <p>JD.com had <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/alibabas-singles-day-shopping-event-set-end-with-subdued-sales-no-fanfare-2022-11-10/">noted</a> Apple sold more than 1 billion yuan worth of products in the first minute of the event's final sales period.翻译:京东<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/alibabas-singles-day-shopping-event-set-end-with-subdued-sales-no-fanfare-2022-11-10/">指出</a>，苹果在活动最后销售期的第一分钟就售出了价值超过10亿元人民币的产品。</p>   <p>However, for this year, several global companies ranging from <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/loreal-shares-down-33-after-q3-sales-miss-2023-10-20/">L'Oreal</a> to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/estee-lauder-cuts-annual-profit-outlook-weaker-recovery-asia-travel-retail-2023-11-01/">Estee Lauder</a> have taken a cautious stance around the spending spree in China during the shopping event.翻译:然而，今年，从<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/loreal-shares-down-33-after-q3-sales-miss-2023-10-20/">欧莱雅</a>到<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/estee-lauder-cuts-annual-profit-outlook-weaker-recovery-asia-travel-retail-2023-11-01/">雅诗兰黛</a>等多家跨国公司都对购物活动期间在中国的消费热潮持谨慎态度。</p>   <p>"The presale period of Tmall and particularly on -- in general, the Singles Day, confirms a softer trend versus a year ago," said Estee Lauder CEO Fabrizio Freda last week, adding that the company was more optimistic about the next part of the Singles Day events in November.翻译:雅诗兰黛首席执行官法布里奇奥·弗雷达 (Fabrizio Freda) 上周表示：“天猫的预售期，尤其是双十一，证实了与一年前相比疲软的趋势。”他补充说，该公司对接下来的销售情况更加乐观。十一月的光棍节活动。</p>   <p>L'Oreal CEO Nicolas Hieronimus on a post earnings call with analysts in October said it was too soon to comment on "Double 11."翻译:欧莱雅首席执行官 Nicolas Hieronimus 在 10 月份与分析师举行的财报电话会议上表示，现在对“双 11”发表评论还为时过早。</p>   <p>"The shy consumers are less shy during the big events, and we have seen that whether it's during Valentine's Day, whether it is 6/18, the market has had its best peaks of growth during this moment," Hieronimus said, adding he had lots of hope for the shopping bonanza.翻译:Hieronimus 表示：“害羞的消费者在大型活动期间不再那么害羞，我们看到，无论是情人节期间，还是 6/18，市场都在这一刻迎来了最佳的增长高峰。”对购物狂潮抱有很大的希望。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2800 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2800 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Granth Vanaik in Bengaluru; Editing by Aditya Soni and Diane Craft翻译:Granth Vanaik 在班加罗尔的报道； Aditya Soni 和 Diane Craft 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 13:01:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">GHLGUN7W2BOCVGZXECIIRMMEJE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/what-is-chinas-singles-day-how-is-it-celebrated-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Granth Vanaik]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HOLIDAYSHOPPING</category>
                
                <category>SINGLES DAY/ (REPEAT, EXPLAINER, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[爱沙尼亚称中国船只是电缆损坏调查的主要焦点]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/yDdE86SbMhp0LSEbsTq4PV4PDRM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XDFRITUO3FNAFICPLGKIKVXOQE.jpg" alt="Finnish Border Guard's photo of a Hong Kong registered cargo ship 'Newnew Polar Bear'翻译:芬兰边防卫队拍摄的香港注册货船“Newnew Polar Bear”号的照片" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Finnish Border Guard's photo of a Hong Kong registered cargo ship 'Newnew Polar Bear'翻译:芬兰边防卫队拍摄的香港注册货船“Newnew Polar Bear”号的照片, which was spotted moving close to the Balticconnector gas line, during the joint press conference of the investigation of the possible attack on the Balticconnector gas line on 8th Oct., 2023 between Finland and Estonia at the headquarters of the National Bureau of Investigation in Vantaa, Finland, 24 October 2023.  Lehtikuva/HEIKKI SAUKKOMAA via REUTERS /File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Estonian prosecutors said on Friday the Hong Kong-registered NewNew Polar Bear container ship was the main focus of their investigations into the damage of two subsea telecoms cables last month.翻译:爱沙尼亚检察官周五表示，在香港注册的NewNew Polar Bear集装箱船是他们对上个月两条海底电信电缆受损情况进行调查的主要焦点。</p>   <p>Soon after, police from Estonia's near neighbour Finland said an anchor found on the sea bed next to a gas pipeline damaged on the same night probably belonged to the same ship, building on <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/finland-retrieves-anchor-seabed-near-broken-gas-pipeline-2023-10-24/">earlier inquiries</a>.翻译:不久之后，爱沙尼亚近邻芬兰警方表示，根据<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/finland-retrieves-anchor-seabed-near-broken-gas-pipeline-2023-10-24/">之前的调查，</a>当晚在受损的天然气管道旁边的海床上发现的一个锚可能属于同一艘船。</p>   <p>Officials from both countries have said they are looking into <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-cooperating-balticconnector-investigation-finland-says-2023-10-31/">the ship's role</a>, as its movements on Oct. 7-8 matched the time and place of the damage. It is the first time Estonia has said it was the primary scenario it was investigating.翻译:两国官员均表示，他们正在调查<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-cooperating-balticconnector-investigation-finland-says-2023-10-31/">这艘船的作用</a>，因为该船 10 月 7 日至 8 日的行动与受损的时间和地点相符。这是爱沙尼亚第一次表示这是其正在调查的主要情况。</p>   <p>China has previously said it is willing to provide necessary information on the incident in accordance with international law. NewNew Shipping, the owner and operator of the NewNew Polar Bear, has previously declined to comment when contacted by Reuters.翻译:中方此前曾表示，愿意根据国际法就该事件提供必要信息。 NewNew Polar Bear 的所有者和运营商 NewNew Shipping 此前在路透社联系时拒绝置评。</p>   <p>NATO stepped up its patrols in the Baltic Sea after the damage was reported.翻译:受损情况报告后，北约加强了在波罗的海的巡逻。</p>   <p>Estonia's prosecutor general said on Friday the main lead they were following was that "damage to the telecom cables between Estonia and Finland and Estonia and Sweden is connected to the vessel Newnew Polar Bear flying the flag of Hong Kong".翻译:爱沙尼亚总检察长周五表示，他们关注的主要线索是“爱沙尼亚与芬兰、爱沙尼亚与瑞典之间的电信电缆受损与悬挂香港旗帜的Newnew Polar Bear号船只有关”。</p>   <p>"We prepared a legal assistance request to China so that the local law enforcement authorities would perform the procedural operations, primarily those connected to the vessel and its crew," State Prosecutor Triinu Olev said in a statement.翻译:国家检察官特里努·奥列夫(Triinu Olev)在一份声明中表示：“我们向中国准备了一份法律援助请求，以便当地执法机构执行程序行动，主要是与船只及其船员有关的行动。”</p>   <p>A criminal investigation into the Estonia-Finland cable had now been formally extended to cover the other cable to Sweden after investigators concluded that had also been damaged by human activity, the prosecutor added.翻译:检察官补充说，在调查人员得出结论认为该电缆也受到人类活动损坏后，对爱沙尼亚-芬兰电缆的刑事调查现已正式扩大到另一条通往瑞典的电缆。</p>   <p>Finland's police force said on Friday evidence suggested the anchor likely belonged to the NewNew Polar Bear, and that paint from that anchor had been found on the damaged Balticconnector gas pipeline between Finland and Estonia.翻译:芬兰警方周五表示，有证据表明该锚可能属于“新新北极熊”号，并且在芬兰和爱沙尼亚之间受损的波罗的海连接器天然气管道上发现了该锚上的油漆。</p>   <p>"At this stage we can state that the anchor lifted from the sea ... may for some technical details be considered to belong to Newnew Polar Bear," detective superintendent Risto Lohi said, without spelling out the technical details.翻译:侦探警司里斯托·洛希 (Risto Lohi) 表示：“现阶段我们可以说，从海上升起的锚……从某些技术细节来看，可能被认为属于纽纽北极熊。”但他没有详细说明技术细节。</p>   <p>Finland's Foreign Minister Elina Valtonen on Wednesday said China had promised full cooperation with their investigation.翻译:芬兰外交部长埃琳娜·瓦尔托宁周三表示，中国已承诺全力配合他们的调查。</p>   <p>Reuters has reported that two vessels, the NewNew Polar Bear and the Russia-flagged Sevmorput, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/chinese-russian-vessels-vicinity-baltic-sea-links-damage-vessel-tracking-data-2023-10-20/">were present</a> near the cables and pipeline around the time of the damage, according to data from MarineTraffic, a ship-tracking and maritime analytics provider.翻译:路透社报道称，根据船舶跟踪和海事分析提供商 MarineTraffic 的数据，在损坏发生时，两艘船“NewNew Polar Bear”和“悬挂俄罗斯国旗的 Sevmorput” <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/chinese-russian-vessels-vicinity-baltic-sea-links-damage-vessel-tracking-data-2023-10-20/">出现</a>在电缆和管道附近。</p>    <span>Reporting by Andrius Sytas in Vilnius and Essi Lehto in Helsinki, editing by Terje Solsvik, Christina Fincher and Andrew Heavens翻译:Andrius Sytas 在维尔纽斯和 Essi Lehto 在赫尔辛基报道，Terje Solsvik、Christina Fincher 和 Andrew Heavens 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 12:15:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7EUZM7M42BJ27J3NOKW44QQJPY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/estonia-says-chinese-ship-is-main-focus-probe-into-cables-damage-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Andrius Sytas, Essi Lehto]]></author>
            
                
                <category>FINLAND</category>
                
                <category>ESTONIA/GAS (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国商务部长与欧盟布雷顿讨论贸易关系、电动汽车等问题]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ajeD7mEQL9lfEM2cB1fJRHhjABc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/RAYJICJNZZMENG2W3TEWPJ2F4Y.jpg" alt="China Development Forum 2023 in Beijing翻译:2023年中国发展高层论坛在北京举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>China's Commerce Minister Wang Wentao delivers a speech at the China Development Forum 2023, in Beijing, China, March 26, 2023. REUTERS/Jing Xu/File Photo翻译:中国商务部部长王文涛于2023年3月26日在中国北京举行的2023年中国发展高层论坛上发表讲话。路透社/Jing Xu/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's Commerce Minister Wang Wentao had "in-depth" discussions with the EU's industry chief Thierry Breton on China-EU trade relations, electric vehicles, 5G, supply chain and other topics on Friday.翻译:中国商务部部长王文涛周五与欧盟工业委员会主席蒂埃里·布雷顿就中欧贸易关系、电动汽车、5G、供应链等话题进行了“深入”讨论。</p>   <p>Wang also raised China's concerns about the EU's anti-subsidy investigations over China's electric vehicles, according to a statement from the Chinese Ministry of Commerce.翻译:中国商务部的一份声明称，王毅还就欧盟对中国电动汽车进行反补贴调查提出了中方的关切。</p>    <span>Reporting by Beijing Newsroom; editing by Christina Fincher翻译:北京新闻编辑室报道；克里斯蒂娜·芬奇编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 12:08:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">IJHS3PSPPNOPROI3LROHABK43E</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-commerce-minister-discusses-trade-ties-ev-other-issues-with-eus-breton-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>EU/TRADE (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[香港第三季度GDP同比增长4.1%，增长预测下调]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Q3 GDP grows 4.1% y/y versus 1.5% in Q2</li>  <li>Q3 seasonally adjusted GDP up 0.1% q/q vs Q2's 1.3% slide</li>  <li>Govt trims full year forecast to 3.2% growth</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>第三季度 GDP 同比增长 4.1%，而第二季度为 1.5%</li><li>第三季度经季节性调整的 GDP 环比增长 0.1%，而第二季度则下滑 1.3%</li><li>政府将全年增长预期下调至 3.2%</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/onmfzCocZqEswTzVccYcY5sXicM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/S5RY7VXUCZKU3K3NBW4V2GU2GY.jpg" alt="Traffic is seen between office buildings in downtown Hong Kong翻译:香港市中心写字楼之间的交通" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Traffic is seen between office buildings at sunset in downtown Hong Kong, China  June 29, 2017. Picture taken June 29, 2017.      REUTERS/Bobby Yip/File Photo翻译:2017年6月29日，中国香港市中心日落时分，办公楼之间的交通。照片拍摄于2017年6月29日。REUTERS/Bobby Yip/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Hong Kong's economy expanded 4.1% in the third quarter from a year earlier, beating growth of 1.5% in the second quarter and 2.9% in the first, the government said on Friday, adding that inbound tourism and private consumption would underpin growth for the rest of the year.翻译:政府周五表示，香港经济第三季度同比增长4.1%，超过第二季度的1.5%和第一季度的2.9%，并补充说，入境旅游业和私人消费将支撑其他地区的增长今年的。</p>   <p>However, the government revised down the full-year economic growth forecast to 3.2% from an earlier estimate of a 4.0% to 5.0% range. The economy shrank 3.5% in 2022.翻译:然而，政府将全年经济增长预测从早前的4.0%至5.0%范围下调至3.2%。 2022年经济萎缩3.5%。</p>   <p>Adolph Leung, a government economist, said in a statement that private consumption, improvement in household income and the government's support initiatives should bolster growth, while more visitors could be received as handling capacity recovers further.翻译:政府经济学家梁志强在一份声明中表示，私人消费、家庭收入的改善以及政府的支持举措应该会提振经济增长，而随着处理能力的进一步恢复，可能会接待更多游客。</p>   <p>"The difficult external environment amid increasing geopolitical tensions and tight financial conditions would continue to weigh on exports of goods and investment and consumption sentiment," Leung said.翻译:梁振英表示：“地缘政治紧张局势加剧和金融状况紧张，外部环境困难，将继续影响货物出口以及投资和消费情绪。”</p>   <p>Visitor arrivals for September were 2.77 million, bringing the total for the first nine month of 2023 to 23.32 million, according to Hong Kong Tourism Board preliminary data. That compared with last year's 66,037 and 249,699, respectively, when China was still in the grip of COVID-19 restrictions.翻译:香港旅游发展局初步数据显示，9 月份入境旅客人数为 277 万人次，使 2023 年前 9 个月的旅客总数达到 2,332 万人次。相比之下，去年中国仍受到 COVID-19 限制的情况下，分别有 66,037 人和 249,699 人。</p>   <p>"Although Hong Kong will see support from consumption, the net tourism outflows ... and poor export performance will likely weigh on growth," said Gary Ng, Asia Pacific senior economist at Natixis.翻译:法国外贸银行(Natixis)亚太区高级经济学家加里·吴(Gary Ng)表示，“尽管香港将获得消费的支持，但旅游业净流出……以及出口表现不佳可能会拖累经济增长。”</p>   <p>Meanwhile, Financial Secretary Paul Chan told global financial leaders at an investment summit earlier this week that innovation and technology were also core engines to drive growth.翻译:与此同时，财政司司长陈茂波在本周早些时候的投资峰会上向全球金融领袖表示，创新和技术也是推动增长的核心引擎。</p>   <p>On a seasonally adjusted quarterly basis, the economy grew 0.1% in the July-September period. That compared with a 1.3% slide in the April-June quarter and 5.4% growth in the first.翻译:按季度调整后，7-9月经济增长0.1%。相比之下，4 月至 6 月季度下滑 1.3%，第一季度增长 5.4%。</p>   <p>A challenging external environment may bring downside risks for Hong Kong, with exports continuing to be under pressure amid weak demand from mainland China and globally, said Samuel Tse, an economist at DBS Bank, in a research note.翻译:星展银行经济学家塞缪尔·谢(Samuel Tse)在一份研究报告中表示，充满挑战的外部环境可能会给香港带来下行风险，由于中国内地和全球需求疲软，出口继续面临压力。</p>   <p>"After all, a solid recovery of asset markets and economy hinges crucially on a clear timeline of interest rates cuts," Tse said.翻译:“毕竟，资产市场和经济的稳健复苏关键取决于明确的降息时间表，”谢说。</p>   <p>Hong Kong lowered its full-year underlying consumer price inflation forecast to 1.8% from 2.0%, and lowered its forecast for the headline rate to 2.2% from 2.4%.翻译:香港将全年基本消费者价格通胀预测从 2.0% 下调至 1.8%，并将总体通胀率预测从 2.4% 下调至 2.2%。</p>    <span>Reporting by Twinnie Siu and Donny Kwok; Editing by Edmund Klamann and Alex Richardson翻译:Twinnie Siu 和 Donny Kwok 报道；埃德蒙·克拉曼和亚历克斯·理查森编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 11:16:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ETU7DO35GJPDHIDR7INA5OHGUY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-q3-gdp-expands-41-yy-growth-forecast-revised-lower-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HONGKONG</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/GDP (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中方表示与越南就双边关系进行了坦诚友好的会谈]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/t4FWXeCQPPqUyrfXg27iVzwjfzo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MMKW6JXGQZOXTGEBU67UJNQTZA.jpg" alt="A Vietnamese pupil holds Vietnamese and Chinese flags before the welcoming ceremony at the Presidential Palace in Hanoi翻译:在河内总统府举行的欢迎仪式前，一名越南学生举着越南和中国国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Vietnamese pupil holds Vietnamese and Chinese flags before the welcoming ceremony at the Presidential Palace in Hanoi翻译:在河内总统府举行的欢迎仪式前，一名越南学生举着越南和中国国旗, Vietnam November 12, 2017. REUTERS/Hoang Dinh Nam/Pool/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China said its vice foreign minister held frank and friendly talks with his Vietnamese counterpart in Hanoi on Thursday that encompassed bilateral ties, land borders and maritime issues.翻译:中国表示，中国外交部副部长周四在河内与越南副外长举行了坦诚友好的会谈，会谈内容涵盖双边关系、陆地边界和海上问题。</p>   <p>The meeting between Vice Foreign Minister Sun Weidong and Vietnam's Deputy Foreign Minister Nguyen Minh Vu had not previously been disclosed by Beijing.翻译:北京此前并未披露外交部副部长孙卫东与越南外交部副部长阮明武的会晤。</p>   <p>They agreed that bilateral relations have maintained good momentum under both countries' current leadership, Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin said on Friday in response to reporters' questions.翻译:中国外交部发言人汪文斌周五在回答记者提问时表示，双方一致认为，在两国现任领导下，双边关系保持良好发展势头。</p>   <p>The two sides value the progress made in the opening and upgrading of border crossings and infrastructure connectivity, Wang told a regular news conference.翻译:王毅在例行记者会上表示，双方高度评价两国边境口岸开放升级、基础设施互联互通取得的进展。</p>   <p>He added that they had agreed to try to make the Sino-Vietnamese land border a border of "permanent peace" and "intergenerational friendship and prosperous development".翻译:他补充说，他们同意努力使中越陆地边界成为“永久和平”和“代际友谊和繁荣发展”的边界。</p>   <p>The two sides fully affirmed joint efforts made to maintain the stability of their maritime situation in recent years, reaffirmed the need to continue to strengthen dialogue and consultation, as well as to properly manage their differences, he said.翻译:双方充分肯定近年来两国为维护海上局势稳定所做的共同努力，重申需要继续加强对话协商，妥善管控分歧。</p>   <p>When asked if President Xi Jinping would visit Hanoi, Wang said he had no information that he could provide.翻译:当被问及习近平主席是否将访问河内时，王毅表示，他无法提供任何信息。</p>   <p>China and the United States have been jostling for influence among Southeast Asian nations including Vietnam, which in September elevated its ties with Washington to a comprehensive strategic partnership, putting its one-time enemy on par with Beijing and Moscow.翻译:中国和美国一直在争夺在包括越南在内的东南亚国家中的影响力，越南于9月将与华盛顿的关系提升为全面战略伙伴关系，将其曾经的敌人与北京和莫斯科平起平坐。</p>   <p>Reuters last month reported that Vietnamese and Chinese officials were preparing for a possible trip by Xi to Hanoi. At the time, plans were for the trip to take place at the end of October or in early November.翻译:路透社上个月报道称，越南和中国官员正在为习近平可能访问河内做准备。当时计划在十月底或十一月初进行这次旅行。</p>   <p>Three Hanoi-based diplomats subsequently said the visit was likely to be postponed to December.翻译:三名驻河内外交官随后表示，此次访问可能会推迟到 12 月。</p>   <p>(This story has been corrected to fix Nguyen Minh Vu's name in paragraph 2)翻译:（这个故事已被更正，以修正第 2 段中 Nguyen Minh Vu 的名字）</p>    <span>Reporting by Joe Cash; writing by Ryan Woo and Albee Zhang; Editing by Edwina Gibbs翻译:乔·卡什报道；作者：Ryan Woo 和 Albee 张；编辑：埃德温娜·吉布斯</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 09:34:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">IBJBW4HQVFNCHABWMJEFLC6Q3Q</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-says-held-frank-friendly-talks-with-vietnam-bilateral-ties-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>VIETNAM/VISIT (CORRECTED, UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：中国主权基金任命新北美首席消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/pPNP1Vr9Hbte-RMGVM0cV7KUVBc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/AWPPFE4AZFMZZH277PFZHGTR7M.jpg" alt="The headquarter building of China Investment Corporation (CIC) is pictured in Beijing翻译:中国投资有限责任公司（CIC）总部大楼位于北京" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The headquarter building of China Investment Corporation (CIC) is pictured in Beijing翻译:中国投资有限责任公司（CIC）总部大楼位于北京, China, March 1, 2016.  REUTERS/Jason Lee/File Photo翻译:2016 年 3 月 1 日，中国北京，中国投资有限责任公司 (CIC) 总部大楼。路透社/Jason Lee/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China Investment Corp (CIC) has hired a new North America head for its New York office, two people familiar with the matter said, filling a months-long vacancy and showing the sovereign wealth fund wants to maintain the outpost despite flaring U.S.-Sino tensions.翻译:两名知情人士表示，中国投资公司（CIC）为其纽约办事处聘请了一位新的北美主管，填补了长达数月的空缺，这表明尽管中美关系紧张，这家主权财富基金仍希望维持这一前哨基地。 。</p>   <p>New York is the $1.35 trillion fund's only office outside mainland China besides Hong Kong. It was set up in 2015 to help it manage its U.S. assets. Since then, Washington has cracked down on many Chinese investments it deems a national security risk.翻译:纽约是该基金规模1.35万亿美元的除香港以外在中国大陆以外的唯一办事处。它成立于 2015 年，旨在帮助其管理其美国资产。此后，华盛顿对许多它认为构成国家安全风险的中国投资进行了打击。</p>   <p>CIC asked Bai Xiaoqing, who was in charge of some of its private equity investments from Beijing, to move to New York for the North America head role, the sources said, requesting anonymity because the move has not been publicly announced.翻译:消息人士称，中投公司要求在北京负责部分私募股权投资的白晓庆调往纽约担任北美业务负责人。由于此举尚未公开宣布，消息人士要求匿名。</p>   <p>She succeeds Zhang Hong, who left CIC at the end of last year and moved back to China following six years in the role, one of the sources added. The reason behind Zhang's departure could not be learned.翻译:其中一位消息人士补充说，她接替了张宏，张宏于去年底离开中投公司，并在担任该职位六年后回到中国。张离开的原因尚不清楚。</p>   <p>CIC, Bai and Zhang did not respond to requests for comment.翻译:中投公司、白和张没有回应置评请求。</p>   <p>The Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States, which reviews deals for national security concerns, has been blocking Chinese investments it believes may erode U.S. technological edge or jeopardize data security. U.S. authorities have been especially suspicious of investments originating from entities close to China's communist government, like CIC.翻译:出于国家安全考虑而审查交易的美国外国投资委员会一直在阻止中国的投资，它认为这些投资可能会侵蚀美国的技术优势或危及数据安全。美国当局对来自与中国共产党政府关系密切的实体（例如中投公司）的投资尤其持怀疑态度。</p>   <p>As a result, Chinese investments have dropped from a peak of 63 deals totaling $53.5 billion in 2016 to just three deals collectively worth only $400 million this year, according to the American Enterprise Institute, which collates data on investments of more than $95 million.翻译:美国企业研究所 (American Enterprise Institute) 整理了超过 9500 万美元的投资数据，结果显示，中国投资已从 2016 年 63 笔总价值 535 亿美元的交易高峰期下降到今年的 3 笔总价值仅为 4 亿美元的交易。</p>   <p>Still, CIC's most recent disclosures show some of its U.S. holdings remain sizeable. U.S. stocks made up 61.48% of the overseas public market equities it held in 2021, according to its latest annual report. Public equities accounted for 35.4% of its total portfolio.翻译:尽管如此，中投公司最近披露的信息显示，其在美国的部分持股规模仍然相当大。根据其最新年报，2021年其持有的海外公开市场股票中，美股占比为61.48%。公共股票占其投资组合总额的35.4%。</p>   <p>CIC is also a significant investor in U.S. private equity funds, as so-called alternative assets comprise almost half of its portfolio. One of its most prominent investments has been a $2.5 billion Goldman Sachs Group Inc <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GS.N" target="_blank">(GS.N)</a> private equity fund aimed at investing in companies that can benefit from closer U.S.-China ties.翻译:中投公司也是美国私募股权基金的重要投资者，因为所谓的另类资产几乎占其投资组合的一半。其最著名的投资之一是高盛集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GS.N" target="_blank">(GS.N)</a> 25 亿美元的私募股权基金，旨在投资能够从更紧密的中美关系中受益的公司。</p>   <p>Launched in 2017 and dubbed the China-U.S. Industrial Cooperation Fund, it has invested in several companies in the United States and Britain.翻译:该基金成立于2017年，名为中美产业合作基金，已投资美国和英国的多家公司。</p>   <p>CIC has also cultivated ties with BlackRock Inc <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BLK.N" target="_blank">(BLK.N)</a>, the world's largest asset manager. It said last month that CIC Chairman Peng Chun met BlackRock Chief Executive Larry Fink to discuss "cooperation on multiple fronts". It did not provide further details, and a BlackRock spokesperson did not respond to questions about the meeting.翻译:中投公司还与全球最大的资产管理公司贝莱德公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BLK.N" target="_blank">（BLK.N）</a>建立了联系。上个月，中投公司董事长彭纯会见了贝莱德首席执行官拉里·芬克，讨论“多方面合作”。它没有提供更多细节，贝莱德发言人也没有回答有关会议的问题。</p>   <p>Bai joined CIC in 2007. She previously worked for China's Ministry of Finance for over 12 years and served as deputy director, according to the Milken Institute's website.翻译:据米尔肯研究所网站称，白女士于2007年加入中投公司。此前，她在中国财政部工作了12年多，并担任副主任。</p>   <p>Another reminder that China continues to be a major investor in U.S. assets came on Thursday, when a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-largest-bank-icbc-hit-by-ransomware-software-ft-2023-11-09/">ransomware attack</a> on Industrial and Commercial Bank of China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601398.SS" target="_blank">(601398.SS)</a> disrupted trading in the U.S. Treasury market.翻译:周四，中国工商银行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601398.SS" target="_blank">（601398.SS）</a>遭受<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-largest-bank-icbc-hit-by-ransomware-software-ft-2023-11-09/">勒索软件攻击</a>，扰乱了美国国债市场的交易，再次提醒人们，中国仍然是美国资产的主要投资者。</p>    <span>Reporting by Echo Wang in New York and Roxanne Liu in Beijing; Additional reporting by Kane Wu in Hong Kong; Editing by Greg Roumeliotis and Edwina Gibbs翻译:纽约 Echo Wang 和北京 Roxanne Liu 报道；吴凯恩 (Kane Wu) 在香港的补充报道；格雷格·鲁梅利奥蒂斯和埃德温娜·吉布斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 09:03:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RRJCOMZ6EZPBJONQUYXWGSWJKY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/chinas-sovereign-fund-appoints-new-north-america-chief-sources-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Echo Wang]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/CIC (EXCLUSIVE, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国表示将确保中缅边境安全稳定]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/RKtxEpPgm-NnxYH8BO_Q6-pZ-9E=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/S5MWIXEN6NKH5BYDDGSZJID5HY.jpg" alt="Chinese Foreign Ministry news briefing on Chinese President Xi's call with Ukrainian President Zelensky, in Beijing翻译:外交部就习近平主席同乌克兰总统泽连斯基通话举行新闻发布会" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin attends a news briefing following a phone call between Chinese President Xi Jinping and Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy, in Beijing, China April 26, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo翻译:2023年4月26日，中国北京，中国国家主席习近平与乌克兰总统泽连斯基通电话后，中国外交部发言人汪文斌出席新闻发布会。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China will ensure security and stability at its border with Myanmar, the Chinese foreign ministry said on Friday, while urging all parties in Myanmar to immediately stop fighting.翻译:中国外交部周五表示，中方将确保中缅边境安全稳定，同时敦促缅甸各方立即停止战斗。</p>   <p>The president of military-ruled Myanmar has said the country is at risk of breaking apart due to ineffective management of recent violence in its border regions with China.翻译:军政府统治的缅甸总统表示，由于对最近与中国边境地区发生的暴力事件管理不力，该国面临分裂的风险。</p>   <p>The Myanmar junta is facing the biggest challenge to its authority since it seized power in a 2021 coup, with a surge in attacks by pro-democracy and ethnic minority insurgents on military bases in the north, northeast, northwest and southeast.翻译:缅甸军政府正面临自2021年政变夺权以来的最大挑战，亲民主派和少数民族叛乱分子对北部、东北部、西北和东南部军事基地的袭击激增。</p>   <p>China has repeatedly called for the end of fighting and urged Myanmar to cooperate with China in maintaining stability on their common border, and to prevent further casualties.翻译:中方多次呼吁停止战斗，敦促缅方与中方合作，维护共同边境稳定，防止进一步人员伤亡。</p>   <p>There have been several reports of Chinese citizens being killed in clashes, and China has sent advisories to citizens in Myanmar to avoid areas where violence was prevalent.翻译:有多起中国公民在冲突中丧生的报道，中国已向缅甸公民发出警告，避免前往暴力猖獗的地区。</p>   <p>"China is highly concerned about the conflict in northern Myanmar and urges all parties concerned in Myanmar to immediately cease fire and stop fighting, pay practical attention to China's security concerns, and work with China to maintain the safety of China-Myanmar co-operation projects and business personnel," foreign ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin said while fielding questions at a regular press briefing.翻译:中方高度关注缅北冲突，敦促缅甸有关各方立即停火止战，切实关注中方安全关切，与中方共同维护中缅合作项目安全外交部发言人汪文斌在例行记者会上回答提问时表示。</p>   <p>Last week, assistant Chinese foreign minister Nong Rong翻译:上周，中国外交部部长助理农融</p>   <p>visited Myanmar urging the country to take effective measures to strengthen the security for Chinese institutions and personnel there.翻译:访问缅甸，敦促缅方采取有效措施，加强在缅中资机构和人员安全。</p>   <p>China imports fuel in gaseous form via a long-distance pipeline from Myanmar. Nong visited the Myanmar-China Gas Pipeline, part of China's Belt and Road infrastructure and energy network, linking Ramree Island on the western coast of Myanmar with Chinese border city Ruili in southwestern Yunnan Province.翻译:中国通过长输管道从缅甸进口气态燃料。农参观了中缅天然气管道，该管道是中国“一带一路”基础设施和能源网络的一部分，连接缅甸西海岸的拉姆里岛和中国云南省西南部边境城市瑞丽。</p>    <span>Reporting by Beijing Newsroom; Writing by Bernard Orr; Editing by Christopher Cushing &amp; Simon Cameron-Moore翻译:北京新闻编辑室报道；伯纳德·奥尔撰写；克里斯托弗·库欣和西蒙·卡梅伦-摩尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 08:39:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">YYKYNVXZCJLG3NVMD42VJBLNUA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-says-will-ensure-security-stability-border-with-myanmar-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>MYANMAR</category>
                
                <category>VIOLENCE/MILITARY (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国购物节期间的价格战暴露了消费者的困境]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/xrFoqTbS-B8s-KOragKF0CJwx3k=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/H7Z6OVJKIBJGVEM3BOFNXSRUYU.jpg" alt="Illustration picture of e-commerce app Pinduoduo翻译:电商拼多多插画图片" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of e-commerce app Pinduoduo is displayed next to mobile phones displaying the app, in this illustration picture taken October 25, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo翻译:在这张摄于 2023 年 10 月 25 日的插图中，电子商务应用程序拼多多的徽标显示在显示该应用程序的手机旁边。REUTERS/Florence Lo/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>A ferocious price war among China's e-commerce retailers during the "Singles Day" shopping event is exposing further weakness in household consumption and raising concerns that the world's second-largest economy will resume its slowdown.翻译:中国电子商务零售商在“双十一”购物活动期间展开的激烈价格战暴露了家庭消费的进一步疲软，并引发了人们对世界第二大经济体将恢复放缓的担忧。</p>   <p>Originally a 24-hour online shopping event in China held on Nov. 11, Singles Day, a nod to the digits in the date, has expanded into weeks of promotions, including in brick-and-mortar stores, making it the world's largest shopping festival.翻译:“光棍节”原本是中国于 11 月 11 日举行的 24 小时在线购物活动，如今已扩展为为期数周的促销活动，包括在实体店进行，使其成为全球最大的购物活动节日。</p>   <p>This year's festival is being more closely watched than ever as a gauge of consumer confidence as China flirts with deflation and has identified boosting <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-has-no-pain-free-solutions-its-slowing-economy-2023-08-24/">household demand</a> as key to avoiding <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">lost decades</a> of sluggish growth.翻译:今年的节日比以往任何时候都受到更密切的关注，因为中国正面临通货紧缩，并认为提振<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-has-no-pain-free-solutions-its-slowing-economy-2023-08-24/">家庭需求</a>是避免<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">数十年经济增长低迷</a>的关键，因为它衡量了消费者的信心。</p>   <p>On Taobao and Tmall, platforms owned by e-commerce giant Alibaba <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">(9988.HK)</a>, consumers can receive a 50 yuan ($6.86) discount when they spend 300 yuan. The company is <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/alibaba-banks-aggressive-singles-day-pricing-recoup-sales-mojo-2023-10-31/">pressuring</a> merchants to offer rock-bottom prices during Singles Day after promising it will offer 80 million products at their lowest prices this year for the sale, which started in late October.翻译:在电子商务巨头阿里巴巴<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/9988.HK" target="_blank">（9988.HK）</a>旗下的淘宝和天猫平台上，消费者消费满300元即可享受50元（6.86美元）的折扣。该公司承诺今年将以最低价格出售 8000 万件产品，并在双十一期间向商家<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/alibaba-banks-aggressive-singles-day-pricing-recoup-sales-mojo-2023-10-31/">施压</a>，要求他们提供最低价格。促销活动于 10 月底开始。</p>   <p>PDD Holdings' <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PDD.O" target="_blank">(PDD.O)</a> Pinduoduo and JD.com have between them indicated they would offer billions in cashback deals over the sales period for people shopping on their respective platforms.翻译:拼多多控股<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PDD.O" target="_blank">(PDD.O)</a>拼多多和京东已表示，他们将在销售期间为在各自平台上购物的人们提供数十亿美元的现金返还优惠。</p>   <p>"Low prices and discounts has been the overarching theme," said Jason Yu, greater China managing director of market research firm Kantar Worldpanel, noting that even the newly-released iPhone 15 was selling with a 500 yuan discount.翻译:市场研究公司凯度消费者指数 (Kantar Worldpanel) 大中华区董事总经理 Jason Yu 表示：“低价和折扣一直是最重要的主题。”他指出，即使是新发布的 iPhone 15 也以 500 元的折扣出售。</p>   <p>"It's a sign that nobody's going to easily spend 10,000 yuan ($1,371) on a handset right now. Confidence is a bit weak."翻译:“这表明现在没有人会轻易花 10,000 元人民币（1,371 美元）购买手机。信心有点薄弱。”</p>   <p>Data released on Thursday showing a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">drop</a> in consumer prices to their lowest since the COVID-19 pandemic has increased the doubts in China's economic rebound after some months of indicators showing growth stabilising.翻译:周四公布的数据显示，消费者价格<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">跌至</a>自 COVID-19 大流行以来的最低水平，这增加了人们对中国经济反弹的疑虑，此前几个月的指标显示增长趋于稳定。</p>   <p>China's big online shopping platforms did not release final sales figures for 2022, when analysts said COVID-19 restrictions inhibited spending and consumer confidence. It is unclear whether they will release figures for this year, but expectations are subdued, and for good reason.翻译:中国的大型在线购物平台没有公布 2022 年的最终销售数据，当时分析师表示，COVID-19 限制抑制了支出和消费者信心。目前尚不清楚他们是否会公布今年的数据，但预期较低，这是有充分理由的。</p>   <p>Bain and Company found that 77% of the 3,000 consumers it surveyed plan to cut or maintain their level of spending on Singles Day compared with last year.翻译:贝恩公司发现，在其调查的 3,000 名消费者中，77% 计划与去年相比削减或维持双十一的支出水平。</p>   <p>"Macroeconomic headwinds are causing consumers to be more value-conscious," Bain said.翻译:贝恩表示：“宏观经济逆风导致消费者更加注重价值。”</p>   <p>Some indicators point to a slowdown in Singles Day sales. Data provider Syntun estimated e-commerce platforms sold 311 billion yuan of products from Oct. 31 to Nov. 3, a 7.1% decrease year-on-year. But it said that was partly mitigated by livestreaming platforms such as Douyin, Diantao and Kuaishou selling 10.5% more, at 99 billion yuan.翻译:一些指标表明双十一销售放缓。数据提供商Syntun估计，10月31日至11月3日，电商平台销售商品3110亿元，同比下降7.1%。但该公司表示，抖音、点淘和快手等直播平台的销售额增加了 10.5%，达到 990 亿元，在一定程度上缓解了这一影响。</p>   <p>Other analysts are more upbeat. Jacob Cooke, co-founder and CEO of e-commerce consultancy WPIC Marketing+Technologies, expects total sales growth of 14%-18%, saying he is "optimistic" that Chinese growth is "stabilising."</p>    <h 1="">TRIPLE DIP</h>  <p>A downturn in China's giant <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">property sector</a>, where most of the household wealth is parked, indebted <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-can-no-longer-extend-pretend-municipal-debt-2023-08-06/">local governments</a> cutting spending, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-stop-releasing-youth-jobless-rate-data-aug-says-stats-bureau-2023-08-15/">youth unemployment</a> rates surpassing 20%, and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/white-collar-wage-cuts-china-fuel-deflation-risks-hurt-consumption-2023-07-27/">falling wages</a> in some sectors of the economy have been keeping consumers in a thrifty mood.翻译:中国庞大的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">房地产行业</a>（大部分家庭财富都存放在该行业）的低迷、负债累累的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-can-no-longer-extend-pretend-municipal-debt-2023-08-06/">地方政府</a>削减支出、 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-stop-releasing-youth-jobless-rate-data-aug-says-stats-bureau-2023-08-15/">青年失业率</a>超过20%，以及某些经济领域的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/white-collar-wage-cuts-china-fuel-deflation-risks-hurt-consumption-2023-07-27/">工资下降</a>，一直让消费者保持节俭的情绪。</p>   <p>A surprise rise in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-imports-unexpectedly-grow-oct-exports-extend-declines-2023-11-07/">imports</a> in October had raised hopes that spending might be turning a corner, but the fall in consumer prices suggests that higher commodity prices probably had more impact on trade than consumer demand.翻译:10 月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-imports-unexpectedly-grow-oct-exports-extend-declines-2023-11-07/">进口</a>意外增长，引发了人们对支出可能出现好转的希望，但消费者价格下跌表明，大宗商品价格上涨对贸易的影响可能大于对消费者需求的影响。</p>   <p>Coupled with weak manufacturing surveys and waning external demand, the consumer price pressures point to China losing growth momentum into year-end.翻译:加上制造业调查疲弱和外部需求减弱，消费者价格压力表明中国在年底前将失去增长动力。</p>   <p>"We continue to see a serious risk of a triple dip for the economy," Nomura analysts wrote in a note.翻译:野村证券分析师在一份报告中写道：“我们仍然看到经济出现三次探底的严重风险。”</p>   <p>For Tan Jiapeng, a 35-year-old office worker in Beijing, his only Singles Day purchase so far has been a Descente winter jacket, an "essential purchase" for the winter. Worried about job stability, he abstained from buying Pokemon smartphone games, body lotion, and some Moutai liquor, all things he wished for.翻译:对于北京35岁的上班族谭家鹏来说，迄今为止他在双十一购买的唯一一件单品就是一件Descente冬季夹克，这是冬季的“必备品”。由于担心工作稳定性，他不再购买口袋妖怪手机游戏、润肤露和一些茅台酒，这些都是他想要的东西。</p>   <p>"It's known how difficult it is to find a job these days, even for the young people who are cheaper," Tan said. "The economy is moving downhill, I can't spend as freely as before."翻译:谭说：“众所周知，现在找工作有多么困难，即使对于工资较低的年轻人来说也是如此。” “经济正在走下坡路，我不能像以前那样自由花钱了。”</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2931 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2931 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Casey Hall, Sophie Yu; Editing by Marius Zaharia and Christian Schmollinger翻译:凯西·霍尔 (Casey Hall) 报道，苏菲·余 (Sophie Yu)；马吕斯·扎哈里亚和克里斯蒂安·施莫林格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 08:32:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">KUREFXORDZJUZI3SZHIMKZW244</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/price-wars-during-chinese-shopping-fest-expose-consumer-woes-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Sophie Yu, Casey Hall]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECOMMERCE/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国和中国在 COP28 会谈前就气候问题达成“谅解”——克里]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/qkOupn3tUmJYaRjoqQ3dtCv-y4o=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7XIPL5ECIVLABAJK7YUPPCLZ7E.jpg" alt="John Kerry, U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate speaks during an earlier interview with Reuters, in  Abu Dhabi翻译:美国总统气候特使约翰·克里早些时候在阿布扎比接受路透社采访时发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>John Kerry, U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate speaks during an earlier interview with Reuters, in  Abu Dhabi翻译:美国总统气候特使约翰·克里早些时候在阿布扎比接受路透社采访时发表讲话, United Arab Emirates, on October 31, 2023. REUTERS/Abdel Hadi Ramahi/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>The United States and China have reached "understandings and agreements" on climate issues that will help ensure progress is made at the COP28 talks starting late this month in Dubai, U.S. climate envoy John Kerry said on Friday.翻译:美国气候特使约翰·克里周五表示，美国和中国已就气候问题达成“谅解和协议”，这将有助于确保本月末在迪拜举行的 COP28 会谈取得进展。</p>   <p>Kerry met with his Chinese counterpart Xie Zhenhua at Sunnylands, California, this week for four days of talks he described as tough and serious.翻译:克里本周在加利福尼亚州桑尼兰兹会见了中国外长解振华，进行了为期四天的会谈，他称会谈是艰难而严肃的。</p>   <p>"We had a few moments where, as in any negotiation, you think it's all despair," Kerry said at the Bloomberg New Economy Forum in Singapore. "We did come up with some very solid understandings and agreements which will help the COP and will also put us both in a place where we can help the world by focusing on more renewables and other kinds of things," he said.翻译:克里在新加坡举行的彭博新经济论坛上表示：“我们有过一些时刻，就像在任何谈判中一样，你会觉得一切都令人绝望。”他说：“我们确实达成了一些非常扎实的谅解和协议，这将有助于缔约方会议，也将使我们双方能够通过关注更多的可再生能源和其他事物来帮助世界。”</p>   <p>Common ground between the world's two top economies and biggest greenhouse gas emitters is considered a crucial part of any consensus at COP28, which is expected to focus on issues like climate finance and more ambitious energy transition goals.翻译:世界两大经济体和最大温室气体排放国之间的共同点被认为是 COP28 共识的重要组成部分，预计该会议将重点讨论气候融资和更雄心勃勃的能源转型目标等问题。</p>   <p>Kerry said details of the agreements between the two would be released soon.翻译:克里表示，两国协议的细节将很快公布。</p>   <p>One important agreement reached on climate loss and damage would allow any country to contribute to a fund to support the regions most vulnerable to climate impacts, Kerry said.翻译:克里表示，就气候损失和损害达成的一项重要协议将允许任何国家向基金捐款，以支持最容易受到气候影响的地区。</p>   <p>Much of the focus on China at COP28 will be on its ongoing programme to build more coal-fired power plants, and Beijing's reluctance to commit to a concrete target to cut fossil fuel use as it tries to guarantee energy security and economic growth.翻译:COP28 上对中国的关注主要集中在其正在进行的建设更多燃煤电厂的计划，以及北京方面在努力保证能源安全和经济增长的同时不愿承诺削减化石燃料使用的具体目标。</p>   <p>China envoy Xie told diplomats in September that phasing out fossil fuels was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-climate-envoy-says-phasing-out-fossil-fuels-unrealistic-2023-09-22/">"unrealistic"</a> while key technologies like energy storage remained immature.翻译:中国特使谢九月对外交官表示，逐步淘汰化石燃料是<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-climate-envoy-says-phasing-out-fossil-fuels-unrealistic-2023-09-22/">“不现实的”</a> ，而储能等关键技术仍不成熟。</p>   <p>Kerry, when asked if he expected any compromise on coal from China, said: "You wait and see."翻译:当被问及是否预计中国会在煤炭问题上做出妥协时，克里表示：“你等着瞧吧。”</p>   <p>China now has 360 gigawatts of coal-fired power capacity in its project construction pipeline, he said, but "they're trying very hard to move away."翻译:他说，中国现在有360吉瓦的燃煤发电能力正在建设中，但“他们正在努力撤离”。</p>   <p>Right now, "it is irresponsible to be funding a coal-fired power plant anywhere in the world," he said.翻译:目前，“为世界任何地方的燃煤电厂提供资金都是不负责任的，”他说。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Stanway; Editing by Tom Hogue翻译:大卫·斯坦威报道；汤姆·霍格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 06:51:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">X6YGRWKP4FO25CKONSEW5TFJ24</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us-china-reach-understandings-climate-ahead-cop28-talks-kerry-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Stanway]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CLIMATE</category>
                
                <category>UN/USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：碧桂园计划年底前制定离岸债务重组计划]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/_Mc4SIE1WtqT8CsyTSnmE-wN9MA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NVNZTB5BOBPXVPC4NHT725HA6Y.jpg" alt="The company logo of Chinese developer Country Garden is displayed at a news conference in Hong Kong翻译:中国开发商碧桂园的公司标志出现在香港的新闻发布会上" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The company logo of Chinese developer Country Garden is displayed at a news conference in Hong Kong翻译:中国开发商碧桂园的公司标志出现在香港的新闻发布会上, China March 20, 2018. REUTERS/Bobby Yip/File Photo翻译:2018年3月20日，中国开发商碧桂园的公司标志在中国香港举行的新闻发布会上展示。路透社/Bobby Yip/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's embattled Country Garden <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">(2007.HK)</a> is aiming to pull together a tentative plan to restructure its offshore debt by the end of this year, two sources with direct knowledge of the matter said.翻译:两名直接了解情况的消息人士称，陷入困境的中国碧桂园<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">(2007.HK)</a>计划在今年年底前制定一项重组其离岸债务的暂定计划。</p>   <p>The nation's biggest private property developer, which <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-country-garden-offshore-debt-default-looms-2023-10-18/">missed</a> a coupon payment in October triggering default terms, then aims to start formal negotiations with offshore bondholders by February or March next year.翻译:该国最大的私人房地产开发商在 10 月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-country-garden-offshore-debt-default-looms-2023-10-18/">未能</a>支付息票，引发了违约条款，该开发商计划在明年 2 月或 3 月之前开始与离岸债券持有人进行正式谈判。</p>   <p>They added the firm expects to inform key bondholders of its cash flow projections by the year's end, as part of the basis for the tentative restructuring plan.翻译:他们补充说，该公司预计将在年底前向主要债券持有人通报其现金流预测，作为暂定重组计划基础的一部分。</p>   <p>The sources declined to be identified as the matter was confidential. Country Garden, which has almost $11 billion of offshore bonds, declined to comment.翻译:由于此事属于机密，消息人士拒绝透露姓名。拥有近 110 亿美元离岸债券的碧桂园拒绝置评。</p>   <p>The timeline for the company's debt restructuring plan has not been reported before.翻译:该公司债务重组计划的时间表此前尚未有报道。</p>   <p>Country Garden has been in the spotlight since August when its debt woes became public, rattling markets and forcing Beijing to roll out more support measures for the property sector.翻译:自8月份碧桂园债务问题公开以来一直备受关注，令市场不安，迫使北京推出更多房地产行业支持措施。</p>   <p>It has joined a long list of Chinese property developers that are either working on debt restructuring proposals or have presented them to creditors after having defaulted on offshore debt over the past two years.翻译:它加入了众多中国房地产开发商的行列，这些开发商要么正在制定债务重组方案，要么在过去两年发生海外债务违约后已向债权人提交了这些方案。</p>   <p>Reuters reported this week that <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">Chinese authorities have asked</a> domestic financial behemoth Ping An Insurance Group to take a controlling stake in Country Garden. That report was denied by Ping An.翻译:路透社本周报道称， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">中国当局已要求</a>国内金融巨头平安保险集团控股碧桂园。中国平安否认了这一报道。</p>   <p>A state-engineered rescue of Country Garden would be one of the most significant interventions to date by authorities to support the cash-squeezed and highly indebted property sector, which accounts for a quarter of China's economy.翻译:国家对碧桂园的救助将是迄今为止当局为支持现金紧张且负债累累的房地产行业而采取的最重大干预措施之一，该行业占中国经济的四分之一。</p>   <p>The two sources, who have no information on the bailout talks, said some Country Garden bondholders do not expect a higher recovery rate on their investments even if such a deal were to eventuate.</p>    <h 1="">ADVISERS BEGIN DUE DILIGENCE</h>  <p>Offshore bondholders <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/country-garden-says-founder-board-chairperson-work-havent-left-china-2023-10-19/">sought urgent talks</a> with Country Garden after it did not pay the $15 million coupon on Oct.18 - the end of a 30-day grace period, sources with direct knowledge of the matter have said.翻译:据直接了解情况的消息人士称，碧桂园在 10 月 18 日（30 天宽限期结束）未支付 1500 万美元息票后，海外债券持有人寻求与碧桂园<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/country-garden-says-founder-board-chairperson-work-havent-left-china-2023-10-19/">进行紧急谈判</a>。</p>   <p>CreditSights said in a Nov. 2 research note that Country Garden had "formally defaulted" on its offshore bonds due to the missed payment.翻译:CreditSights 在 11 月 2 日的一份研究报告中表示，由于未能及时付款，碧桂园已对其离岸债券“正式违约”。</p>   <p>The company has been privately communicating with some bondholders about its efforts to formulate a debt repayment plan since then, the sources said.翻译:消息人士称，此后该公司一直在私下与一些债券持有人沟通，以制定债务偿还计划。</p>   <p>Country Garden said on Oct. 10 that it had appointed CICC, Houlihan Lokey, and law firm Sidley Austin as advisers to examine its capital structure and liquidity position and formulate a "holistic" solution to repay its offshore debt.翻译:碧桂园10月10日表示，已任命中金公司、Houlihan Lokey和盛德律师事务所为顾问，审查其资本结构和流动性状况，并制定偿还境外债务的“整体”解决方案。</p>   <p>CICC did not immediately respond to Reuters' queries. Houlihan and Sidley Austin declined to comment.翻译:中金公司没有立即回应路透社的询问。霍利汉和盛德拒绝置评。</p>   <p>The advisers have begun due diligence on Country Garden's financial condition, including looking at cash flow for onshore projects, said the two sources and a separate source familiar with the matter.翻译:两位消息人士和另一位知情人士表示，顾问已开始对碧桂园的财务状况进行尽职调查，包括研究陆上项目的现金流。</p>   <p>As yet, few Chinese property developers have reached agreements on debt repayment plans.翻译:迄今为止，很少有中国房地产开发商就债务偿还计划达成协议。</p>   <p>Sunac China Holdings Ltd <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/1918.HK" target="_blank">(1918.HK)</a> in October became the first to complete the debt revamp scheme for its $9 billion offshore debt after winning approval from creditors and courts.翻译:融创中国控股有限公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/1918.HK" target="_blank">（1918.HK）</a>在获得债权人和法院批准后，于10月成为首家完成90亿美元离岸债务债务重组计划的公司。</p>   <p>Bigger rival China Evergrande <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a>, however, saw its initial $23 billion offshore debt restructuring plan thrown off course in September after Chinese authorities launched an investigation into its billionaire founder Hui Ka Yan and a flagship unit.翻译:然而，更大的竞争对手中国恒大<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）在</a>中国当局对其亿万富翁创始人许家印及其旗舰部门展开调查后，其最初的 230 亿美元海外债务重组计划于 9 月被搁置。</p>    <span>Reporting by Xie Yu; Additional reporting by Clare Jim; Editing by Sumeet Chatterjee and Edwina Gibbs翻译:谢宇报道；克莱尔·吉姆的补充报道；苏米特·查特吉和埃德温娜·吉布斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 05:42:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RM5EUMHIHZIVRAA4S3DY2UA74Q</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/country-garden-aims-have-offshore-debt-restructuring-plan-by-year-end-sources-2023-11-10/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Yu Xie]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/DEBT</category>
                
                <category>COUNTRY GARDEN</category>
                
                <category>BONDHOLDERS (EXCLUSIVE)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早在救援谈判之前，碧桂园就难以支付账单]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/p1mE9raSgEudl5Z-Mmiv1SDHlIg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XMHMBKM5VZMUFNJN3OXDMHAS7M.jpg" alt="Construction site of residential buildings by Chinese developer Country Garden in Tianjin翻译:中国开发商碧桂园在天津的住宅建筑工地" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A person rides a scooter past a construction site of residential buildings by Chinese developer Country Garden, in Tianjin, China August 18, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang翻译:2023年8月18日，中国天津，一个人骑着摩托车经过中国开发商碧桂园的住宅建筑工地。路透社/Tingshu Wang</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/LeE1pEW6qsIl73AhRbqnmn0i92g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JGPVZE4RMFOFPMRNIPMXZH4S7M.jpg" alt="The company logo of Chinese developer Country Garden is pictured at the Shanghai Country Garden Center in Shanghai翻译:中国开发商碧桂园的公司标志位于上海碧桂园中心" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The company logo of Chinese developer Country Garden is pictured at the Shanghai Country Garden Center in Shanghai翻译:中国开发商碧桂园的公司标志位于上海碧桂园中心, China August 9, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:中国开发商碧桂园的公司标志于2023年8月9日在中国上海碧桂园中心拍摄。路透社/Aly Song/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/vl-hRjJlh6qDTdfCZQ3sOyDhKBU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KRB72IEDGRLBTIKIG32FFF5CMQ.jpg" alt="A view of the residential apartments in Country Garden's Forest City development in Johor Bahru翻译:新山碧桂园森林城市发展项目的住宅公寓景观" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view of the residential apartments in Country Garden's Forest City development in Johor Bahru翻译:新山碧桂园森林城市发展项目的住宅公寓景观, Malaysia August 16, 2023. REUTERS/Edgar Su翻译:2023 年 8 月 16 日，马来西亚新山碧桂园森林城市开发项目的住宅公寓景观。REUTERS/Edgar Su</figcaption></figure>                 <p>When China's largest developer Country Garden first <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-country-garden-missed-two-dollar-bond-coupon-payments-2023-08-08/">skipped debt payments</a> in August, its shares tumbled 14%, marking a reversal of fortunes: from industry poster child to another troubled property company struggling to pay its creditors.翻译:当中国最大的开发商碧桂园8月份首次<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-country-garden-missed-two-dollar-bond-coupon-payments-2023-08-08/">跳过债务偿还</a>时，其股价暴跌14%，标志着命运的逆转：从行业典范变成了另一家陷入困境、难以偿还债权人的房地产公司。</p>   <p>The same month, Chinese authorities <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">quietly started talks</a> with Ping An asking the insurance group to take a controlling stake in the developer, according to a Reuters report that was denied by Ping An.翻译:据路透社报道，同月，中国当局<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">悄悄开始与平安进行谈判</a>，要求该保险集团持有该开发商的控股权，但平安否认了这一报道。</p>   <p>Interviews with contractors, workers and home buyers, as well as a review of lawsuits involving Country Garden, show that for months before its problems became public, the company was struggling to deliver homes and pay contractors on time.翻译:对承包商、工人和购房者的采访以及对涉及碧桂园的诉讼的审查表明，在其问题公开之前的几个月里，该公司一直在努力按时交付房屋并向承包商付款。</p>   <p>Until the middle of this year, the company was seen by most investors and home buyers as a beacon of strength in a real estate sector grappling with ballooning debt, tighter regulations and slumping sales. It was one of the few developers able to issue state-guaranteed onshore bonds last year and get credit lines from banks in early 2023.翻译:直到今年年中，该公司还被大多数投资者和购房者视为房地产行业的力量灯塔，该行业正在努力应对债务膨胀、监管收紧和销售下滑​​的问题。它是去年能够发行国家担保的境内债券并在 2023 年初获得银行信贷额度的少数开发商之一。</p>   <p>China, the world's second-largest economy, has struggled to recover from COVID shutdowns and issues with its giant property sector. Country Garden's woes highlight the challenge Beijing faces as it seeks to engineer a rescue plan for the company and improve conditions for the wider industry.翻译:作为世界第二大经济体的中国一直在努力从新冠疫情导致的停工和庞大的房地产行业问题中恢复过来。碧桂园的困境突显了北京在寻求为该公司制定救援计划并改善更广泛行业的条件时所面临的挑战。</p>   <p>"Nobody believed that Country Garden would fail. One important reason is that it seemed to have the implicit guarantee from the state," the Economist Intelligence Unit's Xu Tianchen told Reuters.翻译:“没有人相信碧桂园会失败。一个重要原因是它似乎有国家的隐性担保，”经济学人智库的徐天辰告诉路透社。</p>   <p>Observers believed Country Garden, which has liabilities of around $190 billion and more than 3,000 projects under development, was "good enough and big enough to escape a default or a collapse," he added.翻译:他补充说，观察人士认为，碧桂园负债约 1,900 亿美元，有 3,000 多个正在开发的项目，“足够好、足够大，可以避免违约或倒闭”。</p>   <p>Examples of Country Garden's earlier financial strains, reported here for the first time, include: A valve supplier unpaid since 2022; a steel provider partially paid with apartments; homeowners and workers reporting projects stalled from as early as January; and a Country Garden subsidiary which told a court earlier this year it was "insolvent and overwhelmed."翻译:在此首次报道的碧桂园早期财务紧张的例子包括： 一家阀门供应商自 2022 年以来一直未付款；钢铁供应商部分支付公寓费用；房主和工人报告项目早在一月份就陷入停滞；碧桂园的一家子公司今年早些时候向法庭表示，该公司“资不抵债，不堪重负”。</p>   <p>Lawsuits involving Country Garden and its contractors, including disputes over delayed construction and missing payments, have jumped to a record 459 cases this year, according to data compiled by EIU’s Xu.翻译:根据 EIU 的 Xu 汇编的数据，今年涉及碧桂园及其承包商的诉讼，包括延迟施工和拖欠付款的纠纷，已跃升至创纪录的 459 起。</p>   <p>Country Garden declined to comment.翻译:碧桂园拒绝置评。</p>   <p>After its default, Country Garden has stressed that delivery of homes will remain its top priority, saying last week it had delivered around 460,000 units in the first 10 months of 2023.翻译:违约后，碧桂园强调交付房屋仍将是其首要任务，上周表示，该公司在 2023 年前 10 个月已交付约 46 万套住宅。</p>   <p>In July, only weeks before it skipped debt payments, Country Garden launched a campaign on its WeChat channel titled “Beautiful Delivery”, showcasing newly built apartments and happy homeowners. Some of the projects, it said, were even delivered ahead of schedule.</p>    <h 1="">'FACING LOSSES'</h>  <p>While disputes and delays are par for the course for any large developer, and data in China is often incomplete, the court documents shed light on a contrast between the image Country Garden presented publicly and some of its challenges behind closed doors.翻译:尽管争议和延误对任何大型开发商来说都是司空见惯的事情，而且中国的数据往往不完整，但法庭文件揭示了碧桂园公开展示的形象与闭门造车面临的一些挑战之间的对比。</p>   <p>In a case over alleged delayed delivery of apartments in the central megacity Chongqing, the local Country Garden subsidiary told the court it owed 60 million yuan ($8.2 million) in project payments and "faced severe financial losses and was unable to cover its liabilities", according to a verdict handed down in June.翻译:在中央大城市重庆涉嫌延迟交付公寓的案件中，碧桂园当地子公司告诉法院，其欠下 6000 万元人民币（820 万美元）的工程款，并且“面临严重的财务损失，无法偿还债务”，根据六月份作出的判决。</p>   <p>It said it was, "insolvent and overwhelmed, and even if the court reduced the damages at its own discretion, it may still be hard for the defendant to fulfill its obligations in the future."翻译:其表示，“资不抵债，不堪重负，即使法院自行裁量减少损害赔偿，被告今后仍可能难以履行其义务。”</p>   <p>Other court cases feature similar examples from last year and early this year: They involve sums as small as 267,475 yuan in arrears for 50% of an elevator installation fee or 2.8 million yuan demanded by an electrical installation company.翻译:去年和今年年初的其他法院案件也有类似的例子：其中涉及拖欠电梯安装费50%的267,475元或电气安装公司索要的280万元。</p>   <p>Some large contractors decided to skip the court process altogether, according to a steel supplier based in south China. He told Reuters "the priority for us is to get our money back through negotiations instead of filing a lawsuit, which is very time-consuming and won’t necessarily yield a satisfactory result."翻译:据华南一家钢铁供应商称，一些大型承包商决定完全跳过法庭程序。他告诉路透社，“我们的首要任务是通过谈判拿回我们的钱，而不是提起诉讼，这非常耗时，而且不一定会产生令人满意的结果。”</p>   <p>Country Garden owed the supplier, who did not want to be identified due to the sensitivity of the situation, an equivalent of several million dollars for reinforced steel bars.翻译:碧桂园欠该供应商相当于数百万美元的钢筋，由于情况敏感，该供应商不愿透露姓名。</p>   <p>He was promised half of the owed amount in unfinished apartments. The other half was to be paid in cash, but the supplier has so far only received a quarter of the payment.翻译:他得到了半数未完工公寓欠款的承诺。另一半则以现金支付，但供应商迄今为止只收到了四分之一的货款。</p>   <p>"The situation deteriorated from the second half of 2022, and it’s become even worse from the start of this year, when the payment to us was delayed,” said the supplier.翻译:该供应商表示：“从2022年下半年开始，情况就开始恶化，从今年年初开始，情况变得更糟，我们的付款被推迟了。”</p>   <p>The impact of Country Garden’s cash crunch has reverberated even after the missed August payments.翻译:即使在八月份未能付款之后，碧桂园现金紧缩的影响仍然产生了影响。</p>   <p>A week after that, contractor Qiao Jingjing, said his construction site in Xinzheng, a city of 1.2 million in Henan Province, also stalled.翻译:一周后，承包商乔晶晶表示，他位于河南省新郑市（拥有 120 万人口的城市）的建筑工地也陷入停滞。</p>   <p>Qiao, 38, was left with 20,000 yuan in unpaid wages for two months of his work. He said his company, Jujiang Group, which was a subcontractor at the site installing aluminum sheets, is owed more than 770,000 yuan.翻译:38岁的乔被拖欠了两个月的工资2万元。他说，他的公司钜江集团是现场安装铝板的分包商，欠债超过77万元。</p>   <p>Country Garden did not respond to questions about the payment or delivery disputes.翻译:碧桂园没有回应有关付款或交货纠纷的问题。</p>   <p>Qiao said apartment buyers and construction workers kept coming to Country Garden offices seeking information.翻译:乔说，公寓买家和建筑工人不断来到碧桂园办公室寻求信息。</p>   <p>"But Country Garden's sales staff have never given us any reply to these questions: When will the construction resume? When can the property be handed over to the owners? When will the workers get their wages?”翻译:“但碧桂园的销售人员从来没有给我们任何答复：什么时候恢复施工？什么时候可以把房产交给业主？工人什么时候可以拿到工资？”</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2800 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2800 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Clare Jim, Liangping Gao, Amy Lv, Laurie Chen and Beijing newsroom; Editing by Antoni Slodkowski and Lincoln Feast.翻译:Clare Jim、高亮平、Amy Lv、Laurie Chen 和北京新闻编辑室报道；安东尼·斯洛德科夫斯基和林肯·费斯特编辑。</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 02:46:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">EGBH6BS27BN5DPDIV6ZF7J7VWI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/long-before-rescue-talks-country-garden-struggled-build-homes-pay-bills-2023-11-09/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/DEBT</category>
                
                <category>COUNTRYGARDEN (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
