<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 18:27:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国在首次金融工作组会议上“坦诚提出”与中国的分歧]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/slhmzWrAQUGr8MCcbKpvD8PMuYw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VXFHK2QF6ZKRLFLJMHYEX7CX54.jpg" alt="Illustration shows U.S. and Chinese flags<br><br>插图显示美国和中国国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. and Chinese flags are seen in this illustration taken, January 30, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File photo<br><br>这张摄于 2023 年 1 月 30 日的插图中可以看到美国和中国国旗。 REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S. officials "frankly raised areas of disagreement" with China at the first meeting of a new financial working group, where financial stability, supervision and regulation were discussed, the U.S. Treasury said on Wednesday.<br><br>美国财政部周三表示，美国官员在新金融工作组的第一次会议上“坦率地提出了与中国的分歧领域”，会议讨论了金融稳定、监督和监管问题。</p>   <p>Attendees included senior officials from China's central bank and the U.S. Treasury Department, according to a Treasury statement.<br><br>根据美国财政部的一份声明，与会者包括中国央行和美国财政部的高级官员。</p>   <p>"The two-hour virtual meeting included a substantive and wide-ranging discussion on domestic and global financial stability, financial supervision and regulation, sustainable finance, and anti-money laundering and countering the financing of terrorism," the Treasury said.<br><br>美国财政部表示：“两个小时的虚拟会议就国内和全球金融稳定、金融监督和监管、可持续金融、反洗钱和打击资助恐怖主义等问题进行了实质性和广泛的讨论。”</p>   <p>The financial working group and a parallel economic working group were <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us-treasury-launches-us-china-economic-financial-working-groups-2023-09-22/">launched last month</a> after U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen's visit to Beijing in July aimed at fostering regular communications between the world's two largest economies.<br><br>美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦 (Janet Yellen) 7 月访问北京后， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us-treasury-launches-us-china-economic-financial-working-groups-2023-09-22/">上个月成立了</a>金融工作组和平行经济工作组，旨在促进世界最大两个经济体之间的定期沟通。</p>   <p>The economic working group, led by senior officials from the Treasury and China's Finance Ministry <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-us-officials-discuss-macroeconomic-developments-meeting-2023-10-24/">held its first meeting</a> on Monday.<br><br>由财政部和中国财政部高级官员领导的经济工作组周一<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-us-officials-discuss-macroeconomic-developments-meeting-2023-10-24/">举行了第一次会议</a>。</p>   <p>Yellen met with People's Bank of China Governor Pan Gongsheng on Oct. 13 on the sidelines of International Monetary Fund and World Bank annual meetings in Marrakech, Morocco, and discussed debt issues plaguing developing economies and the global financial architecture.<br><br>10月13日，耶伦在摩洛哥马拉喀什出席国际货币基金组织和世界银行年会期间会见中国人民银行行长潘功胜，双方讨论了困扰发展中经济体的债务问题和全球金融架构。</p>   <p>Yellen <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/yellen-says-us-backed-imf-funding-increase-pretty-likely-2023-10-13/">told Reuters in an interview</a> that the discussion included a U.S.-backed plan to increase IMF quota-based lending resources without changes to its shareholding structure. China has been reluctant to support the funding increase without an increase in its IMF shares, but Yellen said the "equi-proportional" quota increase is "pretty likely" to succeed.<br><br>耶伦<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/yellen-says-us-backed-imf-funding-increase-pretty-likely-2023-10-13/">在接受路透社采访时表示</a>，讨论内容包括一项美国支持的计划，即在不改变其股权结构的情况下增加国际货币基金组织基于配额的贷款资源。中国一直不愿在不增加其国际货币基金组织份额的情况下支持增加资金，但耶伦表示，“等比例”配额增加“很有可能”成功。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ismail Shakil, Costas Pitas and David Lawder; editing by Paul Grant and Diane Craft<br><br>伊斯梅尔·沙基尔 (Ismail Shakil)、科斯塔斯·皮塔斯 (Costas Pitas) 和大卫·劳德 (David Lawder) 报道；保罗·格兰特和黛安·克拉夫特编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 18:20:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">EGNAGTG7TRKQLJAEYXXFRVEV6A</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/us-frankly-raised-disagreements-with-china-first-financial-working-group-meeting-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/DISAGREEMENTS (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[五角大楼官员：美国潜艇工业基地能够而且将会支持AUKUS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. submarine industrial base can and will support the AUKUS project to supply Australia with nuclear-powered submarines and will itself be strengthened by that project, a senior Pentagon official said in prepared testimony on Wednesday.<br><br>五角大楼高级官员周三在准备好的证词中表示，美国潜艇工业基地能够而且将会支持 AUKUS 项目，为澳大利亚提供核动力潜艇，并将通过该项目得到加强。</p>   <p>Mara Karlin, the acting deputy under secretary of defense for policy, made the statement in testimony for a hearing of a subcommittee of the House of Representatives Armed Services Committee, during a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-australia-discuss-china-pacific-security-white-house-visit-2023-10-25/">visit to Washington</a> by Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese.<br><br>澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内斯<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-australia-discuss-china-pacific-security-white-house-visit-2023-10-25/">访问华盛顿</a>期间，国防部负责政策的代理副部长玛拉·卡林在众议院军事委员会小组委员会的听证会上作证时发表了上述声明。</p>   <p>"AUKUS contributes to building a more robust defense industrial base ecosystem that contributes to integrated deterrence; and ... the submarine industrial base can and will support AUKUS," her testimony said.<br><br>她的证词说：“AUKUS有助于建立一个更强大的国防工业基础生态系统，有助于综合威慑；而且......潜艇工业基地可以而且将会支持AUKUS。”</p>    <span>Reporting by David Brunnstrom and Mike Stone<br><br>大卫·布伦斯特罗姆和迈克·斯通报道</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 18:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MMKRHPHRVBPRPDOLPXTS32DUDA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us-submarine-industrial-base-can-will-support-aukus-pentagon-official-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA/AUKUS (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stellantis接近收购中国电动汽车制造商零跑汽车股份的交易--消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/xSzl_4sc_ayjQGBk8kNIw6IGfAY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TQWOAFXWMVIDVDROS3LADTPPOA.jpg" alt="A flag with the logo of Stellantis is seen near Paris<br><br>巴黎附近出现一面带有斯特兰蒂斯标志的旗帜" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A flag with the logo of Stellantis is seen at the company's corporate office building in Saint-Quentin-en-Yvelines near Paris, France, May 5, 2021. REUTERS/Gonzalo Fuentes/File Photo<br><br>2021 年 5 月 5 日，法国巴黎附近圣康坦伊夫林省的公司办公大楼内悬挂着一面带有 Stellantis 标志的旗帜。 REUTERS/Gonzalo Fuentes/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Stellantis NV <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/STLAM.MI" target="_blank">(STLAM.MI)</a> is nearing a deal to acquire a stake in electric vehicle company Zhejiang Leapmotor &lt;9863.HK&gt;, a source close to the matter said on Wednesday, and the car maker said it would give an important update on Thursday.<br><br>据知情人士周三透露，Stellantis NV <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/STLAM.MI" target="_blank">(STLAM.MI)</a>即将达成收购电动汽车公司零跑汽车 &lt;9863.HK&gt; 股权的交易，该汽车制造商表示将在周四发布重要最新消息。</p>   <p>Earlier on Wednesday, Bloomberg reported that Stellantis was close to agreeing the purchase of a stake of roughly 20% in Leapmotor.<br><br>周三早些时候，彭博社报道称，Stellantis即将同意收购零跑汽车约20%的股份。</p>   <p>Stellantis and Leapmotor are also discussing setting up a joint venture as part of the transaction, the Bloomberg report said, adding that a partnership could allow Stellantis to manufacture and sell some Leapmotor cars outside China.<br><br>彭博社报道称，Stellantis 和零跑汽车还在讨论作为交易的一部分建立一家合资企业，并补充说，合作伙伴关系可以让 Stellantis 在中国境外生产和销售一些零跑汽车。</p>   <p>The partnership would give Stellantis access to the EV maker's parts and certain technologies, Bloomberg said.<br><br>彭博社表示，此次合作将使 Stellantis 能够获得这家电动汽车制造商的零部件和某些技术。</p>   <p>Stellantis, whose brands include Fiat and Peugeot, has only a very small presence in China, the world's largest auto market. The group and rivals such as Renault <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RENA.PA" target="_blank">(RENA.PA)</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/western-car-makers-look-slash-ev-costs-fight-chinese-invasion-2023-07-27/">are concerned</a> about growing competition from cheap Chinese electric cars in Europe.<br><br>Stellantis旗下品牌包括菲亚特和标致，但在全球最大的汽车市场中国的业务规模很小。该集团和雷诺<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RENA.PA" target="_blank">（RENA.PA）</a>等竞争对手<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/western-car-makers-look-slash-ev-costs-fight-chinese-invasion-2023-07-27/">担心</a>欧洲廉价中国电动汽车的竞争日益激烈。</p>   <p>In a statement, Stellantis said it had previously announced it was "studying scenarios to seize business opportunities linked to the dynamics of Chinese manufacturers in the context of the electrification of the global automobile market". It did not elaborate.<br><br>Stellantis在一份声明中表示，该公司此前曾宣布“正在研究情景，以在全球汽车市场电气化的背景下抓住与中国制造商动态相关的商机”。它没有详细说明。</p>   <p>On Wednesday, the company sent out an invitation to journalists for Thursday morning for an "important update," without giving details.<br><br>周三，该公司向记者发出了周四上午发布“重要更新”的邀请，但没有透露细节。</p>   <p>Leapmotor, which has a market value of around 42 billion Hong Kong dollars ($5.4 billion), declined to comment. Its shares have gained some 22% this year.<br><br>零跑汽车的市值约为 420 亿港元（54 亿美元），拒绝置评。今年其股价上涨了约22%。</p>   <p>Stellantis is due to publish its third-quarter revenue figures next Tuesday.<br><br>Stellantis 定于下周二公布第三季度营收数据。</p>   <p>The group said a year ago it was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/stellantis-q3-sales-up-29-better-chip-supplies-lift-shipments-2022-11-03/">closing its joint venture</a> that makes Jeeps in China with local partner Guangzhou Automobile Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601238.SS" target="_blank">(601238.SS)</a> amid disappointing results.<br><br>该集团一年前表示，由于业绩令人失望，它将关闭与当地合作伙伴广州汽车集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601238.SS" target="_blank">（601238.SS）</a>在中国生产吉普车的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/stellantis-q3-sales-up-29-better-chip-supplies-lift-shipments-2022-11-03/">合资企业</a>。</p>   <p>Leapmotor said last week its gross margin in the third quarter had turned positive, the first time for the startup even though the industry has been suffering a price war this year.<br><br>零跑汽车上周表示，尽管今年该行业遭遇了价格战，但其第三季度的毛利率已转为正数，这对于初创公司来说还是第一次。</p>   <p>It is a goal the company has been striving for this year, mainly to improve its valuation with a view to a further fundraising, a person with direct knowledge of the matter said.<br><br>一位直接知情人士表示，这是该公司今年一直在努力实现的目标，主要是为了提高估值，以期进一步融资。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.8215 Hong Kong dollars)<br><br>(1 美元 = 7.8215 港元)</p>    <span>Reporting by Akanksha Khushi in Bengaluru, Gilles Guillaume in Paris and Giulio Piovaccari in Milan; additional reporting by Zhang Yan in Shanghai; Writing by Keith Weir and Silvia Aloisi; Editing by Shilpi Majumdar, Shweta Agarwal, Mike Harrison, Jan Harvey and David Gregorio<br><br>班加罗尔的 Akanksha Khushi、巴黎的 Gilles Guillaume 和米兰的 Giulio Piovaccari 的报道；张岩上海补充报道；作者：Keith Weir 和 Silvia Aloisi；编辑：Shilpi Majumdar、Shweta Agarwal、Mike Harrison、Jan Harvey 和 David Gregorio</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:30:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">KNN275OOI5PWZAIFKY2PS5H7JI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/stellantis-nears-deal-buy-20-chinese-ev-maker-leapmotor-bloomberg-news-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Gilles Guillaume, Giulio Piovaccari]]></author>
            
                
                <category>STELLANTIS</category>
                
                <category>LEAPMOTOR/STAKE (UPDATE 4)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[德国芯片套件供应商受到中国出口审查收紧的打击]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>German chip-making kit supplier Süss MicroTec <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SMHNn.DE" target="_blank">(SMHNn.DE)</a> cut its sales forecasts for the second time in three months, blaming tightened government controls for exports to China, sending shares tumbling 11%.<br><br>德国芯片制造套件供应商 Süss MicroTec <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SMHNn.DE" target="_blank">(SMHNn.DE)</a>三个月内第二次下调销售预期，指责政府加强对中国出口的控制，导致股价下跌 11%。</p>   <p>The south German company said on Wednesday that deliveries worth 23.5 million euros ($24.86 million) were stuck at customs, adding that, though rules had not changed, customs appeared to have significantly stepped up their inspections for deliveries to China since August.<br><br>这家德国南部公司周三表示，价值 2350 万欧元（合 2486 万美元）的货物滞留在海关，并补充说，尽管规则没有改变，但自 8 月以来，海关似乎大幅加强了对运往中国的货物的检查。</p>   <p>German customs did not immediately respond to a request for comment.<br><br>德国海关没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>In July, the government urged German firms to reduce their dependence on demand from China as part of a strategy of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/derisking-dilemma-how-german-companies-are-tackling-china-risk-2023-10-19/">"de-risking" its economic relationship</a> with the superpower.<br><br>7月，德国政府敦促德国企业减少对中国需求的依赖，作为<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/derisking-dilemma-how-german-companies-are-tackling-china-risk-2023-10-19/">“降低”与这个超级大国经济关系风险的</a>战略的一部分。</p>   <p>The uncertainty meant it was impossible to predict how many machines would have been delivered by the end of the year. The goods affected would have been especially lucrative, the small-cap maker of lithography equipment and other chipmaking gear said.<br><br>这种不确定性意味着无法预测到年底将交付多少台机器。这家光刻设备和其他芯片制造设备的小型制造商表示，受影响的商品利润特别丰厚。</p>   <p>Süss Microtec expects sales of between 300 and 340 million euros this year, compared to 299.1 million euros last year, a smaller increase than they expected earlier. The company trimmed its EBIT margin outlook to 4%-8% from an earlier 9%-11%.<br><br>Süss Microtec 预计今年的销售额将在 300 至 3.4 亿欧元之间，而去年为 2.991 亿欧元，增幅小于他们之前的预期。该公司将息税前利润率预期从之前的 9%-11% 下调至 4%-8%。</p>   <p>($1 = 0.9454 euros)<br><br>（1 美元 = 0.9454 欧元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Alexander Hübner, writing by Thomas Escritt; Editing by Rod Nickel<br><br>亚历山大·胡布纳 (Alexander Hübner) 报道，托马斯·埃斯克里特 (Thomas Escritt) 撰稿；罗德·尼克尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:02:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">D5YGYXSINJIIBHPAOYXAEEACFU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/german-chip-kit-supplier-hit-by-tightened-china-export-scrutiny-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GERMANY</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/SUESS MICROTEC (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[超过一半的哈马斯人质拥有外国国籍——以色列]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/CB19H1aE0oAalxc7nvvNOrGafTc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NTVQM7TMDNO47CO5EPDIET7JYU.jpg" alt="A view shows teddy bears, each representing children who are believed to be held hostage in Gaza, in Tel Aviv<br><br>图为特拉维夫的泰迪熊，每只泰迪熊都代表据信在加沙被扣为人质的儿童" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view shows teddy bears, each representing children who are believed to be held hostage in Gaza after being taken by Hamas gunmen during a deadly infiltration, at Dizengoff Square in Tel Aviv, Israel October 25, 2023. REUTERS/Janis Laizans<br><br>2023 年 10 月 25 日，以色列特拉维夫迪岑哥夫广场上的一幅画中，泰迪熊代表了据信在加沙地带被哈马斯枪手劫持后被扣为人质的儿童。 以色列特拉维夫迪岑哥夫广场</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/aysADm8n1OzTyXvlMq6W2EBYs2c=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GWJB64IDYBINLFLUSG7ZBRB75U.jpg" alt="President of the German Bundestag Baerbel Bas receives family members of Germans kidnapped by Hamas militants, in Berlin<br><br>德国联邦议院主席巴尔贝尔·巴斯在柏林接见被哈马斯武装分子绑架的德国人的家人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>President of the German Bundestag Baerbel Bas receives relatives of the German citizens kidnapped by Palestinian Islamist group Hamas, at the Bundestag in Berlin, Germany October 19, 2023. REUTERS/Annegret Hilse/File photo<br><br>2023 年 10 月 19 日，德国柏林联邦议院主席巴尔贝尔·巴斯 (Baerbel Bas) 在德国柏林联邦议院接见被巴勒斯坦伊斯兰组织哈马斯绑架的德国公民的亲属。 REUTERS/Annegret Hilse/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TnF2ExAURdQH9L0pxWFhRNM_ivE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZK6W445T6ZMQNIX2ECBE4U7PN4.jpg" alt="Bodies of Thai workers killed in Israel, arrive in Bangkok<br><br>在以色列遇难的泰国工人尸体抵达曼谷" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Coffins carrying bodies of Thai migrant agricultural workers who were killed in an attack by the Palestinian militant group Hamas on Israel, arrive at Bangkok's Suvarnabhumi Airport, Thailand, October 20, 2023. REUTERS/Artorn Pookasook/File Photo<br><br>2023 年 10 月 20 日，运载着在巴勒斯坦激进组织哈马斯对以色列的袭击中丧生的泰国农民工尸体的棺材抵达泰国曼谷素万那普机场。 REUTERS/Artorn Pookasook/档案照片</figcaption></figure>                 <p>More than half the estimated 220 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/what-do-we-now-about-hamas-hostages-2023-10-19/">hostages</a> held by Palestinian group Hamas have foreign passports from 25 different countries, including 54 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/thai-worker-ducks-crawls-flee-kibbutz-hamas-guns-down-friends-2023-10-13/">Thai</a> nationals, the Israeli government said on Wednesday.<br><br>以色列政府周三表示，巴勒斯坦组织哈马斯扣押的 220 名<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/what-do-we-now-about-hamas-hostages-2023-10-19/">人质</a>中，一半以上持有来自 25 个不同国家的外国护照，其中包括 54 名<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/thai-worker-ducks-crawls-flee-kibbutz-hamas-guns-down-friends-2023-10-13/">泰国</a>国民。</p>   <p>In providing updated figures, the government also said 328 people from 40 countries were confirmed as dead or missing after the surprise Oct. 7 attack by Hamas fighters on southern Israel. In all, an estimated 1,400 people were killed in the assault.<br><br>政府在提供最新数据时还表示，10 月 7 日哈马斯武装分子对以色列南部发动突然袭击后，已确认来自 40 个国家的 328 人死亡或失踪。总共估计有 1,400 人在袭击中丧生。</p>   <p>Israel said 138 of the hostages had foreign passports, including 15 Argentinians, 12 Germans, 12 Americans, six French and six Russians.<br><br>以色列称，其中138名人质持有外国护照，其中包括15名阿根廷人、12名德国人、12名美国人、6名法国人和6名俄罗斯人。</p>   <p>Many were believed to have had dual Israeli nationality, however some, like the Thais and five Nepalese hostages, almost certainly did not. There was also one Chinese hostage, one Sri Lankan, two from Tanzania and two from the Philippines.<br><br>据信，许多人拥有以色列双重国籍，但有些人，如泰国人质和五名尼泊尔人质，几乎可以肯定没有。还有一名中国人质、一名斯里兰卡人质、两名坦桑尼亚人质和两名菲律宾人质。</p>   <p>Thais also made up the largest single group of foreign dead and missing, with 24 confirmed killed and 21 unaccounted for.<br><br>泰国人也是外国死亡和失踪人数最多的群体，确认有 24 人死亡，21 人下落不明。</p>   <p>Thailand is one of the largest sources of migrant workers in Israel, with around 30,000 working in the agriculture sector, according to government data.<br><br>政府数据显示，泰国是以色列最大的移民工人来源国之一，约有 3 万人在农业部门工作。</p>   <p>Among other foreign nations that suffered heavy losses were the United States, with 34 killed and five missing, Ukraine, with 25 killed and two missing, France, with 23 killed and one missing, and Russia with 23 killed and four missing.<br><br>其他遭受重创的国家包括美国（34人死亡、5人失踪）、乌克兰（25人死亡、2人失踪）、法国（23人死亡、1人失踪）、俄罗斯（23人死亡、4人失踪）。</p>   <p>Five Chinese citizens were killed and one was missing, while Nepal had five killed and five missing.<br><br>中国公民有5人死亡、1人失踪，尼泊尔有5人死亡、5人失踪。</p>    <span>Reporting by Crispian Balmer; Editing by Rod Nickel<br><br>克里斯皮安·巴尔默报道；罗德·尼克尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 16:34:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">KMFWLBOCORJA5M5QVDX3MRHQUI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/more-than-half-hamas-hostages-have-foreign-nationality-israel-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ISRAEL</category>
                
                <category>PALESTINIANS/FOREIGNERS (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[赛默飞世尔警告生物技术资金紧缩将给行业带来更多痛苦]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/l6uh99Debo97a6ZgpGa13ukg8dE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4JC6WZO33BNWFNFKEMOYPM2SCQ.jpg" alt="The offices of Thermo Fisher Scientific stand in Waltham<br><br>Thermo Fisher Scientific 位于沃尔瑟姆的办公室" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A sign marks the offices of Thermo Fisher Scientific offices in Waltham, Massachusetts, U.S., August 2, 2023. REUTERS/Brian Snyder/File Photo<br><br>2023 年 8 月 2 日，美国马萨诸塞州沃尔瑟姆赛默飞世尔科技公司办公室的标志牌。路透社/Brian Snyder/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Thermo Fisher Scientific <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TMO.N" target="_blank">(TMO.N)</a> on Wednesday signaled that a slump in demand from biotechs for its services used in making therapies and vaccines could extend into the next year, sending its shares tumbling more than 7% and weighing on the sector.<br><br>赛默飞世尔科技<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TMO.N" target="_blank">(TMO.N)</a>周三表示，生物技术公司对其用于制造疗法和疫苗的服务的需求下滑可能会持续到明年，导致其股价下跌超过 7%，给该行业带来压力。</p>   <p>Biotechs, hit by a funding crunch due to higher interest rates, have reined in spending on drug development since the start of the year while slowing growth in China has also crimped demand for contract research services and lab equipment.<br><br>生物技术公司因利率上升而受到资金紧缩的打击，自今年年初以来一直在控制药物开发支出，而中国经济增长放缓也抑制了对合同研究服务和实验室设备的需求。</p>   <p>"Short term, if you're visiting a smaller biotech customer, what you're seeing is concerns about when the funding environment is going to improve. So, there's a level of caution," CEO Marc Casper said on an earnings call.<br><br>“短期来看，如果你拜访一家规模较小的生物技术客户，你会看到融资环境何时会改善的担忧。因此，需要保持一定程度的谨慎，”首席执行官马克·卡斯珀(Marc Casper)在财报电话会议上表示。</p>   <p>On the call, finance chief Stephen Williamson said core revenue growth and adjusted profit in 2024 will be similar to that in 2023.<br><br>财务主管斯蒂芬·威廉姆森在电话会议上表示，2024 年核心收入增长和调整后利润将与 2023 年类似。</p>   <p>The company cut its revenue expectations for this year to $42.7 billion, from $43.4 billion to $44 billion. It also forecast 2023 adjusted profit of $21.50 per share, below analysts' estimates of $22.28.<br><br>该公司将今年的收入预期从 434 亿美元下调至 440 亿美元，下调至 427 亿美元。它还预测 2023 年调整后每股利润为 21.50 美元，低于分析师预期的 22.28 美元。</p>   <p>Thermo Fisher's 2024 comments on potential rebound from current challenges were "little bit more bearish" than expected, said Raymond James analyst Andrew Cooper.<br><br>雷蒙德·詹姆斯 (Raymond James) 分析师安德鲁·库珀 (Andrew Cooper) 表示，赛默飞世尔对 2024 年当前挑战可能反弹的评论比预期“略显悲观”。</p>   <p>The medical equipment maker forecast adjusted earnings of $21.75 per share in 2024, short of analysts' estimates by $2.23.<br><br>这家医疗设备制造商预计 2024 年调整后每股收益为 21.75 美元，比分析师的预期低 2.23 美元。</p>   <p>Shares of rivals Agilent Technologies <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/A.N" target="_blank">(A.N)</a> and Danaher <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DHR.N" target="_blank">(DHR.N)</a> declined between 2% and 3%.<br><br>竞争对手安捷伦科技<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/A.N" target="_blank">(AN)</a>和丹纳赫<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/DHR.N" target="_blank">(DHR.N)</a>的股价下跌 2% 至 3%。</p>      <p>Thermo Fisher, which has bet on deals to become a one-stop shop for its biotech and large pharmaceutical clients, said sales in its life sciences solution unit plunged about 18% to $2.43 billion, declining for all the three quarters this year.<br><br>赛默飞世尔致力于成为其生物技术和大型制药客户的一站式商店，该公司表示，其生命科学解决方案部门的销售额下降了约 18%，至 24.3 亿美元，今年三个季度都在下降。</p>   <p>Third-quarter revenue of $10.57 billion missed analysts' expectations of $10.60 billion while adjusted profit of $5.69 per share topped estimates of $5.61, according to LSEG data.<br><br>LSEG 数据显示，第三季度营收为 105.7 亿美元，低于分析师预期的 106 亿美元，而调整后每股利润 5.69 美元高于预期的 5.61 美元。</p>    <span>Reporting by Bhanvi Satija in Bengaluru; Editing by Shinjini Ganguli, Shounak Dasgupta and Sriraj Kalluvila<br><br>Bhanvi Satija 班加罗尔报道；编辑：Shinjini Ganguli、Shounak Dasgupta 和 Sriraj Kalluvila</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 16:33:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">GDB4ZP6FB5JXBFLH4KRZM3R5ZY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/thermo-fisher-cuts-annual-profit-forecast-weak-biotech-demand-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Bhanvi Satija]]></author>
            
                
                <category>THERMO FISHER</category>
                
                <category>RESULTS/ (UPDATE 5, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[澳大利亚阿尔巴尼斯会见拜登，强调在以色列-哈马斯危机中保护生命]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/KbctbdCtCbMFEbJEDsiDnK8j1O8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WZ4GHRG2CBPLJHCPIEZIVMY7LM.jpg" alt="U.S. President Biden welcomes Australia’s Prime Minister Albanese at official White House State Arrival ceremony at the White House in Washington<br><br>美国总统拜登在华盛顿白宫举行的正式白宫国庆仪式上欢迎澳大利亚总理阿尔巴内斯<br><br>美国总统拜登在华盛顿白宫举行的正式白宫国庆仪式上欢迎澳大利亚总理阿尔巴内斯" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden speaks as Australia’s Prime Minister Anthony Albanese listens during an official White House State Arrival ceremony on the South Lawn of the White House in Washington, U.S., October 25, 2023. REUTERS/Leah Millis<br><br>2023 年 10 月 25 日，美国华盛顿，美国总统乔·拜登在美国华盛顿白宫南草坪举行的正式白宫国庆仪式上发表讲话，澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博尼斯在旁听。路透社/Leah Millis</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/V3kunE7UpsfatmALwey_xNSNjxY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CZZ2IXO3H5NZ7DRJLFWNP2XLMQ.jpg" alt="U.S. President Biden welcomes Australia’s Prime Minister Albanese at official White House State Arrival ceremony at the White House in Washington<br><br>美国总统拜登在华盛顿白宫举行的正式白宫国庆仪式上欢迎澳大利亚总理阿尔巴内斯<br><br>美国总统拜登在华盛顿白宫举行的正式白宫国庆仪式上欢迎澳大利亚总理阿尔巴内斯" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden and first lady Jill Biden walk with Australia’s Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and his partner Ms. Jodie Haydon as they arrive for an official White House State Arrival ceremony on the South Lawn of the White House in Washington, U.S., October 25, 2023. REUTERS/Leah Millis<br><br>10 月 25 日，美国总统乔·拜登和第一夫人吉尔·拜登与澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内斯及其伴侣朱迪·海顿女士一起抵达美国华盛顿白宫南草坪，参加正式的白宫国庆仪式。 2023.路透社/利亚·米利斯</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/kMz8R3unysejvuo99yU7BgIGDgQ=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2UJYSRMRQFI57O7CQR75G3KLQA.jpg" alt="Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese's visits Washington<br><br>澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞访问华盛顿" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden and first lady Jill Biden welcome Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and his partner Jodie Haydon to the White House ahead of an official state visit at the White House in Washington, D.C., U.S., October 24, 2023. REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger<br><br>美国总统乔·拜登和第一夫人吉尔·拜登于 2023 年 10 月 24 日在美国华盛顿特区白宫欢迎澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞和他的伴侣朱迪·海顿在对白宫进行正式国事访问之前抵达白宫。 REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger<br><br>美国总统乔·拜登和第一夫人吉尔·拜登于 2023 年 10 月 24 日在美国华盛顿特区白宫欢迎澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞和他的伴侣朱迪·海顿在对白宫进行正式国事访问之前抵达白宫。 REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger<br><br>美国总统乔·拜登和第一夫人吉尔·拜登于 2023 年 10 月 24 日在美国华盛顿特区白宫欢迎澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞和他的伴侣朱迪·海顿在对白宫进行正式国事访问之前抵达白宫。 REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/A5d65zVVPq8NceEFHPH5wdNpOok=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KWMF7S5RDJJ2FFHI2IHG2UTVIE.jpg" alt="Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits Washington<br><br>澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞访问华盛顿<br><br>澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞访问华盛顿" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden and first lady Jill Biden welcome Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and his partner Jodie Haydon to the White House ahead of an official state visit at the White House in Washington, D.C., U.S., October 24, 2023. REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger<br><br>美国总统乔·拜登和第一夫人吉尔·拜登于 2023 年 10 月 24 日在美国华盛顿特区白宫欢迎澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞和他的伴侣朱迪·海顿在对白宫进行正式国事访问之前抵达白宫。 REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger<br><br>美国总统乔·拜登和第一夫人吉尔·拜登于 2023 年 10 月 24 日在美国华盛顿特区白宫欢迎澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞和他的伴侣朱迪·海顿在对白宫进行正式国事访问之前抵达白宫。 REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger<br><br>美国总统乔·拜登和第一夫人吉尔·拜登于 2023 年 10 月 24 日在美国华盛顿特区白宫欢迎澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞和他的伴侣朱迪·海顿在对白宫进行正式国事访问之前抵达白宫。 REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Q8RDb-pHE-e-KPnKCs3FVZ8wNb4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3VWOE4U4JBPXPHO5ZITYJXHLT4.jpg" alt="Australia state dinner preview at White House in Washington<br><br>澳大利亚国宴在华盛顿白宫预演" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Guest chef Katie Button and White House chefs preview the menu and place settings for the state dinner in honor of Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese in the State Dining Room at the White House in Washington, D.C., U.S., October 24, 2023. REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger<br><br>2023 年 10 月 24 日，美国华盛顿特区白宫国宴厅，客座主厨凯蒂·巴顿 (Katie Button) 和白宫厨师预览澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内斯 (Anthony Albanese) 国宴的菜单和餐位设置。 REUTERS/Sarah西尔比格</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/-yYDbuXSOq-KG3RgBtQWftPnDJY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/LWJW2ZYAAZJFDFNOBVGZFO36HI.jpg" alt="Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits Washington<br><br>澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞访问华盛顿<br><br>澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞访问华盛顿" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden and first lady Jill Biden welcome Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and his partner Jodie Haydon to the White House ahead of an official state visit at the White House in Washington, D.C., U.S., October 24, 2023. REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger<br><br>美国总统乔·拜登和第一夫人吉尔·拜登于 2023 年 10 月 24 日在美国华盛顿特区白宫欢迎澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞和他的伴侣朱迪·海顿在对白宫进行正式国事访问之前抵达白宫。 REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger<br><br>美国总统乔·拜登和第一夫人吉尔·拜登于 2023 年 10 月 24 日在美国华盛顿特区白宫欢迎澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞和他的伴侣朱迪·海顿在对白宫进行正式国事访问之前抵达白宫。 REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger<br><br>美国总统乔·拜登和第一夫人吉尔·拜登于 2023 年 10 月 24 日在美国华盛顿特区白宫欢迎澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内塞和他的伴侣朱迪·海顿在对白宫进行正式国事访问之前抵达白宫。 REUTERS/Sarah Silbiger</figcaption></figure>                       <p>U.S. President Joe Biden welcomed Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese to the White House on Wednesday to talk defense and China strategy, but the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/world-leaders-seek-suspend-israel-hamas-fighting-gaza-aid-2023-10-24/">growing Middle East crisis</a> took center stage.<br><br>美国总统乔·拜登周三欢迎澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内斯来到白宫，讨论国防和中国战略，但<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/world-leaders-seek-suspend-israel-hamas-fighting-gaza-aid-2023-10-24/">日益严重的中东危机</a>成为焦点。</p>   <p>"You have spoken with moral clarity, and you have stood up for a simple principle - the principle that every innocent life matters, Israeli and Palestinian,” Albanese said on the White House lawn about Biden's approach to the crisis.<br><br>阿尔巴内斯在白宫草坪上谈到拜登应对危机的方法时说：“你的讲话道德清晰，你坚持了一个简单的原则——每一个无辜的生命都很重要，无论是以色列还是巴勒斯坦。”</p>   <p>"American leadership is indispensable, but it is not inevitable," he added. "It takes a leader to deliver it…it takes true leadership to seek peace, because protecting innocent people is not a show of weakness, it is a measure of strength."<br><br>“美国的领导作用不可或缺，但并非不可避免，”他补充道。 “这需要一个领导人来实现……寻求和平需要真正的领导力，因为保护无辜人民不是示弱，而是力量的衡量标准。”</p>   <p>A growing chorus of nations are pushing Israel to take a humanitarian pause in its attacks on Hamas in Gaza that have killed thousands of Palestinians, many of them children. Biden, a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/i-am-zionist-how-joe-bidens-lifelong-bond-with-israel-shapes-war-policy-2023-10-21/">self-described "Zionist"</a>, has strongly supported Israel following Hamas' Oct. 7 attack while cautioning the country to abide by democratic principles.<br><br>越来越多的国家齐声敦促以色列暂停对加沙哈马斯的袭击，这场袭击已造成数千名巴勒斯坦人死亡，其中许多是儿童。 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/i-am-zionist-how-joe-bidens-lifelong-bond-with-israel-shapes-war-policy-2023-10-21/">自称“犹太复国主义者”的</a>拜登在哈马斯 10 月 7 日袭击后强烈支持以色列，同时警告该国遵守民主原则。</p>   <p>Australia is a key ally in the Pacific, and Biden scheduled the visit after <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-facing-debt-ceiling-debate-could-skip-australia-part-asia-trip-2023-05-16/">canceling a trip to Sydney</a> in May to stay in Washington and negotiate a government funding crisis.<br><br>澳大利亚是太平洋地区的重要盟友，拜登在5月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-facing-debt-ceiling-debate-could-skip-australia-part-asia-trip-2023-05-16/">取消了悉尼之行，</a>留在华盛顿并就政府资金危机进行谈判后，安排了这次访问。</p>   <p>The U.S.-Australia partnership is "an alliance that is marked by imagination, ingenuity and innovation," Biden told the prime minister in opening remarks upon his arrival at the U.S. presidential complex in Washington, citing their partnership on World War One, World War Two and the war on terror.<br><br>拜登在抵达华盛顿美国总统府的开幕词中对总理说，美澳伙伴关系是“一个以想象力、独创性和创新为标志的联盟”，并援引了两国在第一次世界大战和第二次世界大战中的伙伴关系和反恐战争。</p>   <p>The visit is expected to result in agreements aimed at deterring and competing with China, even as separately the two countries try to thaw relations with Beijing. The two nations are committed to making sure the "Indopacific remains free, open, prosperous and secure," Biden said.<br><br>预计这次访问将达成旨在威慑中国并与中国竞争的协议，尽管两国分别试图解冻与北京的关系。拜登表示，两国致力于确保“印度太平洋地区保持自由、开放、繁荣和安全”。</p>   <p>Albanese, greeted with a red carpet, military bands and a receiving line of Biden's top advisers, praised American democratic values and lauded Biden for maintaining "that every innocent life matters, Israeli and Palestinian, and that in every conflict every effort must be made to protect civilians."<br><br>阿尔巴尼斯受到了红地毯、军乐队和拜登高级顾问的欢迎，他赞扬了美国的民主价值观，并赞扬拜登坚持“每一个无辜的生命都很重要，无论是以色列还是巴勒斯坦，在每一次冲突中都必须尽一切努力保护平民。”</p>   <p>He also pledged continued cooperation in Ukraine's ongoing fight against Russia's invasion last year.<br><br>他还承诺继续与乌克兰去年对抗俄罗斯入侵的斗争进行合作。</p>   <p>The expected deals include launching an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/google-run-internet-cables-pacific-islands-australia-us-deal-2023-10-25/">undersea internet cable project</a> and maritime wharf infrastructure investment designed to benefit and woo Pacific Island nations whose assistance may be needed to respond to any future <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australians-say-they-would-support-taiwan-if-china-attacked-with-limits-poll-2023-06-20/">conflict over Taiwan</a> or the South China Sea, according to U.S. officials.<br><br>美国官员表示，预期的交易包括启动<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/google-run-internet-cables-pacific-islands-australia-us-deal-2023-10-25/">海底互联网电缆项目</a>和海上码头基础设施投资，旨在造福和吸引太平洋岛国，这些国家可能需要援助来应对未来<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australians-say-they-would-support-taiwan-if-china-attacked-with-limits-poll-2023-06-20/">台湾或南中国海的任何冲突</a>。</p>   <p>Washington and Canberra, already partners in a decades-old collective defense agreement, will also announce wider security cooperation with Japan.<br><br>华盛顿和堪培拉已经是数十年之久的集体防御协议的合作伙伴，它们也将宣布与日本进行更广泛的安全合作。</p>   <p>The balancing act of strengthening deterrence against China without offending Beijing too much is made more complicated by a Middle East crisis that has again diverted Washington's attention away from the Indo-Pacific.<br><br>中东危机再次将华盛顿的注意力从印太地区转移，这使得加强对华威慑而又不过分冒犯北京的平衡行动变得更加复杂。</p>   <p>A leadership vacuum in the U.S. House of Representatives has also complicated the approval of a set of laws needed to deliver on Biden's promise to support the AUKUS defense partnership between the United States, Britain and Australia. The AUKUS deal includes transferring sensitive U.S. and British nuclear submarine technology to Australia.<br><br>美国众议院的领导真空也使得兑现拜登支持美国、英国和澳大利亚之间 AUKUS 防务伙伴关系的承诺所需的一系列法律的批准变得复杂。 AUKUS 协议包括将敏感的美国和英国核潜艇技术转让给澳大利亚。</p>   <p>Financing and approvals related to AUKUS still need to come from Congress, where Republican lawmakers, who have a narrow majority, have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-house-republicans-try-again-pick-leader-2023-10-24/">repeatedly failed</a> to line up enough support behind a party candidate to elect a new speaker of the House.<br><br>AUKUS 相关的融资和批准仍然需要来自国会，在国会中，占微弱多数的共和党议员 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-house-republicans-try-again-pick-leader-2023-10-24/">一再未能</a>为党内候选人争取足够的支持来选举新的众议院议长。</p>   <p>On Friday, the Biden administration submitted a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/aukus-critical-minerals-focus-australian-pm-us-trip-2023-10-20/">supplementary budget request</a> to Congress that includes measures to support U.S. commitments under AUKUS.<br><br>周五，拜登政府向国会提交了一份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/aukus-critical-minerals-focus-australian-pm-us-trip-2023-10-20/">补充预算请求</a>，其中包括支持美国在 AUKUS 下的承诺的措施。</p>   <p>A senior administration official said Biden would reassure Albanese the U.S. will follow through on its end of the deal as Australians express private frustrations over the delays in moving ahead on the partnership.<br><br>一名高级政府官员表示，拜登将向阿尔巴尼斯保证，美国将履行协议，因为澳大利亚人对推迟推进这一伙伴关系表示私下的沮丧。</p>   <p>"We're in close and deep consultations on Capitol Hill," the official told reporters. "We are confident that the various procedural steps and budget conditions necessary to move forward with pillar one of AUKUS will move through in a way that will support our larger endeavor."<br><br>这位官员告诉记者：“我们正在国会山进行密切而深入的磋商。” “我们相信，推进 AUKUS 第一支柱所需的各种程序步骤和预算条件将以支持我们更大努力的方式获得通过。”</p>    <h 1="">BEIJING TENSIONS</h>  <p>The U.S.-Australian efforts, designed to counter China's territorial claims and reduce trade dependence on the Asian country, come as both countries also work to reduce diplomatic tensions with Beijing.<br><br>美国和澳大利亚的努力旨在对抗中国的领土主张并减少对这个亚洲国家的贸易依赖，与此同时，两国也都在努力缓解与北京的外交紧张关系。</p>   <p>Albanese will visit China, Australia's largest trade partner and biggest buyer of its iron ore, on Nov. 4.<br><br>阿尔巴内斯将于11月4日访问中国，澳大利亚最大的贸易伙伴和铁矿石的最大买家。</p>   <p>White House aides are working to lock down a meeting between Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping during the Nov. 11 to 17 Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation summit in San Francisco.<br><br>白宫助手正在努力锁定拜登与中国国家主席习近平在 11 月 11 日至 17 日在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会期间举行的会面。</p>   <p>Biden and Albanese will also seek to boost <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-us-leaders-discuss-pacific-infrastructure-critical-minerals-2023-10-24/">cooperation on cybersecurity</a> and Australia's rare earth minerals output to reduce reliance on China, the dominant supplier.<br><br>拜登和阿尔巴尼斯还将寻求加强<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/australia-us-leaders-discuss-pacific-infrastructure-critical-minerals-2023-10-24/">网络安全和澳大利亚稀土矿产量方面的合作</a>，以减少对主要供应商中国的依赖。</p>   <p>Biden will also announce that a cyberattack on Australia could be taken as an "armed" attack that would trigger U.S. collective defense obligations. In the event of such an attack, the United States would make a case-by-case decision on whether to invoke the treaty, according to another U.S. official.<br><br>拜登还将宣布，对澳大利亚的网络攻击可能被视为“武装”攻击，从而触发美国的集体防御义务。另一位美国官员表示，如果发生此类攻击，美国将根据具体情况决定是否援引该条约。</p>   <p>Australia has been <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/five-eyes-intelligence-chiefs-warn-chinas-theft-intellectual-property-2023-10-18/">a major hacking target</a> for China.<br><br>澳大利亚一直是中国的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/five-eyes-intelligence-chiefs-warn-chinas-theft-intellectual-property-2023-10-18/">主要黑客攻击目标</a>。</p>   <p>Biden will also work on the more intangible parts of the U.S.-Australian alliance, hosting Albanese and his partner Jodie Haydon for an official state dinner.<br><br>拜登还将致力于美澳联盟的更无形的部分，接待阿尔巴尼斯和他的搭档朱迪·海顿参加官方国宴。</p>   <p>Attendees will eat a three-course banquet prepared by five-time James Beard Foundation Award nominee Katie Button, set against a canvas of American Monarch butterflies and Australian Cairns Birdwing butterflies.<br><br>与会者将享用由五次詹姆斯比尔德基金会奖提名者凯蒂·巴顿准备的三道菜宴会，宴会上有美国帝王蝶和澳大利亚凯恩斯鸟翼蝶。</p>   <p>Nodding to the downbeat politics of the moment, a planned performance by the pop group B-52s at the dinner <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/no-love-shack-white-house-b-52s-wont-play-aussie-dinner-2023-10-24/">is being scrapped</a> in favor of music from a U.S. military band.<br><br>为了迎合当前悲观的政治形势，流行乐队 B-52s 在晚宴上的表演计划<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/no-love-shack-white-house-b-52s-wont-play-aussie-dinner-2023-10-24/">被取消</a>，取而代之的是一支美国军乐队的音乐。</p>    <span>Reporting by Trevor Hunnicutt; additional reporting by Susan Heavey; Editing by Tom Hogue, Heather Timmons and Josie Kao<br><br>特雷弗·亨尼卡特报道；苏珊·希维 (Susan Heavey) 的补充报道；汤姆·霍格、希瑟·蒂蒙斯和乔西·高编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 16:21:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">DENPZOADARL2JKSTDOQU42NTHQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us-australia-discuss-china-pacific-security-white-house-visit-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Trevor Hunnicutt]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA/ (UPDATE 2, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[爱沙尼亚重点关注中国船只，调查水下电缆损坏情况]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/YCL_ORFpE-2tOFUkdeOHyq7Aa2U=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DDXQBMOAMFLS3N4WR7JTGAKMT4.jpg" alt="Finnish Border Guard's photo of a Hong Kong registered cargo ship 'Newnew Polar Bear'<br><br>芬兰边防卫队拍摄的香港注册货船“Newnew Polar Bear”号的照片" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Finnish Border Guard's photo of a Hong Kong registered cargo ship 'Newnew Polar Bear'<br><br>芬兰边防卫队拍摄的香港注册货船“Newnew Polar Bear”号的照片, which was spotted moving close to the Balticconnector gas line, during the joint press conference of the investigation of the possible attack on the Balticconnector gas line on 8th Oct., 2023 between Finland and Estonia at the headquarters of the National Bureau of Investigation in Vantaa, Finland, 24 October 2023.  Lehtikuva/HEIKKI SAUKKOMAA via REUTERS  </figcaption></figure>       <p>Estonia's investigation into a damaged Baltic Sea telecoms cable will focus on the actions of a Chinese-owned vessel, the country's prosecutor general said, after Finland blamed damage to a nearby pipeline on a ship.<br><br>爱沙尼亚总检察长表示，在芬兰指责一艘船只损坏了附近的管道后，爱沙尼亚对波罗的海电信电缆受损的调查将重点关注一艘中国船只的行为。</p>   <p>Early on Oct. 8, a gas pipeline and a telecoms cable connecting Finland and Estonia under the Baltic Sea were broken. Another telecoms cable, between Sweden and Estonia, was also damaged that night.<br><br>10月8日早些时候，波罗的海海底连接芬兰和爱沙尼亚的一条天然气管道和一条电信电缆破裂。当晚，瑞典和爱沙尼亚之间的另一条电信电缆也被损坏。</p>   <p>Finnish investigators said on Tuesday that they had found a large anchor near the pipeline, which they believe was broken as a ship dragged the anchor <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/finland-retrieves-anchor-seabed-near-broken-gas-pipeline-2023-10-24/">along the seabed</a>.<br><br>芬兰调查人员周二表示，他们在管道附近发现了一个大锚，他们认为，当一艘船<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/finland-retrieves-anchor-seabed-near-broken-gas-pipeline-2023-10-24/">沿着海底</a>拖动锚时，该锚已破裂。</p>   <p>They named the Chinese-owned and Hong-Kong-flagged container carrier NewNew Polar Bear as the prime suspect.<br><br>他们将悬挂香港国旗的中资集装箱运输公司NewNew Polar Bear列为主要嫌疑人。</p>   <p>Helsinki is investigating the pipeline incident, while Tallinn is looking into the cables incidents.<br><br>赫尔辛基正在调查管道事件，塔林正在调查电缆事件。</p>   <p>The spokesperson for Estonia's general prosecutor said the investigation into the damage to the Estonia-Finland cable is moving its focus to the same vessel, despite the cable being located "somewhat further" from the pipeline.<br><br>爱沙尼亚总检察长发言人表示，对爱沙尼亚-芬兰电缆受损情况的调查正在将重点转移到同一艘船上，尽管该电缆距离管道“稍远”。</p>   <p>"The aim of the investigation is still to determine whether the vessel is responsible for damaging the telecommunications cables or not, and whether the damage was caused intentionally or by accident," he added.<br><br>他补充说：“调查的目的仍然是确定该船是否对损坏电信电缆负有责任，以及损坏是故意还是意外造成的。”</p>   <p>Reuters reported that two vessels, NewNew Polar Bear and Russia-flagged Sevmorput, were present at all three sites around the time of the damage, according to data from MarineTraffic, a ship-tracking and maritime analytics provider.<br><br>路透社报道称，根据船舶跟踪和海事分析提供商 MarineTraffic 的数据，在损坏发生时，两艘船 NewNew Polar Bear 和悬挂俄罗斯国旗的 Sevmorput 出现在所有三个地点。</p>   <p>"I hope we will receive the necessary support from China to make constructive contact with the crew and owners of the ship," Estonia's Foreign Affairs Minister Margus Tsahkna said on Tuesday.<br><br>爱沙尼亚外交部长马古斯·查克纳周二表示：“我希望我们能得到中国的必要支持，以便与船员和船东进行建设性接触。”</p>   <p>On Monday, China called for an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-calls-fair-gas-pipeline-damage-probe-by-finland-2023-10-23/">"objective, fair and professional"</a> investigation into the gas pipeline damage.<br><br>周一，中国呼吁对天然气管道受损事件进行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-calls-fair-gas-pipeline-damage-probe-by-finland-2023-10-23/">“客观、公正、专业”的</a>调查。</p>   <p>"It is understood that the Chinese vessel was normal in the relevant waters at the time of the incident, and no abnormalities were found due to the poor sea conditions at that time," a Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson told reporters.<br><br>中国外交部发言人对记者表示：“据了解，事发时中方船只在有关海域一切正常，因当时海况较差，未发现异常情况。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Andrius Sytas in Vilnius; Editing by Sharon Singleton<br><br>Andrius Sytas 在维尔纽斯的报道；莎朗·辛格尔顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 16:01:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">OLI73HPJT5JUTDVVPAHXR24B2U</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/estonia-focuses-chinese-vessel-investigation-into-underwater-cable-damage-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Andrius Sytas]]></author>
            
                
                <category>FINLAND</category>
                
                <category>ESTONIA/GAS</category>
                
                <category>CABLE</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[电动汽车需求放缓敲响更多警钟]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/N8MKkwah9EoU28zFoQq02W4Za88=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CGQIHVYWWRKJDLTBIBZSZNJ3CM.jpg" alt="Tesla China-made Model 3 vehicles are seen during a delivery event at its factory in Shanghai<br><br>特斯拉中国制造的 Model 3 车辆在上海工厂的交付活动中亮相" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Tesla China-made Model 3 vehicles are seen during a delivery event at its factory in Shanghai<br><br>特斯拉中国制造的 Model 3 车辆在上海工厂的交付活动中亮相, China January 7, 2020. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>High interest rates are derailing the ambitions of climate regulators and automakers to accelerate the shift to electric vehicles, underscored Wednesday by the scrapping of a GM-Honda partnership and a warning from a battery maker.<br><br>高利率正在破坏气候监管机构和汽车制造商加速向电动汽车转型的雄心，周三通用汽车与本田合作伙伴关系的取消以及一家电池制造商的警告凸显了这一点。</p>   <p>Electric vehicle sales are still growing strongly, but that demand is not keeping up with the expectations of carmakers and other companies that have invested billions of dollars in the EV space. Expectations for persistently higher interest rates has led companies to alter plans as they eye 2024 warily.<br><br>电动汽车销量仍在强劲增长，但这种需求未能跟上汽车制造商和其他在电动汽车领域投资数十亿美元的公司的预期。对利率持续走高的预期导致企业改变计划，谨慎地展望 2024 年。</p>   <p>"EV demand next year could be lower than expectations," Lee Chang-sil, chief financial officer at South Korean battery maker <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/battery-firm-lg-energy-solution-q3-profit-rises-40-increased-us-output-2023-10-25/">LG Energy Solution</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/373220.KS" target="_blank">(373220.KS)</a> said on Wednesday, due to global economic uncertainty.<br><br>“由于全球经济的不确定性，明年的电动汽车需求可能低于预期，”韩国电池制造商<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/battery-firm-lg-energy-solution-q3-profit-rises-40-increased-us-output-2023-10-25/">LG Energy Solution</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/373220.KS" target="_blank">(373220.KS)</a>首席财务官 Lee Chang-sil 周三表示。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/honda-shelves-plan-co-develop-smaller-evs-with-gm-bloomberg-news-2023-10-25/">Also on Wednesday</a>, Honda <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/7267.T" target="_blank">(7267.T)</a> and General Motors <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GM.N" target="_blank">(GM.N)</a> announced they were ending a $5 billion plan to develop lower-cost EVs together just a year after announcing the effort. GM <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/gm-withdraws-2023-guidance-uaw-strike-costs-soar-2023-10-24/">on Tuesday</a> said it would focus near-term EV efforts on meeting demand rather than hitting specific volume targets.<br><br><a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/honda-shelves-plan-co-develop-smaller-evs-with-gm-bloomberg-news-2023-10-25/">同样在周三</a>，本田<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/7267.T" target="_blank">(7267.T)</a>和通用汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GM.N" target="_blank">(GM.N)</a>宣布，在宣布这一努力一年后，他们将终止一项耗资 50 亿美元的共同开发低成本电动汽车的计划。通用汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/gm-withdraws-2023-guidance-uaw-strike-costs-soar-2023-10-24/">周二</a>表示，近期电动汽车业务的重点将是满足需求，而不是达到具体的销量目标。</p>   <p>"We're taking immediate steps to enhance the profitability of our EV portfolio and adjust to slowing near-term growth," GM CEO Mary Barra told analysts.<br><br>通用汽车首席执行官玛丽·巴拉（Mary Barra）对分析师表示：“我们正在立即采取措施，提高电动汽车产品组合的盈利能力，并适应近期增长放缓的情况。”</p>   <p>Investors have responded to the changed outlook. Over the last three months, the iShares Self-Driving EV and Tech exchange-traded fund has plunged more than 24%, far more than the 8.3% fall for the MSCI All-World Index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIWD00000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIWD00000PUS)</a>, a proxy for global equities.<br><br>投资者对前景的改变做出了反应。过去三个月，iShares 自动驾驶电动汽车和科技交易所交易基金暴跌超过 24%，远远超过全球股市代理 MSCI 全球指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIWD00000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIWD00000PUS)</a> 8.3% 的跌幅。</p>   <p>EV sales are growing, however. They topped 300,000 units in the United States for the first time in the third quarter, according to a Cox Automotive report. They rose 14.3% in September in the European Union and 22% in China, the world's largest EV market.<br><br>然而，电动汽车销量正在增长。根据 Cox Automotive 的一份报告，第三季度它们在美国的销量首次突破 30 万辆。 9 月份，欧盟增长了 14.3%，全球最大电动汽车市场中国增长了 22%。</p>    <h 1="">FALLING RAW MATERIAL PRICES</h>  <p>Tesla <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a> CEO Elon Musk <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/tesla-reports-lower-third-quarter-margin-2023-10-18/">raised the alarm</a> last week in explaining why he was slowing plans for a Mexico factory.<br><br>特斯拉<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/TSLA.O" target="_blank">(TSLA.O)</a>首席执行官埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 上周在解释为何放慢墨西哥工厂计划时<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/tesla-reports-lower-third-quarter-margin-2023-10-18/">发出了警报</a>。</p>   <p>"I am worried about the high interest rate environment that we're in," he said on Tesla's earnings conference call. "As I just can't emphasize this enough that the vast majority of people buying a car is about the monthly payment. If interest rates remain high or if they go even higher, it's that much harder for people to buy the car."<br><br>“我对我们所处的高利率环境感到担忧，”他在特斯拉的财报电话会议上表示。 “我无法强调这一点，绝大多数人买车都是为了每月还款。如果利率居高不下或者更高，人们买车就会变得更加困难。”</p>   <p>Other automakers have sounded similar notes of caution.<br><br>其他汽车制造商也发出了类似的警告。</p>   <p>Germany's Volkswagen <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VOWG_p.DE" target="_blank">(VOWG_p.DE)</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/volkswagen-cuts-profit-outlook-raw-material-hedges-hit-2023-10-20/">last week</a> cut its profit margin outlook for the year, blaming negative effects for raw material hedges at the end of the third quarter. Some of those materials are used in EV batteries.<br><br>德国大众汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VOWG_p.DE" target="_blank">(VOWG_p.DE)</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/volkswagen-cuts-profit-outlook-raw-material-hedges-hit-2023-10-20/">上周</a>下调了今年的利润率预期，并将其归咎于第三季度末原材料对冲带来的负面影响。其中一些材料用于电动汽车电池。</p>   <p>Like many other industrial firms, carmakers hedge against commodity price swings, and with EV demand slowing, raw material prices have softened, including those used heavily in batteries.<br><br>与许多其他工业公司一样，汽车制造商对冲大宗商品价格波动的风险，随着电动汽车需求放缓，原材料价格已经走软，包括大量用于电池的原材料价格。</p>   <p>Lithium prices have tumbled 67% so far this year based on spot lithium carbonate prices assessed by Fastmarkets . Prices of cobalt metal on the CME have slid 20% this year and more than halved since May last year.<br><br>根据 Fastmarkets 评估的现货碳酸锂价格，今年迄今为止，锂价格已下跌 67%。 CME 钴金属价格今年已下跌 20%，自去年 5 月以来已下跌逾一半。</p>   <p>U.S. automaker Ford <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/F.N" target="_blank">(F.N)</a> earlier this month said it would <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/ford-temporarily-cut-one-shift-michigan-ev-plant-2023-10-13/">temporarily cut one of three shifts</a> at the plant that builds its electric F-150 Lightning pickup truck, and in July <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/ford-raises-annual-pre-tax-profit-view-supply-chain-woes-ease-2023-07-27/">slowed its EV ramp-up</a>, shifting investment to commercial vehicles and hybrids.<br><br>美国汽车制造商福特<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/F.N" target="_blank">(FN)</a>本月早些时候表示，将<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/ford-temporarily-cut-one-shift-michigan-ev-plant-2023-10-13/">暂时削减生产电动 F-150 Lightning 皮卡车的工厂三班制之一</a>，并于 7 月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/ford-raises-annual-pre-tax-profit-view-supply-chain-woes-ease-2023-07-27/">放慢了电动汽车的产能扩张</a>，将投资转向商用车和混合动力车。</p>   <p>Shares of Japan's Nidec <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6594.T" target="_blank">(6594.T)</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/nidec-shares-tumble-after-it-sticks-annual-profit-outlook-2023-10-24/">logged their biggest decline</a> in a decade and a half on Tuesday, tumbling more than 10% on investor concerns over the motor manufacturer's prospects in an increasingly tough Chinese market for EVs.<br><br>日本电产公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6594.T" target="_blank">（Nidec，6594.T）</a>的股价周二<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/nidec-shares-tumble-after-it-sticks-annual-profit-outlook-2023-10-24/">创下十五年来的最大跌幅</a>，因投资者担心这家汽车制造商在日益严峻的中国电动汽车市场中的前景而下跌超过 10%。</p>   <p>The Japanese motor manufacturer now expects a 15 billion yen ($100 million) full-year loss at its key e-axle business, rather than the profit it had previously seen. E-axle manufacture combines motors, gears and power-control electronics.<br><br>这家日本汽车制造商目前预计其主要电桥业务全年将出现 150 亿日元（1 亿美元）的亏损，而不是之前的利润。电子车桥制造结合了电机、齿轮和电力控制电子设备。</p>   <p>China's CATL <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300750.SZ" target="_blank">(300750.SZ)</a>, the world's largest battery maker for EVs, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/ev-battery-firm-catls-sept-china-market-share-slumps-bodes-ill-q3-results-2023-10-19/">said last week</a> that third-quarter profit rose 10.7%, its weakest quarter since the start of last year due to slowing demand and stiff competition.<br><br>全球最大的电动汽车电池制造商中国宁德时代<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300750.SZ" target="_blank">（300750.SZ）</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/ev-battery-firm-catls-sept-china-market-share-slumps-bodes-ill-q3-results-2023-10-19/">上周表示</a>，由于需求放缓和竞争激烈，第三季度利润增长10.7%，是去年年初以来最弱的季度。</p>   <p>The company's market share in China tumbled in September to the lowest in more than a year, data showed, underscoring the challenges it faces from smaller rivals and weakening demand.<br><br>数据显示，该公司在中国的市场份额九月份跌至一年多来的最低水平，突显了该公司面临来自规模较小的竞争对手和需求疲软的挑战。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ben Klayman in Detroit and David Gaffen in New York; additional reporting by Eric Onstad in London and Victoria Waldersee in Berlin; editing by Jonathan Oatis<br><br>本·克莱曼 (Ben Klayman) 底特律报道和大卫·加芬 (David Gaffen) 纽约报道； Eric Onstad 在伦敦和 Victoria Waldersee 在柏林的补充报道；乔纳森·奥蒂斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 16:01:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BEYY3R3CKVI27OBQQPVXBACP5E</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/more-alarm-bells-sound-slowing-demand-electric-vehicles-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ben Klayman]]></author>
            
                
                <category>AUTOS</category>
                
                <category>ELECTRIC/DEMAND (WRAPUP 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[下半场表现让山东队亚冠夺冠]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Shandong Taishan moved to the top of Group G of the Asian Champions League on Wednesday as Brazilian striker Cryzan and former Manchester United midfielder Marouane Fellaini scored in the second half to secure a 2-0 win over hosts Incheon United.<br><br>周三，亚冠联赛G组山东泰山队凭借巴西前锋克雷赞和前曼联中场费莱尼在下半场的进球，以2-0战胜东道主仁川联队，以小组第一的身份晋级。</p>   <p>Cryzan came off the bench in the 55th minute and broke the deadlock three minutes later with a strike from distance that bent into the top corner before Fellaini scored from close range to confirm the three points for the Chinese Super League side.<br><br>第55分钟，克赖赞替补登场，三分钟后远射破门打破僵局，费莱尼近距离射门破门，中超球队确认三分。</p>   <p>The South Koreans led the standings ahead of the game but are now level on six points with Shandong, who move into pole position thanks to a better head-to-head record over Incheon and third-placed Yokohama F Marinos.<br><br>韩国队在比赛前领先积分榜，但现在与山东队同积 6 分，山东队凭借对仁川队和排名第三的横滨水手队的更好交锋记录，取得杆位。</p>   <p>The Japanese outfit also picked up their second win of the group phase when they handed visitors Kaya FC-Iloilo from the Philippines a 3-0 defeat with Kota Mizunuma, Kenyu Sugimoto and Anderson Lopes on target for Kevin Muscat's team.<br><br>日本球队还取得了小组赛的第二场胜利，他们以 3-0 击败了来自菲律宾的卡亚 FC-伊洛伊洛，水沼光太、杉本健宇和安德森·洛佩斯为凯文·马斯喀特的球队进球。</p>   <p>Only the winners of each of the 10 groups in the Asian Champions League are certain to progress to the last 16, where they will be joined by the three runners-up from the eastern and western halves of the continent with the best records.<br><br>只有亚冠联赛10个小组的冠军才有资格晋级16强，与东、西战绩最好的三支亚军一起晋级。</p>   <p>Thailand's Bangkok United maintained their perfect start in Group F by coming from behind to beat Kitchee 2-1 in Hong Kong.<br><br>泰国曼谷联队在香港赛场上以2-1逆转击败杰志队，保持了F组的完美开局。</p>   <p>Austria international Jakob Jantscher, a summer signing for the Hong Kong champions, gave Kitchee a seventh-minute lead but Rungrath Phumichantuk levelled four minutes into first half stoppage time.<br><br>香港冠军队夏季签约的奥地利国脚雅各布·詹切尔（Jakob Jantscher）在第七分钟为杰奇取得领先，但朗格拉特·普米恰图克（Rungrath Phumichantuk）在上半场补时四分钟后扳平了比分。</p>   <p>Willen Mota put Bangkok in front from the penalty spot seven minutes after the interval when Fernando handled inside the area and the Thais held on to all three points despite Bassel Jradi's 84th-minute sending off.<br><br>中场休息七分钟后，费尔南多在禁区内处理球，维伦·莫塔在点球点帮助曼谷取得领先，尽管巴塞尔·贾拉迪在第 84 分钟被罚下，泰国队还是保住了全部三分。</p>   <p>Bangkok lead twice champions Jeonbuk Motors by three points after Dan Petrescu's team eased to a 3-0 win over Lion City Sailors, with the Singaporeans in third and Kitchee rooted to the bottom without a point.<br><br>丹·彼得雷斯库 (Dan Petrescu) 率领的球队以 3-0 轻取狮城水手队 (Lion City Sailors)，曼谷队领先两届冠军全北汽车队 (Jeonbuk Motors) 3 分，新加坡队排名第三，杰志 (Kitchee) 则一分未得，垫底。</p>   <p>In Group H, first half goals from Alessandro Lopane and Jamie Maclaren saw Melbourne City secure a 2-0 win over Buriram United in Thailand to move onto seven points from three games.<br><br>H组中，凭借亚历山德罗·洛帕内和杰米·麦克拉伦上半场的进球，墨尔本城队在泰国2-0战胜武里南联队，三场比赛积7分。</p>   <p>The Australians lead the standings by three points from Japan's Ventforet Kofu, who slipped to their first loss when Lucas Possignolo and Nyasha Mushekwi earned the Chinese hosts a 2-0 win and their first points of the campaign.<br><br>澳大利亚队在积分榜上领先日本队文特福雷特甲府队 3 分，后者在卢卡斯·波西尼洛和尼亚沙·穆舍奎为中国东道主队以 2-0 获胜并取得本赛季首个积分后，滑向了他们的首场失利。</p>    <span>Reporting by Michael Church, Editing by Christian Radnedge<br><br>迈克尔·丘奇 (Michael Church) 报道，克里斯蒂安·拉德内奇 (Christian Radnedge) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 14:35:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">XRZ7O4MG3ZMVNISJKLIX7GEVHE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sports/soccer/second-half-show-earns-shandong-win-asian-champions-league-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Michael Church]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SOCCER</category>
                
                <category>AFCCHAMPIONS/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国与美国亲密盟友哥伦比亚升级外交关系]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>China, Colombia elevate ties to strategic partnership<br><br>中国与哥伦比亚将关系提升为战略伙伴关系</li>  <li>Colombia is one of closest U.S. allies in Latin America<br><br>哥伦比亚是美国在拉丁美洲最亲密的盟友之一</li>  <li>Colombia yet to join Xi's Belt and Road Initiative<br><br>哥伦比亚尚未加入习近平的“一带一路”倡议</li> </ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/gn0NtqomKQfFiw6wB6uBqzggqMk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ATSEO2VYUJKMJBF3IER2HUQ6YU.jpg" alt="Colombian President Gustavo Petro meets Chinese President Xi Jinping during a welcoming ceremony in Beijing<br><br>哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗在北京举行的欢迎仪式上会见中国国家主席习近平<br><br>哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗在北京举行的欢迎仪式上会见中国国家主席习近平<br><br>哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗在北京举行的欢迎仪式上会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping speaks with Colombian President Gustavo Petro during a meeting at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, China, October 25, 2023. Ken Ishii/Pool via REUTERS<br><br>2023 年 10 月 25 日，中国国家主席习近平在中国北京人民大会堂会见哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗。Ken Ishii/Pool via REUTERS</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TNu50RDPXY-wSYWpOZPv9nbzm2o=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/J3BKEQORWRO4DDZKZIW57AWXH4.jpg" alt="Colombian President Gustavo Petro meets Chinese President Xi Jinping during a welcoming ceremony in Beijing<br><br>哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗在北京举行的欢迎仪式上会见中国国家主席习近平<br><br>哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗在北京举行的欢迎仪式上会见中国国家主席习近平<br><br>哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗在北京举行的欢迎仪式上会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Colombian President Gustavo Petro inspects an honor guard with Chinese President Xi Jinping during a welcoming ceremony at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, China, October 25, 2023. Ken Ishii/Pool via REUTERS<br><br>2023 年 10 月 25 日，在中国北京人民大会堂举行的欢迎仪式上，哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗与中国国家主席习近平检阅仪仗队。Ken Ishii/Pool 图片来源：路透社<br><br>2023 年 10 月 25 日，在中国北京人民大会堂举行的欢迎仪式上，哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗与中国国家主席习近平检阅仪仗队。Ken Ishii/Pool 图片来源：路透社</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/WtPWp5k2VVhR5GOyAEYaavH2Feg=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/T2XDCS4RNBI7BHHRA4FXG6EG2Q.jpg" alt="Colombian President Gustavo Petro meets Chinese President Xi Jinping during a welcoming ceremony in Beijing<br><br>哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗在北京举行的欢迎仪式上会见中国国家主席习近平<br><br>哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗在北京举行的欢迎仪式上会见中国国家主席习近平<br><br>哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗在北京举行的欢迎仪式上会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Colombian President Gustavo Petro inspects an honor guard with Chinese President Xi Jinping during a welcoming ceremony at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, China, October 25, 2023. Ken Ishii/Pool via REUTERS<br><br>2023 年 10 月 25 日，在中国北京人民大会堂举行的欢迎仪式上，哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗与中国国家主席习近平检阅仪仗队。Ken Ishii/Pool 图片来源：路透社<br><br>2023 年 10 月 25 日，在中国北京人民大会堂举行的欢迎仪式上，哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗与中国国家主席习近平检阅仪仗队。Ken Ishii/Pool 图片来源：路透社</figcaption></figure>                 <p>China elevated diplomatic relations with Colombia to a strategic partnership on Wednesday, deepening a push with one of the oldest U.S. allies to expand its influence and strengthen its foothold in Latin America.<br><br>中国周三将与哥伦比亚的外交关系提升为战略伙伴关系，深化与美国最古老的盟友之一的合作，以扩大其影响力并加强其在拉丁美洲的立足点。</p>   <p>The two countries upgraded their relations, first established in 1980, as Colombian President Gustavo Petro met his Chinese counterpart Xi Jinping on a visit to Beijing this week, his first to the world's second-largest economy since assuming office last year.<br><br>两国升级了自 1980 年首次建立的关系，哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗 (Gustavo Petro) 本周访问北京会见了中国国家主席习近平，这是他自去年上任以来首次访问世界第二大经济体。</p>   <p>The upgrade of relations with Colombia means China now has strategic ties with 10 out of the 11 South American countries with which it has relations. Guyana is the only country in the region with which it has ordinary bilateral ties.<br><br>与哥伦比亚关系升级意味着中国与11个南美国家中的10个建立了战略关系。圭亚那是该地区唯一与其建立正常双边关系的国家。</p>   <p>China in recent years has stepped up a charm offensive in South America, Central America and the Caribbean, a region of strategic significance for arch-rival the United States.<br><br>近年来，中国加大了对南美、中美洲和加勒比地区的魅力攻势，这些地区对美国的主要竞争对手具有战略意义。</p>   <p>The region is also significant to China as it hosts a handful of countries that have no ties with Beijing but instead recognise democratically governed Taiwan as a sovereign state. Paraguay is the last South American nation that has ties with Taiwan, which China claims as part of its territory.<br><br>该地区对中国也很重要，因为它拥有少数与北京没有关系但承认民主治理的台湾为主权国家的国家。巴拉圭是最后一个与台湾有关系的南美国家，中国声称台湾是其领土的一部分。</p>   <p>During the COVID pandemic, China was the first country that sent vaccines to Colombia. In 2021, in recognition of China's help in fighting the coronavirus, Xi was invited to give a <a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/eng/gjhdq_665435/3447_665449/3483_665038/3485_665042/202103/t20210322_9169509.html" target="_blank">speech</a> via video link to the people of Colombia.<br><br>新冠疫情期间，中国是第一个向哥伦比亚运送疫苗的国家。 2021年，为表彰中国为抗击新冠病毒所提供的帮助，习近平应邀向哥伦比亚人民发表视频<a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/eng/gjhdq_665435/3447_665449/3483_665038/3485_665042/202103/t20210322_9169509.html" target="_blank">讲话</a>。</p>   <p>Chinese imports from Colombia have risen sharply in the last few years, becoming the South American nation's second-biggest trading partner after the United States. In 2022, shipments from Colombia to China totalled $7 billion, up almost 20% from five years earlier.<br><br>过去几年，中国从哥伦比亚的进口大幅增长，成为该南美国家仅次于美国的第二大贸易伙伴。 2022年，哥伦比亚向中国出口总额达70亿美元，比五年前增长近20%。</p>   <p>The two countries signed 12 cooperation deals during the visit, Petro's office said in a statement, including one allowing Colombian beef imports from next year and another allowing shipments of quinoa, as well as the establishment of several working groups meant to improve commerce.<br><br>石油公司办公室在一份声明中表示，两国在访问期间签署了 12 项合作协议，其中一项允许从明年开始进口哥伦比亚牛肉，另一项允许装运藜麦，此外还成立了多个旨在改善商业的工作组。</p>   <p>Colombia is one of the closest U.S. allies in the region. A middle-income nation and one of the oldest democracies in Latin America, it established ties with the United States in 1822.<br><br>哥伦比亚是美国在该地区最亲密的盟友之一。作为一个中等收入国家，也是拉丁美洲最古老的民主国家之一，它于 1822 年与美国建立了联系。</p>   <p>Colombia has yet to join Xi's multi-region infrastructure Belt and Road Initiative (BRI), unlike many of its Latin American and Caribbean neighbours.<br><br>与许多拉丁美洲和加勒比邻国不同，哥伦比亚尚未加入习近平的多区域基础设施“一带一路”倡议。</p>   <p>Former Colombia President Ivan Duque, who welcomed warmer ties with China and visited Beijing in 2019, had previously expressed a willingness to join the BRI.<br><br>哥伦比亚前总统伊万·杜克欢迎与中国的关系升温，并于2019年访问北京，此前曾表示愿意加入“一带一路”。</p>    <h 1="">'GREAT IMBALANCE'</h>  <p>On his arrival in Beijing on Tuesday, Petro hailed the potential to increase Colombian exports to China and re-launch the Andean country's national rail network.<br><br>周二抵达北京时，佩特罗对增加哥伦比亚对中国出口和重新启动这个安第斯国家的国家铁路网络的潜力表示欢迎。</p>   <p>China Harbour Engineering Company (CHEC) is expected to complete by 2026 two subway lines of the Bogota Metro, a $4 billion project 30% funded by Chinese banks awarded to the CHEC, Xian Metro Company and Canada's Bombardier Inc consortium in 2019.<br><br>中国港湾工程公司 (CHEC) 预计将在 2026 年之前完成波哥大地铁的两条地铁线路，该项目耗资 40 亿美元，其中 30% 由中资银行出资，并于 2019 年授予中国港湾工程公司、西安地铁公司和加拿大庞巴迪公司财团。</p>   <p>Colombia also awarded its RegioTram light rail system project to China Civil Engineering Construction Corporation (CCECC) in 2019.<br><br>哥伦比亚还于2019年将其RegioTram轻轨系统项目授予中国土木工程建设集团公司（CCECC）。</p>   <p>Chinese state-run mining firm Zijin Mining acquired a gold mine in Colombia in 2019 but the project has faced <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/gold-diggers-illegal-mining-near-colombian-town-hits-zijin-output-2021-05-18/">repeated security issues</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/operations-zijin-colombia-mine-partially-halted-after-attacks-2023-06-02/">road blockades</a>.<br><br>中国国营矿业公司紫金矿业于2019年收购了哥伦比亚的一座金矿，但该项目<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/gold-diggers-illegal-mining-near-colombian-town-hits-zijin-output-2021-05-18/">多次面临安全问题</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/operations-zijin-colombia-mine-partially-halted-after-attacks-2023-06-02/">道路封锁</a>。</p>   <p>Despite loans, investments and offers to build infrastructure, China was asked to import more from South America.<br><br>尽管有贷款、投资和建设基础设施的提议，中国仍被要求从南美洲进口更多产品。</p>   <p>"When we look at the trade balance between Colombia and China, we find a great imbalance, a great inequality, a product of the economic history of the two countries," Petro told Xi on Wednesday. "There is a huge deficit."<br><br>“当我们审视哥伦比亚和中国之间的贸易平衡时，我们发现严重的不平衡、严重的不平等，这是两国经济历史的产物，”佩特罗周三对习近平表示。 “存在巨大的赤字。”</p>   <p>Among the 11 South American countries that have diplomatic ties with Beijing, Colombia has the largest trade deficit with China despite increased Chinese imports. Colombia had a trade deficit of more than $8 billion last year.<br><br>在与北京建交的11个南美国家中，尽管中国进口增加，但哥伦比亚对中国的贸易逆差最大。哥伦比亚去年的贸易逆差超过80亿美元。</p>   <p>Argentina, Venezuela, Bolivia and Suriname also posted trade deficits with China in 2022.<br><br>阿根廷、委内瑞拉、玻利维亚和苏里南2022年也对中国出现贸易逆差。</p>    <span>Reporting by Liz Lee and Ryan Woo; Additional reporting by Ellen Zhang and Julia Symmes Cobb; Editing by Bernadette Baum, Robert Birsel, Nick Macfie and Mark Porter<br><br>Liz Lee 和 Ryan Woo 的报道； Ellen 张和 Julia Symmes Cobb 的补充报道；编辑：Bernadette Baum、Robert Birsel、Nick Macfie 和 Mark Porter</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 14:06:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6AGGKVIBANNF7EF75QOIKQWNTQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-upgrades-diplomatic-ties-with-close-us-ally-colombia-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Liz Lee, Ryan Woo]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>COLOMBIA/ (UPDATE 3, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[加州州长纽瑟姆会见中国国家主席习近平]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/w0cRNN8bZ8h4kaWAa7E6llHxjfw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/M7RDIDEGTVM55BSBEF6NSS2NPU.jpg" alt="Gavin Newsom, governor of the State of California, speaks at the 2023 Milken Institute Global Conference in Beverly Hills<br><br>加利福尼亚州州长加文·纽瑟姆 (Gavin Newsom) 在比佛利山庄举行的 2023 年米尔肯研究所全球会议上发表讲话" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Gavin Newsom, governor of the State of California, speaks at the 2023 Milken Institute Global Conference in Beverly Hills<br><br>加利福尼亚州州长加文·纽瑟姆 (Gavin Newsom) 在比佛利山庄举行的 2023 年米尔肯研究所全球会议上发表讲话, California, U.S., May 2, 2023. REUTERS/Mike Blake/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>California governor Gavin Newsom met Chinese president Xi Jinping on Wednesday to discuss climate change, raising hopes that China and the United States can find common ground ahead of an APEC summit and COP28 climate meeting next month.<br><br>加州州长加文·纽瑟姆周三会见了中国国家主席习近平，讨论了气候变化问题，这让人们希望中美能够在下个月的亚太经合组织峰会和第二十八次缔约方会议气候会议之前找到共同点。</p>   <p>Xi and U.S President Joe Biden are expected to meet at the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit in San Francisco in November, although the meeting has not been confirmed.<br><br>习近平和美国总统乔·拜登预计将于 11 月在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会上会面，但会议尚未得到证实。</p>   <p>Newsom told reporters after the meeting that he had an opportunity to focus more deeply and substantively on the issue of climate with Xi, while they also discussed Israel and the deadly drug fentanyl.<br><br>纽瑟姆在会后告诉记者，他有机会与习近平更深入、更实质性地关注气候问题，同时他们还讨论了以色列和致命药物芬太尼。</p>   <p>"We're not going to move the needle on climate change unless the United States and China collaborate together," he said.<br><br>“除非美国和中国共同合作，否则我们不会在气候变化问题上取得进展，”他说。</p>   <p>There were "strategic red lines" in the relationship between the world's top two greenhouse gas emitters, but both sides were capable of managing them, he added.<br><br>他补充说，世界最大的两个温室气体排放国之间的关系存在“战略红线”，但双方都有能力管理它们。</p>   <p>During their meeting, Xi told Newsom that there was "huge potential" for the two countries to cooperate on green development and addressing climate change, state broadcaster CCTV said.<br><br>据中央电视台报道，习近平在会见期间告诉纽瑟姆，两国在绿色发展和应对气候变化方面的合作“潜力巨大”。</p>   <p>Xi said climate change could still become a "new bright spot" in the relationship between the two sides.<br><br>习近平表示，气候变化仍可能成为双方关系的“新亮点”。</p>   <p>Climate cooperation between the two countries has been disrupted in recent years, with Chinese officials insisting that climate issues could not be treated in isolation from the broader diplomatic and trade disputes between the two sides.<br><br>近年来，两国之间的气候合作受到干扰，中国官员坚称气候问题不能脱离两国之间更广泛的外交和贸易争端来处理。</p>   <p>U.S. climate envoy John Kerry visited Beijing in July to resume formal discussions with his Chinese counterpart Xie Zhenhua following a year-long hiatus caused by former House of Representatives Speaker Nancy Pelosi's visit to Taiwan, a self-governing island that China claims.<br><br>美国气候特使约翰·克里 (John Kerry) 于 7 月访问北京，恢复与中国同行解振华的正式讨论，此前众议院议长南希·佩洛西 (Nancy Pelosi) 访问台湾（中国声称拥有主权），导致这一讨论中断了一年。</p>   <p>Kerry's three-day visit also included talks with Foreign Minister Wang Yi and Vice-President Han Zheng, but he did not meet Xi.<br><br>克里为期三天的访问还包括与外交部长王毅和国家副主席韩正举行会谈，但他没有会见习近平。</p>   <p>Newsom began his week-long trip to China on Monday, visiting Hong Kong and Shenzhen before meeting senior officials in Beijing on Wednesday, including Han and Wang.<br><br>纽瑟姆周一开始了为期一周的中国之行，访问了香港和深圳，然后于周三在北京会见了包括韩和王在内的高级官员。</p>   <p>He also signed a memorandum of understanding with China's planning agency, the National Development and Reform Commission, on climate cooperation.<br><br>他还与中国规划机构国家发展和改革委员会签署了气候合作谅解备忘录。</p>    <span>Reporting by Laurie Chen, Writing by David Stanway; Editing by Toby Chopra and Deborah Kyvrikosaios<br><br>劳里·陈 (Laurie Chen) 报道，大卫·斯坦威 (David Stanway) 撰稿；托比·乔普拉 (Toby Chopra) 和黛博拉·基夫里科赛奥斯 (Deborah Kyvrikosaios) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 12:16:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZMSJKKH3NNP6LGAMCLRS56HLAI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/california-governor-newsom-meets-chinas-president-xi-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Laurie Chen]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>CALIFORNIA/XI (UPDATE 1 (PIX))</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[电梯制造商通力第三季度订单超出预期，因中国市场强劲]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/JV3gj_ZDL8Aat_3YIaOAv5SnDYc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OFNNBS5TTJIPFIEFHAMETN6QBY.jpg" alt="Logo is displayed in an elevator at the KONE Academy of Finish manufacturer KONE in Hanover<br><br>标志显示在位于汉诺威的通力表面处理学院制造商通力的电梯中" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Logo is displayed in an elevator at the KONE Academy of Finish elevators and escalators manufacturer KONE in Hanover, Germany, February 6, 2020. Picture taken February 6, 2020.  REUTERS/Fabian Bimmer/File Photo<br><br>2020 年 2 月 6 日，德国汉诺威通力电梯和自动扶梯制造商通力电梯学院的电梯中显示徽标。图片拍摄于 2020 年 2 月 6 日。路透社/Fabian Bimmer/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Finnish elevator and escalator maker Kone <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/KNEBV.HE" target="_blank">(KNEBV.HE)</a> reported on Wednesday better-than-expected new orders for the third quarter, boosted by strong momentum from its key Chinese market.<br><br>芬兰电梯和自动扶梯制造商通力<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/KNEBV.HE" target="_blank">(KNEBV.HE)</a>周三报告称，受其主要中国市场强劲势头的推动，第三季度新订单好于预期。</p>   <p>Kone's orders received fell by 7.7% to 1.99 billion euros ($2.10 billion) in the quarter, but that slightly beat analysts' estimate of 1.98 billion euros in a company-provided poll. At comparable exchange rates, the orders were up 0.3%.<br><br>通力本季度收到的订单下降了 7.7%，至 19.9 亿欧元（合 21 亿美元），但这略高于分析师在公司提供的调查中预测的 19.8 亿欧元。按可比汇率计算，订单增长了 0.3%。</p>   <p>The company's shares were up 3.9% at 1023 GMT after it posted the quarterly data.<br><br>截至格林威治标准时间 1023 点，该公司公布季度数据后，其股价上涨 3.9%。</p>   <p>"Orders received were stable, which I consider a good achievement given the soft overall New Business Solutions market," CEO Henrik Ehrnrooth said in an earnings statement.<br><br>首席执行官 Henrik Ehrnrooth 在一份收益声明中表示：“收到的订单很稳定，考虑到整体新业务解决方案市场疲软，我认为这是一个很好的成就。”</p>   <p>JPMorgan said in a briefing note that the strong order momentum was "supportive" in an earnings report that was on the whole "weaker-than-expected".<br><br>摩根大通在一份简报中表示，强劲的订单势头对整体“弱于预期”的财报起到了“支撑”。</p>   <p>Kone, which makes about a third of its sales in China, had earlier said it expected the new equipment market in the country to decline between 10% and 15% this year.<br><br>通力约三分之一的销售额来自中国，该公司早些时候曾表示，预计今年中国的新设备市场将下降 10% 至 15%。</p>   <p>Due to its bigger exposure to China, the Helsinki-listed company would be more vulnerable to that than its Swiss rival <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/swiss-elevator-maker-schindler-hikes-fy-outlook-strong-services-business-2023-10-19/">Schindler</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SCHP.S" target="_blank">(SCHP.S)</a>. The Chinese market makes up about 15% of Schindler's sales.<br><br>由于在中国的业务规模更大，这家在赫尔辛基上市的公司比其瑞士竞争对手<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/swiss-elevator-maker-schindler-hikes-fy-outlook-strong-services-business-2023-10-19/">迅达</a><a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SCHP.S" target="_blank">(SCHP.S)</a>更容易受到影响。中国市场约占迅达销售额的15%。</p>   <p>Schindler last week <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/swiss-elevator-maker-schindler-hikes-fy-outlook-strong-services-business-2023-10-19/">raised</a> 2023 guidance after a 23% jump in quarterly profit, driven by growth in maintenance and other services.<br><br>在维护和其他服务增长的推动下，季度利润增长 23%，迅达上周<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/swiss-elevator-maker-schindler-hikes-fy-outlook-strong-services-business-2023-10-19/">上调了</a>2023 年业绩指引。</p>   <p>Kone reiterated its business outlook, still expecting its sales growth at comparable exchange rates for the year 2023 to be in the range of 3.0%–6.0% and EBIT margin (earnings before interest and taxes) to be in the range of 11.0%–12.0%.<br><br>通力重申了其业务前景，仍预计 2023 年按可比汇率计算的销售增长将在 3.0%–6.0% 范围内，息税前利润率（息税前利润）将在 11.0%–12.0 范围内%。</p>   <p>Earlier on Wednesday, Kone also appointed Philippe Delorme as its new CEO, saying he would take over from Ehrnrooth from Jan. 1. JPMorgan said it was an "excellent appointment for Kone".<br><br>周三早些时候，通力还任命菲利普·德洛姆 (Philippe Delorme) 为其新任首席执行官，并表示他将从 1 月 1 日起接替埃恩鲁特。摩根大通表示，这是“对通力来说非常出色的任命”。</p>   <p>Kone on Tuesday said it had <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finnish-elevator-maker-kone-sells-russian-assets-s8-capital-2023-10-24/">completed</a> selling its Russian operations to a Russian holding company S8 Capital.<br><br>通力周二表示，已<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finnish-elevator-maker-kone-sells-russian-assets-s8-capital-2023-10-24/">完成</a>将其俄罗斯业务出售给俄罗斯控股公司 S8 Capital。</p>   <p>The company said in March 2022 that it would cease deliveries and not sign new orders, announcing plans to divest its business and operations in Russia three months later.<br><br>该公司于 2022 年 3 月表示，将停止交付且不再签署新订单，三个月后宣布计划剥离其在俄罗斯的业务和业务。</p>   <p>Its adjusted EBIT rose by 3.3% to 315.9 million euros in the quarter, missing analysts' estimate of 329 million euros.<br><br>该季度调整后息税前利润增长 3.3%，达到 3.159 亿欧元，低于分析师预期的 3.29 亿欧元。</p>    <span>Reporting by Elviira Luoma in Gdansk
Editing by Milla Nissi and Helen Popper<br><br>埃尔维拉·卢玛 (Elviira Luoma) 在格但斯克的报道 米拉·尼西 (Milla Nissi) 和海伦·波普尔 (Helen Popper) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 12:15:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">677BHST3JJOLJDNZNMC7LUMISY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/elevator-maker-kones-third-quarter-orders-beat-expectations-strong-china-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>RESULTS</category>
                
                <category>KONE/ (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[姚明表示，尽管经历了过去的动荡，NBA在中国仍是“一流”]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/-1zRcZWFeIPc2A-cCSS-WlNZwh0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TEALG2LNQJPOXFOWKNLEEVTFME.jpg" alt="Ice and Snow Sports Promotion Ambassador Yao Ming attends an event in Beijing<br><br>冰雪运动推广大使姚明在北京出席活动" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>President of Chinese Basketball Association and Ice and Snow Sports Promotion Ambassador Yao Ming attends a media event ahead of the Beijing 2022 Winter Olympics in Beijing, China January 17, 2022. REUTERS/Yew Lun Tian/File Photo<br><br>2022年1月17日，中国北京，中国篮球协会主席兼冰雪运动推广大使姚明出席北京2022年冬奥会前媒体活动。路透社/Yew Lun Tian/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The National Basketball Association (NBA) and China may have encountered turbulence in their relations over the years but retired great Yao Ming told Reuters the league is still "first class" in his home country.<br><br>多年来，美国国家篮球协会（NBA）和中国的关系可能遇到了动荡，但退役球星姚明告诉路透社，NBA在他的祖国仍然是“一流的”。</p>   <p>Yao, the president of the Chinese Basketball Association, soared to stardom in the United States as the eight-time All-Star for the Houston Rockets, an affable, 7-foot, 6-inch NBA big man who dominated the league before retiring in 2011.<br><br>中国篮球协会主席姚明作为休斯敦火箭队八次入选全明星，在美国一举成名。他是一位和蔼可亲、身高 7 英尺 6 英寸的 NBA 大个子，在 2017 年退役前统治了联盟。 2011年。</p>   <p>Yao propelled the league's popularity in his home country but relations between China and the NBA have not always been smooth.<br><br>姚明推动了NBA在祖国的受欢迎程度，但中国与NBA的关系并不总是一帆风顺。</p>   <p>Chinese broadcasters stopped airing Rockets games in 2019 after general manager Daryl Morey posted a message in support of anti-government protests in Hong Kong and, earlier <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sports/basketball/former-nba-star-howard-stirs-chinese-anger-by-calling-taiwan-country-2023-05-12/">this year</a>, former NBA player Dwight Howard appeared in a promotional video in which he referred to Taiwan as a country, prompting backlash.<br><br>在总经理达里尔·莫雷发布支持香港反政府抗议活动的消息后，中国广播公司于 2019 年停止转播火箭队的比赛； <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sports/basketball/former-nba-star-howard-stirs-chinese-anger-by-calling-taiwan-country-2023-05-12/">今年</a>早些时候，前 NBA 球员德怀特·霍华德出现在一段宣传视频中，他在视频中将台湾称为“台湾”。国，引发强烈反弹。</p>   <p>"I have to say, the NBA is in the first class... (because) you know the players being exposed in China for so long," Yao said, when asked about the past issues between China and the NBA.<br><br>当被问及中国与NBA之间过去的问题时，姚明说：“我不得不说，NBA是一流的......（因为）你知道球员在中国被曝光这么久。”</p>   <p>"The players, the teams (are) all still very well welcome in China and (we had) a couple of players with (in) China just this past summer."<br><br>“球员、球队在中国仍然很受欢迎，就在去年夏天，我们有几名球员在中国。”</p>   <p>Minnesota Timberwolves small forward Kyle Anderson competed with China at the FIBA World Cup, while the Miami Heat's six-times All-Star Jimmy Butler embarked on a tour of the country over the summer.<br><br>明尼苏达森林狼队的小前锋凯尔·安德森随中国队参加了国际篮联世界杯，而迈阿密热火队的六届全明星球员吉米·巴特勒则在今年夏天开始了中国之旅。</p>   <p>Yao travelled to New York this week for the first time in nearly four years as part of a roughly 30-person Chinese delegation, and met with NBA Commissioner Adam Silver at a time when international participation in the league is at an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sports/basketball/record-125-international-players-nba-opening-night-rosters-2023-10-24/">all-time high</a>.<br><br>本周，姚明作为大约 30 人的中国代表团的一员，近四年来首次前往纽约，并在国际球员对联盟的参与度达到<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sports/basketball/record-125-international-players-nba-opening-night-rosters-2023-10-24/">历史最高</a>水平之际会见了 NBA 总裁亚当·萧华。</p>   <p>"Everything looks (like it is) running very, very well (under) his management," he said of Silver, who took the reins in 2014.<br><br>“在他的管理下，一切看起来（就像是）运行得非常非常好，”他在谈到 2014 年上任的西尔弗时说道。</p>   <p>The trip coincides with the thawing of relations between China and another major sports body, the Women's Tennis Association (WTA), which concluded its China Open earlier this month after previously suspending competitions there over <a href="https://jp.reuters.com/article/tennis-wta-china-idCAKBN2WA120">the disappearance</a> of Peng Shuai.<br><br>此行恰逢中国与另一个主要体育机构——女子网球协会（WTA）之间的关系解冻。WTA 因彭帅<a href="https://jp.reuters.com/article/tennis-wta-china-idCAKBN2WA120">失踪</a>而暂停了中国公开赛，并于本月早些时候结束了中国公开赛。</p>   <p>Yao, a longtime friend of the former doubles number one, said he had met with Peng over dinner about two months ago and that she was doing well.<br><br>姚明是这位前双打第一的老朋友，他说他大约两个月前在晚餐时见过彭丽媛，她表现得很好。</p>    <span>Reporting by Amy Tennery in New York, additional reporting by Echo Wang in New York
Editing by Christian Radnedge<br><br>艾米·坦纳利 (Amy Tennery) 在纽约的报道，艾科·王 (Echo Wang) 在纽约的补充报道，克里斯蒂安·拉德内奇 (Christian Radnedge) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:24:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">YR76RVWXGZJRHHAYG3I6QIX4XY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sports/basketball/nba-first-class-china-despite-past-turbulence-says-yao-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Amy Tennery]]></author>
            
                
                <category>BASKETBALL</category>
                
                <category>YAO/ (TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[姚明表示，Wembanyama 是一位无与伦比的人才]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/-RXwzIXgFnh69c57m38CpHEbqpM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/D3OIEG4PEZMHRKPJ23L5AFAHOQ.jpg" alt="LNB Pro A - Boulogne-Levallois v Cholet<br><br>LNB Pro A - 布洛涅-勒瓦卢瓦 v 绍莱" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Basketball - LNB Pro A - Boulogne-Levallois v Cholet<br><br>LNB Pro A - 布洛涅-勒瓦卢瓦 v 绍莱 - Palais des sports Marcel-Cerdan, Levallois-Perret, France - May 25, 2023 Boulogne-Levallois' Victor Wembanyama in action REUTERS/Benoit Tessier/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>France's Victor Wembanyama possesses a talent that defies comparison, retired great Yao Ming told Reuters, as the seven-foot four-inch (2.24-metre) rookie makes his highly anticipated National Basketball Association (NBA) regular-season debut on Wednesday.<br><br>退役球星姚明告诉路透社，法国球员维克多·文巴尼亚马拥有无与伦比的天赋，这位身高七英尺四英寸（2.24米）的新秀将于周三迎来他备受期待的美国国家篮球协会（NBA）常规赛首秀。</p>   <p>Not since LeBron James 20 years ago has a prospect generated excitement on the level seen for the San Antonio Spurs' first overall pick, who will start at home against Texan rivals Dallas Mavericks after a remarkable preseason.<br><br>自 20 年前的勒布朗·詹姆斯以来，还没有一位新秀能像圣安东尼奥马刺队的状元秀那样令人兴奋，在经历了出色的季前赛后，马刺队将在主场对阵德克萨斯对手达拉斯小牛队。</p>   <p>"I never see a big guy like, you know, (who) can do such a thing like he does," said Yao, an eight-times NBA All-Star who stands two inches (five cms) taller than Wembanyama.<br><br>“我从来没有见过像他这样的大个子，你知道，他能做到这样的事情，”八次入选 NBA 全明星的姚明说，他的身高比温班亚马高两英寸（五厘米）。</p>   <p>"In a scout report where we say 'This guy is -- how old he is, you know, his height, his wingspan and his capabilities'... and 'He looks like, let's say, a former somebody', you know. For him it's like, I don't know who shall I put up... no comparing."<br><br>“在一份球探报告中，我们说‘这个人多大了，你知道，他的身高、他的臂展和他的能力’……还有‘他看起来像，比如说，一个前任’，你知道的。” .对他来说，这就像，我不知道我该忍受谁......没有比较。”</p>   <p>Yao spent his entire NBA career with the Houston Rockets and remains an iconic figure of Chinese sport after fuelling the popularity of the NBA in his home country. He retired from the NBA in 2011.<br><br>姚明的整个 NBA 职业生涯都在休斯敦火箭队度过，在推动 NBA 在祖国的受欢迎程度之后，他仍然是中国体育界的标志性人物。他于2011年从NBA退役。</p>   <p>The Hall of Famer was reluctant to offer advice to Frenchman Wembanyama, who enters the NBA at a time of unprecedented <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sports/basketball/record-125-international-players-nba-opening-night-rosters-2023-10-24/">international participation</a> in the league.<br><br>这位名人堂成员不愿意向法国人温班亚马提供建议，后者在联盟中<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sports/basketball/record-125-international-players-nba-opening-night-rosters-2023-10-24/">国际参与度</a>空前的时期进入 NBA。</p>   <p>"He has his own expedition to go (on)," said Yao, who was travelling to New York as part of a some 30-person Chinese delegation this week.<br><br>“他有自己的探险任务要继续，”本周作为约 30 人的中国代表团成员前往纽约的姚明说。</p>   <p>"And my experience probably from 20 years ago, I'm not sure is still fit for today. So I just wish him all good luck."<br><br>“我的经历可能是20年前的，我不确定今天是否仍然适用。所以我祝他一切顺利。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Amy Tennery in New York, additional reporting by Echo Wang in New York; Editing by Clare Fallon<br><br>Amy Tennery 在纽约的报道，Echo Wang 在纽约的补充报道；克莱尔·法伦编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:17:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4JGPDLV5RZKKLJE2FPODQW3RLE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sports/baseball/wembanyama-is-talent-beyond-compare-says-yao-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Amy Tennery]]></author>
            
                
                <category>BASKETBALL</category>
                
                <category>YAO/ (TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[克里姆林宫表示，俄罗斯并不关心中国增加核武库能力]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/18IeEX46xLRWt6IDQdHP1yRYeH4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GGCMTJLWD5PH7CS2NSLKZP3RGM.jpg" alt="To match Special Report USA-CHINA-TECH/SURVEILLANCE<br><br>配合特别报道美国-中国-技术/监视" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>FILE PHOTO: Chinese Navy's nuclear-powered submarine Long March 11 takes part in a naval parade off the eastern port city of Qingdao, to mark the 70th anniversary of the founding of Chinese People's Liberation Army Navy, China, April 23, 2019. REUTERS/Jason Lee/File Photo<br><br>资料图片：2019年4月23日，中国海军核动力潜艇长征十一号参加东部港口城市青岛附近举行的纪念中国人民解放军海军成立70周年阅兵式。路透社/贾森·李/资料图</figcaption></figure>       <p>The Kremlin said on Wednesday it was not concerned by China increasing the capabilities of its nuclear arsenal, stressing Moscow's "advanced strategic partnership" with Beijing and China's sovereign right to ensure its own security.<br><br>克里姆林宫周三表示，并不担心中国增强核武库能力，并强调莫斯科与北京的“高级战略伙伴关系”以及中国确保自身安全的主权。</p>   <p>China has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-chases-us-russia-guided-missile-submarine-capabilities-with-new-vessels-2023-10-25/">launched</a> its first nuclear-powered guided missile submarines, according to the Pentagon's latest report on China's military, giving it land and sea attack options that were once the sole province of U.S. and Russian vessels.<br><br>根据五角大楼关于中国军事的最新报告，中国已经<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-chases-us-russia-guided-missile-submarine-capabilities-with-new-vessels-2023-10-25/">下水了</a>第一艘核动力导弹潜艇，使其拥有了陆地和海上攻击能力，而这曾经是美国和俄罗斯船只的唯一选择。</p>   <p>"This does not cause us concern, our relations are an advanced strategic partnership, we have the most advanced stage of political dialogue, economic interaction," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov told reporters.<br><br>克里姆林宫发言人德米特里·佩斯科夫对记者表示：“这并没有引起我们的担忧，我们的关系是高级战略伙伴关系，我们拥有最先进的政治对话、经济互动阶段。”</p>   <p>"And in this case, China, which faces very serious challenges for its own security in the region, is taking steps that it considers appropriate.<br><br>“在这种情况下，中国在该地区的自身安全面临非常严峻的挑战，正在采取它认为适当的措施。</p>   <p>"This is the absolute sovereign right of this country."<br><br>“这是这个国家的绝对主权。”</p>   <p>Russia has forged even closer commercial, political and security ties with China, part of what they call a "no limits" partnership, since Moscow's decision to send tens of thousands of troops into Ukraine in February 2022, triggering sweeping Western sanctions.<br><br>自2022年2月莫斯科决定向乌克兰派遣数万名军队并引发西方全面制裁以来，俄罗斯与中国建立了更加密切的商业、政治和安全关系，这是他们所谓的“无限制”伙伴关系的一部分。</p>   <p>The Pentagon <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-most-significant-pentagons-china-military-report-2023-10-21/">report</a>, published on Oct. 20, marks the first apparent confirmation that modified submarines seen in Chinese shipyards over the last 18 months are Type 093B guided missile submarines.<br><br>五角大楼于 10 月 20 日发布的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-most-significant-pentagons-china-military-report-2023-10-21/">报告</a>首次明显证实过去 18 个月在中国造船厂看到的改装潜艇是 093B 型导弹潜艇。</p>   <p>Russia has been tweaking its own legislation on nuclear matters this month, with parliament on Wednesday <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russian-upper-house-approves-de-ratification-nuclear-test-ban-treaty-2023-10-25/">completing</a> the passage of a law that withdraws Moscow's ratification of the global treaty banning nuclear weapons tests.<br><br>俄罗斯本月一直在调整自己的核问题立法，议会周三<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russian-upper-house-approves-de-ratification-nuclear-test-ban-treaty-2023-10-25/">完成了</a>一项法律的通过，该法律撤回了莫斯科对禁止核武器试验全球条约的批准。</p>   <p>Russia says it will not resume nuclear testing unless Washington does, but arms control experts are concerned it may be inching towards a test that the West would perceive as a threatening escalation in the context of the Ukraine war.<br><br>俄罗斯表示，除非华盛顿恢复核试验，否则它不会恢复核试验，但军控专家担心，俄罗斯可能正在缓慢进行核试验，而西方会认为这是乌克兰战争背景下的威胁性升级。</p>    <span>Reporting by Reuters; Writing by Alexander Marrow
Editing by Gareth Jones<br><br>路透社报道；亚历山大·马罗 (Alexander Marrow) 撰稿 加雷斯·琼斯 (Gareth Jones) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 09:46:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5YNLTDVT5ZOR3CRWAPGMUCIONM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/russia-unconcerned-by-china-increasing-nuclear-arsenal-capabilities-says-kremlin-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>MILITARY/SUBMARINE</category>
                
                <category>RUSSIA (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[M&amp;G Investments 任命 Amy Cho 为亚太区主管]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/3VmcwU91I3jbuP1Kq-2l_cnmKnk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MBGYA7US35NORFRWQANVBXGV74.jpg" alt="Illustration shows a smartphone with displayed M&amp;G plc logo<br><br>插图显示了带有 M&amp;G plc 徽标的智能手机" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>M&amp;G plc logo is seen on a smartphone in front of displayed same logo in this illustration taken, December 1, 2021. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo<br><br>M&amp;G plc 徽标出现在智能手机上，前面显示了 2021 年 12 月 1 日拍摄的插图中的相同徽标。 REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>M&amp;G Investments said on Wednesday it has appointed Amy Cho as Asia Pacific head and chief executive officer (CEO) of M&amp;G Investments Singapore, subject to regulatory approval.<br><br>M&amp;G Investments 周三表示，已任命 Amy Cho 为 M&amp;G Investments Singapore 亚太区负责人兼首席执行官 (CEO)，尚待监管部门批准。</p>   <p>Cho, who was most recently at Schroders where she was CEO of Hong Kong and deputy head of Asia Pacific, will join the investment manager on Nov. 1. She will succeed Loretta Ng, who has decided to leave M&amp;G in pursuit of personal aspirations.<br><br>Cho 最近在 Schroders 担任香港首席执行官兼亚太区副总裁，她将于 11 月 1 日加入投资经理。她将接替 Loretta Ng，Loretta Ng 决定离开 M&amp;G 以追求个人抱负。</p>   <p>Cho will be responsible for accelerating M&amp;G's distribution ambitions in Asia Pacific enabling the firm to better serve existing and prospective clients, M&amp;G said in a statement.<br><br>M&amp;G 在一份声明中表示，Cho 将负责加速 M&amp;G 在亚太地区的分销雄心，使公司能够更好地服务现有和潜在客户。</p>   <p>M&amp;G is part of UK-based M&amp;G plc <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MNG.L" target="_blank">(MNG.L)</a>, a savings and investment business which was formed in 2017 via the merger of Prudential's UK and Europe savings and insurance operation and M&amp;G.<br><br>M&amp;G 是总部位于英国的 M&amp;G plc <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MNG.L" target="_blank">(MNG.L)</a>的一部分，M&amp;G plc (MNG.L) 是一家储蓄和投资公司，于 2017 年通过保德信 (Prudential) 的英国和欧洲储蓄和保险业务与 M&amp;G 合并而成立。</p>    <span>Reporting by Yantoultra Ngui; Editing by Mrigank Dhaniwala<br><br>Yantoultra Ngui 的报道；编辑：姆里甘克·达尼瓦拉</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 09:20:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4CQNY7JXWFPCVPMB2JCXQ6JVHQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/mg-investments-appoints-amy-cho-asia-pacific-head-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>M&#38;G</category>
                
                <category>MOVES/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：中国国务院抑制12个“高风险”地区债务增长——消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/bGLidR9PXjt2s1n7XH5xncHngJI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/IXCC6TKQJFI47DEEWJEBFT5WTA.jpg" alt="The Chinese national flag is seen in front of the financial district Central on the Chinese National Day in Hong Kong<br><br>国庆节香港中环金融区前悬挂的中国国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The Chinese national flag is seen in front of the financial district Central on the Chinese National Day in Hong Kong<br><br>国庆节香港中环金融区前悬挂的中国国旗, China October 1, 2022. REUTERS/Tyrone Siu</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's cabinet has restricted the ability of local governments in 12 heavily indebted regions to take on new debt and placed limits on what new state-funded projects they can launch, three sources with knowledge of the matter said.<br><br>三名知情人士称，中国国务院限制了 12 个重债地区地方政府承担新债务的能力，并限制了它们可以启动的新的国家资助项目。</p>   <p>The 12 regions, which cover a wide swathe of the nation, will only be allowed to take on specified projects, such as those approved by the central government, the sources said. Other projects, such new railway stations and power plants, will not be permitted.<br><br>消息人士称，这12个地区覆盖全国大部分地区，只能承接特定项目，例如经中央政府批准的项目。其他项目，例如新火车站和发电厂，将不会被允许。</p>   <p>The sources were citing a cabinet document dated late September that was delivered to local governments and state lenders this month.<br><br>消息人士援引了一份日期为 9 月底的内阁文件，该文件已于本月交付给地方政府和国有贷款机构。</p>   <p>The order also specifies that debt growth of local government financing vehicles (LGFVs) should not be higher than average loan growth rates of the corporate sector in the province where the LGFVs are located, two of the sources said.<br><br>两位消息人士称，该命令还规定，地方政府融资平台（LGFV）的债务增长不得高于地方政府融资平台所在省份企业部门的平均贷款增长率。</p>   <p>The move by China's cabinet, or the State Council, to contain local government debt has not been previously reported.<br><br>此前并未报道过中国内阁或国务院遏制地方政府债务的举措。</p>   <p>The State Council did not reply to a Reuters' request for comment.<br><br>国务院没有回复路透社的置评请求。</p>   <p>The measures reflect an effort by China's government to balance the need to defuse local government debt risks while pumping money into major infrastructure projects to stimulate the country's flagging economy.<br><br>这些措施反映了中国政府在化解地方政府债务风险和向重大基础设施项目注入资金以刺激中国疲弱经济之间取得平衡的努力。</p>   <p>In practice, that means increasing debt at the national level while attempting to lower debt at the local level. On Tuesday, China approved an additional <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/chinas-new-bonds-help-economic-recovery-official-says-budget-deficit-rises-2023-10-25/">1 trillion yuan</a> ($137 billion) sovereign bond issue to support the economy.<br><br>实际上，这意味着增加国家层面的债务，同时试图降低地方层面的债务。周二，中国批准额外发行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/chinas-new-bonds-help-economic-recovery-official-says-budget-deficit-rises-2023-10-25/">1 万亿元人民币</a>（1,370 亿美元）主权债券以支持经济。</p>   <p>According to the new order from the State Council, local governments will only be permitted to take on debt to fund major projects approved by the state council as well as a few types of projects in key areas. Those projects include the redevelopment of urban neighbourhoods and building affordable housing, two of the sources said.<br><br>根据国务院的新命令，地方政府举债只能用于国务院批准的重大项目和重点领域的少数类型项目。两位消息人士称，这些项目包括城市社区的重建和建设经济适用房。</p>    <h 1="">HIGH-RISK REGIONS</h>  <p>The 12 regions were previously identified as areas with "high risks" of defaulting on debt obligations. They were 7 provinces, including Liaoning and Jilin on the border with North Korea as well as Guizhou and Yunnan in the southwest, three autonomous regions and Tianjin and Chongqing cities.<br><br>这12个地区此前被确定为债务违约“高风险”地区。分别是与朝鲜接壤的辽宁、吉林以及西南的贵州、云南等7个省份、3个自治区以及天津、重庆市。</p>   <p>Repayment of debt due this year and 2024 by the regions will be prioritised, and debt extensions and new bank loans to replace existing loans will be allowed, the document said, according to two of the sources.<br><br>据两位消息人士透露，该文件称，各地区将优先偿还今年和 2024 年到期的债务，并允许债务延期和新的银行贷款取代现有贷款。</p>   <p>All three sources declined to be identified as the policies were confidential.<br><br>由于政策属于机密，三位消息人士均拒绝透露姓名。</p>   <p>Debt-laden municipalities represent a major risk to the world's second-largest economy and its financial stability, amid a deepening property crisis, years of over-investment in infrastructure and huge bills to contain the COVID-19 pandemic.<br><br>在不断加深的房地产危机、多年来基础设施的过度投资以及遏制新冠肺炎 (COVID-19) 疫情的巨额支出的背景下，负债累累的城市对世界第二大经济体及其金融稳定构成了重大风险。</p>   <p>The crash in property prices and a cash crunch have left developers in no shape to buy more land, traditionally a key source of local government revenue. Land sales in January-September were down almost 20 percent from the year-ago period.<br><br>房地产价格暴跌和现金紧缩导致开发商无力购买更多土地，而土地历来是地方政府收入的主要来源。 1-9月土地出让金同比下降近20%。</p>   <p>Local government debt loads are far higher than at the central government level.<br><br>地方政府债务负担远高于中央政府。</p>   <p>While central government debt is only 21% OF GDP, local debt reached 92 trillion yuan ($12.58 trillion), or 76% of the country's economic output in 2022, up from 62.2% in 2019. The massive piles of debt highlights local governments' financial stress, fuelling concerns of a systemic financial crisis.<br><br>虽然中央政府债务仅占 GDP 的 21%，但地方债务将达到 92 万亿元人民币（12.58 万亿美元），占中国经济产出的 76%，高于 2019 年的 62.2%。巨额债务凸显了地方政府的财政状况压力，加剧了对系统性金融危机的担忧。</p>   <p>Part of that is debt issued by LGFVs, which cities use to raise money for infrastructure projects, often at the urging of the central government when it needs to boost economic growth.<br><br>其中一部分是地方政府融资平台发行的债务，城市利用这些债务为基础设施项目筹集资金，通常是在中央政府需要促进经济增长时的敦促下进行的。</p>   <p>China's Politburo, a top decision-making body of the ruling Communist Party, said in late July said it would announce a basket of measures to reduce local government debt risks, but no detailed plans have been officially unveiled yet.<br><br>中国共产党最高决策机构政治局7月底表示，将宣布一揽子措施降低地方政府债务风险，但尚未正式公布具体计划。</p>   <p>China has told state-owned banks to roll over existing local government debt with longer-term loans at lower interest rates, Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-instructs-banks-roll-over-local-government-debt-sources-2023-10-17/">reported</a> last week.<br><br>据路透社上周<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-instructs-banks-roll-over-local-government-debt-sources-2023-10-17/">报道</a>，中国已要求国有银行以较低利率提供长期贷款来展期现有地方政府债务。</p>   <p>In addition, a slew of local governments - mostly debt-ridden ones such as Yunnan and Guizhou - have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/what-risk-china-investors-snap-up-local-government-bonds-beijing-tackles-big-2023-10-17/">started selling</a> so-called refinancing bonds this month in a special, one-time programme to replace other forms of borrowing. The bond issuance is widely believed to be part of Beijing's measures to defuse debt risks of LGFVs.<br><br>此外，许多地方政府（主要是云南和贵州等负债累累的地方政府）本月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/what-risk-china-investors-snap-up-local-government-bonds-beijing-tackles-big-2023-10-17/">开始通过一项特殊的一次性计划出售</a>所谓的再融资债券，以取代其他形式的借款。人们普遍认为，此次债券发行是北京化解地方政府融资平台债务风险措施的一部分。</p>    <span>Reporting by Beijing Newsroom; Editing by Don Durfee and Raju Gopalakrishnan<br><br>北京新闻编辑室报道；唐·杜菲 (Don Durfee) 和拉朱·戈帕拉克里希南 (Raju Gopalakrishnan) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 09:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">LDSSREYA6JNOPNEWEMBBJOVEJY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-cabinet-curbs-debt-growth-12-high-risk-regions-sources-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>DEBT/LGFV (EXCLUSIVE)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国国防部批评五角大楼年度报告]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/_hxVq59HIHjP5-Kp9Xnkxt7NJ_g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SPITPHHJCFKX7LFBV2AZZKDTYA.jpg" alt="The flags of the United States and China fly in Boston<br><br>美国和中国国旗在波士顿飘扬" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The flags of the United States and China fly from a lamppost in the Chinatown neighborhood of Boston, Massachusetts, U.S., November 1, 2021.   REUTERS/Brian Snyder<br><br>2021年11月1日，美国马萨诸塞州波士顿唐人街附近的灯柱上飘扬着中美两国国旗。路透社/Brian Snyder</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's defence ministry on Wednesday denounced the U.S. Defense Department's annual report on China, saying it distorts the country's security policy and military strategy.<br><br>中国国防部周三谴责美国国防部年度对华报告，称其歪曲中国安全政策和军事战略。</p>   <p>Over the next decade, the People's Republic of China will rapidly modernise, diversify, and expand its nuclear forces, the Pentagon said in its <a href="extension://bfdogplmndidlpjfhoijckpakkdjkkil/pdf/viewer.html?file=https%3A%2F%2Fmedia.defense.gov%2F2023%2FOct%2F19%2F2003323409%2F-1%2F-1%2F1%2F2023-MILITARY-AND-SECURITY-DEVELOPMENTS-INVOLVING-THE-PEOPLES-REPUBLIC-OF-CHINA.PDF" target="_blank">report</a> to U.S. Congress, laying out China's national ambitions, including its defence policy and military strategies.<br><br>五角大楼在向美国国会<a href="extension://bfdogplmndidlpjfhoijckpakkdjkkil/pdf/viewer.html?file=https%3A%2F%2Fmedia.defense.gov%2F2023%2FOct%2F19%2F2003323409%2F-1%2F-1%2F1%2F2023-MILITARY-AND-SECURITY-DEVELOPMENTS-INVOLVING-THE-PEOPLES-REPUBLIC-OF-CHINA.PDF" target="_blank">提交的报告</a>中表示，未来十年，中华人民共和国将迅速实现核力量现代化、多样化和扩张，阐述了中国的国家雄心，包括国防政策和军事战略。</p>   <p>The Pentagon said China has more than 500 nuclear warheads and will probably have more than 1,000 warheads by 2030. The report said China would use new fast-breeder reactors and reprocessing facilities to produce plutonium for its nuclear weapons, despite publicly saying the technologies are intended for peaceful purposes.<br><br>五角大楼表示，中国拥有超过 500 枚核弹头，到 2030 年可能会拥有超过 1,000 枚核弹头。该报告称，中国将使用新的快中子增殖反应堆和后处理设施来生产核武器所需的钚，尽管公开表示这些技术的目的是出于和平目的。</p>   <p>"We express our strong dissatisfaction and resolute opposition to this report," Chinese Defence Ministry spokesperson Wu Qian said in a statement, adding that it "exaggerates and hypes the non-existent 'Chinese military threat'".<br><br>中国国防部发言人吴谦在一份声明中表示，“我们对这份报告表示强烈不满和坚决反对”，并补充说，该报告“夸大和炒作了不存在的‘中国军事威胁’”。</p>   <p>Wu said the development of China's armed forces is aimed at containing the threat of war, safeguarding its own security and safeguarding world peace, and is not aimed at any specific country or target.<br><br>吴邦国表示，中国军队的发展是为了遏制战争威胁、维护自身安全、维护世界和平，不针对任何特定国家和目标。</p>   <p>China and the United States have recently traded barbs over global and national security concerns, military interactions in the South China Sea and over Taiwan, which China claims as its own territory.<br><br>中国和美国最近就全球和国家安全问题、南海军事互动以及中国声称拥有主权的台湾问题互相指责。</p>   <p>The Pentagon said in 2022 that China "amplified diplomatic, political, and military pressure against Taiwan".<br><br>五角大楼在2022年表示，中国“加大了对台湾的外交、政治和军事压力”。</p>   <p>"The so-called report on China's military power released by the United States is full of all kinds of wrong content, including the statement on the Taiwan issue," a spokesperson for China's Taiwan Affairs Office said at a media briefing on Wednesday.<br><br>中国国台办发言人周三在例行记者会上表示，美国发布的所谓中国军力报告充满了各种错误内容，包括有关台湾问题的表述。</p>   <p>Calling the military-to-military relationship an important part of Sino-U.S. relations, the Defence Ministry's Wu said, "we maintain frank and effective communication with the United States through military diplomacy".<br><br>吴仪表示，两军关系是中美关系的重要组成部分，“我们通过军事外交同美国保持着坦诚有效的沟通”。</p>   <p>But he added the difficulties and obstacles facing relations between the two militaries are created by the United States.<br><br>但他补充说，两军关系面临的困难和障碍是美国制造的。</p>   <p>"The United States pretends to be confused, while doing things that harm China's security interests, but at the same time shouting that it wants to manage the crisis and strengthen communication," Wu said.<br><br>“美国装糊涂，一边做损害中国安全利益的事情，一边喊着要管控危机、加强沟通，”吴说。</p>   <p>The latest exchange between the two countries comes days before China hosts foreign defence officials at the 10th Xiangshan Forum in Beijing from Oct. 29 to 31.<br><br>两国之间的最新交流是在中国于 10 月 29 日至 31 日在北京接待外国国防官员出席第十届香山论坛之前几天进行的。</p>   <p>The United States accepted China's invitation after China turned down a meeting a few months ago between the two countries' defence chiefs.<br><br>在中国几个月前拒绝两国国防部长会晤后，美国接受了中国的邀请。</p>    <span>Reporting by Bernard Orr; Editing by Gerry Doyle<br><br>伯纳德·奥尔报道；格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:11:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7KAE4YDU7JLMFJNC5DAI2H444A</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/chinas-defence-ministry-blasts-pentagons-annual-report-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Bernard Orr]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>USA/DEFENCE (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国用新舰艇追赶美国和俄罗斯的导弹潜艇能力]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/iiHGGhyNnUsCpJeeADr96BCzwvE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YEI6LAN4D5IF7JFLYRWILI3JXY.jpg" alt="A Chinese Navy's submarine takes part in a naval parade off the eastern port city of Qingdao to mark the 70th anniversary of the founding of Chinese People's Liberation Army Navy<br><br>中国海军潜艇参加东部港口城市青岛举行的纪念中国人民解放军海军成立70周年海上阅兵" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Chinese Navy's submarine takes part in a naval parade off the eastern port city of Qingdao to mark the 70th anniversary of the founding of Chinese People's Liberation Army Navy<br><br>中国海军潜艇参加东部港口城市青岛举行的纪念中国人民解放军海军成立70周年海上阅兵, China, April 23, 2019. REUTERS/Jason Lee/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/EGAsRo6xr2-DKpJCe8PLdCc4Jq4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PLCXG4FJ25LGLESZ4M2NX6C5A4.jpg" alt="Illustration shows Chinese flag<br><br>插图显示中国国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The Chinese flag is seen in this illustration taken May 30, 2022. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo<br><br>这张摄于 2022 年 5 月 30 日的插图中可以看到中国国旗。 REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>China has launched its first nuclear-powered guided missile submarines, according to the Pentagon's latest report on China's military - giving it land and sea attack options once the sole province of U.S. and Russian vessels.<br><br>根据五角大楼关于中国军事的最新报告，中国已经下水了第一艘核动力导弹潜艇，这让中国拥有了陆地和海上攻击的选择，这曾经是美国和俄罗斯船只的唯一选择。</p>   <p>The Pentagon report, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-most-significant-pentagons-china-military-report-2023-10-21/">published Oct. 20</a>, marks the first apparent confirmation that modified submarines seen in Chinese shipyards over the last 18 months are Type 093B guided missile submarines.<br><br>五角大楼<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-most-significant-pentagons-china-military-report-2023-10-21/">10月20日发布的</a>报告首次明显证实过去18个月在中国造船厂看到的改装潜艇是093B型导弹潜艇。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/satellite-images-raise-prospect-new-class-chinese-submarine-2022-05-10/">Reuters revealed in May 2022</a> that satellite images from Huludao shipyard in northeast China showed a new or upgraded class of submarine, possibly with vertical tubes for launching cruise missiles.<br><br><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/satellite-images-raise-prospect-new-class-chinese-submarine-2022-05-10/">路透社于 2022 年 5 月透露</a>，中国东北葫芦岛造船厂的卫星图像显示了一种新型或升级型潜艇，可能配有用于发射巡航导弹的垂直管。</p>      <p>The Pentagon report says that in the short term, the Chinese navy "will have the ability to conduct long-range precision strikes against land targets from its submarine and surface combatants using land-attack cruise missiles, notably enhancing (China's) power projection capability".<br><br>五角大楼的报告称，短期内，中国海军“将有能力使用对地攻击巡航导弹从潜艇和水面战舰上对陆地目标进行远程精确打击，特别是增强（中国的）力量投送能力” 。</p>   <p>Known as SSGNs, conventionally armed missile submarines were developed by the Soviet Union during the Cold War in part to target U.S. aircraft carriers, while the U.S. Navy developed its own version by converting ballistic missile boats to carry large numbers of land-attack Tomahawk cruise missiles.<br><br>常规武装导弹潜艇被称为SSGN，是苏联在冷战期间开发的，部分目的是针对美国航空母舰，而美国海军则通过将弹道导弹艇改装为携带大量对地攻击战斧巡航导弹来开发自己的版本。</p>   <p>Cruise missiles are typically long-range, precision weapons that, unlike ballistic weapons, fly at low altitudes or skim the surface of the sea.<br><br>巡航导弹通常是远程精确武器，与弹道武器不同，巡航导弹可以低空飞行或掠过海面。</p>   <p>The submarine USS Florida fired 93 Tomahawks against Libyan air defences in 2011 - the first combat strikes from a U.S. SSGN and an event that regional military attaches say was closely studied by Chinese strategists.<br><br>2011年，佛罗里达号潜艇向利比亚防空系统发射了93枚“战斧”导弹——这是美国战略核潜艇的首次战斗打击，地区武官称中国战略家对这一事件进行了密切研究。</p>   <p>Some analysts say the PLA navy will be eager to deploy the vessels as an extra weapon against aircraft carriers as well as a land-attack platform, allowing strikes from a far greater range than its fleets of smaller attack submarines.<br><br>一些分析人士表示，解放军海军将渴望部署这些舰艇，作为对抗航空母舰的额外武器以及对地攻击平台，与小型攻击潜艇舰队相比，可以从更远的范围进行攻击。</p>   <p>The report notes that three of the new SSGNs could be operational by next year, as part of a wider expansion of its submarine fleet - both nuclear and diesel powered - which could number 65 vessels in 2025.<br><br>报告指出，三艘新的弹道导弹核潜艇可能会在明年投入使用，作为其潜艇舰队（核动力和柴油动力）更广泛扩张的一部分，到 2025 年，潜艇舰队的数量可能达到 65 艘。</p>   <p>The Chinese defence ministry did not respond to questions from Reuters.<br><br>中国国防部没有回应路透社的提问。</p>   <p>The confirmation comes amid an <a href="" target="_blank">intensifying submarine arms race</a> as China constructs a new generation of nuclear-armed boats as part of its evolving deterrent force.<br><br>这一确认是在<a href="" target="_blank">潜艇军备竞赛加剧</a>之际做出的，中国正在建造新一代核潜艇，作为其不断发展的威慑力量的一部分。</p>   <p>The effort to track China's submarines at sea is one of the core drivers of increased deployments and contingency planning by the U.S. Navy and other militaries across the Indo-Pacific region.<br><br>在海上追踪中国潜艇的努力是美国海军和印太地区其他军队增加部署和应急计划的核心驱动力之一。</p>   <p>Singapore-based security scholar Collin Koh said the SSGNs were an important new capability for the Chinese navy.<br><br>新加坡安全学者科林·科(Collin Koh)表示，弹道导弹核潜艇是中国海军的一项重要新能力。</p>   <p>With an expected core armament of cruise missiles, "this potentially allows them to carry out saturated land and anti-ship attacks at standoff range”, he said, which would complicate strategic calculations by China's rivals.<br><br>他说，由于预期的核心武器是巡航导弹，“这可能使他们能够在防区外范围内进行饱和陆地和反舰攻击”，这将使中国竞争对手的战略计算复杂化。</p>   <p>"I would also expect the Chinese have learned from the Russian experience in using them to threaten U.S. aircraft carriers – with an SSGN, you can launch strikes at standoff range, unlike a typical attack submarine that could have more limited weapon options, and that is a real advantage," said Koh, of the S. Rajaratnam School of International Studies.<br><br>“我还希望中国人从俄罗斯使用它们威胁美国航空母舰的经验中吸取教训——使用弹道导弹核潜艇，你可以在防区外范围内发动攻击，这与典型的攻击潜艇不同，后者的武器选择可能更加有限，而且这是一个真正的优势，”拉惹勒南国际研究学院的 Koh 说。</p>   <p>Research discussed at the U.S. Naval War College in May noted that the PLA was close to breakthroughs in making its nuclear-powered submarines far quieter and more difficult for the U.S. and its allies to track.<br><br>美国海军战争学院五月份讨论的研究表明，解放军在使其核动力潜艇变得更安静、更难以被美国及其盟国追踪方面即将取得突破。</p>   <p>Some diplomats and analysts said, however, that it was unclear whether those breakthroughs had been incorporated into the recently launched SSGNs. The upgrades are expected in nuclear-powered boats launched before the end of the decade.<br><br>然而，一些外交官和分析人士表示，目前尚不清楚这些突破是否已被纳入最近发射的弹道导弹核潜艇中。预计本世纪末之前推出的核动力船将进行升级。</p>   <p>"Unless they are certain of improvements, we can expect the PLA navy to be cautious in how they initially deploy them," said an Asian military attache who is tracking China's submarine force. The attache declined to be named because of the sensitivity of the matter. "But we know the submarine force is a priority for Xi Jinping, and this is one more sign they are getting there."<br><br>一位正在跟踪中国潜艇部队的亚洲武官表示：“除非他们确定能取得改进，否则我们可以预期解放军海军在最初部署这些潜艇的方式上会持谨慎态度。”由于此事敏感，该专员拒绝透露姓名。 “但我们知道潜艇部队是习近平的首要任务，这是他们正在实现这一目标的又一个迹象。”</p>    <span>Reporting By Greg Torode. Editing by Gerry Doyle<br><br>格雷格·托罗德报道。格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:00:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZM7QZJLKLBJOVJXHWK262UHHCA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-chases-us-russia-guided-missile-submarine-capabilities-with-new-vessels-2023-10-25/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Greg Torode]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>MILITARY/SUBMARINE (ANALYSIS, GRAPHIC)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
