<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 10:33:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国将对澳大利亚葡萄酒进口反补贴关税进行审查]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/_8AD1kQNps_P28eMV7Uvj-0Lvo4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/W567H44ZIFN6XADQEMQTMQWWZY.jpg" alt="Wine bar in Beijing翻译:北京的酒吧" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A staff member sniffs wine in a glass while a customer watches at  theTrio Wine Bar in Beijing, China November 1, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 1 日，中国北京，Trio 酒吧，一名工作人员在嗅着玻璃杯中的葡萄酒，而一名顾客正在观看。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China said on Thursday it would review the need for anti-dumping and anti-subsidy tariffs on Australian wine imports, a highly anticipated move that is part of a push to improve <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-wine-market-ready-welcome-likely-return-aussie-wine-ties-improve-2023-11-03/">the relationship</a> between the two countries.翻译:中国周四表示，将审查对澳大利亚进口葡萄酒征收反倾销和反补贴关税的必要性，这一备受期待的举措是推动改善两国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-wine-market-ready-welcome-likely-return-aussie-wine-ties-improve-2023-11-03/">关系的</a>一部分。</p>   <p>The Commerce Ministry said in a statement it had decided to conduct the review from Thursday.翻译:商务部在一份声明中表示，决定从周四开始进行审查。</p>   <p>Last month, China and Australia said they had reached a consensus to settle a World Trade Organisation dispute about wine, and that the anti-dumping tariffs, set to expire in 2026, would be reviewed.翻译:上个月，中国和澳大利亚表示，双方已就解决世界贸易组织有关葡萄酒的争端达成共识，并将对将于 2026 年到期的反倾销关税进行审查。</p>   <p>"The Ministry of Commerce will carry out a review in accordance with the law to fully protect the rights of all stakeholders," Shu Jueting, a commerce ministry spokesperson, told a regular news conference in Beijing.翻译:商务部新闻发言人舒珏廷在北京举行的例行新闻发布会上表示，“商务部将依法开展审查，充分保障各利益相关方的权利。”</p>   <p>"We will adjudicate objectively, fairly and openly based on the claims of each interested party and after examining the evidence," she added.翻译:她补充说：“我们将根据各方的主张，在审查证据后，客观、公正、公开地做出裁决。”</p>   <p>The ministry said any interested parties or stakeholders may submit comments in writing within 20 days.翻译:该部表示，任何利益相关方或利益相关者可以在 20 天内提交书面意见。</p>   <p>The introduction of a 218% tax on most Australian wine introduced by China in 2021 prompted <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-wine-market-ready-welcome-likely-return-aussie-wine-ties-improve-2023-11-03/">that trade</a>, previously valued as high as $1.2 billion annually, to collapse.翻译:2021年，中国对大多数澳大利亚葡萄酒征收218%的税，导致此前每年价值高达12亿美元<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-wine-market-ready-welcome-likely-return-aussie-wine-ties-improve-2023-11-03/">的贸易</a>崩溃。</p>   <p>"This is good news for the thousands of Australians who work in the wine industry," a spokesperson from the Australian Trade Minister's Office said.翻译:澳大利亚贸易部长办公室发言人表示：“这对于成千上万在葡萄酒行业工作的澳大利亚人来说是个好消息。”</p>   <p>Since the expedited removal of duties on Australian barley, the government has engaged actively with China to secure a similar process to resolve the dispute on wine, the spokesperson added.翻译:该发言人补充说，自从加快取消对澳大利亚大麦的关税以来，政府一直积极与中国接触，以确保采取类似的程序来解决葡萄酒争端。</p>   <p>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has sought to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-albanese-china-seeks-dialogue-cooperation-2023-11-05/">improve ties</a> with major trade partner China which had deteriorated over several years due to disputes over Chinese telecoms firm Huawei, espionage and COVID-19.翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞一直寻求<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-albanese-china-seeks-dialogue-cooperation-2023-11-05/">改善与主要贸易伙伴中国的关系</a>，这种关系多年来因中国电信公司华为、间谍活动和新冠肺炎 (COVID-19) 问题而恶化。</p>   <p>Albanese became the first sitting Australia leader to visit China since 2016 when he travelled to Beijing in early November.翻译:阿尔巴内斯于11月初访问北京，成为自2016年以来第一位访问中国的澳大利亚在任领导人。</p>    <span>Reporting by Albee Zhang, Bernard Orr and Joe Cash in Beijing, Lewis Jackson in Sydney; Editing by Jacqueline Wong, Miral Fahmy and Raju Gopalakrishnan翻译:Albee 张、伯纳德·奥尔和乔·卡什在北京报道，刘易斯·杰克逊在悉尼报道；编辑：Jacqueline Wong、Miral Fahmy 和 Raju Gopalakrishnan</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 10:11:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">YMS43P6SKNJWVHURNH5CNFN6P4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-review-anti-subsidy-tariffs-australia-wine-imports-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA/ (UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[新加坡和苏黎世全球最昂贵城市]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/mHBnCq-yHzOtxNLi9mD01DgW_2Y=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HNQHIO4VEZK7PPK36AJCBECGGU.jpg" alt="A view of the skyline in Singapore翻译:新加坡的天际线景观" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view of the skyline in Singapore翻译:新加坡的天际线景观, January 27, 2023. REUTERS/Caroline Chia/File Photo翻译:新加坡天际线景观，2023 年 1 月 27 日。路透社/Caroline Chia/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/94h5kG1SVY6zq4_9YKkEGJLcj1s=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HEBKIKNPDFKR7A2KRBI42THVDI.jpg" alt="The Limmat river and the city are seen early morning in Zurich翻译:苏黎世清晨可以看到利马特河和城市" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The Limmat river and the city are seen early morning in Zurich翻译:苏黎世清晨可以看到利马特河和城市, Switzerland March 21, 2023. REUTERS/Denis Balibouse/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>Singapore and Zurich tied for the world's most expensive city this year, followed by Geneva, New York and Hong Kong, the Economist Intelligence Unit (EIU) said on Thursday as it cautioned that the global cost-of-living crisis was not yet over.翻译:经济学人智库（EIU）周四表示，新加坡和苏黎世并列今年全球生活成本最高的城市，其次是日内瓦、纽约和香港，并警告称全球生活成本危机尚未结束。</p>   <p>On average, prices have risen by 7.4% year on year in local currency terms for over 200 commonly used goods and services, a drop from the record 8.1% increase last year but still "significantly higher than the trend in 2017-2021," it said in a report.翻译:平均而言，200多种常用商品和服务的价格以当地货币计算同比上涨7.4%，低于去年创纪录的8.1%涨幅，但仍“显着高于2017-2021年的趋势”。在一份报告中说。</p>   <p>Singapore regained the top of the rankings for the ninth time in the past eleven years due to high price levels across several categories.翻译:由于多个类别的高价格水平，新加坡在过去十一年中第九次重登排行榜榜首。</p>   <p>The city state has the world's highest transport prices, owing to strict government controls on car numbers. It is also amongst the most expensive for clothing, groceries and alcohol.翻译:由于政府对汽车数量的严格控制，这个城市国家的交通价格是世界上最高的。它也是服装、杂货和酒类最昂贵的地方之一。</p>   <p>Zurich's rise reflected the strength of the Swiss franc and high prices for groceries, household goods and recreation, it said.翻译:报告称，苏黎世的上涨反映了瑞士法郎的强势以及食品杂货、家庭用品和娱乐产品的高价格。</p>   <p>Geneva and New York tied for third place, while Hong Kong was fifth and Los Angeles in sixth.翻译:日内瓦和纽约并列第三，香港排名第五，洛杉矶排名第六。</p>   <p>Asia continues to see relatively lower price increases on average compared to other regions, it said.翻译:报告称，与其他地区相比，亚洲的平均价格涨幅仍然相对较低。</p>   <p>Chinese cities have fallen in its rankings with four cities - Nanjing, Wuxi, Dalian and Beijing - among the biggest movers down the rankings this year along with Osaka and Tokyo in Japan.翻译:中国城市的排名有所下降，其中南京、无锡、大连和北京这四个城市是今年排名下降幅度最大的城市，另外还有日本的大阪和东京。</p>    <span>Reporting by Farah Master; Editing by Christopher Cushing翻译:法拉大师报道；克里斯托弗·库欣编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 09:38:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">JIVTAPDBUFNCTIVMRMYMR3L3BE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/singapore-zurich-worlds-most-expensive-cities-eiu-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>LIVING/COSTS</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[对美国外交官亨利·基辛格之死的反应]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ampsoWLzo0BR_xnW90YavQbHnxA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TCAZLLJSH5KF3DIFY7JPO3Y4NU.jpg" alt="Kissinger addresses House Committee on International Relations about the Middle East peace process.翻译:基辛格在众议院国际关系委员会就中东和平进程发表讲话。" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Former U.S. Secretary of State Henry Kissinger addresses the House Committee on International Relations in a hearing about the Middle East peace process on Capitol Hill, Washington, U.S. on February 10, 2005. REUTERS/Jonathan Ernst/File Photo翻译:2005 年 2 月 10 日，美国华盛顿国会山，美国前国务卿亨利·基辛格在众议院国际关系委员会就中东和平进程举行的听证会上发表讲话。路透社/乔纳森·恩斯特/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Here are reactions to the death of Henry Kissinger, a controversial Nobel Peace Prize winner who left an indelible mark on U.S. foreign policy:翻译:以下是对亨利·基辛格去世的反应：一位备受争议的诺贝尔和平奖获得者，他在美国外交政策上留下了不可磨灭的印记：</p>   <p>WINSTON LORD, FORMER U.S. AMBASSADOR TO CHINA AND KISSINGER'S FORMER SPECIAL ASSISTANT AT THE NATIONAL SECURITY COUNCIL:翻译:美国前驻华大使、基辛格前国家安全委员会特别助理温斯顿·洛德：</p>   <p>"The world has lost a tireless advocate for peace. America has lost a towering champion for the national interest. I have lost a cherished friend and mentor.翻译:“世界失去了一位孜孜不倦的和平倡导者。美国失去了一位国家利益的杰出捍卫者。我失去了一位珍贵的朋友和导师。</p>   <p>"Henry blended the European sense of tragedy and the American immigrant’s sense of hope.翻译:“亨利融合了欧洲人的悲剧感和美国移民的希望感。</p>   <p>"During more than seven decades, he transformed America’s role in the world, held the nation together during a constitutional crisis, crafted visionary volumes, counseled world leaders, and enriched the national and international discourse."翻译:“在七年多的时间里，他改变了美国在世界上的角色，在宪法危机中团结了国家，撰写了富有远见的著作，为世界领导人提供了咨询，并丰富了国家和国际话语。”</p>   <p>MARTIN INDYK, FORMER U.S. SPECIAL ENVOY FOR ISRAELI-PALESTINIAN NEGOTIATIONS AND AUTHOR OF ‘MASTER OF THE GAME: HENRY KISSINGER AND THE ART OF MIDDLE EAST DIPLOMACY’:翻译:马丁·因迪克，前美国以色列-巴勒斯坦谈判特使，《游戏大师：亨利·基辛格与中东外交的艺术》一书的作者：</p>   <p>"Kissinger was a man of history, but he was also a student of history, and his knowledge of history, his deep understanding, particularly of European 19th-century history, informed his whole approach to the world.翻译:“基辛格是一个研究历史的人，但他也是一名历史的学生，他对历史的了解，他的深刻理解，特别是对欧洲19世纪历史的理解，影响了他对世界的整个看法。</p>   <p>"He was deeply skeptical of those who would aim to try to achieve a peaceful world. He was much more focused on establishing order because order was more reliable than peace.翻译:“他对那些试图实现和平世界的人深表怀疑。他更专注于建立秩序，因为秩序比和平更可靠。</p>   <p>"He was skeptical that nation-states could ever end their conflicts but if they did it would take a long time and, in the meantime, what would matter would be the order in the world ... that would ameliorate conflict, reduce the chances for war, and create conditions in which ... nation-states could learn to settle their differences, short of going to war.翻译:“他对民族国家能否结束冲突表示怀疑，但如果他们这样做，将需要很长时间，同时，重要的是世界秩序......这将缓解冲突，减少冲突的机会战争，并创造条件……民族国家可以学会解决分歧，而不是发动战争。</p>   <p>"His was a very conservative approach, based on the need for a balance of power on the side of those who would maintain the order and against those who would seek to disrupt it."翻译:“他采取了一种非常保守的做法，基于维持秩序的一方与试图破坏秩序的一方之间的权力平衡的需要。”</p>   <p>FORMER U.S. PRESIDENT GEORGE W. BUSH:翻译:美国前总统乔治·W·布什：</p>   <p>"America has lost one of the most dependable and distinctive voices on foreign affairs with the passing of Henry Kissinger. I have long admired the man who fled the Nazis as a young boy from a Jewish family, then fought them in the United States Army.翻译:“随着亨利·基辛格的去世，美国在外交事务上失去了最可靠、最独特的声音之一。我一直很钦佩这个来自犹太家庭的小男孩逃离纳粹，然后在美国军队与他们作战的人。</p>   <p>"When he later became secretary of state, his appointment as a former refugee said as much about his greatness as it did America's greatness.翻译:“当他后来成为国务卿时，他作为前难民的任命既体现了他的伟大，也体现了美国的伟大。</p>   <p>"He worked in the administrations of two presidents and counseled many more. I am grateful for that service and advice, but I am most grateful for his friendship.翻译:“他曾在两任总统的政府中工作，并为更多人提供咨询。我很感谢他的服务和建议，但我最感谢他的友谊。</p>   <p>"Laura and I will miss his wisdom, his charm, and his humor. And we will always be thankful for the contributions of Henry Kissinger."翻译:“劳拉和我会怀念他的智慧、他的魅力和他的幽默。我们将永远感谢亨利·基辛格的贡献。”</p>   <p>CHINA'S AMBASSADOR TO THE UNITED STATES, XIE FENG:翻译:中国驻美国大使谢锋：</p>   <p>"Deeply shocked and saddened to learn of Dr. Kissinger's passing at 100. My deepest condolences go to Nancy (Kissinger's wife) and her family. It is a tremendous loss for both our countries and the world. The history will remember what the centenarian had contributed to China-U.S. relations, and he will always remain alive in the hearts of the Chinese people as a most valued old friend."翻译:“得知基辛格博士以 100 岁高龄去世的消息，我深感震惊和悲痛。我向南希（基辛格的妻子）和她的家人表示最深切的哀悼。这对我们国家和世界来说都是巨大的损失。历史将记住这位百岁老人的一生他为中美关系做出了重要贡献，他将作为最值得尊敬的老朋友永远活在中国人民心中。”</p>   <p>RUSSIAN PRESIDENT VLADIMIR PUTIN:翻译:俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京：</p>   <p>"The name of Henry Kissinger is inextricably linked with a pragmatic foreign policy line, which at one time made it possible to achieve detente in international tensions and reach the most important Soviet-American agreements that contributed to the strengthening of global security.翻译:“亨利·基辛格的名字与务实的外交政策路线有着千丝万缕的联系，这一路线一度使国际紧张局势得以缓和，并达成了有助于加强全球安全的最重要的苏美协议。</p>   <p>"I had the opportunity to personally communicate with this deep, extraordinary man many times, and I will undoubtedly retain the fondest memory of him."翻译:“我有机会多次与这位深刻、非凡的人进行亲自交流，毫无疑问，我将保留对他最美好的记忆。”</p>   <p>ISRAELI PRIME MINISTER BENJAMIN NETANYAHU:翻译:以色列总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡：</p>   <p>"Dr. Kissinger's departure marks the end of an era, one in which his formidable intellect and diplomatic prowess shaped not only the course of American foreign policy but also had a profound impact on the global stage.翻译:“基辛格博士的离开标志着一个时代的结束，在这个时代，他令人惊叹的才智和外交才能不仅决定了美国外交政策的走向，而且对全球舞台产生了深远的影响。</p>   <p>"I had the privilege of meeting Dr. Kissinger on numerous occasions, the most recent being just two months ago in New York. Each meeting with him was not just a lesson in diplomacy but also a masterclass in statesmanship. His understanding of the complexities of international relations and his unique insights into the challenges facing our world were unparalleled."翻译:“我有幸在很多场合见到基辛格博士，最近一次是两个月前在纽约。与他的每次会面不仅是一堂外交课，也是一堂政治家大师课。他对国际事务复杂性的理解他对国际关系的研究以及他对我们世界面临的挑战的独特见解是无与伦比的。”</p>   <p>EUROPEAN COUNCIL PRESIDENT CHARLES MICHEL:翻译:欧洲理事会主席查尔斯·米歇尔：</p>   <p>"My deepest condolences to the American people and family on the passing of Henry Kissinger. I had the privilege to meet with Henry several times. A kind human and a brilliant mind who, over one hundred years, shaped the destinies of some of the most important events of the century. A strategist with attention to the smallest detail."翻译:“我对亨利·基辛格的去世向美国人民和家人表示最深切的哀悼。我有幸多次与亨利会面。他是一个善良的人，一个聪明的头脑，在一百多年的时间里，他塑造了一些最伟大人物的命运。本世纪的重要事件。一位关注最小细节的战略家。”</p>   <p>JAPANESE PRIME MINISTER FUMIO KISHIDA:翻译:日本首相岸田文雄：</p>   <p>"The former secretary of state made great contributions to regional peace and stability, including the normalisation of diplomatic relations between the U.S. and China.翻译:“前国务卿为地区和平与稳定，包括美中外交关系正常化做出了巨大贡献。</p>   <p>"I, myself, have had the privilege of meeting him on many occasions since I was a young man, and I have gained a great deal of knowledge from him. I would like to express my deepest respect for his great achievements."翻译:“我本人从年轻时就有幸多次见到他，从他那里学到了很多知识。我谨对他的伟大成就表示最深切的敬意。”</p>   <p>GERMAN CHANCELLOR OLAF SCHOLZ:翻译:德国总理奥拉夫·肖尔茨：</p>   <p>"Henry Kissinger shaped American foreign policy like few others. His commitment to the transatlantic friendship between the USA and Germany was significant, and he always remained close to his German homeland. The world has lost a great diplomat."翻译:“亨利·基辛格像其他人一样塑造了美国的外交政策。他对美国和德国之间跨大西洋友谊的承诺意义重大，而且他始终与他的德国祖国保持密切联系。世界失去了一位伟大的外交家。”</p>   <p>CINDY MCCAIN, U.S. DIPLOMAT AND WIFE OF LATE SENATOR JOHN MCCAIN:翻译:美国外交官、已故参议员约翰·麦凯恩的妻子辛迪·麦凯恩：</p>   <p>"Henry Kissinger was ever present in my late husband’s life. While John was a prisoner of war, and in the later years, as a senator and statesman. The McCain family will miss his wit, charm, and intelligence terribly."翻译:“亨利·基辛格一直存在于我已故丈夫的生活中。而约翰是一名战俘，在后来的几年里，他成为了一名参议员和政治家。麦凯恩家族将非常怀念他的机智、魅力和智慧。”</p>   <p>PRESIDENT OF THE EU COMMISSION URSULA VON DER LEYEN:翻译:欧盟委员会主席乌苏拉·冯德莱恩：</p>   <p>"Henry Kissinger's strategy and excellence in diplomacy has shaped global politics throughout the 20th century. His influence and legacy will continue to reverberate well into the 21st century"翻译:“亨利·基辛格的战略和卓越的外交塑造了整个 20 世纪的全球政治。他的影响力和遗产将继续影响到 21 世纪”</p>    <span>Reporting by Reuters bureaux; Editing by Edwina Gibbs and Tom Hogue翻译:路透社分社的报道；埃德温娜·吉布斯和汤姆·霍格编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 09:22:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">36XQ2VYSAZOCNMNPI7QI2MUPZ4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/reaction-death-us-diplomat-henry-kissinger-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>PEOPLE</category>
                
                <category>HENRY KISSINGER/QUOTES (QUOTES, UPDATE 6)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[习近平就基辛格逝世向拜登致唁电]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/JS6u5MeZn7GwEzPCLaOi9h6zdJk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YRPSRQEDIJP35ITHMFOUSGQA6Y.jpg" alt="Former U.S. Secretary of State Henry Kissinger meets Chinese President Xi Jinping at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing翻译:美国前国务卿亨利·基辛格在北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Former U.S. Secretary of State Henry Kissinger meets Chinese President Xi Jinping (not pictured) at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, China, November 8, 2018. REUTERS/Thomas Peter/Pool/File Photo翻译:2018 年 11 月 8 日，美国前国务卿亨利·基辛格在中国北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平（无照片）。 REUTERS/Thomas Peter/Pool/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/h8K9rvcTOlMDsItH7dbcy6GjUDk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DYJROE5VJJNAPCIE54CJRVX6P4.jpg" alt="Chinese President Xi is introduced by former U.S. National Security Advisor and Secretary of State Kissinger at a policy speech to Chinese and U.S. CEOs during a dinner reception in Seattle, Washington翻译:美国前国家安全顾问兼国务卿基辛格在华盛顿西雅图举行的晚宴上向中美首席执行官发表政策演讲，介绍中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping (L) is introduced by former U.S. National Security Advisor and Secretary of State Henry Kissinger at a policy speech to Chinese and United States CEOs during a dinner reception in Seattle, Washington, U.S. September 22, 2015. REUTERS/Jason Redmond/File Photo翻译:2015 年 9 月 22 日，美国华盛顿西雅图，美国前国家安全顾问兼国务卿亨利·基辛格在晚宴上向中美两国首席执行官发表政策演讲，介绍了中国国家主席习近平（左）。 REUTERS/Jason Redmond /档案照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>China's President Xi Jinping and senior Chinese officials have sent messages of condolence to U.S. President Joe Biden and others after the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/henry-kissinger-american-diplomat-nobel-winner-dead-100-2023-11-30/">passing</a> of veteran U.S. diplomat Henry Kissinger, the Chinese foreign ministry said on Thursday.翻译:中国外交部周四表示，在美国资深外交官亨利·基辛格<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/henry-kissinger-american-diplomat-nobel-winner-dead-100-2023-11-30/">去世</a>后，中国国家主席习近平和中国高级官员已向美国总统乔·拜登等人致唁电。</p>   <p>Kissinger, who visited China more than 100 times and last <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/chinas-president-xi-meets-with-henry-kissinger-beijing-2023-07-20/">met with Xi</a> during a surprise trip to Beijing in July, died on Wednesday aged 100, prompting widespread mourning among ordinary Chinese people on social media.翻译:基辛格曾访问中国100多次，最后一次<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/chinas-president-xi-meets-with-henry-kissinger-beijing-2023-07-20/">与习近平</a>会面是在7月份出人意料的北京之行。基辛格于周三去世，享年100岁，引发了社交媒体上普通中国民众的广泛哀悼。</p>   <p>"Dr. Kissinger was a good old friend of the Chinese people. He is a pioneer and builder of Sino-U.S. relations," ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin said at a regular news conference.翻译:外交部发言人汪文斌在例行记者会上表示，基辛格博士是中国人民的好老朋友，是中美关系的开拓者和建设者。</p>   <p>Kissinger made "historic" contributions to the normalisation of China-U.S. relations, and Chinese people will remember him for his "sincere devotion and important contribution", Wang added.翻译:王补充道，基辛格为中美关系正常化做出了“历史性”贡献，中国人民将铭记他的“真诚奉献和重要贡献”。</p>   <p>Chinese Premier Li Qiang and Foreign Minister Wang Yi also sent messages of condolence to Kissinger's family and U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken, respectively, Wang told the briefing.翻译:中国国务院总理李强、外交部长王毅也分别向基辛格家属和美国国务卿布林肯致唁电。</p>   <p>Kissinger believed China-U.S. relations are vital to the peace and prosperity of the two countries and the wider world, Wang Wenbin said.翻译:汪文斌表示，基辛格认为，中美关系对两国和世界的和平与繁荣至关重要。</p>   <p>"China and the U.S. should carry forward Kissinger's strategic vision, political courage and diplomatic wisdom... and promote the sound, stable and sustainable development of China-U.S. relations," he said.翻译:中美双方应弘扬基辛格的战略远见、政治勇气、外交智慧……推动中美关系健康稳定可持续发展。</p>   <p>Kissinger, who served as secretary of state and national security adviser in the administrations of Presidents Richard Nixon and Gerald Ford, first visited Beijing in 1971, paving the way for the U.S. diplomatic opening to China.翻译:基辛格曾在理查德·尼克松和杰拉尔德·福特总统的政府中担任国务卿和国家安全顾问，他于1971年首次访问北京，为美国对华外交开放铺平了道路。</p>   <p>His death was widely mourned by Chinese state media and social media users.翻译:中国官方媒体和社交媒体用户广泛哀悼他的去世。</p>   <p>"The overarching impression of Kissinger (in China) was that he was someone in America who understood the Chinese people," said Brian Wong, an assistant professor and geopolitical strategist at Hong Kong University.翻译:香港大学助理教授兼地缘政治战略家布莱恩·黄(Brian Wong)表示：“基辛格（在中国）的总体印象是，他是一位了解中国人民的美国人。”</p>   <p>Kissinger was seen as an outsider who understood China's need to transcend its self-imposed isolation in the 1960s and early 1970s, Wong said.翻译:黄说，基辛格被视为一个局外人，他理解中国需要超越 20 世纪 60 年代和 1970 年代初自我施加的孤立。</p>   <p>"So, in short, he was seen as someone who, crucially, stood for a 'China understander'."翻译:“因此，简而言之，最重要的是，他被视为‘中国理解者’的代表。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Liz Lee, Ethan Wang and Nicoco Chan; Editing by Kim Coghill and Gareth Jones翻译:Liz Lee、Ethan Wang 和 Nicoco Chan 的报道；金·科吉尔和加雷斯·琼斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 09:18:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">O2KHNXEVG5PJHMMFG57AF7S3XM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/chinas-xi-sends-condolences-biden-over-kissingers-death-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>PEOPLE</category>
                
                <category>HENRY KISSINGER/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>BIDEN (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国中金公司分析师被告知不要发表悲观观点，穿奢侈品——备忘录]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/nIyY0VZFfXBfnWruHLfFTwSdDQs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2CYA2YPJCBO7NNHQ4BRBZGM7ZQ.jpg" alt="The company logo of China International Capital Corporation Ltd is displayed at a news conference on the company's annual results in Hong Kong翻译:中国国际金融有限公司的公司标志出现在香港举行的公司年度业绩新闻发布会上" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The company logo of China International Capital Corporation Ltd (CICC), China’s first joint venture investment bank, is displayed at a news conference on the company's annual results in Hong Kong, China March 30, 2016. REUTERS/Bobby Yip/File Photo翻译:2016年3月30日，中国第一家合资投资银行中国国际金融有限公司（中金公司）的公司标志出现在中国香港举行的公司年度业绩新闻发布会上。路透社/Bobby Yip/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China International Capital Corp (CICC) <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3908.HK" target="_blank">(3908.HK)</a>, the country's third-largest investment bank by market value, has told analysts not to publish bearish views on China's economy or its financial markets, according to an internal memo seen by Reuters.翻译:据路透社看到的一份内部备忘录，中国市值第三大投资银行中国国际金融公司（中金公司） <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3908.HK" target="_blank">（3908.HK）</a>已告知分析师不要发表对中国经济或金融市场的悲观观点。</p>   <p>The memo, which was sent to the bank's research department, also told them to refrain from commenting on issues that are not in line with government policies.翻译:这份发送给该银行研究部门的备忘录还告诉他们不要对不符合政府政策的问题发表评论。</p>   <p>Additionally, staff at the state-owned investment bank have been asked to not wear luxury brands or disclose their pay. Employees should "make sure their family members adhere to social and ethical standards", the memo said.翻译:此外，这家国有投资银行的员工被要求不得穿着奢侈品牌或透露自己的薪酬。备忘录称，员工应“确保其家庭成员遵守社会和道德标准”。</p>   <p>CICC did not respond to Reuters' request for comments.翻译:中金公司没有回应路透社的置评请求。</p>   <p>Bloomberg first reported the memo on Thursday.翻译:彭博社周四首先报道了这份备忘录。</p>   <p>CICC, the most active Chinese investment bank in offshore dealmaking, also said in the memo that extra caution should be applied when dealing with overseas clients to avoid political and national security risks.翻译:离岸交易最活跃的中资投行中金公司也在备忘录中表示，在与海外客户打交道时应格外谨慎，以避免政治和国家安全风险。</p>   <p>While negative comments by market analysts and commentators in China have often been censored by authorities, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/outspoken-market-analysts-chinese-social-media-accounts-suspended-2022-05-01/">the trend</a> became more noticeable after China's economic growth began to weaken last year.翻译:尽管中国市场分析师和评论员的负面评论经常受到当局的审查， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/outspoken-market-analysts-chinese-social-media-accounts-suspended-2022-05-01/">但这种趋势</a>在去年中国经济增长开始疲软后变得更加明显。</p>   <p>The central government has also widened crackdowns on corruption and used rhetoric that criticises the country's "financial elite" for leading "hedonistic" lifestyles - part of its "common prosperity" drive that began in 2021.翻译:中央政府还加大了对腐败的打击力度，并使用言论批评该国“金融精英”过着“享乐主义”的生活方式——这是2021年开始的“共同富裕”行动的一部分。</p>   <p>Chinese banks began giving <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-common-prosperity-drive-slashes-pay-perks-investment-bankers-2022-07-29/">verbal guidance</a> as early as 2022, warning bankers to stop posting photos that depicted lavish lifestyles on social media.翻译:中国的银行早在2022年就开始发出<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-common-prosperity-drive-slashes-pay-perks-investment-bankers-2022-07-29/">口头指导</a>，警告银行家停止在社交媒体上发布描绘奢华生活方式的照片。</p>   <p>Banks have also been forced to cut pay and perks for investment bankers, including compensation and budget reductions for travel and entertainment.翻译:银行还被迫削减投资银行家的薪酬和福利，包括旅行和娱乐方面的薪酬和预算削减。</p>   <p>Reuters reported in April that CICC <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/brokerage-cicc-slashes-bonuses-beijing-dials-up-income-disparity-rhetoric-2023-04-06/">slashed</a> bankers' bonuses by as much as 40%.翻译:路透社4月份报道称，中金公司将银行家的奖金<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/brokerage-cicc-slashes-bonuses-beijing-dials-up-income-disparity-rhetoric-2023-04-06/">削减</a>了40%之多。</p>    <span>Reporting by Selena Li and Jason Xue; Editing by Sumeet Chatterjee and Edwina Gibbs翻译:赛琳娜·李和杰森·薛的报道；苏米特·查特吉和埃德温娜·吉布斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 09:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">APF4HYNPHZKSVGAHILFXD4BC6A</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/analysts-chinas-cicc-told-not-publish-bearish-views-wear-luxury-items-memo-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>CICC/AUSTERITY (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[雷米希望年底前解决美国库存问题，利润下降]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/224lD-YWArrXYWgfKgptgZd95fs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/P2HQOS6VDFJNZABKGROHNIFEWM.jpg" alt="A bottle of Cointreau is displayed at the Carre Cointreau in the Cointreau distillery in Saint-Barthelemy-d'Anjou翻译:圣巴泰勒米当茹君度酒厂的 Carre Cointreau 内展示着一瓶君度酒" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A bottle of Cointreau, the orange-flavoured triple sec liqueur, is displayed at the Carre Cointreau in the Cointreau distillery in Saint-Barthelemy-d'Anjou, near Angers, France, February 8, 2019. REUTERS/Stephane Mahe翻译:2019 年 2 月 8 日，法国昂热附近圣巴泰勒米当茹的君度酿酒厂的卡雷君度 (Carre Cointreau) 展示一瓶君度 (Cointreau) 橙味三秒利口酒。 REUTERS/Stephane Mahe</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/B398T79dNbNTaczlweW0SLxPTfk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KK55CVMPKZOH5LIX5XUWIQQJPM.jpg" alt="Photo du logo de la liqueur Cointreau dans la distillerie du groupe Remy Cointreau à Saint-Barthélemy-d'Anjou翻译:圣巴泰勒米当茹集团人头马君度酒厂君度利口酒标志照片" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Photo du logo de la liqueur Cointreau dans la distillerie du groupe Remy Cointreau à Saint-Barthélemy-d'Anjou翻译:圣巴泰勒米当茹集团人头马君度酒厂君度利口酒标志照片. /Photo prise le 8 février 2019/REUTERS/Stéphane Mahé</figcaption></figure>               <p>Remy Cointreau's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RCOP.PA" target="_blank">(RCOP.PA)</a> CEO said on Thursday he aimed to end the year with a "sound" level of stock in the United States but it was unclear when these would start to move, after reporting a 43% fall in first-half operating profit.翻译:人头马君度<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/RCOP.PA" target="_blank">(RCOP.PA)</a>首席执行官周四表示，他的目标是在今年年底前确保美国库存处于“健康”水平，但目前尚不清楚这些库存何时会开始变化，因为该公司上半年的库存下降了 43%营业利润。</p>   <p>High levels of unsold inventories in Remy's key market have become a key issue for watchers of the French spirits group, which makes Remy Martin cognac and Cointreau liqueur, after they contributed to a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/remy-cointreau-lowers-fy-202324-goals-due-slower-than-expected-recovery-us-2023-10-27/">cut in full-year guidance</a> in October.翻译:人头马主要市场的高水平未售出库存已成为法国烈酒集团观察人士关注的一个关键问题，该集团生产人头马干邑和君度利口酒，此前这家公司导致 10 月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/remy-cointreau-lowers-fy-202324-goals-due-slower-than-expected-recovery-us-2023-10-27/">全年指导方针的下调</a>。</p>   <p>Americas, led by the United States, account for about half of the group's sales and the U.S. market is critical for its overall performance.翻译:以美国为首的美洲地区约占该集团销售额的一半，美国市场对其整体业绩至关重要。</p>   <p>The company's U.S. sales have fallen as retailers and wholesalers try to clear their elevated inventories following a post-pandemic boom for Remy.翻译:由于零售商和批发商在人头马疫情后的繁荣之后试图清理增加的库存，该公司在美国的销售额有所下降。</p>   <p>That was exacerbated by a squeeze on their finances that left them less willing to hold Remy's slower-moving brands, and heavy discounting from competitors.翻译:由于财务紧缩，他们不太愿意持有人头马发展缓慢的品牌，加上竞争对手的大幅折扣，加剧了这种情况。</p>   <p>Chief executive Eric Vallat told journalists the group still had around five months' worth of stock in the U.S. market, and while demand was improving it was unclear when sales from wholesalers to retailers would pick back up.翻译:首席执行官埃里克·瓦拉特(Eric Vallat)告诉记者，该集团在美国市场仍有大约五个月的库存，虽然需求正在改善，但尚不清楚批发商向零售商的销售何时会回升。</p>   <p>"The goal is to end the year with sound stocks," he said, adding this would mean around three or four months' worth.翻译:他说：“我们的目标是在年底实现稳健的库存。”他补充说，这意味着大约三四个月的价值。</p>   <p>Remy's shares fell just over 1% at market open but recovered to trade around 3% higher by 0815 GMT.翻译:Remy 的股价开盘时下跌略高于 1%，但到格林尼治标准时间 0815 时回升至上涨约 3%。</p>   <p>The group's operating profit for the six months to Sept. 30 fell 43% to 169.1 million euros ($185.64 million), in line with analyst expectations in a company-compiled poll.翻译:截至 9 月 30 日的六个月，该集团的营业利润下降了 43%，至 1.691 亿欧元（1.8564 亿美元），与公司编制的调查中分析师的预期一致。</p>   <p>It already reported a 22.2% drop in first-half sales. Out of a 100 million euro ($109.47 million) cost-cutting plan announced in October, it had so far achieved 25 million euros, the group said.翻译:该公司已报告上半年销售额下降 22.2%。该集团表示，在 10 月份宣布的 1 亿欧元（1.0947 亿美元）成本削减计划中，迄今为止已实现 2500 万欧元。</p>   <p>Charles de Riedmatten, fund manager at Myria AM, a Remy investor, said this was low and Remy could struggle to control its marketing costs.翻译:人头马投资者 Myria AM 的基金经理 Charles de Riedmatten 表示，这一比例较低，人头马可能难以控制其营销成本。</p>   <p>"For H2, I will be really cautious," he said, adding the U.S. market in particular remains difficult and its not clear when it will improve.翻译:“对于下半年，我会非常谨慎，”他表示，并补充说美国市场尤其仍然困难，而且还不清楚何时会有所改善。</p>   <p>Remy reiterated its full-year forecast, saying the U.S. would not see growth in sales before the next financial year.翻译:雷米重申了全年预测，称美国在下一财年之前不会出现销售额增长。</p>   <p>($1 = 0.9135 euros)翻译:（1 美元 = 0.9135 欧元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Dominique Vidalon in Paris and Emma Rumney in London, Editing by Charlotte Van Campenhut, Varun H K and Tomasz Janowski翻译:巴黎多米尼克·维达隆 (Dominique Vidalon) 和伦敦艾玛·拉姆尼 (Emma Rumney) 报道，夏洛特·范坎彭胡特 (Charlotte Van Campenhut)、瓦伦·香港 (Varun HK) 和托马斯·雅诺夫斯基 (Tomasz Janowski) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 08:35:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3LL4R6CLJJPBZJBM647UFDEQD4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/remy-cointreau-first-half-profits-fall-43-us-weighs-keeps-goals-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Dominique Vidalon, Emma Rumney]]></author>
            
                
                <category>REMY</category>
                
                <category>RESULTS/ (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：中国恒大寻求通过最后一搏债务计划避免清算]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/x1Un4BLp4DPSUue4O3jzAcJENxA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/N6SYACE4HVNN7JLTSD4D725HUE.jpg" alt="The company logo is seen on the headquarters of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen翻译:中国恒大集团深圳总部的公司标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The company logo is seen on the headquarters of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen翻译:中国恒大集团深圳总部的公司标志, Guangdong province, China September 26, 2021. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China Evergrande Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a>, the world's most indebted property developer, is seeking to avert a potentially imminent liquidation with a last-minute debt restructuring proposal, three people with direct knowledge of the matter said.翻译:三名直接了解情况的人士表示，全球负债最重的房地产开发商中国恒大集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）</a>正在寻求通过最后一刻的债务重组方案来避免可能迫在眉睫的清算。</p>   <p>The defaulted company has until a Hong Kong court <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-faces-winding-up-challenge-hong-kong-court-2023-10-29/">hearing</a> on Monday to present a "concrete" revised debt restructuring proposal for offshore creditors, a judge said last month after its <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/evergrande-proposes-offshore-creditors-get-30-equity-stake-subsidiaries-sources-2023-11-01/">original plan</a> had lapsed.翻译:上个月，在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/evergrande-proposes-offshore-creditors-get-30-equity-stake-subsidiaries-sources-2023-11-01/">原计划</a>失效后，一名法官表示，这家违约公司必须在周一香港法庭<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-faces-winding-up-challenge-hong-kong-court-2023-10-29/">听证会</a>之前向离岸债权人提交一份“具体的”修订后的债务重组方案。</p>   <p>But the sources, who declined to be named as the talks are private, told Reuters that creditors were <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/possible-evergrande-liquidation-order-what-happens-next-2023-11-30/">unlikely</a> to accept Evergrande's new proposal given low recovery prospects and growing concerns about the developer's future.翻译:但由于谈判是私下进行而不愿透露姓名的消息人士告诉路透社，鉴于复苏前景黯淡以及对开发商未来的担忧日益加剧，债权人<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/possible-evergrande-liquidation-order-what-happens-next-2023-11-30/">不太可能</a>接受恒大的新提议。</p>   <p>With more than $300 billion in liabilities, Evergrande exemplifies a crisis in China's property sector, which makes up one-quarter of the world's second-biggest economy. The authorities have scrambled to support the sector as the troubles of embattled developers roiled global markets.翻译:恒大集团的负债超过3000亿美元，是中国房地产业危机的典型例子，而中国房地产业占世界第二大经济体的四分之一。由于陷入困境的开发商的麻烦扰乱了全球市场，当局已争先恐后地支持该行业。</p>   <p>Guangzhou-based Evergrande, which defaulted on its offshore debt in late 2021, did not respond to a request for comment.翻译:总部位于广州的恒大集团于 2021 年底出现离岸债务违约，该公司没有回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Ahead of the hearing when the Hong Kong High Court will rule on a liquidation petition, Evergrande this week offered to swap some debt held by offshore creditors into equity in the company and two Hong Kong-listed units, and repay the rest with non-tradeable "certificates" backed by offshore assets, two sources said.翻译:在香港高等法院就清算申请作出裁决之前，恒大集团本周提出将境外债权人持有的部分债务转换为该公司和两家香港上市公司的股权，并以非流通股偿还剩余部分。两位消息人士称，这些“证书”由离岸资产支持。</p>   <p>The offshore assets include the developer's minority stakes in other companies and its receivables, one of the two sources said, and the certificates would be redeemed by Evergrande when it successfully disposes of the assets. The plan is not expected to require regulatory approval, as Chinese regulators have banned the developer from issuing new bonds, he added.翻译:两位消息人士之一表示，离岸资产包括开发商在其他公司的少数股权及其应收账款，恒大成功处置这些资产后将赎回这些凭证。他补充说，该计划预计不需要监管部门批准，因为中国监管机构已禁止开发商发行新债券。</p>   <p>The new proposal also offers creditors a 17.8% stake in Evergrande, in addition to an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/evergrande-proposes-offshore-creditors-get-30-equity-stake-subsidiaries-sources-2023-11-01/">October offer</a>, previously reported by Reuters, of 30% stakes in each of its two Hong Kong units - Evergrande Property Services Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">(6666.HK)</a> and Evergrande New Energy Vehicle Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0708.HK" target="_blank">(0708.HK)</a> - the person said.翻译:新提案还向债权人提出了恒大17.8%的股份，此外，据路透社此前报道，债权人在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/evergrande-proposes-offshore-creditors-get-30-equity-stake-subsidiaries-sources-2023-11-01/">10月份</a>提出了恒大物业服务集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">（6666.HK）</a>和恒大新城两个香港子公司各30%的股份。新能源汽车集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0708.HK" target="_blank">（0708.HK）</a> ——上述人士表示。</p>   <p>Many creditors were dissatisfied with the October terms as they implied a major haircut on investments, sources have said, forcing Evergrande to scramble to sweeten the deal in what could be its final attempt to avoid liquidation.</p>    <h 1="">LIQUIDATION CHALLENGES</h>  <p>The spectre of a messy collapse of Evergrande has been a major concern for global investors as the Chinese economy sputters, with property sales slowing and hundreds of thousands of unfinished homes across the country.翻译:随着中国经济陷入困境，房地产销售放缓，全国各地有数十万套未完工房屋，恒大集团混乱倒闭的担忧一直是全球投资者的主要担忧。</p>   <p>Chinese authorities have announced a string of measures to revive the sector destabilised by the debt woes of giants like Evergrande and Country Garden <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">(2007.HK)</a>.翻译:中国当局宣布了一系列措施，以重振因恒大和碧桂园<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">（2007.HK）</a>等巨头的债务危机而不稳定的行业。</p>   <p>Evergrande's debt revamp hopes were derailed in late September when the company said billionaire founder Hui Ka Yan was under <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shares-china-evergrande-suspended-chairman-under-police-watch-2023-09-28/">investigation</a> for unspecified "illegal crimes".翻译:恒大集团的债务重组希望在9月下旬落空，当时该公司表示亿万富翁创始人许家印因未具体说明的“非法犯罪”正在接受<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shares-china-evergrande-suspended-chairman-under-police-watch-2023-09-28/">调查</a>。</p>   <p>The developer was banned from issuing dollar bonds, a key part of the restructuring plan, and its flagship mainland unit was put under investigation by regulators.翻译:该开发商被禁止发行美元债券，这是重组计划的关键部分，其大陆旗舰子公司也受到监管机构的调查。</p>   <p>If the Hong Kong court orders Evergrande's liquidation, a provisional liquidator and then an official liquidator would be appointed to take control and arrange to sell the company's assets to repay its debts.翻译:如果香港法院下令恒大清算，将任命一名临时清算人，然后任命一名正式清算人来接管公司并安排出售公司资产以偿还债务。</p>   <p>In addition to shares of its two Hong Kong-listed units, this would include selling its onshore assets, which could face significant challenges, restructuring experts say.翻译:重组专家表示，除了出售其在香港上市的两家子公司的股票外，这还包括出售其境内资产，这可能面临重大挑战。</p>   <p>A lawyer for an ad hoc group of key offshore bondholders told the Hong Kong court last month that the restructuring plan could have a higher recovery rate for creditors than liquidation, in which they would get back less than 3%.翻译:一个由主要离岸债券持有人组成的特别小组的律师上个月向香港法院表示，重组计划对债权人的回收率可能高于清算，而清算时债权人的回收率将低于 3%。</p>   <p>Still, the group has nominated consultancy Alvarez &amp; Marsal as its preferred liquidator, two other sources said, as creditors anticipate a potential liquidation of Evergrande, whose liabilities and assets are largely in mainland China.翻译:另外两名消息人士称，尽管如此，该集团仍提名咨询公司 Alvarez &amp; Marsal 作为其首选清算人，因为债权人预计恒大可能会被清算，而恒大的负债和资产主要位于中国大陆。</p>   <p>Alvarez &amp; Marsal did not immediately respond to request for comment.翻译:Alvarez &amp; Marsal 没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Top Shine, an investor in Evergrande unit Fangchebao, filed the liquidation petition in June 2022 after it said the developer failed to honour an agreement to repurchase shares the investor had bought in the subsidiary.翻译:恒大旗下房车宝的投资者Top Shine于2022年6月提交了清算申请，此前该公司称该开发商未能履行回购其投资者所购买的子公司股份的协议。</p>    <span>Reporting by Clare Jim and Xie Yu in Hong Kong, Scott Murdoch in Sydney; Editing by Sumeet Chatterjee and William Mallard翻译:克莱尔·吉姆和谢宇在香港报道，斯科特·默多克在悉尼报道；编辑：Sumeet Chatterjee 和 William Mallard</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 08:28:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">VXGPWSZ4VBKA3FVE3FOZFFB7GQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-seeks-avoid-liquidation-with-last-ditch-debt-plan-sources-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Clare Jim, Scott Murdoch, Yu Xie]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/DEBT</category>
                
                <category>EVERGRANDE (EXCLUSIVE, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[台湾敦促老年人和年轻人因呼吸道疾病避免前往中国]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/WJ2b_viJkiZi-TD1io511ocd5L0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/O7UWNWGTAFPU3M2L4XGSZ3V74U.jpg" alt="People wait for their rides outside a children's hospital in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家儿童医院外等候乘车" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People wait for their rides outside a children's hospital in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家儿童医院外等候乘车, China November 27, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Taiwan's health ministry on Thursday urged the elderly, very young and those with poor immunity to avoid travel to China due to the recent increase in respiratory illnesses there, a move some experts said was ineffective to manage public health risks.翻译:台湾卫生部周四敦促老年人、幼儿和免疫力差的人避免前往中国，因为最近中国呼吸道疾病的增加，一些专家表示此举对于管理公共卫生风险无效。</p>   <p>The World Health Organization (WHO) last week requested China provide detailed information on the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/who-asks-china-details-respiratory-illness-outbreaks-2023-11-23/">spike</a>, which a WHO official said was not as high as before the COVID-19 pandemic and that no unusual or novel pathogens had been detected.翻译:世界卫生组织 (WHO) 上周要求中国提供有关<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/who-asks-china-details-respiratory-illness-outbreaks-2023-11-23/">病例激增</a>的详细信息，世界卫生组织官员表示，病例数没有 COVID-19 大流行之前那么高，并且没有发现异常或新型病原体。</p>   <p>Taiwan has been wary of disease outbreaks in its giant neighbour since the Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome (SARS) outbreak that started in China and killed nearly 800 people globally in 2002-2003.翻译:自2002年至2003年在中国爆发并导致全球近800人死亡的严重急性呼吸系统综合症（SARS）以来，台湾一直对其巨大邻国的疾病爆发保持警惕。</p>   <p>China, whose government claims democratically governed Taiwan as its own, initially tried to cover up that outbreak.翻译:中国政府声称对台湾实行民主治理，并称其为自己的领土，最初试图掩盖这一疫情。</p>   <p>In a statement released after a weekly Cabinet meeting, Taiwan's health ministry said that due to the rise in respiratory illnesses in China, the elderly, young children and other people with poor immunity are requested not to travel to mainland China, Hong Kong and Macau unless necessary.翻译:台湾卫生部在每周一次的内阁会议后发表的一份声明中表示，由于中国大陆呼吸道疾病的增加，请老年人、幼儿和其他免疫力较差的人不要前往中国大陆、香港和澳门，除非必要的。</p>   <p>If travel is necessary, then people should get flu and COVID vaccinations before going to China, it added.翻译:报告补充说，如果有必要旅行，那么人们应该在前往中国之前接种流感和新冠疫苗。</p>   <p>Shu-Ti Chiou, an epidemiologist at the Health &amp; Sustainable Development Foundation in Taipei, said the advisory would lead the public to mistakenly believe they would not contract respiratory illnesses as long as they did not go to China.翻译:台北健康与可持续发展基金会的流行病学家邱淑蒂表示，该建议将导致公众错误地认为，只要不前往中国，他们就不会感染呼吸道疾病。</p>   <p>Rajib Dasgupta, an epidemiologist and professor of community health at Jawaharlal Nehru University in New Delhi, also said "travel restrictions for respiratory infections are not an effective measure for interrupting transmission".翻译:新德里贾瓦哈拉尔尼赫鲁大学流行病学家兼社区卫生教授拉吉布·达斯古普塔也表示，“针对呼吸道感染的旅行限制并不是阻断传播的有效措施”。</p>   <p>Some public health researchers said the travel advisory was reasonable, saying Taiwan was also likely to experience a surge in respiratory illnesses in winter and following the lifting of pandemic restrictions. "They would be cautious not to hasten it by overseas travels," said Sung-il Cho, an epidemiologist at Seoul National University.翻译:一些公共卫生研究人员表示，这一旅行建议是合理的，并称台湾在冬季和大流行限制取消后也可能出现呼吸道疾病激增的情况。首尔国立大学流行病学家赵成日 (Sung-il Cho) 表示：“他们会谨慎行事，以免海外旅行加速疫情蔓延。”</p>   <p>China's Foreign Minister Wang Yi said on Wednesday that the rise in respiratory illnesses in China was a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-cluster-flu-cases-under-effective-control-foreign-minister-2023-11-29/">common issue</a> faced by all countries and that Chinese authorities have it under effective control.翻译:中国外交部长王毅周三表示，中国呼吸道疾病发病率上升是各国面临的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-cluster-flu-cases-under-effective-control-foreign-minister-2023-11-29/">共同问题</a>，中国当局已有效控制疫情。</p>   <p>China's Taiwan affairs office and authorities in Hong Kong and Macau did not immediately respond to requests for comment.翻译:中国台湾事务办公室以及香港和澳门当局没有立即回应置评请求。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ben Blanchard in Taipei and Andrew Silver in Shanghai; Additional reporting by Anne Marie Roantree and Farah Master in Hong Kong; Editing by Miral Fahmy翻译:Ben Blanchard 在台北和 Andrew Silver 在上海的报道； Anne Marie Roantree 和 Farah Master 在香港的补充报道；米拉尔·法赫米编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 08:15:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">HW4ATTXFHNPDHGXGZJUKB2EXVY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-urges-elderly-young-avoid-china-visits-due-respiratory-illnesses-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ben Blanchard, Andrew Silver]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HEALTH</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/TAIWAN (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[解说：恒大可能的清算令以及接下来会发生什么]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tqI1y-GgtnZnRcgS_8aGbwwWep8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/IJUVLQYLFRLNZJ4CUO2EXGW6DQ.jpg" alt="Partially removed company logo of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen翻译:深圳恒大集团公司标识部分拆除" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A partially removed company logo of China Evergrande Group is seen on the facade of its headquarters in Shenzhen, Guangdong province, China January 10, 2022. REUTERS/David Kirton/File Photo翻译:2022 年 1 月 10 日，在中国广东省深圳市总部的正面，可以看到部分被移除的中国恒大集团公司标志。 REUTERS/David Kirton/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China Evergrande Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a>, the world's most indebted property developer, is seeking to avert a potentially imminent liquidation with a last-minute debt <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-seeks-avoid-liquidation-with-last-ditch-debt-plan-sources-2023-11-30/">restructuring</a> proposal, three people with direct knowledge of the matter said.翻译:三名直接了解情况的人士表示，全球负债最重的房地产开发商中国恒大集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）</a>正在寻求通过最后一刻的债务<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-seeks-avoid-liquidation-with-last-ditch-debt-plan-sources-2023-11-30/">重组</a>方案来避免可能迫在眉睫的清算。</p>   <p>The defaulted company faces a Monday deadline to present a "concrete" revised debt restructuring proposal for offshore creditors. But the sources told Reuters that creditors were unlikely to accept Evergrande's new proposal given low recovery prospects and growing concerns about the developer's future.</p>    <h 1="">WHAT HAPPENS IF THE COURT ORDERS EVERGRANDE LIQUIDATED?</h>  <p>If a liquidation order is issued, a provisional liquidator and then an official liquidator will be appointed to take control and prepare to sell the developer's assets to repay its debts.翻译:如果发出清算令，将任命临时清算人，然后任命正式清算人来接管并准备出售开发商的资产以偿还债务。</p>   <p>The liquidators could propose a new debt restructuring plan to creditors if they determine the company had enough assets or if a white knight investor appeared. They would also investigate the company's affairs and could refer any suspected misconduct by directors to Hong Kong prosecutors.翻译:如果清算人确定公司拥有足够的资产或者白衣骑士投资者出现，他们可以向债权人提出新的债务重组计划。他们还将调查公司的事务，并可以将董事的任何可疑不当行为提交给香港检察官。</p>   <p>Evergrande could appeal a liquidation order, but the liquidation process would proceed pending appeal.翻译:恒大可以对清算令提出上诉，但清算程序将在上诉期间继续进行。</p>   <p>It is unclear if Evergrande shares would be suspended from trading after a liquidation order, but listing rules require a company to demonstrate a business structure with sufficient operations and asset values.翻译:目前尚不清楚恒大股票在清算令后是否会停牌，但上市规则要求公司展示具有足够运营和资产价值的业务结构。</p>   <p>China Oceanwide Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0715.HK" target="_blank">(0715.HK)</a> suspended its shares in September after a Bermuda Court issued a liquidation order.</p>    <h 1="">HOW MUCH DEBT CAN CREDITORS RECOVER AND WHAT ARE THE MAIN CHALLENGES?</h>  <p>Evergrande cited a Deloitte analysis during a Hong Kong court hearing in July that <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-court-hold-hearings-china-evergrande-restructuring-plan-sept-2023-07-24/">estimated</a> a recovery rate from a restructuring it was then proposing of about 22.5%, compared with 3.4% if the developer were liquidated.翻译:恒大集团在 7 月份的香港法庭听证会上引用了德勤的分析， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-court-hold-hearings-china-evergrande-restructuring-plan-sept-2023-07-24/">估计</a>其当时提议的重组的回收率约为 22.5%，而如果开发商被清算，回收率仅为 3.4%。</p>   <p>However, after Evergrande said in September its flagship unit and its chairman Hui Ka Yan were being <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shares-china-evergrande-suspended-chairman-under-police-watch-2023-09-28/">investigated</a> by the authorities for unspecified "illegal crimes", creditors now expect a recovery rate of less than 3%.翻译:然而，在恒大9月表示其旗舰子公司及其董事长许家印因涉嫌“非法犯罪”而接受当局<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shares-china-evergrande-suspended-chairman-under-police-watch-2023-09-28/">调查</a>后，债权人目前预计追偿率将低于3%。</p>   <p>Evergrande's main offshore assets are its two listed units in Hong Kong - Evergrande Property Services Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">(6666.HK)</a> and Evergrande New Energy Vehicle Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0708.HK" target="_blank">(0708.HK)</a> - as most of its other assets have been sold or seized by creditors.翻译:恒大的主要境外资产是其在香港的两个上市单位——恒大物业服务集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">（6666.HK）</a>和恒大新能源汽车集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0708.HK" target="_blank">（0708.HK）</a> ——而其大部分其他资产已被债权人出售或扣押。</p>   <p>A liquidator could sell Evergrande's holdings in the two units, although it might be difficult to find buyers.翻译:清算人可以出售恒大在这两个单位中的持股，尽管可能很难找到买家。</p>   <p>After a liquidation, the liquidator could take control of Evergrande's subsidiaries in mainland China by replacing their legal representatives, a process that could take months or years.翻译:清算后，清算人可以通过更换法定代表人来控制恒大在中国大陆的子公司，这一过程可能需要数月甚至数年的时间。</p>   <p>Insolvency experts said it would be a challenge for the liquidator to change the representatives as Guangzhou, where Evergrande is based, is not one of the three Chinese cities that mutually recognise liquidation orders with Hong Kong.翻译:破产专家表示，由于恒大总部所在地广州不是与香港相互承认清算令的三个中国城市之一，因此清算人更换代表将是一个挑战。</p>   <p>Even if a liquidator were to take possession of the units that have onshore projects, many of these have already been taken over by creditors, have little value left or are even in negative equity because of falling property prices.翻译:即使清算人要接管拥有陆上项目的单位，但其中许多单位已经被债权人接管，价值所剩无几，甚至因房价下跌而出现负资产。</p>   <p>So far over 53 billion yuan ($7.2 billion) of Evergrande's assets have been seized or frozen across China, local media have reported, citing court records.</p>    <h 1="">HOW SIGNIFICANT WOULD LIQUIDATION BE FOR CHINA'S PROPERTY MARKET?</h>  <p>While a winding-up of the developer with $240 billion of assets would send shockwaves through already fragile capital markets, experts said it would not offer a blueprint on how liquidation might unfold for other embattled developers.翻译:虽然这家拥有 2400 亿美元资产的开发商的清算将对本已脆弱的资本市场产生冲击波，但专家表示，这不会为其他陷入困境的开发商提供清算可能如何展开的蓝图。</p>   <p>Given the sheer size of Evergrande's projects and debt, the process would involve many authorities and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/evergrande-crisis-tests-beijings-fallout-management-creditor-jitters-mount-2023-10-05/">political considerations</a>.翻译:鉴于恒大项目和债务规模庞大，这一过程将涉及许多当局和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/evergrande-crisis-tests-beijings-fallout-management-creditor-jitters-mount-2023-10-05/">政治考虑</a>。</p>   <p>Completing ongoing home construction projects will be a top priority for the company and the sector, even though a liquidation of the property giant could make homebuyers wary of developments by private companies.翻译:完成正在进行的房屋建设项目将是该公司和该行业的首要任务，尽管这家房地产巨头的清算可能会让购房者对私营公司的开发项目保持警惕。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.3170 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.3170 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Clare Jim in Hong Kong and Scott Murdoch in Sydney; Editing by Sumeet Chatterjee, Lincoln Feast and William Mallard翻译:克莱尔·吉姆 (Clare Jim) 在香港的报道和斯科特·默多克 (Scott Murdoch) 在悉尼的报道；编辑：Sumeet Chatterjee、Lincoln Feast 和 William Mallard</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 08:06:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">PEPKSTLBSJOE3ISZRRT2ZLYP3U</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/possible-evergrande-liquidation-order-what-happens-next-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Clare Jim, Scott Murdoch]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/DEBT</category>
                
                <category>EVERGRANDE (EXPLAINER, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着选举临近，台湾报告中国有更多军事活动]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Otpp4Ck8EAe6MxdU--W8bx9rDOs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PYYHGKCUDRN7DLKK4GURFSSSAE.jpg" alt="Illustration shows Chinese and Taiwanese flags翻译:插图显示中国和台湾国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Navy miniature is seen in front of displayed Chinese and Taiwanese flags in this illustration taken, April 11, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File photo翻译:在这张摄于 2023 年 4 月 11 日的插图中，可以看到在展示的中国和台湾国旗前有一个海军微型模型。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Taiwan again reported Chinese warplanes and warships around the island on Thursday, including aircraft crossing the sensitive median line of the Taiwan Strait, as Beijing keeps up its military activities ahead of Taiwan's January election.翻译:周四，台湾再次报告中国战机和军舰在台湾周围活动，其中包括飞机穿越台湾海峡敏感的中线，而北京在台湾一月份大选之前继续其军事活动。</p>   <p>Democratically governed Taiwan, which China claims as its own territory, has complained for the past four years of regular Chinese military patrols and drills near the island.翻译:中国声称台湾是民主统治的台湾，过去四年来，台湾一直抱怨中国在台湾附近定期进行军事巡逻和演习。</p>   <p>Taiwan holds presidential and parliamentary polls on Jan. 13 and campaigning has already kicked into high gear. Relations with China are a major point of contention.翻译:台湾将于1月13日举行总统和立法院选举，竞选活动已经进入紧锣密鼓的阶段。与中国的关系是一个主要争论点。</p>   <p>Taiwan's defence ministry said that starting Thursday morning it had detected J-10 and J-16 fighters as well as ship-borne helicopters operating off central Taiwan and to the island's southwest.翻译:台湾国防部表示，从周四早上开始，它发现了在台湾中部和台湾西南部附近执行任务的歼10和歼16战斗机以及舰载直升机。</p>   <p>Eleven of those aircraft crossed the Taiwan Strait's median line, or areas close by, working with Chinese warships to carry out "joint combat readiness patrols", the ministry added.翻译:国防部补充说，其中 11 架飞机飞越台湾海峡中线或附近地区，与中国军舰一起进行“联合战备巡逻”。</p>   <p>The strait's median line once served as an unofficial barrier between the two sides, but Chinese planes now regularly fly over it.翻译:海峡中线曾经是两岸之间的非正式屏障，但中国飞机​​现在经常飞越该海峡。</p>   <p>Taiwan sent its own forces to monitor, the ministry said.翻译:国防部表示，台湾派出自己的部队进行监视。</p>   <p>This month, Taiwan has reported at least three other similar large-scale sorties by China's air force, which Beijing has not commented on.翻译:本月，台湾报告称中国空军至少进行了另外三次类似的大规模飞行，北京方面尚未对此发表评论。</p>   <p>China says its activities near Taiwan are aimed at preventing "collusion" between Taiwan separatists and the United States, and protecting China's territorial integrity.翻译:中国表示，其在台湾附近的活动旨在防止台湾分裂分子与美国“勾结”，保护中国的领土完整。</p>   <p>Taiwan's government, which has repeatedly offered talks with China, rejects Beijing's sovereignty claims and says only the island's people can decide their future.翻译:台湾政府多次提出与中国进行谈判，拒绝北京的主权主张，并表示只有台湾人民才能决定他们的未来。</p>   <p>The ruling Democratic Progressive Party's Lai Ching-te, whom Beijing has denounced as a separatist, is the frontrunner to be Taiwan's next president, according to opinion polls.翻译:民意调查显示，执政党民进党的赖清德是台湾下届总统的热门人选，北京方面谴责赖清德为分裂分子。</p>   <p>Taiwan's main opposition party, the Kuomintang, traditionally supports close ties with Beijing, and has pledged to re-open dialogue with China if it wins the election.翻译:台湾主要反对党国民党传统上支持与北京的密切关系，并承诺如果赢得选举将与中国重新开启对话。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ben Blanchard; Editing by Sonali Paul and Gerry Doyle翻译:本·布兰查德报道；索纳利·保罗和格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 07:55:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RHBC6BTV3NMLVKD75WLTXPCQ6Y</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-reports-more-chinese-military-activity-election-nears-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>TAIWAN</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[持有 4.3 万亿美元的公共投资者对中国的看法有所下降，但净额为零]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>No funds surveyed positive on China outlook - OMFIF</li>  <li>India top pick amongst emerging markets</li>  <li>Investors concerned about higher-for-longer rates</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>调查显示，没有基金对中国前景持乐观态度 - OMFIF</li><li>印度是新兴市场中的首选</li><li>投资者担心长期较高的利率</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/2cWg61CS8GO_1IMXrXFCO9NhwLU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/J6OZSX7ITBISVHSH6RJN3R2CIU.jpg" alt="Beijing Stock Exchange翻译:北京证券交易所" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view of the new Beijing Stock Exchange翻译:北京证券交易所 in Beijing, China, November 15, 2021. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang//File Photo翻译:2021 年 11 月 15 日，中国北京新北京证券交易所一景。路透社/Tingshu Wang//资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Qukr18jkbMyPNsXVA6zUPaRhXWU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4JHIH6B76JIODBXUCMW2IQPT2I.jpg" alt="German share price index DAX graph is pictured at the stock exchange in Frankfurt翻译:德国股价指数 DAX 图为法兰克福证券交易所" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The German share price index DAX graph is pictured at the stock exchange in Frankfurt翻译:德国股价指数 DAX 图为法兰克福证券交易所, Germany, November 28, 2023.    REUTERS/Staff/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>Public pension and sovereign wealth funds managing $4.3 trillion in assets are pessimistic about investing in China, but keen to cut net emissions of their portfolios, according to a survey by the Official Monetary and Financial Institutions Forum (OMFIF).翻译:官方货币和金融机构论坛 (OMFIF) 的一项调查显示，管理着 4.3 万亿美元资产的公共养老金和主权财富基金对投资中国持悲观态度，但热衷于削减其投资组合的净排放量。</p>   <p>The survey of 22 funds by OMFIF, a think tank for central banking, economic policy and public investment, also showed that 62% of the 50 largest pension funds and nearly half of the largest sovereign wealth funds suffered losses last year amid high inflation and historically rapid global rate hikes.翻译:央行、经济政策和公共投资智库 OMFIF 对 22 家基金的调查还显示，去年，由于高通胀和历史性的高通胀，全球 50 家最大养老基金中有 62% 以及近一半最大主权财富基金遭受损失。全球加息迅速。</p>   <p>OMFIF outlined a dark mood among the funds, with more than half expecting a global economic recession in the next 12 months. None reported a positive outlook for China's economy, citing the regulatory environment and geopolitics among primary factors dissuading them from investing.翻译:OMFIF 概述了基金中的悲观情绪，超过一半的基金预计未来 12 个月全球经济将陷入衰退。没有人对中国经济前景表示乐观，称监管环境和地缘政治是阻碍他们投资的主要因素。</p>   <p>The world's second-largest economy is struggling to boost growth amid a debt-laden real estate sector and consumers who are looking to save more due to the economic uncertainty.翻译:在债务负担沉重的房地产行业以及由于经济不确定性而希望增加储蓄的消费者中，世界第二大经济体正在努力促进增长。</p>   <p>"India is the most attractive emerging market among respondents, while the majority identified regulation and geopolitics as hurdles to investing in China," authors of the report launched on Thursday found.翻译:周四发布的报告作者发现，“印度是受访者中最具吸引力的新兴市场，而大多数人认为监管和地缘政治是投资中国的障碍。”</p>   <p>The funds remain worried about interest rates, the survey showed, with 63% citing them as the top factor in their investment strategies over the coming decade, double the share from last year's survey.翻译:调查显示，这些基金仍然担心利率，63% 的基金将利率视为未来十年投资策略的首要因素，这一比例是去年调查的两倍。</p>   <p>"(Investors) are now focused on how to deal with a macroeconomic environment that is stuck in a higher-for-longer interest rate cycle," the report said.翻译:报告称：“（投资者）现在关注的焦点是如何应对陷入较高利率周期和较长利率周期的宏观经济环境。”</p>   <p>While 73% of the funds said they have a pledge to achieve net zero emissions in their portfolio by 2050, and more than a third planning to increase their allocation to green bonds and green real assets in the next 12-24 months, any investments still need to make money for the funds.翻译:虽然 73% 的基金表示，他们承诺到 2050 年在其投资组合中实现净零排放，超过三分之一的基金计划在未来 12-24 个月内增加对绿色债券和绿色实物资产的配置，但任何投资仍然需要为资金赚钱。</p>   <p>"We're looking for deals where there is a meeting of ESG and returns, and we don’t accept lower returns just to comply with ESG targets," David Morley, managing director and head of Europe at Caisse de Depot et Placement du Québec, said in the survey.翻译:Caisse de Depot et Placement du Québec 董事总经理兼欧洲主管 David Morley 表示：“我们正在寻找能够兼顾 ESG 和回报的交易，我们不会仅仅为了遵守 ESG 目标而接受较低的回报。” ，调查中表示。</p>   <p>Overall, sovereign funds fared better than their public pension peers, OMFIF added. Aggregate assets under management of the top 50 sovereign funds edged 2.3% higher to $11.6 trillion from $11.3 trillion a year before, helped by outsized gains in Middle East funds as they benefit from the surge in commodity prices.翻译:OMFIF 补充说，总体而言，主权基金的表现优于公共养老金同行。前 50 名主权基金管理的总资产从一年前的 11.3 万亿美元小幅增长 2.3%，达到 11.6 万亿美元，这得益于中东基金受益于大宗商品价格飙升带来的巨额收益。</p>   <p>The UAE's Abu Dhabi Investment Authority and Saudi Public Investment Corporation grew by 13.8% and 12.9% respectively, gaining over $200 billion between them.翻译:阿联酋阿布扎比投资局和沙特公共投资公司分别增长13.8%和12.9%，净收益超过2000亿美元。</p>    <span>Reporting By Libby George; Editing by Sharon Singleton翻译:利比·乔治报道；莎朗·辛格尔顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 07:54:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TQMIBO4LJZO37OXVLJF7GF7S3E</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/public-investors-with-43-trln-are-down-china-net-zero-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Libby George, Bansari Kamdar]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>INVESTMENT/OMFIF (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[马来西亚森那美 (Sime Darby) 寻求将汽车零售业务扩展到印度和印度尼西亚 - 首席执行官]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ROYD8l9wV0xwGornvhiACbxGPs4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/I33POPK2NVOOTNFRFSK7K6DHE4.jpg" alt="A logo of Sime Darby is seen at its car showroom in Petaling Jaya翻译:森那美 (Sime Darby) 的标志出现在八打灵再也的汽车陈列室中" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A logo of Sime Darby is seen at its car showroom in Petaling Jaya翻译:森那美 (Sime Darby) 的标志出现在八打灵再也的汽车陈列室中, Malaysia November 30, 2023. REUTERS/Hasnoor Hussain/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Sime Darby <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SIME.KL" target="_blank">(SIME.KL)</a>, Malaysia's industrial and automotive conglomerate, is looking to set up a luxury car retail business in India and expand in Indonesia to tap into the growth potential of both economies, its top executive told Reuters.翻译:马来西亚工业和汽车集团森那美<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SIME.KL" target="_blank">(SIME.KL)</a>首席执行官告诉路透社，该公司正寻求在印度建立豪华汽车零售业务，并在印度尼西亚扩张，以挖掘两国经济的增长潜力。</p>   <p>"We cannot ignore India," Group Chief Executive Officer Jeffri Salim Davidson told Reuters.翻译:“我们不能忽视印度，”集团首席执行官杰弗里·萨利姆·戴维森告诉路透社。</p>   <p>"It's just something too big, you cannot ignore. So we're looking for opportunities in India to see whether we can do something with a local partner and start a car retail business there," he added. India, the world's most populous country, is its fifth-largest economy.翻译:“这件事太大了，你无法忽视。因此，我们正在印度寻找机会，看看我们是否可以与当地合作伙伴合作，在那里开展汽车零售业务，”他补充道。印度是世界上人口最多的国家，也是第五大经济体。</p>   <p>Jeffri said Sime Darby also plans to expand in Indonesia, Southeast Asia's largest economy, following a joint venture with a local firm to sell BMW cars in Jakarta and Medan.翻译:杰弗里表示，森那美还计划在东南亚最大经济体印度尼西亚扩张，此前与当地一家公司成立合资企业，在雅加达和棉兰销售宝马汽车。</p>   <p>Sime Darby, which derives 35% of its revenue from China, sees demand for luxury cars there remaining strong despite slowing economic growth. "Chinese people have money, they still buy cars," Jeffri said. "The problem in China is not the demand problem, it's a supply problem."翻译:森那美 35% 的收入来自中国，该公司认为，尽管经济增长放缓，但中国对豪华车的需求仍然强劲。 “中国人有钱，他们仍然买汽车，”杰弗里说。 “中国的问题不是需求问题，而是供应问题。”</p>   <p>Jeffri said car makers in China ramped up production in the hopes of gaining market share post-pandemic, creating a supply imbalance which prompted manufacturers to cut prices, squeezing the profit margins of retail distributors.翻译:杰弗里表示，中国的汽车制造商提高产量，希望在疫情后获得市场份额，造成供应失衡，促使制造商降价，挤压零售分销商的利润率。</p>   <p>Sime Darby was founded in 1910 and is one of Malaysia's oldest conglomerates with businesses spanning plantations to manufacturing. It currently has operations in 17 countries.翻译:森那美 (Sime Darby) 成立于 1910 年，是马来西亚历史最悠久的企业集团之一，业务涵盖种植园和制造业。目前该公司在 17 个国家开展业务。</p>   <p>It spun off its palm oil and property businesses in 2017, and had divested other businesses including Ramsay Sime Darby Health Care which was sold off <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/malaysias-sime-darby-sell-stake-asia-jv-12-bln-2023-11-10/">this month</a>.翻译:该公司于 2017 年剥离了棕榈油和房地产业务，并剥离了其他业务，包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/malaysias-sime-darby-sell-stake-asia-jv-12-bln-2023-11-10/">本月</a>被出售的 Ramsay Sime Darby Health Care。</p>   <p>Sime Darby now focuses on industrial and motor businesses, including assembling Porsche cars in Malaysia and distributing BYD electric vehicles in Malaysia and Singapore.翻译:森那美现在专注于工业和汽车业务，包括在马来西亚组装保时捷汽车以及在马来西亚和新加坡分销比亚迪电动汽车。</p>   <p>In August, it announced <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/malaysias-permodalan-nasional-weighs-215-bln-automotive-merger-ev-push-sources-2023-08-24/">the acquisition</a> of a 61.2% stake in Malaysian automotive-to-manufacturing company UMW Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/UMWS.KL" target="_blank">(UMWS.KL)</a> - which assembles Toyota cars in Malaysia and owns a stake in local car maker Perodua - for 3.57 billion ringgit ($767.41 million).翻译:8月，它宣布以35.7亿林吉特（767.41美元） <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/malaysias-permodalan-nasional-weighs-215-bln-automotive-merger-ev-push-sources-2023-08-24/">收购</a>马来西亚汽车制造公司UMW Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/UMWS.KL" target="_blank">（UMWS.KL）</a> 61.2％的股份，该公司在马来西亚组装丰田汽车，并拥有当地汽车制造商Perodua的股份。百万）。</p>   <p>Jeffri said the deal will make Sime Darby the biggest automotive player in Malaysia, capturing over 50% of the country's automotive market.翻译:Jeffri表示，这笔交易将使森那美成为马来西亚最大的汽车公司，占领该国超过50%的汽车市场。</p>   <p>"We very much play largely in the luxury segment," he said. "By doing this, we suddenly play in the mass market... so suddenly, we're all the way through the value chain."翻译:“我们主要涉足奢侈品领域，”他说。 “通过这样做，我们突然进入了大众市场......突然之间，我们就一路贯穿了价值链。”</p>   <p>($1 = 4.6520 ringgit)翻译:(1 美元 = 4.6520 林吉特)</p>    <span>Reporting by Rozanna Latiff in Kuala Lumpur and Yantoultra Ngui in Singapore; editing by Miral Fahmy翻译:Rozanna Latiff 在吉隆坡和 Yantoultra Ngui 在新加坡的报道；米拉尔·法赫米 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 07:46:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">WGSH3QRJCZN55AKR6A3MUJNOYQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/malaysias-sime-darby-seeks-expand-car-retail-business-into-india-indonesia-ceo-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Rozanna Latiff, Yantoultra Ngui]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SIME DARBY</category>
                
                <category>MALAYSIA/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着美国利率押注的转变，投资者看好大多数亚洲货币]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Bullish bets on most Asian FX prevail</li>  <li>Rupee and ringgit most shorted currency</li>  <li>Long bets on Taiwan dollar highest since Feb. 9</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>大多数亚洲货币的看涨押注占上风</li><li>卢比和林吉特最被做空的货币</li><li>新台币多头押注创2月9日以来新高</li></ul>     <p>Investors turned bullish on most emerging Asian currencies, as prospects of a potential end to U.S. interest rate hikes led to weakness in the greenback and triggered a rush into riskier assets in the region, a Reuters poll showed on Thursday.翻译:路透周四的一项民意调查显示，由于美国可能结束加息的前景导致美元走软，并引发投资者纷纷涌入该地区风险较高的资产，投资者转而看好大多数亚洲新兴货币。</p>   <p>Bullish bets on South Korean won , Taiwanese dollar , and Philippine peso were at their highest since Feb. 9, while long positions on the Singapore dollar and Indonesian rupiah stood at a four month high, the fortnightly survey of 12 respondents showed.翻译:对 12 名受访者进行的每两周一次调查显示，韩元、新台币和菲律宾比索的看涨押注达到 2 月 9 日以来的最高水平，而新加坡元和印尼卢比的多头头寸则达到四个月高位。</p>   <p>Market participants are betting on prolonged weakness in the U.S. dollar, taking cues from a spate of economic data that reinforced optimism that the U.S. Federal Reserve is probably done raising interest rates this cycle, with markets even anticipating a cut in mid-2024.翻译:市场参与者押注美元将长期疲软，从一系列经济数据中得到线索，这些数据增强了美联储可能在本周期加息的乐观情绪，市场甚至预计 2024 年中期降息。</p>   <p>The dollar index , which measures the U.S. currency against six rivals, has lost nearly 0.6% so far in November, helping emerging Asian currencies recover some ground.翻译:衡量美元兑六种货币的美元指数11月份迄今已下跌近0.6%，帮助亚洲新兴货币收复部分失地。</p>   <p>Poon Panichpibool, a markets strategist with Krung Thai Bank, however, said there is still a possibility of a rebound in the dollar depending on risk of data in the U.S. coming in stronger than expected.翻译:不过，泰京银行市场策略师Poon Panichpibool表示，美元仍有反弹的可能性，具体取决于美国数据强于预期的风险。</p>   <p>"The dollar could edge higher in the third and fourth quarter of 2024, when markets would start pricing in political risks arising from a presidential election in the U.S., though, dollar weakness could prolong until the third quarter of 2024," Panichpibool said.翻译:Panichpibool表示：“美元可能在2024年第三和第四季度小幅走高，届时市场将开始消化美国总统选举带来的政治风险，但美元疲软可能会持续到2024年第三季度。”</p>   <p>Back in Asia, the Taiwan dollar has strengthened over 3.5% so far in November, snapping a seven-month losing streak. The unit is set log its best month in a year.翻译:回到亚洲，新台币 11 月份迄今已升值 3.5% 以上，结束了连续 7 个月的下跌。该单位创下了一年中最好的月份。</p>   <p>Increased political uncertainty in Taiwan has led to volatility in the local currency, with two main opposition parties <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-opposition-parties-name-vp-candidates-after-unity-talks-collapse-2023-11-24/">naming their vice presidential</a> candidates after talks about running a joint ticket to take on the ruling party failed.翻译:台湾政治不确定性的增加导致当地货币波动，两个主要反对党在联合竞选对抗执政党的谈判失败后<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-opposition-parties-name-vp-candidates-after-unity-talks-collapse-2023-11-24/">提名了副总统</a>候选人。</p>   <p>The Korean won, too, has performed considerably well, adding over 4% in value. The unit is set log its best month since last November.翻译:韩元也表现相当出色，升值超过 4%。该单位创下自去年 11 月以来最好的月份。</p>   <p>Investors, however, remained bearish for the Indian rupee , Chinese yuan , and the Malaysian ringgit despite an improvement in sentiment.翻译:然而，尽管市场情绪有所改善，但投资者仍看跌印度卢比、人民币和马来西亚林吉特。</p>   <p>"I think people, including myself, are not confident about the economical recovery in China, though I still make a call that China's economy has already passed the worst point but remains full of uncertainty going forward," Panichpibool said.翻译:帕尼奇皮布尔表示：“我认为，包括我自己在内的人们对中国经济复苏并没有信心，尽管我仍然认为中国经济已经度过了最糟糕的时期，但未来仍然充满不确定性。”</p>   <p>Investors were most bearish on the Malaysian ringgit among the pack. Confidence in the local unit has faltered lately, amid lingering uncertainty around demand for palm oil and other commodities.翻译:其中，投资者最看跌马来西亚林吉特。由于棕榈油和其他大宗商品需求的不确定性挥之不去，人们对当地部门的信心最近动摇了。</p>   <p>The Asian currency positioning poll is focused on what analysts and fund managers believe are the current market positions in nine Asian emerging market currencies: the Chinese yuan, South Korean won, Singapore dollar, Indonesian rupiah, Taiwan dollar, Indian rupee, Philippine peso, Malaysian ringgit and the Thai baht.翻译:亚洲货币头寸调查的重点是分析师和基金经理认为的九种亚洲新兴市场货币当前的市场头寸：人民币、韩元、新加坡元、印尼卢比、新台币、印度卢比、菲律宾比索、马来西亚比索林吉特和泰铢。</p>   <p>The poll uses estimates of net long or short positions on a scale of minus 3 to plus 3. A score of plus 3 indicates the market is significantly long U.S. dollars.翻译:该调查使用净多头或空头头寸的估计值，范围为负3到正3。正3的分数表明市场明显多头美元。</p>   <p>The figures include positions held through non-deliverable forwards (NDFs).翻译:这些数字包括通过无本金交割远期合约（NDF）持有的头寸。</p>   <p>The survey findings are provided below (positions in U.S. dollar versus each currency):翻译:调查结果如下（美元兑每种货币的头寸）：</p>       <span>Reporting by Roushni Nair in Bengaluru; Editing by Varun H K翻译:鲁什尼·奈尔 (Roushni Nair) 班加罗尔报道；编辑：Varun HK</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:41:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">S5ABPKMOTZNURG5TCJWL3M5MG4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/investors-bullish-most-asian-fx-us-interest-rate-bets-shift-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Roushni Nair]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ASIA</category>
                
                <category>FOREX/EMERGING (POLL)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美军飞机在日本海域坠毁 至少一人死亡]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/yLaL8A1RQN54M5EZm_33ly9oqc8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CA573QTUTVNPFD7FSAEC2RQQHM.jpg" alt="Handout photo shows a floating object believed belonging to the U.S. military aircraft MV-22 Osprey that crashed into the sea is seen off Yakushima Island, Japan翻译:分发的照片显示，日本屋久岛附近有一个漂浮物，据信属于坠入海中的美国军用飞机 MV-22“鱼鹰”" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Collected object looks-like a life raft believed belonging to the U.S. military aircraft MV-22 Osprey that crashed into the sea off Yakushima Island, Kagoshima prefecture, western Japan, is seen through a live-camera screen recorded by Japan Coast Guard vessel Takachiho, November 29, 2023, in this handout photo taken by Japan Coast Guard and provided by Japan Coast Guard. 10th Regional Coast Guard Headquarters - Japan Coast Guard/Handout via REUTERS翻译:通过日本海岸警卫队船只高千穗号记录的实时摄像机屏幕可以看到，收集到的物体看起来像是救生筏，据信属于坠入日本西部鹿儿岛县屋久岛附近海域的美国军用飞机 MV-22“鱼鹰”， 2023 年 11 月 29 日，日本海上保安厅拍摄并提供的这张讲义照片中。第 10 地区海岸警卫队总部 - 日本海岸警卫队/路透社讲义</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Nx3WA5N4bU6rDrsoUEHMrEzEzi8=/1440x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BPRNHWYZINOK3FHHEZKDGLGEDM.jpg" alt="Handout photo shows a wreck believed to belong to the U.S. military aircraft MV-22 Osprey that crashed into the sea off Yakushima Island, Japan翻译:分发的照片显示了坠入日本屋久岛附近海域的据信属于美国军用飞机 MV-22 Osprey 的残骸" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A wreck believed to belong to the U.S. military aircraft MV-22 Osprey that crashed into the sea off Yakushima Island, Kagoshima prefecture, western Japan November 29, 2023, in this handout photo taken by Japan Coast Guard airplane and provided by Japan Coast Guard. 10th Regional Coast Guard Headquarters - Japan Coast Guard/Handout via REUTERS翻译:这张由日本海岸警卫队飞机拍摄并由日本海岸警卫队提供的宣传照片中，一架据信属于美国军用飞机 MV-22 鱼鹰的残骸于 2023 年 11 月 29 日在日本西部鹿儿岛县屋久岛附近海域坠毁。第 10 地区海岸警卫队总部 - 日本海岸警卫队/路透社讲义</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/diynO-VjCqSKbzHVKrXBeurOF0o=/1152x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7RDD4OHA3VI3LMZWNTBOGUBALI.jpg" alt="Handout photo shows a floating object believed to belong to the U.S. military aircraft MV-22 Osprey that crashed into the sea is seen off Yakushima Island, Japan翻译:讲义照片显示，在日本屋久岛附近看到一个坠入海中的漂浮物体，据信属于美国军用飞机 MV-22“鱼鹰”" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A looking-like life raft floating object believed to belong to the U.S. military aircraft MV-22 Osprey that crashed into the sea is seen off Yakushima Island, Kagoshima prefecture, western Japan November 29, 2023, in this handout photo taken by Japan Coast Guard airplane and provided by Japan Coast Guard. 10th Regional Coast Guard Headquarters - Japan Coast Guard/Handout via REUTERS翻译:2023 年 11 月 29 日，在日本海岸警卫队拍摄的这张宣传照片中，日本西部鹿儿岛县屋久岛附近出现了一个看起来像救生筏的漂浮物，据信属于坠入海中的美军飞机 MV-22 Osprey飞机并由日本海上保安厅提供。第 10 地区海岸警卫队总部 - 日本海岸警卫队/路透社讲义</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/M1iWXcuQL1m94Jj243irS3dW_kc=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VB2J5F22D5I4TMKYZUM646TODY.jpg" alt="Japan Coast Guard conducts search and rescue operation at the site where a U.S. military aircraft MV-22 Osprey crashed into the sea off Yakushima Island, Japan翻译:日本海上保安厅在日本屋久岛附近海域美军MV-22“鱼鹰”坠毁现场开展搜救行动" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Japan Coast Guard vessel and a helicopter conduct search and rescue operation at the site where a U.S. military aircraft MV-22 Osprey crashed into the sea off Yakushima Island, Kagoshima prefecture, western Japan November 29, 2023, in this photo taken by Kyodo. Mandatory credit Kyodo via REUTERS翻译:2023 年 11 月 29 日，共同社拍摄的这张照片中，一艘日本海上保安厅船只和一架直升机在日本西部鹿儿岛县屋久岛附近一架美军飞机 MV-22“鱼鹰”坠入海域的现场进行搜救。强制性信用共同社（路透社）</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UkHNn-HizlhO-2HuUpQPd-p5gx4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/32WQE6UQDZLTDMQDPZXTHD2NRQ.jpg" alt="A Japan Coast Guard vessel conducts search and rescue operation at the site where a U.S. military aircraft MV-22 Osprey crashed into the sea off Yakushima Island, Japan翻译:日本海岸警卫队船只在日本屋久岛附近海域美军MV-22“鱼鹰”坠毁地点进行搜救" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Japan Coast Guard vessel conducts search and rescue operation at the site where a U.S. military aircraft MV-22 Osprey crashed into the sea off Yakushima Island, Kagoshima prefecture, western Japan November 29, 2023, in this photo taken by Kyodo. Mandatory credit Kyodo via REUTERS 翻译:共同社拍摄的这张照片于 2023 年 11 月 29 日在日本西部鹿儿岛县屋久岛附近海域，一艘日本海上保安厅船只在一架美军飞机 MV-22“鱼鹰”坠毁现场进行搜救行动。强制性信用共同社（路透社）</figcaption></figure>                     <p>(This Nov. 29 story has been corrected after a clarification from the the Yakushima Fisheries Cooperative that one person had been found, not three, in paragraph 5)翻译:（屋久岛渔业合作社澄清第 5 段中发现的是一人，而不是三人后，11 月 29 日的报道已得到更正）</p>   <p>A U.S. military aircraft carrying eight people crashed into the sea in Japan on Wednesday, killing at least one crew member.翻译:周三，一架载有八人的美军飞机在日本坠入大海，造成至少一名机组人员死亡。</p>   <p>The U.S. military said the mishap occurred during a routine training mission off the shores of Yakushima Island, about 1,040 km (650 miles) southwest of the capital Tokyo.翻译:美国军方表示，这起事故发生在屋久岛海岸附近的例行训练任务中，屋久岛位于首都东京西南约 1,040 公里（650 英里）处。</p>   <p>"The crew’s conditions are unknown at this time," a statement from U.S. Air Force Special Operations Command said.翻译:美国空军特种作战司令部在一份声明中说：“目前机组人员的状况尚不清楚。”</p>   <p>Japan's coast guard said what appeared to be wreckage from the tilt-rotor V-22 Osprey and one person, who was later confirmed to have died, were found about 3 km (2 miles) from the shore.翻译:日本海岸警卫队表示，在距海岸约 3 公里（2 英里）处发现了似乎是倾转旋翼机 V-22 鱼鹰的残骸和一名人员，后来证实该人员已经死亡。</p>   <p>A representative for the Yakushima Fisheries Cooperative initially said fishing boats in the area found three people in the surrounding waters, but later clarified that just one person had been found.翻译:屋久岛渔业合作社的一名代表最初表示，该地区的渔船在周围水域发现了三人，但后来澄清说只发现了一人。</p>   <p>Another Osprey thought to have been travelling with the crashed aircraft landed safely at the island's airport on Wednesday afternoon, a spokesperson for the local government said.翻译:当地政府发言人表示，另一架被认为与失事飞机一起飞行的鱼鹰于周三下午安全降落在该岛机场。</p>   <p>The United States has more than 50,000 U.S. troops in Japan, many in the strategically important southwestern Okinawan islands, amid growing Chinese military assertiveness around nearby Taiwan.翻译:美国在日本驻有超过 5 万美军，其中许多驻扎在具有重要战略意义的冲绳西南部岛屿，而中国在台湾附近的军事自信日益增强。</p>   <p>The crash happened just before 3 p.m. (0600 GMT), with witnesses saying the aircraft's left engine appeared to be on fire as it approached an airport for an emergency landing, despite clear weather and light wind, media reported.翻译:据媒体报道，坠机事件发生在下午 3 点（格林威治标准时间 0600）之前，目击者称，尽管天气晴朗、微风，但飞机在接近机场紧急着陆时左侧发动机似乎着火。</p>   <p>The aircraft was part of a unit based in Okinawa trained to transport and supply special operations forces, according to the U.S. military.翻译:据美国军方称，这架飞机是驻扎在冲绳的一支部队的一部分，该部队接受过特种作战部队运输和补给训练。</p>   <p>Japan, which also operates Osprey aircraft, said on Wednesday it had asked the U.S. military to investigate the crash.翻译:同样拥有鱼鹰飞机的日本周三表示，已要求美国军方调查这起坠机事件。</p>   <p>Developed jointly by Boeing <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BA.N" target="_blank">(BA.N)</a> and Bell Helicopter, the Osprey can fly both like a helicopter and fixed-wing aircraft and is operated by the U.S. Air Force, Marines and Navy and the Japan Self-Defense Forces.翻译:鱼鹰由波音公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BA.N" target="_blank">（BA.N）</a>和贝尔直升机公司联合开发，可以像直升机和固定翼飞机一样飞行，由美国空军、海军陆战队和海军以及日本自卫队使用。</p>   <p>The deployment of the hybrid aircraft in Japan has been controversial, with critics saying it is prone to accidents. The U.S. military and Japan say it is safe.翻译:日本部署混合动力飞机一直存在争议，批评者称其容易发生事故。美军和日本均表示安全。</p>   <p>In August, a U.S. Osprey <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/aircraft-with-us-military-personnel-crashes-australia-defence-ministry-2023-08-27/">crashed off the coast of northern Australia</a> while transporting troops during a routine military exercise, killing three U.S. Marines.翻译:8月，美国一架鱼鹰在例行军事演习中运送部队时<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/aircraft-with-us-military-personnel-crashes-australia-defence-ministry-2023-08-27/">在澳大利亚北部海岸坠毁</a>，造成三名美国海军陆战队员死亡。</p>   <p>Another crash-landed in the ocean off Japan's southern island of Okinawa in December 2016, prompting a temporary U.S. military grounding of the aircraft.翻译:2016 年 12 月，另一架飞机在日本南部冲绳岛附近海域坠毁，导致美军暂时停飞该飞机。</p>    <span>Reporting by Kiyoshi Takenaka, Tim Kelly, Kantaro Komiya, Idrees Ali and Phil Stewart; Writing by John Geddie; Editing by David Dolan, Gerry Doyle, Nick Macfie and Deepa Babington翻译:Kiyoshi Takenaka、Tim Kelly、Kantaro Komiya、Idrees Ali 和 Phil Stewart 报道；约翰·格迪撰写；编辑：David Dolan、Gerry Doyle、Nick Macfie 和 Deepa Babington</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:31:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FEASVCGUKFM7XFFPE35RJMSZLU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us-military-aircraft-crashes-into-ocean-near-japans-yakushima-island-jiji-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Kiyoshi Takenaka, Tim Kelly]]></author>
            
                
                <category>JAPAN</category>
                
                <category>CRASH/USA (CORRECTED, UPDATE 8, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：法国巴黎银行将聘用十几名员工进行亚洲股票改革，结束交易来源研究]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/iWFUKBMPSwgmcazt6iyBwEsBXU8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4QHBJOGRMRPZZCUT4VPM6I2VKI.jpg" alt="Illustration shows BNP Paribas Bank logo翻译:插图显示法国巴黎银行徽标" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>BNP Paribas Bank logo is seen in this illustration taken March 12, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:这张摄于 2023 年 3 月 12 日的插图中可以看到法国巴黎银行的标志。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>BNP Paribas <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BNPP.PA" target="_blank">(BNPP.PA)</a> plans to make at least a dozen hires in its equities business in Asia next year and will end a research outsourcing pact with Morningstar <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MORN.O" target="_blank">(MORN.O)</a>, two sources with knowledge of the matter said, in a revamp to boost market share.翻译:两位知情人士称，法国巴黎银行<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BNPP.PA" target="_blank">(BNPP.PA)</a>计划明年在亚洲股票业务中招聘至少十几名员工，并将终止与晨星<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MORN.O" target="_blank">(MORN.O) 的</a>研究外包协议以提高市场份额。</p>   <p>BNP's move to add more research analysts, salespeople and traders comes as a bank spokesperson said in Asia Pacific it had started integrating and expanding coverage by Exane, a global platform it fully acquired in 2021 that specialises in cash equities execution and research.翻译:法国巴黎银行增加更多研究分析师、销售人员和交易员之际，该行发言人表示，该行已开始在亚太地区整合并扩大 Exane 的覆盖范围。Exane 是法国巴黎银行于 2021 年完全收购的全球平台，专门从事现金股票执行和研究。</p>   <p>The spokesperson said "key hires" would join the bank as part of the revamp, but declined to provide the hiring target. The French bank also did not comment on plans to end its research partnership with Morningstar after more than four years.翻译:该发言人表示，作为重组的一部分，“关键员工”将加入该银行，但拒绝透露招聘目标。这家法国银行也没有对结束与晨星四年多的研究合作关系的计划发表评论。</p>   <p>The sources declined to be named as they were not authorised to speak to the media.翻译:消息人士拒绝透露姓名，因为他们无权接受媒体采访。</p>   <p>Morningstar did not immediately respond to a request for comment.翻译:晨星没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>The expansion of the equities business by BNP comes as its Wall Street peers have reduced investment banking headcount this year amid sluggish trading and dealmaking activities.翻译:法国巴黎银行扩张股票业务之际，由于交易和交易活动低迷，今年华尔街同行纷纷削减投资银行员工人数。</p>   <p>The move also comes close on the heels of BNP completing the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/bnp-paribas-set-expand-exane-us-2022-11-08/">integration of Exane</a> with its existing cash equities operation in Europe and in the U.S., resulting in the platform's transfer of all the clients, teams and technology to BNP.翻译:此前，法国巴黎银行完成了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/bnp-paribas-set-expand-exane-us-2022-11-08/">Exane 与其在欧洲和美国现有现金股票业务的整合</a>，导致该平台的所有客户、团队和技术均转移至法国巴黎银行。</p>   <p>Under CEO Jean-Laurent Bonnafe, the euro zone's biggest bank has bolstered its investment banking business, a move that has benefited BNP in recent years as market volatility propelled trading, particularly last year after Russia invaded Ukraine.翻译:在首席执行官让-洛朗·博纳夫(Jean-Laurent Bonnafe)的领导下，这家欧元区最大的银行加强了其投资银行业务，近年来，随着市场波动推动交易，尤其是去年俄罗斯入侵乌克兰之后，法国巴黎银行受益匪浅。</p>   <p>The bank has also invested in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/bnp-says-tough-economy-could-spur-opportunities-bolt-on-deals-2023-10-26/">building up its equities trading business</a> in the last few years, notably by acquiring Deutsche Bank's electronic equity and prime broking operations, a deal that was completed in early 2022.翻译:该银行在过去几年中还<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/bnp-says-tough-economy-could-spur-opportunities-bolt-on-deals-2023-10-26/">投资建立了股票交易业务</a>，特别是收购了德意志银行的电子股票和大宗经纪业务，该交易于 2022 年初完成。</p>   <p>In Asia, BNP competes with large Western banks including Morgan Stanley <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MS.N" target="_blank">(MS.N)</a>, Goldman Sachs <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GS.N" target="_blank">(GS.N)</a>, JPMorgan <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/JPM.N" target="_blank">(JPM.N)</a> and UBS <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/UBSG.S" target="_blank">(UBSG.S)</a>, as well as a host of local investment banks in the cash equities business.翻译:在亚洲，法国巴黎银行的竞争对手包括摩根士丹利<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MS.N" target="_blank">(MS.N)</a> 、高盛<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GS.N" target="_blank">(GS.N)</a> 、摩根大通<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/JPM.N" target="_blank">(JPM.N)</a>和瑞银<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/UBSG.S" target="_blank">(UBSG.S)</a>等大型西方银行，以及许多亚洲本地投资银行。现金股票业务。</p>   <p>One of the sources said BNP could boost its Asia equities headcount by as much as 20 over the next year.翻译:其中一位消息人士称，法国巴黎银行可能会在明年将其亚洲股票部门的员工人数增加多达 20 人。</p>   <p>Equities capital market business in Asia has been sluggish for a period of time, but BNP sees the need to be ready for an "inflection point" of a bounceback in activity, said Jason Yates, BNP's head of cash equity in Asia Pacific.翻译:法国巴黎银行亚太区现金股票主管杰森·耶茨(Jason Yates)表示，亚洲股票资本市场业务一段时间以来一直低迷，但法国巴黎银行认为需要为活动反弹的“拐点”做好准备。</p>   <p>"Some clients are pulling back (from Asia), but other clients are telling us that actually they are committing to Asia and are adding more resources," said William Bratton, the bank's Asia-Pacific head of cash equity research.</p>    <h 1="">INCREASING STOCK COVERAGE</h>  <p>In 2019, BNP entered into a pact with Morningstar as part of which the French bank sourced the bulk of its Asia-Pacific equity research from the independent research provider, joining other banks seeking to cut costs after regulatory changes.翻译:2019 年，法国巴黎银行与晨星公司签订了一项协议，根据协议，这家法国银行从独立研究提供商处采购大部分亚太股票研究，加入了其他银行在监管变化后寻求削减成本的行列。</p>   <p>The bulk of BNP's in-house equities research team, mainly in Hong Kong and Singapore, departed as a result of that deal.翻译:法国巴黎银行内部股票研究团队的大部分成员（主要在香港和新加坡）因该交易而离职。</p>   <p>The bank has now started unwinding its outsourced research partnership in the region, said the first source. The second source said the tie-up with Morningstar was expected to end in 2024, as Exane gradually takes control of the function.翻译:第一位消息人士称，该银行现已开始解除其在该地区的外包研究合作伙伴关系。第二位消息人士称，随着 Exane 逐渐控制该职能，与晨星的合作预计将于 2024 年结束。</p>   <p>BNP aims to increase its stock coverage in the Asia-Pacific region by three to four times in the coming years, the spokesperson said. It was not immediately clear how many regional companies are covered by BNP and Morningstar as part of the partnership.翻译:该发言人表示，法国巴黎银行的目标是在未来几年内将其在亚太地区的股票覆盖率增加三到四倍。目前尚不清楚法国巴黎银行和晨星公司的合作伙伴关系涵盖了多少家地区公司。</p>   <p>The research coverage within the bank will be strengthened initially in the industrials, technology and consumer sectors, Bratton said, adding BNP would also add to the coverage of automobile, semiconductor and consumer companies in China, and new energy companies from China and South Korea.翻译:布拉顿表示，银行内部的研究覆盖范围将首先加强在工业、科技和消费领域，并补充说，法国巴黎银行还将扩大对中国汽车、半导体和消费品公司以及中国和韩国新能源公司的覆盖范围。</p>   <p>"It's very important that you have a view ... rather than having independent research and expecting clients to piece that together," Yates said, adding it was easier to bring the talent and product management in-house than use external parties.翻译:耶茨说：“拥有自己的观点非常重要……而不是进行独立研究并期望客户将其拼凑在一起。”他补充说，将人才和产品管理引入内部比使用外部各方更容易。</p>   <p>India, a market where BNP did not outsource its research coverage, will be fully integrated into the Exane platform on Thursday, said the spokesperson, 
 making it the first Asian market to be integrated as part of the gradual regional rollout.翻译:该发言人表示，印度是法国巴黎银行没有外包其研究覆盖范围的市场，该市场将于周四完全整合到 Exane 平台中，成为第一个作为逐步区域推广的一部分而整合的亚洲市场。</p>    <span>Reporting by Selena Li and Sumeet Chatterjee; Editing by Jamie Freed翻译:Selena Li 和 Sumeet Chatterjee 报道；杰米·弗里德编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:25:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">NHTIAFLAHBM5LB222NIWZKBPQA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/bnp-hire-dozen-staff-asia-equities-revamp-end-research-deal-sources-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Selena Li, Sumeet Chatterjee]]></author>
            
                
                <category>BNP PARIBAS</category>
                
                <category>ASIA/ (EXCLUSIVE, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[梅赛德斯-奔驰与宝马将在中国成立合资公司建设高功率充电网络]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/dDLtEknT4B2g2xpuCJISZoslMWM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PD3OUFT6SFMXRPQXWJSGXDPSLM.jpg" alt="The logo of Mercedes-Benz is seen outside a Mercedes-Benz car dealer in Brussels翻译:布鲁塞尔一家梅赛德斯-奔驰汽车经销商外可见梅赛德斯-奔驰的标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The logo of Mercedes-Benz is seen outside a Mercedes-Benz car dealer in Brussels翻译:布鲁塞尔一家梅赛德斯-奔驰汽车经销商外可见梅赛德斯-奔驰的标志, Belgium June 1, 2023. REUTERS/Yves Herman/File Photo翻译:2023年6月1日，比利时布鲁塞尔，梅赛德斯-奔驰汽车经销商外可见梅赛德斯-奔驰的标志。路透社/Yves Herman/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>German automaker Mercedes-Benz <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MBGn.DE" target="_blank">(MBGn.DE)</a> said on Thursday it had reached an agreement with BMW <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BMWG.DE" target="_blank">(BMWG.DE)</a> to establish a joint venture for operating a high-power charging network in China.翻译:德国汽车制造商梅赛德斯-奔驰<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MBGn.DE" target="_blank">(MBGn.DE)</a>周四表示，已与宝马<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BMWG.DE" target="_blank">(BMWG.DE)</a>达成协议，成立一家合资企业，在中国运营高功率充电网络。</p>   <p>At least 1,000 high-power charging stations with around 7,000 charging piles in the country are expected to be installed by the end of 2026, the company said in the statement, adding the deal was subject to regulatory approval.翻译:该公司在声明中表示，预计到 2026 年底，该国将安装至少 1,000 个大功率充电站和约 7,000 个充电桩，并补充说该交易尚待监管部门批准。</p>   <p>The first stations are scheduled to start operating in 2024 in regions with higher sales of electric vehicles.翻译:第一批充电站计划于 2024 年在电动汽车销量较高的地区开始运营。</p>   <p>Mercedes-Benz <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/mercedes-launch-vehicle-charging-network-starting-north-america-2023-01-05/">announced</a> earlier this year that it would invest billions of euros in building its own charging network of 10,000 fast-charging points in North America, Europe and China by 2030.翻译:梅赛德斯-奔驰今年早些时候<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/mercedes-launch-vehicle-charging-network-starting-north-america-2023-01-05/">宣布</a>，将投资数十亿欧元，到2030年在北美、欧洲和中国建设拥有1万个快速充电点的充电网络。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ozan Ergenay, Editing by Victoria Waldersee翻译:奥赞·埃尔格奈 (Ozan Ergenay) 报道，维多利亚·瓦尔德西 (Victoria Waldersee) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:23:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6IXISOACTNKH7IHXMVRRUD3UAY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/mercedes-benz-bmw-establish-jv-high-power-charging-network-china-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>MERCEDES BENZ GR</category>
                
                <category>BMW/CHARGING (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[早盘竞价：国债正处于 2008 年以来最佳月份的风口浪尖]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/3wD_83vqgrs5DtwKrbrBA54SZsU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/AINTT23SNBK5VJLZZM5H47HDJU.jpg" alt="The U.S Treasury building in Washington翻译:位于华盛顿的美国财政部大楼" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view shows a bronze seal beside a door at the U.S. Treasury building in Washington, U.S., January 20, 2023.&nbsp; REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque/File Photo翻译:2023 年 1 月 20 日，美国华盛顿美国财政部大楼门旁的青铜印章。路透社/Kevin Lamarque/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>A look at the day ahead in European and global markets from Wayne Cole.翻译:韦恩·科尔 (Wayne Cole) 对欧洲和全球市场未来一天的展望。</p>   <p>Let's start with Treasuries because, if this were sports, we'd be calling it a comeback for the ages. Not long ago the market was collapsing so fast that, going by some headlines, civilisation as we know it was under threat.翻译:让我们从国债开始，因为如果这是体育运动，我们会称其为多年来的卷土重来。不久前，市场崩溃得如此之快，以至于根据一些头条新闻，我们所知道的文明受到了威胁。</p>   <p>Now, with some <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/feds-barkin-wants-rate-hike-option-no-talk-rate-cuts-2023-11-29/">encouraging hints</a> from Fed officials, 10-year notes are poised to celebrate their best month since the 2008 global crash, with yields down 61 basis points for November so far.翻译:现在，随着美联储官员发出一些<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/feds-barkin-wants-rate-hike-option-no-talk-rate-cuts-2023-11-29/">令人鼓舞的暗示</a>，10 年期国债有望迎来自 2008 年全球金融危机以来表现最好的月份，截至目前 11 月份收益率已下跌 61 个基点。</p>   <p>Yields on two-year paper are down 31 bps just this week, the steepest drop since the U.S. mini-banking crisis in March. And almost all of that came because one Fed governor said that, should inflation keep falling for a few months, then policy would need to be loosened just to stop real rates from rising.翻译:就在本周，两年期票据收益率下跌了 31 个基点，这是自 3 月份美国小型银行危机以来的最大跌幅。几乎所有这一切都是因为一位美联储理事表示，如果通胀持续下降几个月，那么就需要放松政策以阻止实际利率上升。</p>   <p>Then again, it did come from Governor <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/feds-waller-increasingly-confident-policy-is-right-spot-2023-11-28/">Waller</a>, normally such a reliable hawk that the sudden conversion to dovishness had a far greater impact. Markets also assume he would not have flagged such a possibility without running it by Fed Chair Powell first.翻译:话又说回来，它确实来自<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/feds-waller-increasingly-confident-policy-is-right-spot-2023-11-28/">沃勒</a>州长，他通常是一位可靠的鹰派，突然转向鸽派产生了更大的影响。市场还认为，如果没有美联储主席鲍威尔的先行，他就不会提出这种可能性。</p>   <p>And Powell just happens to have a Q&amp;A appearance on Friday, so of course bulls are betting that he will accommodate their rate-cut wishes.翻译:鲍威尔恰好在周五出席问答环节，因此多头当然押注他会满足他们的降息愿望。</p>   <p>Rarely has a "fireside chat" had so much staked on it. Futures have now fully priced in a quarter-point cut in May, and are even 50-50 for March. Fed fund futures for December next year have surged 35 ticks so far this week, taking the total easing expected for 2024 to 115 bps.翻译:很少有一次“炉边谈话”有如此大的赌注。目前，5 月份期货价格已完全下跌 25 个基点，3 月份的价格甚至为 50-50。本周到目前为止，明年 12 月联邦基金期货已飙升 35 个基点，使 2024 年预期的总体宽松政策达到 115 个基点。</p>   <p>Note that influential Fed New York President Williams is speaking later on Thursday, and he carries a lot of weight with investors.翻译:请注意，颇具影响力的纽约联储主席威廉姆斯将于周四晚些时候发表讲话，他在投资者中具有很大的影响力。</p>   <p>Markets will also be vulnerable to any upside surprise from the U.S. personal consumption expenditures (PCE) report, which they are counting on to echo the benign CPI data and show core inflation slowed to 3.5% in October.翻译:市场也很容易受到美国个人消费支出（PCE）报告的任何上行意外影响，他们指望该报告与良好的消费者物价指数（CPI）数据相呼应，并显示10月份核心通胀率放缓至3.5%。</p>   <p>The European Union has inflation data of its own later on Thursday and analysts suspect the risks are for a downside surprise following subdued readings from <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/german-inflation-eases-23-november-2023-11-29/">Germany</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/spains-12-month-inflation-falls-32-november-2023-11-29/">Spain</a>.翻译:周四晚些时候，欧盟将公布自己的通胀数据，分析师怀疑，在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/german-inflation-eases-23-november-2023-11-29/">德国</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/spains-12-month-inflation-falls-32-november-2023-11-29/">西班牙</a>的数据疲软之​​后，通胀数据可能会出现意外下行的风险。</p>   <p>The median forecast is already for the EU's HICP inflation to slow to 2.7%, the lowest since mid-2021. That is one reason futures are almost fully priced for an ECB rate cut as soon as April.翻译:欧盟 HICP 通胀率的预测中值已放缓至 2.7%，为 2021 年中期以来的最低水平。这就是欧洲央行最早在四月份降息的期货几乎完全定价的原因之一。</p>   <p>The dizzying drop in Treasury yields has left the dollar looking a little green in the gills. The dollar index looks set for its worst month since November last year, with a loss so far of 3.7%.翻译:美国国债收益率的大幅下跌让美元看起来有些绿色。美元指数看起来将迎来自去年11月以来最糟糕的一个月，迄今为止已下跌3.7%。</p>   <p>It is also down 3.1% on the yen , which if sustained would be the sharpest fall this year, while the euro is ahead by 3.8% for the month.翻译:日元也下跌 3.1%，如果持续下去，将是今年最大幅度的跌幅，而欧元本月则下跌 3.8%。</p>   <p>The dollar has lost 2.6% on the yuan, a major move for such a tightly managed currency pair, and failed to get any lift from a rather disappointing <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/spains-12-month-inflation-falls-32-november-2023-11-29/">China PMI</a> survey on Thursday.翻译:美元兑人民币汇率已下跌 2.6%，对于管理如此严格的货币对而言，这是一个重大举措，而且周四令人失望的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/spains-12-month-inflation-falls-32-november-2023-11-29/">中国 PMI</a>调查也未能给美元带来任何提振。</p>      <p>Key developments that could influence markets on Thursday:翻译:周四可能影响市场的主要事态发展：</p>   <p>- Appearances by ECB members Lagarde, Enria, McCaul and Jochnick翻译:- 欧洲央行成员拉加德、恩里亚、麦考尔和约赫尼克出席</p>   <p>- BoE Monetary Policy Committee member Greene speaks, as does Riksbank Deputy Governor Bunge翻译:- 英国央行货币政策委员会成员格林和瑞典央行副行长邦吉发表讲话</p>   <p>- EU HICP flash inflation data for Nov, German retail sales and unemployment figures, French CPI, PPI and consumer spending翻译:- 11 月份欧盟 HICP 通胀数据、德国零售销售和失业数据、法国 CPI、PPI 和消费者支出</p>   <p>- U.S. data on PCE, weekly jobless claims, pending home sales and the Chicago PMI翻译:- 美国个人消费支出数据、每周初请失业金人数、待售房屋销售和芝加哥采购经理人指数</p>    <span>By Wayne Cole; Editing by Edmund Klamann翻译:作者：韦恩·科尔；编辑：埃德蒙·克拉曼</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 05:47:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZXMFV7VPC5OXLC42UHJQKOOKUA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/global-markets-view-europe-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/VIEW</category>
                
                <category>EUROPE</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[与债权人的债务协议可能有助于斯里兰卡通过国际货币基金组织的救助审查]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>IMF board to take up Sri Lanka's review by mid-Dec</li>  <li>Sri Lanka to get $334 mln if IMF clears first review</li>  <li>Deal with bondholders next on Sri Lanka's agenda</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>国际货币基金组织董事会将于12月中旬开始对斯里兰卡进行审查</li><li>如果国际货币基金组织通过首次审查，斯里兰卡将获得3.34亿美元</li><li>斯里兰卡的下一个议程是与债券持有人打交道</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/CSF9J8egReMGz3dH99O_0UyJ3p0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NXPJGI5XA5PHPPXISMKMBPLKWE.jpg" alt="The IMF logo is seen outside the headquarters building in Washington翻译:华盛顿总部大楼外可见国际货币基金组织的标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) logo is seen outside the headquarters building in Washington, U.S., September 4, 2018. REUTERS/Yuri Gripas/File Photo翻译:2018年9月4日，国际货币基金组织（IMF）标志出现在美国华盛顿总部大楼外。REUTERS/Yuri Gripas/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Sri Lanka's pact with creditor nations to restructure its debt prepares the way for the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to consider clearing the first review of a bailout next month, the global lender said on Thursday.翻译:国际货币基金组织(IMF)周四表示，斯里兰卡与债权国达成的债务重组协议为国际货币基金组织(IMF)考虑批准下个月的首次救助审查铺平了道路。</p>   <p>Battling its worst financial crisis in decades, the Indian Ocean nation had been trying since last year to strike restructuring deals with creditors after record low foreign exchange reserves led to a default on foreign debt in May 2022.翻译:这个印度洋国家正在应对数十年来最严重的金融危机，自去年以来一直试图与债权人达成重组协议，此前创纪录的低外汇储备导致2022年5月外债违约。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/creditor-nations-likely-agree-sri-lanka-debt-restructuring-report-2023-11-29/">Wednesday's in-principle deal</a> comes about a month after Sri Lanka's pact with the Export-Import Bank of China covering about <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/sri-lanka-says-it-has-deal-with-china-exim-bank-cover-42-bln-debt-2023-10-12/">$4.2 billion</a> of outstanding debt, while clearing the IMF review could trigger a second tranche of about $334 million in funds.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/creditor-nations-likely-agree-sri-lanka-debt-restructuring-report-2023-11-29/">周三的原则性协议</a>是在斯里兰卡与中国进出口银行达成涵盖约<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/sri-lanka-says-it-has-deal-with-china-exim-bank-cover-42-bln-debt-2023-10-12/">42亿美元</a>未偿债务的协议一个月后达成的，同时通过国际货币基金组织的审查可能会引发第二笔约3.34亿美元的资金。</p>   <p>Sri Lanka and the IMF clinched the staff-level agreement on the first review of the four-year extended fund facility arrangement in October, after a month's delay.翻译:斯里兰卡和国际货币基金组织在推迟一个月后于 10 月就四年期延期基金安排的首次审查达成了工作人员级协议。</p>   <p>The second tranche will be disbursed once the IMF's executive board clears the review.翻译:一旦国际货币基金组织执行董事会通过审查，第二笔款项将被支付。</p>   <p>"These understandings pave the way for the IMF executive board to consider completion of the first review," Peter Breuer, the IMF's mission chief for Sri Lanka, said in a statement.翻译:国际货币基金组织斯里兰卡代表团团长彼得·布劳尔在一份声明中表示：“这些谅解为国际货币基金组织执行董事会考虑完成第一次审查铺平了道路。”</p>   <p>"We look forward to the executive board taking up this review by mid-December and the continuation of our productive collaboration with Sri Lanka."翻译:“我们期待执行委员会在 12 月中旬之前进行此项审查，并继续与斯里兰卡开展富有成效的合作。”</p>   <p>Sri Lankan authorities did not immediately respond to a request for comment on the IMF statement.翻译:斯里兰卡当局没有立即回应对国际货币基金组织声明发表评论的请求。</p>   <p>The finance ministry said the deal with the creditor panel covered about $5.9 billion of outstanding public debt, consisting of a mix of long-term maturity extension and reduction in interest rates.翻译:财政部表示，与债权人小组达成的协议涵盖了约 59 亿美元的未偿公共债务，其中包括长期期限延长和利率降低。</p>   <p>Japan, together with France and India, co-chairs the committee of 15 nations. But Sri Lanka's largest bilateral creditor, China, has not joined as a formal member.翻译:日本与法国和印度共同担任 15 个国家委员会的主席。但斯里兰卡最大的双边债权人中国尚未成为正式成员。</p>   <p>Since locking down the IMF bailout of $2.9 billion in March, Sri Lanka has managed to partly stabilise its economy, bring down runaway inflation and rebuild currency reserves.翻译:自 3 月份锁定国际货币基金组织 29 亿美元的救助以来，斯里兰卡已成功部分稳定了经济、降低了失控的通货膨胀并重建了货币储备。</p>   <p>Finance ministry data shows external debt of $36.6 billion at the end of June. Once the debt restructuring is completed, Sri Lanka hopes to cut its overall debt by $16.9 billion.翻译:财政部数据显示，6月底外债为366亿美元。一旦债务重组完成，斯里兰卡希望将总体债务削减169亿美元。</p>   <p>After receiving the IMF money, Sri Lanka could get further funding from the Asian Development Bank and the World Bank, taking the total to about $900 million, the central bank governor, P. Nandalal Weerasinghe, said last week.翻译:斯里兰卡央行行长 P. Nandalal Weerasinghe 上周表示，在获得国际货币基金组织的资金后，斯里兰卡可以从亚洲开发银行和世界银行获得进一步的资金，使总额达到约 9 亿美元。</p>   <p>Sri Lanka's dollar bond maturing in July 2026 was up 0.28 cents at 51.53 cents by 0500 GMT, Tradeweb data showed. Wednesday's rise of 1.19 cents was its largest single-day gain in more than a month.翻译:Tradeweb 数据显示，截至格林威治标准时间 0500，斯里兰卡将于 2026 年 7 月到期的美元债券上涨 0.28 美分，至 51.53 美分。周三上涨 1.19 美分，是一个多月以来的最大单日涨幅。</p>   <p>Stock market reaction to the IMF statement was muted, however, with the benchmark index climbing 0.67% when trading opened.翻译:然而，股市对国际货币基金组织声明的反应平淡，开盘时基准指数上涨 0.67%。</p>   <p>The finance ministry said it would next focus on striking similar deals with other bilateral creditors for debt amounting to $274 million and seek pacts with bondholders who have the bulk of its $12.5 billion of international sovereign bonds.翻译:财政部表示，下一步将集中精力与其他双边债权人就价值 2.74 亿美元的债务达成类似协议，并寻求与拥有 125 亿美元国际主权债券中大部分的债券持有人达成协议。</p>   <p>A debt restructuring proposal by private creditors in October did not get a favourable response from the finance ministry, which said it had "serious reservations" about the proposed macro-linked bonds.翻译:10月份私人债权人提出的债务重组提案并未得到财政部的积极回应，财政部表示对拟议的宏观挂钩债券持“严重保留”。</p>    <span>Reporting by Uditha Jayasinghe, additional reporting by Dharamraj Dhutia in Mumbai; Writing by Sudipto Ganguly; Editing by Stephen Coates and Clarence Fernandez翻译:Uditha Jayasinghe 报道，Dharamraj Dhutia 孟买补充报道；苏迪普托·甘古利 (Sudipto Ganguly) 撰写；斯蒂芬·科茨和克拉伦斯·费尔南德斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 05:15:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">JBPSBBMH7ROJNJTSJVBCTOVMDI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/imf-says-sri-lanka-debt-deal-could-help-board-clear-first-bailout-review-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Uditha Jayasinghe]]></author>
            
                
                <category>SRI LANKA</category>
                
                <category>CRISIS/IMF (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国电动汽车品牌Zeekr暂停美国IPO——消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/isBe0IBRFwA4eM42jPY81Jc1rVY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CV7TH7NCVBPTTMD7I3TU5YBIJE.jpg" alt="People walk past a booth of Zeekr, Chinese automaker Geely's premium electric vehicle (EV) brand, at a shopping mall in Beijing翻译:在北京的一家购物中心，人们走过中国汽车制造商吉利旗下的高端电动汽车 (EV) 品牌 Zeekr 的展位" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk past a booth of Zeekr, Chinese automaker Geely's premium electric vehicle (EV) brand, at a shopping mall in Beijing翻译:在北京的一家购物中心，人们走过中国汽车制造商吉利旗下的高端电动汽车 (EV) 品牌 Zeekr 的展位, China November 3, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 3 日，中国北京一家购物中心，人们走过中国汽车制造商吉利旗下高端电动汽车 (EV) 品牌 Zeekr 的展位。路透社/Tingshu Wang/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Zeekr, Chinese automaker Geely's premium electric vehicle (EV) brand, has put its U.S. initial public offering (IPO) on hold due to a mismatch in valuation expectations, according to two sources with direct knowledge of the matter.翻译:据两位直接了解情况的消息人士透露，中国汽车制造商吉利旗下的高端电动汽车 (EV) 品牌 Zeekr 由于估值预期不匹配，已暂停其在美国的首次公开募股 (IPO)。</p>   <p>The decision was made as global financial markets remain volatile, a third source added.翻译:第三位消息人士补充说，这一决定是在全球金融市场仍然波动的情况下做出的。</p>   <p>The sources could not be named because they were discussing confidential information.翻译:消息人士无法透露姓名，因为他们正在讨论机密信息。</p>   <p>"The company has made a public filing to the SEC and is proceeding with the preparatory work," a Zeekr statement said.翻译:Zeekr 声明称：“该公司已向 SEC 公开提交文件，并正在进行准备工作。”</p>   <p>It declined to answer Reuters questions about the deal being put on hold due to the company's valuation target not being met and uncertain market conditions.翻译:该公司拒绝回答路透社有关由于该公司估值目标未达到且市场状况不确定而搁置交易的问题。</p>    <span>Reporting by Julie Zhu in Hong Kong and Scott Murdoch in Sydney; Editing by Jamie Freed and Christopher Cushing翻译:朱莉·朱 (Julie Zhu) 在香港的报道和斯科特·默多克 (Scott Murdoch) 在悉尼的报道；杰米·弗里德和克里斯托弗·库欣编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 04:10:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MQTC7I2AQJNOPIMS5VG4FCWYDI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/china-ev-brand-zeekr-puts-us-ipo-hold-sources-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ZEEKR</category>
                
                <category>IPO/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[不丹在全国选举初轮中投票]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Bhutan began voting on Thursday in the preliminary round of national elections to choose two political parties that will contest the fourth free vote since democracy was established in the Himalayan kingdom 15 years ago.翻译:不丹周四开始在全国选举初轮中投票，选出两个政党，参加这个喜马拉雅王国15年前建立民主以来的第四次自由投票。</p>   <p>Nestled between China and India, Bhutan is known for its Gross National Happiness (GNH) index, an economic gauge that takes into account factors normally ignored by gross domestic product measures, like recreation and emotional well-being.翻译:不丹位于中国和印度之间，以其国民总幸福指数（GNH）而闻名，该指数是一种经济衡量指标，考虑了通常被国内生产总值指标忽略的因素，例如娱乐和情感健康。</p>   <p>Nearly half a million of the country’s fewer than 800,000 people are eligible to vote for the five political parties that are in the fray.翻译:该国不到80万人口中，有近50万人有资格投票给参与竞争的五个政党。</p>   <p>The two parties that win the highest number of votes will qualify for the final round of the election to the 47-member National Assembly, set to take place on Jan. 9.翻译:赢得最高票数的两个政党将有资格参加定于 1 月 9 日举行的由 47 名议员组成的国民议会最后一轮选举。</p>   <p>Voting started at 8 a.m. (0200 hours GMT) and will close at 4 p.m. Results are expected by Friday, the Election Commission of Bhutan (ECB) said.翻译:不丹选举委员会 (ECB) 表示，投票于上午 8 点（格林威治标准时间 0200 点）开始，下午 4 点结束，预计结果将在周五公布。</p>   <p>“I am rushing to the polling centre to cast my vote,” said Karma, a voter who uses one name and hails from Punakha, located 55 km (34 miles) north east of the capital Thimphu.翻译:“我正赶往投票中心投票，”来自普纳卡的选民卡玛 (Karma) 说道，普纳卡位于首都廷布东北 55 公里（34 英里）处。</p>   <p>Analysts say all five political parties have vowed to boost the $3 billion economy that is dependent on aid and tourism.翻译:分析人士称，所有五个政党都誓言要提振依赖援助和旅游业的 30 亿美元经济。</p>   <p>Their other pledges are also similar, such as promising to tap the country’s vast potential to generate hydro-electric power and to boost agricultural growth.翻译:他们的其他承诺也相似，例如承诺挖掘该国水力发电的巨大潜力并促进农业增长。</p>   <p>Bhutan, which is roughly the size of Switzerland, has deep economic and trade relations with its southern neighbor, India, which is its biggest donor.翻译:不丹面积与瑞士大致相当，与其南部邻国印度有着深厚的经贸关系，而印度是其最大的捐助国。</p>    <span>Reporting by Gopal Sharma; Editing by Stephen Coates翻译:戈帕尔·夏尔马报道；斯蒂芬·科茨编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 04:04:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZETO6VS6QRJERJUQ42X54XEZZ4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/bhutan-votes-preliminary-round-national-elections-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Gopal Sharma]]></author>
            
                
                <category>BHUTAN</category>
                
                <category>ELECTION/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
