<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 16:37:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[普华永道附属公司和中国公司因美国审计失败而支付 790 万美元]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Jtnhqkbk3WgX1FAc3WHA6qhyxK8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SD6J5ZP6JVP7LMWBU2VJXY5CKQ.jpg" alt="Illustration shows U.S. and Chinese flags翻译:插图显示美国和中国国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. and Chinese flags are seen in this illustration taken, January 30, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:这张摄于 2023 年 1 月 30 日的插图中可以看到美国和中国国旗。 REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>PricewaterhouseCoopers affiliates in Hong Kong and China and a Chinese audit firm have agreed to pay a total of $7.9 million in fines for failures related to audits of U.S.-listed Chinese companies, the U.S. accounting watchdog said on Thursday.翻译:美国会计监管机构周四表示，普华永道在香港和中国大陆的分支机构以及一家中国审计公司已同意就在美国上市的中国公司的审计失败支付总计 790 万美元的罚款。</p>   <p>The penalties come over a year after Beijing and Washington <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-asks-firms-auditors-prepare-us-checks-hong-kong-sources-2022-08-26/">struck a landmark deal</a> that has allowed the U.S. Public Company Accounting Oversight Board (PCAOB) to inspect the books and records of Chinese companies listed in New York for the first time. While the fines are relatively small, they are among the biggest the watchdog has ever issued and indicate that the inspection deal, a decade in the making, is working as hoped.翻译:一年多前，北京和华盛顿<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-asks-firms-auditors-prepare-us-checks-hong-kong-sources-2022-08-26/">达成了一项具有里程碑意义的协议</a>，允许美国上市公司会计监督委员会（PCAOB）首次检查在纽约上市的中国公司的账簿和记录。虽然罚款金额相对较小，但这是监管机构有史以来开出的最大罚款之一，这表明这项历时十年的检查协议正在按预期发挥作用。</p>   <p>"
 The days of China-based firms evading accountability are over. The PCAOB is demonstrating that we will take action to protect investors in U.S. markets and impose tough sanctions against anyone who violates PCAOB rules and standards, no matter where they are located," said PCAOB chair Erica Williams in a statement.翻译:“中国公司逃避责任的时代已经结束。PCAOB 正在表明，我们将采取行动保护美国市场的投资者，并对任何违反 PCAOB 规则和标准的人实施严厉制裁，无论他们身在何处。” PCAOB 主席艾丽卡·威廉姆斯 (Erica Williams) 在一份声明中表示。</p>   <p>PricewaterhouseCoopers firms in Hong Kong and China agreed to pay a total of $7 million for violating quality control standards after they failed to detect or prevent extensive answer-sharing on mandatory training courses, the PCAOB said.翻译:PCAOB 表示，普华永道在香港和中国大陆的公司因未能发现或阻止强制性培训课程中广泛的答案共享而同意支付总计 700 万美元的违反质量控制标准的费用。</p>   <p>"After becoming aware of these issues, the firms investigated these matters promptly and took remedial action," the PwC affiliates said in a joint statement, noting they reported the problems to the PCAOB.翻译:普华永道附属公司在一份联合声明中表示，“在意识到这些问题后，这些公司立即调查了这些问题并采取了补救措施”，并指出他们向 PCAOB 报告了这些问题。</p>   <p>The PCAOB also fined Shandong Haoxin Certified Public Accountants Co., Ltd. and four accountants $940,000 for violations including issuing a false audit report and failing to maintain independence from a public company client. The individuals are also facing industry bars of varying lengths, the PCAOB said.翻译:PCAOB 还对山东浩信会计师事务所有限公司和四名会计师处以 94 万美元的罚款，罪名包括发布虚假审计报告和未能保持与上市公司客户的独立性。 PCAOB 表示，这些个人还面临着不同长度的行业限制。</p>   <p>Haoxin did not respond immediately to requests for comment.翻译:浩鑫没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>The U.S. has for years worried that the auditors of U.S.-listed Chinese companies were falling down on the job, putting investors at risk. But Beijing had resisted allowing the PCAOB access to its auditors' records, citing state secrecy concerns.翻译:多年来，美国一直担心在美上市的中国公司的审计师失职，让投资者面临风险。但北京方面以国家保密问题为由，拒绝允许美国上市公司会计监管委员会查阅其审计师记录。</p>   <p>In August 2022, the two countries - spurred on by a new U.S. law that threatened to kick potentially 200 Chinese companies off U.S. exchanges - finally agreed a framework for beginning inspections of eight audits.翻译:2022 年 8 月，在美国一项新法律的推动下，该法律威胁要将 200 家中国公司踢出美国交易所，两国最终同意了开始对八项审计进行检查的框架。</p>   <p>In May, the PCAOB <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us-watchdog-says-it-found-unacceptable-problems-with-chinese-company-audits-2023-05-10/">said it found a slew of deficiencies</a> in audits of U.S.-listed Chinese companies performed by PwC in Hong Kong and KPMG. At the time, the watchdog said it was common to find issues when first accessing a country's auditors.翻译:今年5月，PCAOB <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us-watchdog-says-it-found-unacceptable-problems-with-chinese-company-audits-2023-05-10/">表示，普华永道香港分公司和毕马威会计师事务所对在美上市的中国公司进行的审计存在一系列缺陷</a>。当时，监管机构表示，首次接触一个国家的审计师时发现问题是很常见的。</p>   <p>It did not disclose which companies' audits it had selected for inspection, but Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/exclusive-jdcom-yum-china-among-chinese-firms-chosen-us-audit-inspection-sources-2022-08-31/">has previously reported that Alibaba Group Holding and Yum China Holdings were among them.</a>翻译:该公司没有透露选择了哪些公司进行审计，但路透社<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/exclusive-jdcom-yum-china-among-chinese-firms-chosen-us-audit-inspection-sources-2022-08-31/">此前曾报道称，阿里巴巴集团控股公司和百胜中国控股公司均在其中。</a></p>   <p>The PCAOB's inspection in the region continue and the regulator continues to have "complete access" in its inspections, Williams said on Thursday.翻译:威廉姆斯周四表示，PCAOB对该地区的检查仍在继续，监管机构在检查中继续拥有“完全权限”。</p>   <p>"American investors are better protected when the PCAOB can audit the auditors of issuers listed in the United States," U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission chair Gary Gensler said in a statement.翻译:美国证券交易委员会主席加里·根斯勒(Gary Gensler)在一份声明中表示：“当PCAOB能够对在美国上市的发行人的审计师进行审计时，美国投资者将得到更好的保护。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Chris Prentice; Editing by Michelle Price, Chizu Nomiyama and Nick Zieminski翻译:克里斯·普伦蒂斯报道；编辑：Michelle Price、Chizu Nomiyama 和 Nick Zieminski</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 16:32:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">O4BLVNT72ZO3DER74OJW3ZNMC4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/pwc-affiliates-chinese-audit-firm-agree-pay-79-mln-over-us-sanctions-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/AUDITS (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TikTok 迈出开启挪威数据中心的第一步]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/1fHmlQkFUp93Rf753tDUJ-8t_qI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/37CSGVINX5NDDP2JLKXZFWGR5E.jpg" alt="Illustration shows TikTok app logo翻译:插图显示 TikTok 应用徽标" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The TikTok app logo is seen in this illustration taken August 22, 2022. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:这张 2022 年 8 月 22 日拍摄的插图中可以看到 TikTok 应用程序徽标。 REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>TikTok has taken possession of a facility in Norway built by data centre group Green Mountain AS which will become the social media company's largest in Europe as it seeks to store data generated in the region locally.翻译:TikTok 已拥有数据中心集团 Green Mountain AS 在挪威建造的设施，该设施将成为这家社交媒体公司在欧洲最大的设施，因为它寻求在本地存储该地区生成的数据。</p>   <p>The company, owned by China-headquartered Bytedance, has been trying to address concerns over whether the Chinese government could access the data of European citizens who use TikTok.翻译:这家总部位于中国的字节跳动公司旗下的公司一直在努力解决有关中国政府是否可以访问使用 TikTok 的欧洲公民数据的担忧。</p>   <p>Several countries, the European Parliament, European Commission and others have <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/european-parliament-ban-tiktok-staff-phones-eu-official-says-2023-02-28/">banned</a> TikTok from staff phones due to those concerns.翻译:出于这些担忧，一些国家、欧洲议会、欧盟委员会和其他机构已<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/european-parliament-ban-tiktok-staff-phones-eu-official-says-2023-02-28/">禁止</a>在员工手机上使用 TikTok。</p>   <p>"We understand the skepticism. And that's precisely why we're not just doing the step of putting the data in Europe, building that digital barrier around it," Theo Bertram, TikTok's VP of government relations and public policy, told Reuters.翻译:TikTok 政府关系和公共政策副总裁西奥·伯特伦 (Theo Bertram) 对路透社表示：“我们理解这种怀疑。这正是我们不只是采取将数据放在欧洲、围绕其建立数字屏障的原因。”</p>   <p>"We are taking the extra step of saying we know you're skeptical about us, and so we know we have to earn that trust."翻译:“我们采取了额外的措施，表示我们知道您对我们持怀疑态度，因此我们知道我们必须赢得这种信任。”</p>   <p>TikTok in March launched a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/under-pressure-tiktok-unveils-new-european-data-security-regime-2023-03-08/">data security regime</a> called Project Clover to build data centres and store European user data locally.翻译:TikTok于3月份推出了名为Project Clover的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/under-pressure-tiktok-unveils-new-european-data-security-regime-2023-03-08/">数据安全制度</a>，在本地建立数据中心并存储欧洲用户数据。</p>   <p>The Norwegian data centre will be in the town of Hamar where TikTok will store data spread over three buildings and the first phase will start operating from next summer.翻译:挪威数据中心将位于哈马尔镇，TikTok 将在那里存储分布在三栋建筑中的数据，第一阶段将从明年夏天开始运营。</p>   <p>The Norway data centre will run completely on renewable energy and generate heat that could be re-used. TikTok said a third-party provider is talking with multiple industries and research institutions for potential projects that can benefit from this level of heat re-use.翻译:挪威数据中心将完全依靠可再生能源运行，并产生可重复利用的热量。 TikTok 表示，一家第三方提供商正在与多个行业和研究机构洽谈可以从这种程度的热量再利用中受益的潜在项目。</p>   <p>TikTok said it plans to spend 12 billion euros over the next 10 years for Project Clover. It had earlier announced plans to spend 1.2 billion euros annually.翻译:TikTok表示，计划在未来10年为Project Clover斥资120亿欧元。它早些时候曾宣布计划每年支出12亿欧元。</p>   <p>This will cover the cost of building three data centres, the implementation of privacy enhancing technologies and for employing British cybersecurity firm NCC <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NCCG.L" target="_blank">(NCCG.L)</a> to audit its data controls and provide independent verification.翻译:这将涵盖建设三个数据中心、实施隐私增强技术以及聘请英国网络安全公司 NCC <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NCCG.L" target="_blank">(NCCG.L)</a>审核其数据控制并提供独立验证的费用。</p>   <p>"One of the things in the contract with NCC is they can go and talk to data protection authorities, talk to national cyber security organisations, without us being involved," Bertram said.翻译:Bertram 表示：“与 NCC 签订的合同中的一项内容是，他们可以与数据保护机构、国家网络安全组织进行对话，而无需我们参与。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Victoria in Norway; additional reporting by Supantha Mukherjee in Stockholm. Editing by Jane Merriman翻译:维多利亚在挪威的报道； Supantha Mukherjee 在斯德哥尔摩的补充报道。简·梅里曼编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 16:06:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MF2YV4QFINNBZPPWIOB5FXIBQA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/tiktok-takes-first-steps-turning-norwegian-data-centre-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Victoria Klesty]]></author>
            
                
                <category>TIKTOK</category>
                
                <category>NORWAY/ (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[解说：恒大可能的清算令以及接下来会发生什么]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tqI1y-GgtnZnRcgS_8aGbwwWep8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/IJUVLQYLFRLNZJ4CUO2EXGW6DQ.jpg" alt="Partially removed company logo of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen翻译:深圳恒大集团公司标识部分拆除" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A partially removed company logo of China Evergrande Group is seen on the facade of its headquarters in Shenzhen, Guangdong province, China January 10, 2022. REUTERS/David Kirton/File Photo翻译:2022 年 1 月 10 日，在中国广东省深圳市总部的正面，可以看到部分被移除的中国恒大集团公司标志。 REUTERS/David Kirton/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China Evergrande Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a>, the world's most indebted property developer, is seeking to avert a potentially imminent liquidation with a last-minute debt <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-seeks-avoid-liquidation-with-last-ditch-debt-plan-sources-2023-11-30/">restructuring</a> proposal, three people with direct knowledge of the matter said.翻译:三名直接了解情况的人士表示，全球负债最重的房地产开发商中国恒大集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）</a>正在寻求通过最后一刻的债务<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-seeks-avoid-liquidation-with-last-ditch-debt-plan-sources-2023-11-30/">重组</a>方案来避免可能迫在眉睫的清算。</p>   <p>The defaulted company faces a Monday deadline to present a "concrete" revised debt restructuring proposal for offshore creditors. But the sources told Reuters that creditors were unlikely to accept Evergrande's new proposal given low recovery prospects and growing concerns about the developer's future.</p>    <h 1="">WHAT HAPPENS IF THE COURT ORDERS EVERGRANDE LIQUIDATED?</h>  <p>If a liquidation order is issued, a provisional liquidator and then an official liquidator will be appointed to take control and prepare to sell the developer's assets to repay its debts.翻译:如果发出清算令，将任命临时清算人，然后任命正式清算人来接管并准备出售开发商的资产以偿还债务。</p>   <p>The liquidators could propose a new debt restructuring plan to creditors if they determine the company had enough assets or if a white knight investor appeared. They would also investigate the company's affairs and could refer any suspected misconduct by directors to Hong Kong prosecutors.翻译:如果清算人确定公司拥有足够的资产或者白衣骑士投资者出现，他们可以向债权人提出新的债务重组计划。他们还将调查公司的事务，并可以将董事的任何可疑不当行为提交给香港检察官。</p>   <p>Evergrande could appeal a liquidation order, but the liquidation process would proceed pending appeal.翻译:恒大可以对清算令提出上诉，但清算程序将在上诉期间继续进行。</p>   <p>It is unclear if Evergrande shares would be suspended from trading after a liquidation order, but listing rules require a company to demonstrate a business structure with sufficient operations and asset values.翻译:目前尚不清楚恒大股票在清算令后是否会停牌，但上市规则要求公司展示具有足够运营和资产价值的业务结构。</p>   <p>China Oceanwide Holdings <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0715.HK" target="_blank">(0715.HK)</a> suspended its shares in September after a Bermuda Court issued a liquidation order.</p>    <h 1="">HOW MUCH DEBT CAN CREDITORS RECOVER AND WHAT ARE THE MAIN CHALLENGES?</h>  <p>Evergrande cited a Deloitte analysis during a Hong Kong court hearing in July that <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-court-hold-hearings-china-evergrande-restructuring-plan-sept-2023-07-24/">estimated</a> a recovery rate from a restructuring it was then proposing of about 22.5%, compared with 3.4% if the developer were liquidated.翻译:恒大集团在 7 月份的香港法庭听证会上引用了德勤的分析， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/hong-kong-court-hold-hearings-china-evergrande-restructuring-plan-sept-2023-07-24/">估计</a>其当时提议的重组的回收率约为 22.5%，而如果开发商被清算，回收率仅为 3.4%。</p>   <p>However, after Evergrande said in September its flagship unit and its chairman Hui Ka Yan were being <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shares-china-evergrande-suspended-chairman-under-police-watch-2023-09-28/">investigated</a> by the authorities for unspecified "illegal crimes", creditors now expect a recovery rate of less than 3%.翻译:然而，在恒大9月表示其旗舰子公司及其董事长许家印因涉嫌“非法犯罪”而接受当局<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shares-china-evergrande-suspended-chairman-under-police-watch-2023-09-28/">调查</a>后，债权人目前预计追偿率将低于3%。</p>   <p>Evergrande's main offshore assets are its two listed units in Hong Kong - Evergrande Property Services Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">(6666.HK)</a> and Evergrande New Energy Vehicle Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0708.HK" target="_blank">(0708.HK)</a> - as most of its other assets have been sold or seized by creditors.翻译:恒大的主要境外资产是其在香港的两个上市单位——恒大物业服务集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">（6666.HK）</a>和恒大新能源汽车集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0708.HK" target="_blank">（0708.HK）</a> ——而其大部分其他资产已被债权人出售或扣押。</p>   <p>A liquidator could sell Evergrande's holdings in the two units, although it might be difficult to find buyers.翻译:清算人可以出售恒大在这两个单位中的持股，尽管可能很难找到买家。</p>   <p>After a liquidation, the liquidator could take control of Evergrande's subsidiaries in mainland China by replacing their legal representatives, a process that could take months or years.翻译:清算后，清算人可以通过更换法定代表人来控制恒大在中国大陆的子公司，这一过程可能需要数月甚至数年的时间。</p>   <p>Insolvency experts said it would be a challenge for the liquidator to change the representatives as Guangzhou, where Evergrande is based, is not one of the three Chinese cities that mutually recognise liquidation orders with Hong Kong.翻译:破产专家表示，由于恒大总部所在地广州不是与香港相互承认清算令的三个中国城市之一，因此清算人更换代表将是一个挑战。</p>   <p>Even if a liquidator were to take possession of the units that have onshore projects, many of these have already been taken over by creditors, have little value left or are even in negative equity because of falling property prices.翻译:即使清算人要接管拥有陆上项目的单位，但其中许多单位已经被债权人接管，价值所剩无几，甚至因房价下跌而出现负资产。</p>   <p>So far over 53 billion yuan ($7.2 billion) of Evergrande's assets have been seized or frozen across China, local media have reported, citing court records.</p>    <h 1="">HOW SIGNIFICANT WOULD LIQUIDATION BE FOR CHINA'S PROPERTY MARKET?</h>  <p>While a winding-up of the developer with $240 billion of assets would send shockwaves through already fragile capital markets, experts said it would not offer a blueprint on how liquidation might unfold for other embattled developers.翻译:虽然这家拥有 2400 亿美元资产的开发商的清算将对本已脆弱的资本市场产生冲击波，但专家表示，这不会为其他陷入困境的开发商提供清算可能如何展开的蓝图。</p>   <p>Given the sheer size of Evergrande's projects and debt, the process would involve many authorities and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/evergrande-crisis-tests-beijings-fallout-management-creditor-jitters-mount-2023-10-05/">political considerations</a>.翻译:鉴于恒大项目和债务规模庞大，这一过程将涉及许多当局和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/evergrande-crisis-tests-beijings-fallout-management-creditor-jitters-mount-2023-10-05/">政治考虑</a>。</p>   <p>Completing ongoing home construction projects will be a top priority for the company and the sector, even though a liquidation of the property giant could make homebuyers wary of developments by private companies.翻译:完成正在进行的房屋建设项目将是该公司和该行业的首要任务，尽管这家房地产巨头的清算可能会让购房者对私营公司的开发项目保持警惕。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.3170 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.3170 人民币）</p>    <span>Reporting by Clare Jim in Hong Kong and Scott Murdoch in Sydney; Editing by Sumeet Chatterjee, Lincoln Feast and William Mallard翻译:克莱尔·吉姆 (Clare Jim) 在香港的报道和斯科特·默多克 (Scott Murdoch) 在悉尼的报道；编辑：Sumeet Chatterjee、Lincoln Feast 和 William Mallard</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 15:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">PEPKSTLBSJOE3ISZRRT2ZLYP3U</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/possible-evergrande-liquidation-order-what-happens-next-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Clare Jim, Scott Murdoch]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/DEBT</category>
                
                <category>EVERGRANDE (EXPLAINER, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[独家：中国恒大寻求通过最后一搏债务计划避免清算]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/x1Un4BLp4DPSUue4O3jzAcJENxA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/N6SYACE4HVNN7JLTSD4D725HUE.jpg" alt="The company logo is seen on the headquarters of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen翻译:中国恒大集团深圳总部的公司标志" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The company logo is seen on the headquarters of China Evergrande Group in Shenzhen翻译:中国恒大集团深圳总部的公司标志, Guangdong province, China September 26, 2021. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2021年9月26日，该公司标志出现在中国广东省深圳的中国恒大集团总部。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China Evergrande Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">(3333.HK)</a>, the world's most indebted property developer, is seeking to avert a potentially imminent liquidation with a last-minute debt restructuring proposal, three people with direct knowledge of the matter said.翻译:三名直接了解情况的人士表示，全球负债最重的房地产开发商中国恒大集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3333.HK" target="_blank">（3333.HK）</a>正在寻求通过最后一刻的债务重组方案来避免可能迫在眉睫的清算。</p>   <p>The defaulted company has until a Hong Kong court <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-faces-winding-up-challenge-hong-kong-court-2023-10-29/">hearing</a> on Monday to present a "concrete" revised debt restructuring proposal for offshore creditors, a judge said last month after its <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/evergrande-proposes-offshore-creditors-get-30-equity-stake-subsidiaries-sources-2023-11-01/">original plan</a> had lapsed.翻译:上个月，在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/evergrande-proposes-offshore-creditors-get-30-equity-stake-subsidiaries-sources-2023-11-01/">原计划</a>失效后，一名法官表示，这家违约公司必须在周一香港法庭<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-faces-winding-up-challenge-hong-kong-court-2023-10-29/">听证会</a>之前向离岸债权人提交一份“具体的”修订后的债务重组方案。</p>   <p>But the sources, who declined to be named as the talks are private, told Reuters that creditors were <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/possible-evergrande-liquidation-order-what-happens-next-2023-11-30/">unlikely</a> to accept Evergrande's new proposal given low recovery prospects and growing concerns about the developer's future.翻译:但由于谈判是私下进行而不愿透露姓名的消息人士告诉路透社，鉴于复苏前景黯淡以及对开发商未来的担忧日益加剧，债权人<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/possible-evergrande-liquidation-order-what-happens-next-2023-11-30/">不太可能</a>接受恒大的新提议。</p>   <p>With more than $300 billion in liabilities, Evergrande exemplifies a crisis in China's property sector, which makes up one-quarter of the world's second-biggest economy. The authorities have scrambled to support the sector as the troubles of embattled developers roiled global markets.翻译:恒大集团的负债超过3000亿美元，是中国房地产业危机的典型例子，而中国房地产业占世界第二大经济体的四分之一。由于陷入困境的开发商的麻烦扰乱了全球市场，当局已争先恐后地支持该行业。</p>   <p>Guangzhou-based Evergrande, which defaulted on its offshore debt in late 2021, did not respond to a request for comment.翻译:总部位于广州的恒大集团于 2021 年底出现离岸债务违约，该公司没有回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Ahead of the hearing when the Hong Kong High Court will rule on a liquidation petition, Evergrande this week offered to swap some debt held by offshore creditors into equity in the company and two Hong Kong-listed units, and repay the rest with non-tradeable "certificates" backed by offshore assets, two sources said.翻译:在香港高等法院就清算申请作出裁决之前，恒大集团本周提出将境外债权人持有的部分债务转换为该公司和两家香港上市公司的股权，并以非流通股偿还剩余部分。两位消息人士称，这些“证书”由离岸资产支持。</p>   <p>The offshore assets include the developer's minority stakes in other companies and its receivables, one of the two sources said, and the certificates would be redeemed by Evergrande when it successfully disposes of the assets. The plan is not expected to require regulatory approval, as Chinese regulators have banned the developer from issuing new bonds, he added.翻译:两位消息人士之一表示，离岸资产包括开发商在其他公司的少数股权及其应收账款，恒大成功处置这些资产后将赎回这些凭证。他补充说，该计划预计不需要监管部门批准，因为中国监管机构已禁止开发商发行新债券。</p>   <p>The new proposal also offers creditors a 17.8% stake in Evergrande, in addition to an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/evergrande-proposes-offshore-creditors-get-30-equity-stake-subsidiaries-sources-2023-11-01/">October offer</a>, previously reported by Reuters, of 30% stakes in each of its two Hong Kong units - Evergrande Property Services Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">(6666.HK)</a> and Evergrande New Energy Vehicle Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0708.HK" target="_blank">(0708.HK)</a> - the person said.翻译:新提案还向债权人提出了恒大17.8%的股份，此外，据路透社此前报道，债权人在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/evergrande-proposes-offshore-creditors-get-30-equity-stake-subsidiaries-sources-2023-11-01/">10月份</a>提出了恒大物业服务集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/6666.HK" target="_blank">（6666.HK）</a>和恒大新城两个香港子公司各30%的股份。新能源汽车集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/0708.HK" target="_blank">（0708.HK）</a> ——上述人士表示。</p>   <p>Many creditors were dissatisfied with the October terms as they implied a major haircut on investments, sources have said, forcing Evergrande to scramble to sweeten the deal in what could be its final attempt to avoid liquidation.</p>    <h 1="">LIQUIDATION CHALLENGES</h>  <p>The spectre of a messy collapse of Evergrande has been a major concern for global investors as the Chinese economy sputters, with property sales slowing and hundreds of thousands of unfinished homes across the country.翻译:随着中国经济陷入低迷，房地产销售放缓，全国各地有数十万套未完工房屋，恒大集团混乱倒闭的担忧一直是全球投资者的主要担忧。</p>   <p>Chinese authorities have announced a string of measures to revive the sector destabilised by the debt woes of giants like Evergrande and Country Garden <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">(2007.HK)</a>.翻译:中国当局宣布了一系列措施，以重振因恒大和碧桂园<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">（2007.HK）</a>等巨头的债务危机而不稳定的行业。</p>   <p>Evergrande's debt revamp hopes were derailed in late September when the company said billionaire founder Hui Ka Yan was under <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shares-china-evergrande-suspended-chairman-under-police-watch-2023-09-28/">investigation</a> for unspecified "illegal crimes".翻译:恒大集团的债务重组希望在9月下旬落空，当时该公司表示亿万富翁创始人许家印因未具体说明的“非法犯罪”正在接受<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/shares-china-evergrande-suspended-chairman-under-police-watch-2023-09-28/">调查</a>。</p>   <p>The developer was banned from issuing dollar bonds, a key part of the restructuring plan, and its flagship mainland unit was put under investigation by regulators.翻译:该开发商被禁止发行美元债券，这是重组计划的关键部分，其大陆旗舰子公司也受到监管机构的调查。</p>   <p>If the Hong Kong court orders Evergrande's liquidation, a provisional liquidator and then an official liquidator would be appointed to take control and arrange to sell the company's assets to repay its debts.翻译:如果香港法院下令恒大清算，将任命一名临时清算人，然后任命一名正式清算人来接管公司并安排出售公司资产以偿还债务。</p>   <p>In addition to shares of its two Hong Kong-listed units, this would include selling its onshore assets, which could face significant challenges, restructuring experts say.翻译:重组专家表示，除了出售其在香港上市的两家子公司的股票外，这还包括出售其境内资产，这可能面临重大挑战。</p>   <p>A lawyer for an ad hoc group of key offshore bondholders told the Hong Kong court last month that the restructuring plan could have a higher recovery rate for creditors than liquidation, in which they would get back less than 3%.翻译:一个由主要离岸债券持有人组成的特别小组的律师上个月向香港法院表示，重组计划对债权人的回收率可能高于清算，而清算时债权人的回收率将低于 3%。</p>   <p>Still, the group has nominated consultancy Alvarez &amp; Marsal as its preferred liquidator, two other sources said, as creditors anticipate a potential liquidation of Evergrande, whose liabilities and assets are largely in mainland China.翻译:另外两名消息人士称，尽管如此，该集团仍提名咨询公司 Alvarez &amp; Marsal 作为其首选清算人，因为债权人预计恒大可能会被清算，而恒大的负债和资产主要位于中国大陆。</p>   <p>Alvarez &amp; Marsal did not immediately respond to request for comment.翻译:Alvarez &amp; Marsal 没有立即回应置评请求。</p>   <p>Top Shine, an investor in Evergrande unit Fangchebao, filed the liquidation petition in June 2022 after it said the developer failed to honour an agreement to repurchase shares the investor had bought in the subsidiary.翻译:恒大旗下房车宝的投资者Top Shine于2022年6月提交了清算申请，此前该公司称该开发商未能履行回购其投资者所购买的子公司股份的协议。</p>    <span>Reporting by Clare Jim and Xie Yu in Hong Kong, Scott Murdoch in Sydney; Editing by Sumeet Chatterjee and William Mallard翻译:克莱尔·吉姆和谢宇在香港报道，斯科特·默多克在悉尼报道；编辑：Sumeet Chatterjee 和 William Mallard</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 15:38:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">VXGPWSZ4VBKA3FVE3FOZFFB7GQ</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-evergrande-seeks-avoid-liquidation-with-last-ditch-debt-plan-sources-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Clare Jim, Scott Murdoch, Yu Xie]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPERTY/DEBT</category>
                
                <category>EVERGRANDE (EXCLUSIVE, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[耶伦参观北卡罗来纳州锂厂以支持拜登对美国经济的看法]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/hR7_mfA1qWi1H_2qiF7w99ZrZ58=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/S4LYR5QTWRJUZGS2CXCHS3W4UE.jpg" alt="U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen in San Francisco翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦在旧金山" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen attends a press conference in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 10, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria/File Photo翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦于 2023 年 11 月 10 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山出席新闻发布会。路透社/卡洛斯·巴里亚/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen travels to North Carolina on Thursday to tout hundreds of billions of dollars worth of new clean energy investments enabled by U.S. tax incentives as President Joe Biden struggles to win voter credit for their benefits.翻译:美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦周四前往北卡罗来纳州，宣传美国税收优惠政策带来的价值数千亿美元的新清洁能源投资，而总统乔·拜登则在努力赢得选民的信任。</p>   <p>Yellen will tour a Livent Corp <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LTHM.N" target="_blank">(LTHM.N)</a> facility in Bessemer City, North Carolina, that processes lithium hydroxide, a key ingredient in electric vehicle batteries. The plant near Charlotte is doubling its capacity due to increased demand for electric vehicles spurred by consumer tax credits of up $7,500 approved in the 2022 Inflation Reduction Act.翻译:耶伦将参观位于北卡罗来纳州贝塞默城的 Livent Corp <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LTHM.N" target="_blank">(LTHM.N)</a>工厂，该工厂负责加工电动汽车电池的关键成分氢氧化锂。由于 2022 年通货膨胀削减法案批准的高达 7,500 美元的消费者税收抵免刺激了电动汽车需求的增加，夏洛特附近的工厂正在将产能翻倍。</p>   <p>In excerpts of remarks to be delivered at the plant, Yellen said similar investments were taking place across the country, with $614 billion worth of clean energy investments and manufacturing projects announced since the Biden administration took office in 2021. These include $142 billion in EVs and batteries and $71 billion in clean energy manufacturing, and she attributed much of the investment to tax credits in the inflation reduction act.翻译:耶伦在工厂发表的讲话节选中表示，类似的投资正在全国各地进行，自拜登政府 2021 年上任以来，宣布了价值 6,140 亿美元的清洁能源投资和制造项目。其中包括 1,420 亿美元的电动汽车和电池和 710 亿美元的清洁能源制造，她将大部分投资归因于《通货膨胀削减法案》中的税收抵免。</p>   <p>"We're seeing the emergence of a battery belt across the Midwest and South," Yellen said, adding that this would bolster U.S. energy security reducing American dependence on China's EV battery supply chain.翻译:耶伦表示：“我们看到横跨中西部和南部的电池带正在兴起。”他补充说，这将加强美国的能源安全，减少美国对中国电动汽车电池供应链的依赖。</p>   <p>The Biden administration in coming days is expected to release new guidance on the levels of Chinese content that EV batteries can have and still qualify for IRA tax credits. The Livent plant processes lithium brine largely from Argentina and Canada.翻译:拜登政府预计将在未来几天发布关于电动汽车电池可以含有的中国含量水平并仍然有资格获得 IRA 税收抵免的新指南。 Livent 工厂主要加工来自阿根廷和加拿大的锂盐水。</p>   <p>Yellen said the bulk of investments spurred by the legislation was flowing to counties with below-average college graduation rates, providing good jobs "where they are most needed."</p>    <h 1="">STRONG GROWTH, LITTLE CREDIT</h>  <p>Increased investment in new manufacturing projects, machinery and warehouses, which also include new semiconductor plants, helped the U.S. economy to grow at a torrid <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-third-quarter-economic-growth-revised-up-52-2023-11-29/">5.2% annual pace</a> in the third quarter, defying predictions earlier this year that it was headed for a recession.翻译:对新制造项目、机械和仓库（其中还包括新半导体工厂）的投资增加，帮助美国经济在第三季度以<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-third-quarter-economic-growth-revised-up-52-2023-11-29/">年增长率 5.2% 的速度</a>增长，打破了今年早些时候美国经济将走向衰退的预测。</p>   <p>But Biden has struggled to win voter confidence in his handling of the economy, with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/biden-trails-trump-states-likely-decide-2024-us-election-polls-show-2023-11-05/">polls earlier this month</a> showing Republican frontrunner Donald Trump ahead in five of the six most important battleground states.翻译:但拜登一直在努力赢得选民对他处理经济的信心， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/biden-trails-trump-states-likely-decide-2024-us-election-polls-show-2023-11-05/">本月早些时候的民意调查</a>显示，共和党领跑者唐纳德·特朗普在六个最重要的战场州中的五个州领先。</p>   <p>Voters remain deeply scarred by the higher living costs brought about by post-pandemic inflation, said Larry Sabato, director of the University of Virginia's Center for Politics. It will take time for this to fade and for people to feel the benefits of higher wages, he added.翻译:弗吉尼亚大学政治中心主任拉里·萨巴托说，选民仍然对大流行后通货膨胀带来的生活成本上升深感不安。他补充说，这种情况需要一段时间才能消退，人们才能感受到更高工资的好处。</p>   <p>"People are hearing that things are getting much better, inflation is coming down and we're not coming into a recession," Sabato said. "But in their lives every week, when they go to the gas station or into the grocery store, they still perceive higher prices, and their minds are oriented to bad news. And people are going to blame the president."翻译:萨巴托说：“人们听说情况正在好转，通货膨胀正在下降，我们不会陷入衰退。” “但在他们的生活中，每周，当他们去加油站或杂货店时，他们仍然会感知到更高的价格，并且他们的思想会转向坏消息。人们会责怪总统。”</p>    <span>Reporting by David Lawder and Howard Schneider; Editing by Chizu Nomiyama翻译:大卫·劳德和霍华德·施奈德的报道；编辑：野宫千津</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 14:53:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">44ARSCLL2JJKVHWHG3O2VAFOAE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/yellen-tours-north-carolina-lithium-plant-bolster-bidens-case-us-economy-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Lawder, Howard Schneider]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>TREASURY/YELLEN</category>
                
                <category>BATTERIES (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[消息人士称，12月份俄罗斯西部港口的石油装载量将下降6%]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Guu_74lCvAzp_Mp1C--jWDHKhcI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/MXNFZOZABVICDAOGCYVF3CCKJI.jpg" alt="A general view shows the Novorossiysk Fuel Oil Terminal in Novorossiisk翻译:新罗西斯克燃油码头全景图" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A general view shows the Novorossiysk Fuel Oil Terminal (NMT) in the Black Sea port of Novorossiisk, Russia May 30, 2018. Picture taken May 30, 2018. REUTERS/Natalya Chumakova/File Photo翻译:2018年5月30日，俄罗斯新罗西斯克黑海港口的新罗西斯克燃油码头（NMT）全景。照片拍摄于2018年5月30日。REUTERS/Natalya Chumakova/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Russia's planned oil loadings from its western ports are set to decline 6% in December from November to 1.9 million barrels per day (bpd), market sources said and Reuters calculations showed.翻译:市场消息人士称，路透社的计算显示，俄罗斯西部港口计划的 12 月份石油装载量预计将比 11 月份减少 6%，至 190 万桶/日。</p>   <p>Russia's oil shipments from its western ports of Primorsk, Ust-Luga and Novorossiisk are set to be lower <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/russias-western-oil-exports-set-decline-dec-amid-ample-refining-plans-traders-2023-11-22/">in December</a> amid record refinery runs planned for next month and a recent lifting of the state's fuel export ban, traders said.翻译:交易商表示，由于计划下个月炼油厂开工量创纪录，且该州最近取消了燃料出口禁令， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/russias-western-oil-exports-set-decline-dec-amid-ample-refining-plans-traders-2023-11-22/">12月份</a>俄罗斯西部港口普里莫尔斯克、乌斯季卢加和新罗西斯克的石油发货量预计将下降。</p>   <p>Actual oil loadings from Russia's western ports are likely to be above the plan in December as significant volumes meant to be loaded in November will be carried over because of storms in the Black Sea region, traders said.翻译:交易商表示，俄罗斯西部港口12月份的实际石油装载量可能会高于计划，因为由于黑海地区的风暴，原定于11月份装载的大量石油将被结转。</p>   <p>Severe storms have disrupted up to 2 million bpd of oil exports from Kazakhstan and Russia since last Friday.翻译:自上周五以来，严重的风暴已扰乱哈萨克斯坦和俄罗斯多达 200 万桶/日的石油出口。</p>   <p>The delay in oil exports and transit from Novorossiisk port for November exceeded 1 million metric tons as of Wednesday. The port remained shut on Thursday, traders said, so these volumes have to be carried over to December.翻译:截至周三，11月份新罗西斯克港石油出口和过境延误量超过100万吨。贸易商表示，该港口周四仍处于关闭状态，因此这些数量必须结转至 12 月。</p>   <p>Oil producers are seeking to redirect December oil flows from Novorossiisk to other export destinations, in particular to Russia's Baltic ports and the Druzhba pipeline.翻译:石油生产商正在寻求将12月份的石油从新罗西斯克转移到其他出口目的地，特别是俄罗斯的波罗的海港口和德鲁日巴管道。</p>   <p>It was not clear if redirection of flows in December will result in changes to the overall export plan.翻译:目前尚不清楚 12 月份的资金流向调整是否会导致总体出口计划发生变化。</p>   <p>Russia does not disclose its ports' planned export volumes.翻译:俄罗斯没有透露其港口的计划出口量。</p>    <span>Reporting by Reuters
Editing by Sharon Singleton and David Goodman
翻译:路透社报道莎朗·辛格尔顿和大卫·古德曼编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 13:45:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">F2GCYCYBMFMA5GZNAKXSJJAI4Q</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/russias-oil-loadings-western-ports-decline-6-december-sources-reuters-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>RUSSIA</category>
                
                <category>OIL/EXPORTS (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国电动汽车制造商Zeekr暂停美国IPO——消息人士]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/isBe0IBRFwA4eM42jPY81Jc1rVY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CV7TH7NCVBPTTMD7I3TU5YBIJE.jpg" alt="People walk past a booth of Zeekr, Chinese automaker Geely's premium electric vehicle (EV) brand, at a shopping mall in Beijing翻译:在北京的一家购物中心，人们走过中国汽车制造商吉利旗下的高端电动汽车 (EV) 品牌 Zeekr 的展位" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk past a booth of Zeekr, Chinese automaker Geely's premium electric vehicle (EV) brand, at a shopping mall in Beijing翻译:在北京的一家购物中心，人们走过中国汽车制造商吉利旗下的高端电动汽车 (EV) 品牌 Zeekr 的展位, China November 3, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 3 日，在中国北京的一家购物中心，人们走过中国汽车制造商吉利旗下的高端电动汽车 (EV) 品牌 Zeekr 的展位。路透社/Tingshu Wang/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Zeekr, the premium electric vehicle (EV) brand of Chinese automaker Geely, has put its U.S. initial public offering (IPO) on hold because of a mismatch in valuation expectations, two sources with direct knowledge of the matter said.翻译:两位直接了解情况的消息人士称，中国汽车制造商吉利旗下的高端电动汽车 (EV) 品牌 Zeekr 由于估值预期不匹配，已暂停其在美国的首次公开募股 (IPO)。</p>   <p>The decision was made as global financial markets remain volatile, a third source added. All the sources declined to be identified as the information has not yet been made public.翻译:第三位消息人士补充说，这一决定是在全球金融市场仍然波动的情况下做出的。由于信息尚未公开，所有消息人士均拒绝透露姓名。</p>   <p>Zeekr, which publicly filed a prospectus this month to float shares in New York, has aimed to maintain the valuation of $13 billion it achieved in a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/geelys-ev-brand-zeekr-raises-750-mln-fresh-funding-round-2023-02-12/">private fundraising</a> exercise in February, two of the sources said.翻译:两位消息人士称，Zeekr 本月公开提交了在纽约上市的招股说明书，其目标是维持 2 月份<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/geelys-ev-brand-zeekr-raises-750-mln-fresh-funding-round-2023-02-12/">私募融资</a>活动中 130 亿美元的估值。</p>   <p>But informal talks with potential investors since late August saw some of them put a valuation on the two-year-old firm below the IPO figure, as market sentiment was still weak and the company recently widened losses, they added.翻译:但他们补充说，自 8 月底以来，在与潜在投资者的非正式会谈中，一些投资者对这家成立两年的公司的估值低于 IPO 数字，因为市场情绪仍然疲软，而且该公司最近亏损扩大。</p>   <p>"The company has made a public filing to the SEC and is proceeding with the preparatory work," Zeekr said in a statement, without elaborating.翻译:Zeekr 在一份声明中表示：“该公司已向 SEC 公开提交文件，并正在进行准备工作，”但没有详细说明。</p>   <p>Zeekr's prospectus <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinas-zeekr-reveals-revenue-surge-updated-financials-ahead-us-ipo-2023-11-24/">disclosed</a> a surge in total revenue to 35.31 billion yuan ($4.9 billion) in the nine months ended Sept. 30, up from 18.47 billion a year earlier. However, its loss from operations widened to 5.23 billion yuan from 4.90 billion.翻译:Zeekr 的招股说明书<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/chinas-zeekr-reveals-revenue-surge-updated-financials-ahead-us-ipo-2023-11-24/">披露，</a>截至 9 月 30 日的 9 个月内，总收入从去年同期的 184.7 亿元激增至 353.1 亿元人民币（49 亿美元）。然而，其经营亏损从49亿元扩大至52.3亿元。</p>   <p>Some listed peers, such as EV maker Nio, have seen share prices fluctuate or fall in recent months as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-auto-workers-bear-brunt-price-war-fallout-widens-2023-09-05/">a price war</a> in China has hit profitability, spurring efforts to cut costs and build partnerships to survive the consolidating competition.翻译:近几个月来，电动汽车制造商蔚来等一些上市同行的股价出现波动或下跌，原因是中国的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/chinas-auto-workers-bear-brunt-price-war-fallout-widens-2023-09-05/">价格战</a>影响了盈利能力，促使人们努力削减成本和建立合作伙伴关系，以在巩固的竞争中生存下来。</p>   <p>Citing sources, Reuters reported in December that Zeekr had <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/geelys-premium-electric-car-brand-zeekr-seeks-over-1-billion-us-ipo-sources-2022-12-12/">confidentially filed</a> for its IPO, aiming to raise more than $1 billion and go public in New York as early as the second quarter of this year.翻译:路透社去年 12 月援引消息人士的话称，Zeekr 已<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/geelys-premium-electric-car-brand-zeekr-seeks-over-1-billion-us-ipo-sources-2022-12-12/">秘密申请</a>IPO，旨在筹集超过 10 亿美元资金，并最早于今年第二季度在纽约上市。</p>   <p>Sources told Reuters this month that Zeekr still aimed to raise at least $500 million in the IPO before stepping on the brakes.翻译:消息人士本月告诉路透社，Zeekr 仍计划在 IPO 中筹集至少 5 亿美元，然后再踩刹车。</p>   <p>Zeekr was formed in 2021 by Geely, formally known as Zhejiang Geely Holding Group, to tap growing Chinese demand for premium EVs.翻译:Zeekr 由吉利（原名浙江吉利控股集团）于 2021 年成立，旨在满足中国对高端电动汽车日益增长的需求。</p>   <p>In February, it raised $750 million from investors including Amnon Shashua, the CEO of autonomous driving technology company Mobileye Global <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MBLY.O" target="_blank">(MBLY.O)</a> and Chinese battery giant CATL <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300750.SZ" target="_blank">(300750.SZ)</a>.翻译:今年2月，它从自动驾驶技术公司Mobileye Global <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MBLY.O" target="_blank">（MBLY.O）</a>和中国电池巨头CATL <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/300750.SZ" target="_blank">（300750.SZ）</a>首席执行官Amnon Shashua等投资者那里筹集了7.5亿美元。</p>   <p>Zeekr offers four EV models in China, with its best seller, the 001 crossover, priced from 269,000 yuan ($36,927.22).翻译:Zeekr 在中国提供四种电动车型，其中最畅销的是 001 跨界车，售价 269,000 元人民币（36,927.22 美元）起。</p>   <p>It also plans to sell in overseas markets, such as Germany, Israel, Kazakhstan, the Netherlands and Sweden, among others.翻译:它还计划在德国、以色列、哈萨克斯坦、荷兰和瑞典等海外市场销售。</p>    <span>Reporting by Julie Zhu and Scott Murdoch; Additional reporting by Kane Wuy; Editing by Christopher Cushing and Clarence Fernandez翻译:朱莉·朱和斯科特·默多克的报道； Kane Wuy 的补充报道；克里斯托弗·库欣和克拉伦斯·费尔南德斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 10:44:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MQTC7I2AQJNOPIMS5VG4FCWYDI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/china-ev-brand-zeekr-puts-us-ipo-hold-sources-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Julie Zhu, Scott Murdoch]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ZEEKR</category>
                
                <category>IPO/ (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国将对澳大利亚葡萄酒进口反补贴关税进行审查]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/_8AD1kQNps_P28eMV7Uvj-0Lvo4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/W567H44ZIFN6XADQEMQTMQWWZY.jpg" alt="Wine bar in Beijing翻译:北京的酒吧" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A staff member sniffs wine in a glass while a customer watches at  theTrio Wine Bar in Beijing, China November 1, 2023. REUTERS/Florence Lo/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 1 日，中国北京，Trio 酒吧，一名工作人员在嗅着玻璃杯中的葡萄酒，而一名顾客正在观看。路透社/Florence Lo/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China said on Thursday it would review the need for anti-dumping and anti-subsidy tariffs on Australian wine imports, a highly anticipated move that is part of a push to improve <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-wine-market-ready-welcome-likely-return-aussie-wine-ties-improve-2023-11-03/">the relationship</a> between the two countries.翻译:中国周四表示，将审查对澳大利亚进口葡萄酒征收反倾销和反补贴关税的必要性，这一备受期待的举措是推动改善两国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-wine-market-ready-welcome-likely-return-aussie-wine-ties-improve-2023-11-03/">关系的</a>一部分。</p>   <p>The Commerce Ministry said in a statement it had decided to conduct the review from Thursday.翻译:商务部在一份声明中表示，决定从周四开始进行审查。</p>   <p>Last month, China and Australia said they had reached a consensus to settle a World Trade Organisation dispute about wine, and that the anti-dumping tariffs, set to expire in 2026, would be reviewed.翻译:上个月，中国和澳大利亚表示，双方已就解决世界贸易组织有关葡萄酒的争端达成共识，并将对将于 2026 年到期的反倾销关税进行审查。</p>   <p>"The Ministry of Commerce will carry out a review in accordance with the law to fully protect the rights of all stakeholders," Shu Jueting, a commerce ministry spokesperson, told a regular news conference in Beijing.翻译:商务部新闻发言人舒珏廷在北京举行的例行新闻发布会上表示，“商务部将依法开展审查，充分保障各利益相关方的权利。”</p>   <p>"We will adjudicate objectively, fairly and openly based on the claims of each interested party and after examining the evidence," she added.翻译:她补充说：“我们将根据各方的主张，在审查证据后，客观、公正、公开地做出裁决。”</p>   <p>The ministry said any interested parties or stakeholders may submit comments in writing within 20 days.翻译:该部表示，任何利益相关方或利益相关者可以在 20 天内提交书面意见。</p>   <p>The introduction of a 218% tax on most Australian wine introduced by China in 2021 prompted <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-wine-market-ready-welcome-likely-return-aussie-wine-ties-improve-2023-11-03/">that trade</a>, previously valued as high as $1.2 billion annually, to collapse.翻译:2021年，中国对大多数澳大利亚葡萄酒征收218%的税，导致此前每年价值高达12亿美元<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/chinas-wine-market-ready-welcome-likely-return-aussie-wine-ties-improve-2023-11-03/">的贸易</a>崩溃。</p>   <p>"This is good news for the thousands of Australians who work in the wine industry," a spokesperson from the Australian Trade Minister's Office said.翻译:澳大利亚贸易部长办公室发言人表示：“这对于成千上万在葡萄酒行业工作的澳大利亚人来说是个好消息。”</p>   <p>Since the expedited removal of duties on Australian barley, the government has engaged actively with China to secure a similar process to resolve the dispute on wine, the spokesperson added.翻译:该发言人补充说，自从加快取消对澳大利亚大麦的关税以来，政府一直积极与中国接触，以确保采取类似的程序来解决葡萄酒争端。</p>   <p>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has sought to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-albanese-china-seeks-dialogue-cooperation-2023-11-05/">improve ties</a> with major trade partner China which had deteriorated over several years due to disputes over Chinese telecoms firm Huawei, espionage and COVID-19.翻译:澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内塞一直寻求<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australias-albanese-china-seeks-dialogue-cooperation-2023-11-05/">改善与主要贸易伙伴中国的关系</a>，这种关系多年来因中国电信公司华为、间谍活动和新冠肺炎 (COVID-19) 问题而恶化。</p>   <p>Albanese became the first sitting Australia leader to visit China since 2016 when he travelled to Beijing in early November.翻译:阿尔巴内斯于11月初访问北京，成为自2016年以来第一位访问中国的澳大利亚在任领导人。</p>    <span>Reporting by Albee Zhang, Bernard Orr and Joe Cash in Beijing, Lewis Jackson in Sydney; Editing by Jacqueline Wong, Miral Fahmy and Raju Gopalakrishnan翻译:Albee 张、伯纳德·奥尔和乔·卡什在北京报道，刘易斯·杰克逊在悉尼报道；编辑：Jacqueline Wong、Miral Fahmy 和 Raju Gopalakrishnan</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 10:11:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">YMS43P6SKNJWVHURNH5CNFN6P4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-review-anti-subsidy-tariffs-australia-wine-imports-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>AUSTRALIA/ (UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[习近平就基辛格逝世向拜登致唁电]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/JS6u5MeZn7GwEzPCLaOi9h6zdJk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YRPSRQEDIJP35ITHMFOUSGQA6Y.jpg" alt="Former U.S. Secretary of State Henry Kissinger meets Chinese President Xi Jinping at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing翻译:美国前国务卿亨利·基辛格在北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Former U.S. Secretary of State Henry Kissinger meets Chinese President Xi Jinping (not pictured) at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, China, November 8, 2018. REUTERS/Thomas Peter/Pool/File Photo翻译:2018 年 11 月 8 日，美国前国务卿亨利·基辛格在中国北京人民大会堂会见中国国家主席习近平（无照片）。 REUTERS/Thomas Peter/Pool/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/h8K9rvcTOlMDsItH7dbcy6GjUDk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DYJROE5VJJNAPCIE54CJRVX6P4.jpg" alt="Chinese President Xi is introduced by former U.S. National Security Advisor and Secretary of State Kissinger at a policy speech to Chinese and U.S. CEOs during a dinner reception in Seattle, Washington翻译:美国前国家安全顾问兼国务卿基辛格在华盛顿西雅图举行的晚宴上向中美首席执行官发表政策演讲，介绍中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping (L) is introduced by former U.S. National Security Advisor and Secretary of State Henry Kissinger at a policy speech to Chinese and United States CEOs during a dinner reception in Seattle, Washington, U.S. September 22, 2015. REUTERS/Jason Redmond/File Photo翻译:2015 年 9 月 22 日，美国华盛顿西雅图，美国前国家安全顾问兼国务卿亨利·基辛格在晚宴上向中美两国首席执行官发表政策演讲，介绍了中国国家主席习近平（左）。 REUTERS/Jason Redmond /档案照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>China's President Xi Jinping and senior Chinese officials have sent messages of condolence to U.S. President Joe Biden and others after the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/henry-kissinger-american-diplomat-nobel-winner-dead-100-2023-11-30/">passing</a> of veteran U.S. diplomat Henry Kissinger, the Chinese foreign ministry said on Thursday.翻译:中国外交部周四表示，在美国资深外交官亨利·基辛格<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/henry-kissinger-american-diplomat-nobel-winner-dead-100-2023-11-30/">去世</a>后，中国国家主席习近平和中国高级官员已向美国总统乔·拜登等人致唁电。</p>   <p>Kissinger, who visited China more than 100 times and last <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/chinas-president-xi-meets-with-henry-kissinger-beijing-2023-07-20/">met with Xi</a> during a surprise trip to Beijing in July, died on Wednesday aged 100, prompting widespread mourning among ordinary Chinese people on social media.翻译:基辛格曾访问中国100多次，最后一次<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/chinas-president-xi-meets-with-henry-kissinger-beijing-2023-07-20/">与习近平</a>会面是在7月份出人意料的北京之行。基辛格于周三去世，享年100岁，引发了社交媒体上普通中国民众的广泛哀悼。</p>   <p>"Dr. Kissinger was a good old friend of the Chinese people. He is a pioneer and builder of Sino-U.S. relations," ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin said at a regular news conference.翻译:外交部发言人汪文斌在例行记者会上表示，基辛格博士是中国人民的好老朋友，是中美关系的开拓者和建设者。</p>   <p>Kissinger made "historic" contributions to the normalisation of China-U.S. relations, and Chinese people will remember him for his "sincere devotion and important contribution", Wang added.翻译:王补充道，基辛格为中美关系正常化做出了“历史性”贡献，中国人民将铭记他的“真诚奉献和重要贡献”。</p>   <p>Chinese Premier Li Qiang and Foreign Minister Wang Yi also sent messages of condolence to Kissinger's family and U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken, respectively, Wang told the briefing.翻译:中国国务院总理李强、外交部长王毅也分别向基辛格家属和美国国务卿布林肯致唁电。</p>   <p>Kissinger believed China-U.S. relations are vital to the peace and prosperity of the two countries and the wider world, Wang Wenbin said.翻译:汪文斌表示，基辛格认为，中美关系对两国和世界的和平与繁荣至关重要。</p>   <p>"China and the U.S. should carry forward Kissinger's strategic vision, political courage and diplomatic wisdom... and promote the sound, stable and sustainable development of China-U.S. relations," he said.翻译:中美双方应弘扬基辛格的战略远见、政治勇气、外交智慧……推动中美关系健康稳定可持续发展。</p>   <p>Kissinger, who served as secretary of state and national security adviser in the administrations of Presidents Richard Nixon and Gerald Ford, first visited Beijing in 1971, paving the way for the U.S. diplomatic opening to China.翻译:基辛格曾在理查德·尼克松和杰拉尔德·福特总统的政府中担任国务卿和国家安全顾问，他于1971年首次访问北京，为美国对华外交开放铺平了道路。</p>   <p>His death was widely mourned by Chinese state media and social media users.翻译:中国官方媒体和社交媒体用户广泛哀悼他的去世。</p>   <p>"The overarching impression of Kissinger (in China) was that he was someone in America who understood the Chinese people," said Brian Wong, an assistant professor and geopolitical strategist at Hong Kong University.翻译:香港大学助理教授兼地缘政治战略家布莱恩·黄(Brian Wong)表示：“基辛格（在中国）的总体印象是，他是一位了解中国人民的美国人。”</p>   <p>Kissinger was seen as an outsider who understood China's need to transcend its self-imposed isolation in the 1960s and early 1970s, Wong said.翻译:黄说，基辛格被视为一个局外人，他理解中国需要超越 20 世纪 60 年代和 1970 年代初自我施加的孤立。</p>   <p>"So, in short, he was seen as someone who, crucially, stood for a 'China understander'."翻译:“因此，简而言之，最重要的是，他被视为‘中国理解者’的代表。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Liz Lee, Ethan Wang and Nicoco Chan; Editing by Kim Coghill and Gareth Jones翻译:Liz Lee、Ethan Wang 和 Nicoco Chan 的报道；金·科吉尔和加雷斯·琼斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 09:18:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">O2KHNXEVG5PJHMMFG57AF7S3XM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/chinas-xi-sends-condolences-biden-over-kissingers-death-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>PEOPLE</category>
                
                <category>HENRY KISSINGER/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>BIDEN (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国中金公司分析师被告知不要发表悲观观点，穿奢侈品——备忘录]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/nIyY0VZFfXBfnWruHLfFTwSdDQs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2CYA2YPJCBO7NNHQ4BRBZGM7ZQ.jpg" alt="The company logo of China International Capital Corporation Ltd is displayed at a news conference on the company's annual results in Hong Kong翻译:中国国际金融有限公司的公司标志出现在香港举行的公司年度业绩新闻发布会上" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The company logo of China International Capital Corporation Ltd (CICC), China’s first joint venture investment bank, is displayed at a news conference on the company's annual results in Hong Kong, China March 30, 2016. REUTERS/Bobby Yip/File Photo翻译:2016年3月30日，中国第一家合资投资银行中国国际金融有限公司（中金公司）的公司标志出现在中国香港举行的公司年度业绩新闻发布会上。路透社/Bobby Yip/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China International Capital Corp (CICC) <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3908.HK" target="_blank">(3908.HK)</a>, the country's third-largest investment bank by market value, has told analysts not to publish bearish views on China's economy or its financial markets, according to an internal memo seen by Reuters.翻译:据路透社看到的一份内部备忘录，中国市值第三大投资银行中国国际金融公司（中金公司） <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/3908.HK" target="_blank">（3908.HK）</a>已告知分析师不要发表对中国经济或金融市场的悲观看法。</p>   <p>The memo, which was sent to the bank's research department, also told them to refrain from commenting on issues that are not in line with government policies.翻译:这份发送给该银行研究部门的备忘录还告诉他们不要对不符合政府政策的问题发表评论。</p>   <p>Additionally, staff at the state-owned investment bank have been asked to not wear luxury brands or disclose their pay. Employees should "make sure their family members adhere to social and ethical standards", the memo said.翻译:此外，这家国有投资银行的员工被要求不得穿着奢侈品牌或透露自己的薪酬。备忘录称，员工应“确保其家庭成员遵守社会和道德标准”。</p>   <p>CICC did not respond to Reuters' request for comments.翻译:中金公司没有回应路透社的置评请求。</p>   <p>Bloomberg first reported the memo on Thursday.翻译:彭博社周四首先报道了这份备忘录。</p>   <p>CICC, the most active Chinese investment bank in offshore dealmaking, also said in the memo that extra caution should be applied when dealing with overseas clients to avoid political and national security risks.翻译:离岸交易最活跃的中资投行中金公司也在备忘录中表示，在与海外客户打交道时应格外谨慎，以避免政治和国家安全风险。</p>   <p>While negative comments by market analysts and commentators in China have often been censored by authorities, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/outspoken-market-analysts-chinese-social-media-accounts-suspended-2022-05-01/">the trend</a> became more noticeable after China's economic growth began to weaken last year.翻译:尽管中国市场分析师和评论员的负面评论经常受到当局的审查， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/outspoken-market-analysts-chinese-social-media-accounts-suspended-2022-05-01/">但这种趋势</a>在去年中国经济增长开始疲软后变得更加明显。</p>   <p>The central government has also widened crackdowns on corruption and used rhetoric that criticises the country's "financial elite" for leading "hedonistic" lifestyles - part of its "common prosperity" drive that began in 2021.翻译:中央政府还加大了对腐败的打击力度，并使用言论批评该国“金融精英”过着“享乐主义”的生活方式——这是2021年开始的“共同富裕”行动的一部分。</p>   <p>Chinese banks began giving <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-common-prosperity-drive-slashes-pay-perks-investment-bankers-2022-07-29/">verbal guidance</a> as early as 2022, warning bankers to stop posting photos that depicted lavish lifestyles on social media.翻译:中国的银行早在2022年就开始发出<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-common-prosperity-drive-slashes-pay-perks-investment-bankers-2022-07-29/">口头指导</a>，警告银行家停止在社交媒体上发布描绘奢华生活方式的照片。</p>   <p>Banks have also been forced to cut pay and perks for investment bankers, including compensation and budget reductions for travel and entertainment.翻译:银行还被迫削减投资银行家的薪酬和福利，包括旅行和娱乐方面的薪酬和预算削减。</p>   <p>Reuters reported in April that CICC <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/brokerage-cicc-slashes-bonuses-beijing-dials-up-income-disparity-rhetoric-2023-04-06/">slashed</a> bankers' bonuses by as much as 40%.翻译:路透社4月份报道称，中金公司将银行家的奖金<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/brokerage-cicc-slashes-bonuses-beijing-dials-up-income-disparity-rhetoric-2023-04-06/">削减</a>了40%之多。</p>    <span>Reporting by Selena Li and Jason Xue; Editing by Sumeet Chatterjee and Edwina Gibbs翻译:赛琳娜·李和杰森·薛的报道；苏米特·查特吉和埃德温娜·吉布斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 09:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">APF4HYNPHZKSVGAHILFXD4BC6A</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/analysts-chinas-cicc-told-not-publish-bearish-views-wear-luxury-items-memo-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>CICC/AUSTERITY (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[台湾敦促老年人和年轻人因呼吸道疾病避免前往中国]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/WJ2b_viJkiZi-TD1io511ocd5L0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/O7UWNWGTAFPU3M2L4XGSZ3V74U.jpg" alt="People wait for their rides outside a children's hospital in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家儿童医院外等候乘车" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People wait for their rides outside a children's hospital in Beijing翻译:人们在北京一家儿童医院外等候乘车, China November 27, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Taiwan's health ministry on Thursday urged the elderly, very young and those with poor immunity to avoid travel to China due to the recent increase in respiratory illnesses there, a move some experts said was ineffective to manage public health risks.翻译:台湾卫生部周四敦促老年人、幼儿和免疫力差的人避免前往中国，因为最近中国呼吸道疾病的增加，一些专家表示此举对于管理公共卫生风险无效。</p>   <p>The World Health Organization (WHO) last week requested China provide detailed information on the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/who-asks-china-details-respiratory-illness-outbreaks-2023-11-23/">spike</a>, which a WHO official said was not as high as before the COVID-19 pandemic and that no unusual or novel pathogens had been detected.翻译:世界卫生组织 (WHO) 上周要求中国提供有关<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/who-asks-china-details-respiratory-illness-outbreaks-2023-11-23/">峰值</a>的详细信息，世界卫生组织官员表示，峰值没有 COVID-19 大流行之前那么高，并且没有发现异常或新型病原体。</p>   <p>Taiwan has been wary of disease outbreaks in its giant neighbour since the Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome (SARS) outbreak that started in China and killed nearly 800 people globally in 2002-2003.翻译:自2002年至2003年在中国爆发并导致全球近800人死亡的严重急性呼吸系统综合症（SARS）以来，台湾一直对其巨大邻国的疾病爆发保持警惕。</p>   <p>China, whose government claims democratically governed Taiwan as its own, initially tried to cover up that outbreak.翻译:中国政府声称对台湾实行民主治理，并称其为自己的领土，最初试图掩盖这一疫情。</p>   <p>In a statement released after a weekly Cabinet meeting, Taiwan's health ministry said that due to the rise in respiratory illnesses in China, the elderly, young children and other people with poor immunity are requested not to travel to mainland China, Hong Kong and Macau unless necessary.翻译:台湾卫生部在每周一次的内阁会议后发表的一份声明中表示，由于中国大陆呼吸道疾病的增加，请老年人、幼儿和其他免疫力较差的人不要前往中国大陆、香港和澳门，除非必要的。</p>   <p>If travel is necessary, then people should get flu and COVID vaccinations before going to China, it added.翻译:报告补充说，如果有必要旅行，那么人们应该在前往中国之前接种流感和新冠疫苗。</p>   <p>Shu-Ti Chiou, an epidemiologist at the Health &amp; Sustainable Development Foundation in Taipei, said the advisory would lead the public to mistakenly believe they would not contract respiratory illnesses as long as they did not go to China.翻译:台北健康与可持续发展基金会的流行病学家邱淑蒂表示，该建议将导致公众错误地认为，只要不前往中国，他们就不会感染呼吸道疾病。</p>   <p>Rajib Dasgupta, an epidemiologist and professor of community health at Jawaharlal Nehru University in New Delhi, also said "travel restrictions for respiratory infections are not an effective measure for interrupting transmission".翻译:新德里贾瓦哈拉尔尼赫鲁大学流行病学家兼社区卫生教授拉吉布·达斯古普塔也表示，“针对呼吸道感染的旅行限制并不是阻断传播的有效措施”。</p>   <p>Some public health researchers said the travel advisory was reasonable, saying Taiwan was also likely to experience a surge in respiratory illnesses in winter and following the lifting of pandemic restrictions. "They would be cautious not to hasten it by overseas travels," said Sung-il Cho, an epidemiologist at Seoul National University.翻译:一些公共卫生研究人员表示，这一旅行建议是合理的，并称台湾在冬季和大流行限制取消后也可能出现呼吸道疾病激增的情况。首尔国立大学流行病学家赵成日 (Sung-il Cho) 表示：“他们会谨慎行事，以免海外旅行加速疫情蔓延。”</p>   <p>China's Foreign Minister Wang Yi said on Wednesday that the rise in respiratory illnesses in China was a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-cluster-flu-cases-under-effective-control-foreign-minister-2023-11-29/">common issue</a> faced by all countries and that Chinese authorities have it under effective control.翻译:中国外交部长王毅周三表示，中国呼吸道疾病发病率上升是各国面临的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-cluster-flu-cases-under-effective-control-foreign-minister-2023-11-29/">共同问题</a>，中国当局已有效控制疫情。</p>   <p>China's Taiwan affairs office and authorities in Hong Kong and Macau did not immediately respond to requests for comment.翻译:中国台湾事务办公室以及香港和澳门当局没有立即回应置评请求。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ben Blanchard in Taipei and Andrew Silver in Shanghai; Additional reporting by Anne Marie Roantree and Farah Master in Hong Kong; Editing by Miral Fahmy翻译:Ben Blanchard 在台北和 Andrew Silver 在上海的报道； Anne Marie Roantree 和 Farah Master 在香港的补充报道；米拉尔·法赫米编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 08:15:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">HW4ATTXFHNPDHGXGZJUKB2EXVY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-urges-elderly-young-avoid-china-visits-due-respiratory-illnesses-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ben Blanchard, Andrew Silver]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HEALTH</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/TAIWAN (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[随着选举临近，台湾报告中国有更多军事活动]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Otpp4Ck8EAe6MxdU--W8bx9rDOs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PYYHGKCUDRN7DLKK4GURFSSSAE.jpg" alt="Illustration shows Chinese and Taiwanese flags翻译:插图显示中国和台湾国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A Navy miniature is seen in front of displayed Chinese and Taiwanese flags in this illustration taken, April 11, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File photo翻译:在这张摄于 2023 年 4 月 11 日的插图中，可以看到在展示的中国和台湾国旗前有一个海军微型模型。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Taiwan again reported Chinese warplanes and warships around the island on Thursday, including aircraft crossing the sensitive median line of the Taiwan Strait, as Beijing keeps up its military activities ahead of Taiwan's January election.翻译:周四，台湾再次报告中国战机和军舰在台湾周围活动，其中包括飞机穿越台湾海峡敏感的中线，而北京在台湾一月份大选之前继续其军事活动。</p>   <p>Democratically governed Taiwan, which China claims as its own territory, has complained for the past four years of regular Chinese military patrols and drills near the island.翻译:中国声称台湾是民主统治的台湾，过去四年来，台湾一直抱怨中国在台湾附近定期进行军事巡逻和演习。</p>   <p>Taiwan holds presidential and parliamentary polls on Jan. 13 and campaigning has already kicked into high gear. Relations with China are a major point of contention.翻译:台湾将于1月13日举行总统和立法院选举，竞选活动已经进入紧锣密鼓的阶段。与中国的关系是一个主要争论点。</p>   <p>Taiwan's defence ministry said that starting Thursday morning it had detected J-10 and J-16 fighters as well as ship-borne helicopters operating off central Taiwan and to the island's southwest.翻译:台湾国防部表示，从周四早上开始，它发现了在台湾中部和台湾西南部附近执行任务的歼10和歼16战斗机以及舰载直升机。</p>   <p>Eleven of those aircraft crossed the Taiwan Strait's median line, or areas close by, working with Chinese warships to carry out "joint combat readiness patrols", the ministry added.翻译:国防部补充说，其中 11 架飞机飞越台湾海峡中线或附近地区，与中国军舰一起进行“联合战备巡逻”。</p>   <p>The strait's median line once served as an unofficial barrier between the two sides, but Chinese planes now regularly fly over it.翻译:海峡中线曾经是两岸之间的非正式屏障，但中国飞机​​现在经常飞越该海峡。</p>   <p>Taiwan sent its own forces to monitor, the ministry said.翻译:国防部表示，台湾派出自己的部队进行监视。</p>   <p>This month, Taiwan has reported at least three other similar large-scale sorties by China's air force, which Beijing has not commented on.翻译:本月，台湾报告称中国空军至少进行了另外三次类似的大规模飞行，北京方面尚未对此发表评论。</p>   <p>China says its activities near Taiwan are aimed at preventing "collusion" between Taiwan separatists and the United States, and protecting China's territorial integrity.翻译:中国表示，其在台湾附近的活动旨在防止台湾分裂分子与美国“勾结”，保护中国的领土完整。</p>   <p>Taiwan's government, which has repeatedly offered talks with China, rejects Beijing's sovereignty claims and says only the island's people can decide their future.翻译:台湾政府多次提出与中国进行谈判，拒绝北京的主权主张，并表示只有台湾人民才能决定他们的未来。</p>   <p>The ruling Democratic Progressive Party's Lai Ching-te, whom Beijing has denounced as a separatist, is the frontrunner to be Taiwan's next president, according to opinion polls.翻译:民意调查显示，执政党民进党的赖清德是台湾下届总统的热门人选，北京方面谴责赖清德为分裂分子。</p>   <p>Taiwan's main opposition party, the Kuomintang, traditionally supports close ties with Beijing, and has pledged to re-open dialogue with China if it wins the election.翻译:台湾主要反对党国民党传统上支持与北京的密切关系，并承诺如果赢得选举将与中国重新开启对话。</p>    <span>Reporting by Ben Blanchard; Editing by Sonali Paul and Gerry Doyle翻译:本·布兰查德报道；索纳利·保罗和格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 07:55:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RHBC6BTV3NMLVKD75WLTXPCQ6Y</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-reports-more-chinese-military-activity-election-nears-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>TAIWAN</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[持有 4.3 万亿美元的公共投资者对中国的看法有所下降，但净额为零]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>No funds surveyed positive on China outlook - OMFIF</li>  <li>India top pick amongst emerging markets</li>  <li>Investors concerned about higher-for-longer rates</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>调查显示，没有基金对中国前景持乐观态度 - OMFIF</li><li>印度是新兴市场中的首选</li><li>投资者担心长期较高的利率</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/2cWg61CS8GO_1IMXrXFCO9NhwLU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/J6OZSX7ITBISVHSH6RJN3R2CIU.jpg" alt="Beijing Stock Exchange翻译:北京证券交易所" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A view of the new Beijing Stock Exchange翻译:北京证券交易所 in Beijing, China, November 15, 2021. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang//File Photo翻译:2021 年 11 月 15 日，中国北京新北京证券交易所一景。路透社/Tingshu Wang//资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Qukr18jkbMyPNsXVA6zUPaRhXWU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4JHIH6B76JIODBXUCMW2IQPT2I.jpg" alt="German share price index DAX graph is pictured at the stock exchange in Frankfurt翻译:德国股价指数 DAX 图为法兰克福证券交易所" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>The German share price index DAX graph is pictured at the stock exchange in Frankfurt翻译:德国股价指数 DAX 图为法兰克福证券交易所, Germany, November 28, 2023.    REUTERS/Staff/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>Public pension and sovereign wealth funds managing $4.3 trillion in assets are pessimistic about investing in China, but keen to cut net emissions of their portfolios, according to a survey by the Official Monetary and Financial Institutions Forum (OMFIF).翻译:官方货币和金融机构论坛 (OMFIF) 的一项调查显示，管理着 4.3 万亿美元资产的公共养老金和主权财富基金对投资中国持悲观态度，但热衷于削减其投资组合的净排放量。</p>   <p>The survey of 22 funds by OMFIF, a think tank for central banking, economic policy and public investment, also showed that 62% of the 50 largest pension funds and nearly half of the largest sovereign wealth funds suffered losses last year amid high inflation and historically rapid global rate hikes.翻译:央行、经济政策和公共投资智库 OMFIF 对 22 家基金的调查还显示，去年，由于高通胀和历史性的高通胀，全球 50 家最大养老基金中有 62% 以及近一半最大主权财富基金遭受损失。全球加息迅速。</p>   <p>OMFIF outlined a dark mood among the funds, with more than half expecting a global economic recession in the next 12 months. None reported a positive outlook for China's economy, citing the regulatory environment and geopolitics among primary factors dissuading them from investing.翻译:OMFIF 概述了基金中的悲观情绪，超过一半的基金预计未来 12 个月全球经济将陷入衰退。没有人对中国经济前景表示乐观，称监管环境和地缘政治是阻碍他们投资的主要因素。</p>   <p>The world's second-largest economy is struggling to boost growth amid a debt-laden real estate sector and consumers who are looking to save more due to the economic uncertainty.翻译:在债务负担沉重的房地产行业以及由于经济不确定性而希望增加储蓄的消费者中，世界第二大经济体正在努力促进增长。</p>   <p>"India is the most attractive emerging market among respondents, while the majority identified regulation and geopolitics as hurdles to investing in China," authors of the report launched on Thursday found.翻译:周四发布的报告作者发现，“印度是受访者中最具吸引力的新兴市场，而大多数人认为监管和地缘政治是投资中国的障碍。”</p>   <p>The funds remain worried about interest rates, the survey showed, with 63% citing them as the top factor in their investment strategies over the coming decade, double the share from last year's survey.翻译:调查显示，这些基金仍然担心利率，63% 的基金将利率视为未来十年投资策略的首要因素，这一比例是去年调查的两倍。</p>   <p>"(Investors) are now focused on how to deal with a macroeconomic environment that is stuck in a higher-for-longer interest rate cycle," the report said.翻译:报告称：“（投资者）现在关注的焦点是如何应对陷入较高利率周期和较长利率周期的宏观经济环境。”</p>   <p>While 73% of the funds said they have a pledge to achieve net zero emissions in their portfolio by 2050, and more than a third planning to increase their allocation to green bonds and green real assets in the next 12-24 months, any investments still need to make money for the funds.翻译:虽然 73% 的基金表示，他们承诺到 2050 年在其投资组合中实现净零排放，超过三分之一的基金计划在未来 12-24 个月内增加对绿色债券和绿色实物资产的配置，但任何投资仍然需要为资金赚钱。</p>   <p>"We're looking for deals where there is a meeting of ESG and returns, and we don’t accept lower returns just to comply with ESG targets," David Morley, managing director and head of Europe at Caisse de Depot et Placement du Québec, said in the survey.翻译:Caisse de Depot et Placement du Québec 董事总经理兼欧洲主管 David Morley 表示：“我们正在寻找能够兼顾 ESG 和回报的交易，我们不会仅仅为了遵守 ESG 目标而接受较低的回报。” ，调查中表示。</p>   <p>Overall, sovereign funds fared better than their public pension peers, OMFIF added. Aggregate assets under management of the top 50 sovereign funds edged 2.3% higher to $11.6 trillion from $11.3 trillion a year before, helped by outsized gains in Middle East funds as they benefit from the surge in commodity prices.翻译:OMFIF 补充说，总体而言，主权基金的表现优于公共养老金同行。前 50 名主权基金管理的总资产从一年前的 11.3 万亿美元小幅增长 2.3%，达到 11.6 万亿美元，这得益于中东基金受益于大宗商品价格飙升带来的巨额收益。</p>   <p>The UAE's Abu Dhabi Investment Authority and Saudi Public Investment Corporation grew by 13.8% and 12.9% respectively, gaining over $200 billion between them.翻译:阿联酋阿布扎比投资局和沙特公共投资公司分别增长13.8%和12.9%，净收益超过2000亿美元。</p>    <span>Reporting By Libby George; Editing by Sharon Singleton翻译:利比·乔治报道；莎朗·辛格尔顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 07:54:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TQMIBO4LJZO37OXVLJF7GF7S3E</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/public-investors-with-43-trln-are-down-china-net-zero-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Libby George, Bansari Kamdar]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>INVESTMENT/OMFIF (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[台湾总统：中国“不知所措”，无法考虑入侵]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/BQbvkT9rL5yLh5prFxu2YkG4zWM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/UQUYCK27NBM6VHO76K7TGKR46A.jpg" alt="Taiwan's President Tsai Ing-wen listens to a briefing at a military camp翻译:台湾总统蔡英文在军营听取情况通报" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Taiwan's President Tsai Ing-wen listens to a briefing at a military camp翻译:台湾总统蔡英文在军营听取情况通报 that will be one of the training grounds for the new one year compulsory military service starting earlier next year in Taichung, Taiwan November 23, 2023. REUTERS/Ann Wang/File Photo</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lHJNz0xQ03m6FB-CEKBQ2xBQBOM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/Q2BY55TK6BN4XBKSQDPVOUJU54.jpg" alt="Yushan Forum in Taipei翻译:台北玉山论坛" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Taiwan's President Tsai Ing-wen speaks during the Yushan Forum in Taipei翻译:台北玉山论坛, Taiwan October 11, 2023. REUTERS/Annabelle Chih/File Photo</figcaption></figure>               <p>China's leadership is too "overwhelmed" with its internal problems to consider an invasion of Taiwan, President Tsai Ing-wen said in an interview with the New York Times.翻译:蔡英文总统在接受《纽约时报》采访时表示，中国领导层对其内部问题“不堪重负”，不会考虑入侵台湾。</p>   <p>China, which views democratically governed Taiwan as its own territory, has ramped up military pressure against the island over the past four years, leading to concerns of a conflict that would have global repercussions.翻译:中国将民主治理的台湾视为自己的领土，过去四年加大了对该岛的军事压力，引发了人们对冲突可能产生全球影响的担忧。</p>   <p>But Tsai, in a transcript of the New York Times DealBook Summit interview her office published on Thursday, said China had too many issues at the moment.翻译:但蔡英文在其办公室周四发布的纽约时报 DealBook 峰会采访记录中表示，中国目前存在太多问题。</p>   <p>"Well, I think the Chinese leadership at this juncture is overwhelmed by its internal challenges. And my thought is that perhaps this is not a time for them to consider a major invasion of Taiwan," she said.翻译:“嗯，我认为中国领导层在这个时刻被其内部挑战压垮了。我的想法是，也许现在不是他们考虑大规模入侵台湾的时候，”她说。</p>   <p>"Largely because the internal economic and financial as well as political challenges, but also, the international community has made it loud and clear that war is not an option, and peace and stability serves everybody's interests."翻译:“很大程度上是因为国内经济、金融以及政治挑战，而且国际社会已经明确表示，战争不是一种选择，和平与稳定符合每个人的利益。”</p>   <p>Asked about Tsai's comments, China's defence ministry said: "China will eventually and surely be reunified".翻译:当被问及蔡英文的言论时，中国国防部表示：“中国最终一定会统一”。</p>   <p>"The People's Liberation Army will take all necessary measures to firmly safeguard China's sovereignty and territorial integrity," ministry spokesperson Wu Qian told a monthly news briefing in Beijing.翻译:国防部发言人吴谦在北京举行的每月例行新闻发布会上表示，“中国人民解放军将采取一切必要措施，坚定维护中国主权和领土完整。”</p>   <p>Tsai and her government have repeatedly called for talks with China but been rebuffed, as Beijing views Tsai and the ruling Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) as separatists.翻译:蔡英文及其政府多次呼吁与中国进行谈判，但遭到拒绝，因为北京将蔡英文和执政的民进党视为分裂分子。</p>   <p>Tsai says only Taiwan's people can decide their future.翻译:蔡英文表示，只有台湾人民才能决定自己的未来。</p>   <p>Taiwan is in the middle of campaigning for presidential and parliamentary elections to be held on Jan. 13. The DPP's Lai Ching-te, currently vice president, is the frontrunner to be Taiwan's next president according to opinion polls.翻译:台湾正在为1月13日举行的总统和议会选举进行竞选活动。根据民意调查，现任副总统的民进党候选人赖清德是台湾下届总统的领先者。</p>   <p>Tsai said it was "no secret" that China was trying to interfere in Taiwan's elections.翻译:蔡英文表示，中国试图干预台湾选举“不是什么秘密”。</p>   <p>"But I think they're probably not particularly successful in their effort of trying to influence the election here. Primarily, because this is a democracy and people know that they have made their best decisions as to who is going to be the next leader of Taiwan," she added.翻译:“但我认为他们在试图影响这里的选举方面可能并不是特别成功。主要是因为这是一个民主国家，人们知道他们已经就谁将成为下一任领导人做出了最佳决定。台湾，”她补充道。</p>   <p>China's Taiwan Affairs Office on Wednesday stepped up its attacks on Lai and his running mate Hsiao Bi-khim, formerly Taiwan's envoy to the United States.翻译:中国台湾事务办公室周三加大了对赖智及其竞选搭档、前台湾驻美国特使萧美琴的攻击力度。</p>   <p>"Taiwan independence means war. The DPP pushing this dangerous independence double act will only poison the interests and well being of compatriots on the island," spokesperson Chen Binhua told a news conference.翻译:台独就意味着战争，民进党推行这种危险的台独双重行径，只会毒害岛内同胞的利益和福祉。”</p>   <p>Speaking to reporters in Taipei on Thursday, top China-policy maker Chiu Tai-san dismissed Beijing's criticisms.翻译:中国最高决策者邱泰山周四在台北对记者发表讲话，驳斥了北京方面的批评。</p>   <p>"Honestly speaking, those comments show they don't even know what democratic politics and elections are," said Chiu, who heads Taiwan's Mainland Affairs Council.翻译:台湾陆委会主任邱说：“老实说，这些言论表明他们根本不知道什么是民主政治和选举。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Ben Blanchard; Additional reporting by Yew Lun Tian in Beijing; Editing by Lincoln Feast and Christopher Cushing翻译:本·布兰查德报道；田耀伦在北京的补充报道；林肯·法斯特和克里斯托弗·库欣编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 07:53:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">KV7KWZ7QOFNRFFRWVATO7S45C4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-president-china-too-overwhelmed-consider-invasion-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>TAIWAN</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/ (UPDATE 2, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国工厂陷入更严重的萎缩，预计将有更多政策支持]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Nov manufacturing PMI falls further to 49.4</li>  <li>Non-manufacturing index expands at slower pace</li>  <li>New export orders extend decline for ninth month</li>  <li>Factory managers losing confidence in policy support - analysts</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li> 11月制造业PMI进一步下滑至49.4</li><li>非制造业指数扩张速度放缓</li><li>新出口订单连续第九个月下滑</li><li>分析师称工厂经理对政策支持失去信心</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/bosujQuSqCy1cOaCmzaLNw8N9D0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KOTW54REWBLQRIOTPUIF2GLJ7M.jpg" alt="Employees work at a factory in Zunyi翻译:员工在遵义一家工厂工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Employees work on the production line of glass panels for mobile phones at a factory in Zunyi, Guizhou province, China March 6, 2023. cnsphoto via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:2023 年 3 月 6 日，中国贵州省遵义市一家工厂，员工在手机玻璃面板生产线上工作。 cnsphoto via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's manufacturing activity shrank for a second straight month in November and at a quicker pace, suggesting more stimulus will be needed to shore up economic growth and restore confidence that the authorities can ably support industry.翻译:11月份中国制造业活动连续第二个月萎缩，且萎缩速度更快，这表明需要采取更多刺激措施来支撑经济增长，并恢复人们对当局能够有力支持工业的信心。</p>   <p>Economists upgraded their forecasts for the world's second-largest economy after better-than-expected third quarter data, but despite a flurry of policy support measures, negative sentiment among factory managers appears to have become entrenched in the face of weak demand both at home and abroad.翻译:在第三季度数据好于预期后，经济学家上调了对世界第二大经济体的预测，但尽管采取了一系列政策支持措施，但面对国内外需求疲软，工厂经理的负面情绪似乎已根深蒂固。国外。</p>   <p>The official purchasing managers' index (PMI) fell to 49.4 in November from 49.5 in October, National Bureau of Statistics data showed on Thursday, missing economists' forecast of 49.7. The 50-point mark demarcates contraction from expansion.翻译:国家统计局周四公布的数据显示，11 月份官方采购经理人指数 (PMI) 从 10 月份的 49.5 降至 49.4，低于经济学家预测的 49.7。 50分是收缩与扩张的分界线。</p>   <p>"The domestic market cannot make up for losses in Europe and the United States. The data shows that factories are producing less and hiring fewer people," said Dan Wang, chief economist at Hang Seng Bank China.翻译:恒生银行中国首席经济学家王丹表示，“国内市场无法弥补欧洲和美国的损失。数据显示工厂产量减少，雇用人员减少。”</p>   <p>"(The data) could also show a loss of confidence in government policy," she added, warning factory activity was unlikely to improve anytime soon as other economic problems dominate. "The priority now is clearly containing the local government debt risk and the risk posed by regional banks."翻译:她补充说：“（数据）还可能表明人们对政府政策失去信心。”她警告说，由于其他经济问题占主导地位，工厂活动不太可能很快改善。 “现在的首要任务显然是控制地方政府债务风险和地方银行带来的风险。”</p>   <p>The new orders sub-index contracted for a second consecutive month, while the new export orders component extended its decline for a ninth month.翻译:新订单分类指数连续第二个月收缩，而新出口订单分类指数连续第九个月延续跌势。</p>   <p>In another worrying sign, the vast services sector contracted for the first time in 12 months. The non-manufacturing PMI, which includes services and construction, eased to 50.2 in November from 50.6 last month.翻译:另一个令人担忧的迹象是，庞大的服务业12个月来首次出现萎缩。 11 月份包括服务业和建筑业在内的非制造业 PMI 从上个月的 50.6 降至 50.2。</p>      <p>China's economy has struggled this year to mount a strong post-pandemic recovery, held back by a deepening crisis in the property market, local government debt risks, slow global growth and geopolitical tensions.翻译:受房地产市场危机深化、地方政府债务风险、全球经济增长放缓和地缘政治紧张局势的影响，中国经济今年在疫情后难以实现强劲复苏。</p>   <p>The factory PMI has contracted for seven out of the past eight months - rising above the 50-point mark only in September. The last time the indicator was negative for more than three consecutive months was in the six months to October 2019.翻译:过去 8 个月中，工厂 PMI 有 7 个月出现收缩，仅在 9 月份就突破了 50 点大关。该指标上一次连续三个月以上为负值是在截至2019年10月的六个月内。</p>   <p>"The hard data have held up better than the survey-based measures lately... (which) may be overstating the extent of slowdown due to sentiment effects," Sheana Yue, China economist at Capital Economics, said in a note.翻译:凯投宏观(Capital Economics)中国经济学家谢娜·岳(Sheana Yue)在一份报告中表示，“最近的硬数据比基于调查的指标表现得更好……可能夸大了由于情绪影响而导致的经济放缓程度。”</p>   <p>"But if that starts to change, policy support will need to be ramped up further to prevent the economy from backsliding."翻译:“但如果这种情况开始改变，就需要进一步加大政策支持力度，以防止经济倒退。”</p>   <p>The patchy recovery has prompted many analysts to warn that China may <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">decline</a> into Japanese-style stagnation later this decade unless policymakers take steps to reorient the economy towards household consumption and market-allocation of resources.翻译:不完整的复苏促使许多分析师警告称，除非政策制定者采取措施将经济转向家庭消费和资源市场配置，否则中国可能会在本十年晚些时候<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">陷入</a>日本式的停滞。</p>   <p>"Today's PMI reading will further raise expectations towards policy support," said Zhou Hao, economist at Guotai Junan International. "Fiscal policy will be under the spotlight and take centre stage over the coming year and will be closely monitored by the market."翻译:国泰君安国际经济学家周浩表示：“今天的PMI数据将进一步提高对政策支持的预期。” “财政政策将成为未来一年的焦点，并成为焦点，并将受到市场的密切关注。”</p>   <p>Oil prices <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/oil-prices-fall-weak-demand-indicators-china-data-2023-11-30/">fell</a> in early Asia following weaker-than-expected manufacturing activity in China, the world's largest energy consumer, while the offshore yuan also slipped.</p>    <h 1="">MORE SUPPORT NEEDED</h>  <p>China's central bank governor on Tuesday <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">said</a> he was "confident that China will enjoy healthy and sustainable growth in 2024 and beyond," but urged structural reforms to reduce reliance on infrastructure and property for growth.翻译:中国央行行长周二<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/pboc-governor-says-will-keep-monetary-policy-accommodative-expects-inflation-2023-11-28/">表示，</a>他“相信中国将在2024年及以后实现健康、可持续的增长”，但敦促进行结构性改革，减少增长对基础设施和房地产的依赖。</p>   <p>Policy advisers say the government will need to implement further stimulus should it wish to sustain an annual economic growth target of "around 5%" next year, which would match this year's goal.翻译:政策顾问表示，如果政府希望明年维持“5%左右”的年度经济增长目标（这将与今年的目标相匹配），那么政府将需要实施进一步的刺激措施。</p>   <p>But the People's Bank of China (PBOC) is constrained when it comes to implementing further monetary stimulus over concerns a widening interest rate differential with the West may weaken the currency and spur capital outflows.翻译:但由于担心与西方利差扩大可能导致人民币贬值并刺激资本外流，中国人民银行在实施进一步的货币刺激措施方面受到限制。</p>   <p>In October, China unveiled a plan to issue 1 trillion yuan ($138.7 billion) in sovereign bonds by the end of the year, raising the 2023 budget deficit target to 3.8% of GDP from the original 3%.翻译:10月，中国公布了在年底前发行1万亿元人民币（合1,387亿美元）主权债券的计划，将2023年预算赤字目标从原来占GDP的3%提高到3.8%。</p>   <p>The PBOC has also implemented modest interest rate cuts and pumped more cash into the economy in recent months, pledging to sustain policy support.翻译:近几个月来，中国央行还实施了小幅降息并向经济注入更多现金，承诺维持政策支持。</p>   <p>China still channels more funds into infrastructure projects to drive growth, which likely lifted the construction index to 55.0 from 53.5 in October, though the government has been trying to reduce the economy's reliance on property.翻译:尽管政府一直在努力减少经济对房地产的依赖，但中国仍在向基础设施项目投入更多资金以推动增长，这可能将建筑业指数从 10 月份的 53.5 提升至 55.0。</p>   <p>"Despite the raft of stimulus measures announced over the past several months, we believe it is still too early to call the bottom," Ting Lu, chief China economist at Nomura, said in a note. "We expect another economic dip towards end-2023 and spring 2024."翻译:野村证券首席中国经济学家陆挺在一份报告中表示，“尽管过去几个月宣布了一系列刺激措施，但我们认为现在判断底部还为时过早。” “我们预计 2023 年底和 2024 年春季经济将再次下滑。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Joe Cash; Editing by Kim Coghill and Jacqueline Wong翻译:乔·卡什报道；编辑：Kim Coghill 和 Jacqueline Wong</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 05:13:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RB7XHEONXBPALOWEDIJY3DYJ3M</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-factory-activity-contracts-second-month-november-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Joe Cash]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/PMI (UPDATE 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国寻求两国方案解决加沙冲突的“具体”路线图]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/KNKTapwtsPqRVCD3XjA5HiQTLZY=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/S34K365LJFJMXNSI6JK2KJM7YE.jpg" alt="Illustration shows Palestinian and Israel flags翻译:插图显示巴勒斯坦和以色列国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Palestinian and Israel flags are seen in this illustration taken, October 15, 2023. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File photo翻译:这张摄于 2023 年 10 月 15 日的插图中可以看到巴勒斯坦和以色列国旗。 REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China called on the United Nations Security Council on Thursday to formulate a "concrete" timetable and roadmap for a two-state solution to achieve a "comprehensive, just and lasting" settlement of the Palestinian issue.翻译:中国周四呼吁联合国安理会制定两国解决方案的“具体”时间表和路线图，以实现巴勒斯坦问题的“全面、公正和持久”解决。</p>   <p>The proposal was laid out in a paper stating China's position on resolving the Palestinian-Israeli conflict released by the Chinese foreign ministry, and as China took over the rotating presidency of the Security Council for November.翻译:中国外交部在中国接任11月份安理会轮值主席国之际发布了一份文件，阐明了中国对解决巴以冲突的立场，提出了这一建议。</p>   <p>The 15-member council needs to intensify its diplomatic mediation, relaunch the two-state solution and convene a "more authoritative and effective" international peace conference as soon as possible, the paper said.翻译:该报称，由15名成员组成的安理会需要加强外交斡旋，重启两国解决方案，并尽快召开“更权威、更有效”的国际和平会议。</p>   <p>It urged the council to heed the general call of the international community for a "comprehensive ceasefire" to stop the fighting.翻译:它敦促安理会听取国际社会关于“全面停火”以停止战斗的普遍呼吁。</p>   <p>Since the start of hostilities in October, Beijing has refrained from condemning Hamas, but instead said it opposed acts that harm civilians and sought for de-escalation and a two-state solution.翻译:自十月份敌对行动开始以来，北京一直没有谴责哈马斯，而是表示反对伤害平民的行为，并寻求缓和局势和两国解决方案。</p>   <p>China's foreign minister Wang Yi, who chaired a high-level Security Council meeting on the Gaza conflict on Wednesday in New York, urged for a lasting truce in the embattled territory and warned against the conflict from spilling over to the entire Middle East region.翻译:中国外交部长王毅周三在纽约主持了关于加沙冲突的安理会高级别会议，他敦促在这片陷入困境的地区实现持久休战，并警告不要让冲突蔓延到整个中东地区。</p>   <p>"Peace cannot be limited and the ceasefire cannot have an expiration date," China's official Xinhua news agency cited Wang as saying.翻译:中国官方新华社援引王的话说：“和平不能受到限制，停火不能有期限。”</p>   <p>"Once the window of opportunity is open, it should not be closed, and once the fire has been extinguished, it cannot be rekindled," he said while meeting the press.翻译:他在会见记者时表示：“机会之窗一旦打开就不应关闭，火势一旦扑灭就不可能重燃。”</p>   <p>Wang also said China will provide a new batch of emergency humanitarian supplies to Gaza.翻译:王还表示，中方将向加沙提供新一批紧急人道主义物资。</p>   <p>International calls for Israel and Hamas to further <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/talks-intensify-extend-israel-hamas-truce-after-more-hostages-prisoners-freed-2023-11-30/">extend a truce</a> in Gaza have intensified after Israel bombarded the enclave triggered by Hamas' deadly rampage on Oct.7.翻译:10月7日，以色列轰炸了因哈马斯致命暴行引发的飞地，国际社会呼吁以色列和哈马斯进一步<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/talks-intensify-extend-israel-hamas-truce-after-more-hostages-prisoners-freed-2023-11-30/">延长加沙停火协议</a>。</p>   <p>Israel says Hamas gunmen killed 1,200 people and took 240 hostages, while health authorities in Gaza say Israel's attack has so far killed more than 15,000 people in the enclave.翻译:以色列称，哈马斯枪手杀害了 1,200 人，并劫持了 240 名人质，而加沙卫生当局称，以色列的袭击迄今已导致该飞地超过 15,000 人死亡。</p>   <p>China's President Xi Jinping on Thursday also reiterated Beijing's support to the Palestinians' quest for statehood.翻译:中国国家主席习近平周四也重申了北京对巴勒斯坦建国诉求的支持。</p>   <p>"The crux of the Palestinian-Israeli conflict lies in the delay in the realisation of the legitimate national rights of the Palestinian people to establish an independent state," Xinhua cited Xi as saying in a congratulatory message to a conference commemorating the International Day of Solidarity with the Palestinian People, a U.N.-led observance.翻译:新华社援引习近平在纪念国际团结日大会上的贺信说：“巴以冲突的症结在于巴勒斯坦人民建立独立国家的合法民族权利迟迟不能实现。”联合国领导的纪念活动，与巴勒斯坦人民一道举行。</p>   <p>"The bitter lessons of the cycle of the Palestinian-Israeli conflict fully demonstrate that only by upholding the concept of common security can sustainable security be achieved," Xi said.翻译:巴以冲突循环的惨痛教训充分说明，只有秉持共同安全理念，才能实现可持续安全。</p>   <p>He called on the Security Council to shoulder its responsibilities and make efforts to promote an end to the fighting, protect the safety of civilians and stop the humanitarian catastrophe.翻译:他呼吁安理会承担起责任，为推动结束战斗、保护平民安全、制止人道主义灾难作出努力。</p>    <span>Reporting by Liz Lee and Ethan Wang; Editing by Jamie Freed and Gerry Doyle翻译:Liz Lee 和 Ethan Wang 的报道；杰米·弗里德和格里·多伊尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 04:42:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">DDB6J42EFZKONNE4GIKCSRIW7I</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/china-calls-concrete-roadmap-two-state-solution-solve-gaza-conflict-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Liz Lee, Ethan Wang]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ISRAEL</category>
                
                <category>PALESTINIANS/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>PROPOSAL (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[11月份中国工厂活动延续跌势]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/bosujQuSqCy1cOaCmzaLNw8N9D0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KOTW54REWBLQRIOTPUIF2GLJ7M.jpg" alt="Employees work at a factory in Zunyi翻译:员工在遵义一家工厂工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Employees work on the production line of glass panels for mobile phones at a factory in Zunyi, Guizhou province, China March 6, 2023. cnsphoto via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:2023 年 3 月 6 日，中国贵州省遵义市一家工厂，员工在手机玻璃面板生产线上工作。 cnsphoto via REUTERS/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's manufacturing activity contracted for a second straight month in November and at a quicker pace, an official factory survey showed on Thursday, suggesting more policy support measures are needed to help shore up economic growth.翻译:周四的官方工厂调查显示，中国11月份制造业活动连续第二个月收缩，且收缩速度加快，这表明需要更多政策支持措施来帮助支撑经济增长。</p>   <p>The official purchasing managers' index (PMI) fell to 49.4 in November from 49.5 in October, staying below the 50-point level demarcating contraction from expansion. Analysts polled by Reuters had expected a reading of 49.7.翻译:官方采购经理人指数（PMI）从 10 月的 49.5 降至 11 月的 49.4，仍低于 50 点的收缩与扩张界限。路透社调查的分析师此前预期该值为 49.7。</p>   <p>China's economy has struggled this year to mount a strong post-pandemic recovery, held back by a deepening crisis in the property market, local government debt risks, slow global growth and geopolitical tensions.翻译:受房地产市场危机深化、地方政府债务风险、全球经济增长放缓和地缘政治紧张局势的影响，中国经济今年在疫情后难以实现强劲复苏。</p>   <p>A flurry of policy support measures has had only modest effect, raising pressure on authorities to roll out more stimulus.翻译:一系列政策支持措施收效甚微，加大了当局推出更多刺激措施的压力。</p>    <span>Reporting by Joe Cash; Editing by Sam Holmes翻译:乔·卡什报道；山姆·霍姆斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 01:39:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">OLYTAQAZTBIYLDDC4LN2NT4K2I</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-factory-activity-extends-declines-november-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/PMI (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[万达地产称延长6亿美元债券偿还期限已提前获得持有人同意]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/FvA2sgCKbMscCfST3Vaok2cpJD4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/B6W2NSFUMBNLZBY45HH276VPDQ.jpg" alt="Headquarters of Dalian Wanda Group, in Beijing翻译:大连万达集团总部，位于北京" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A sign of Wanda is pictured at the headquarters of Dalian Wanda Group, in Beijing's Central Business District (CBD), China August 8, 2023. REUTERS/Tingshu Wang/File Photo翻译:2023年8月8日，中国北京中央商务区（CBD）大连万达集团总部拍摄的万达标志。路透社/Tingshu Wang/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Chinese real estate firm Wanda Properties International [RIC:RIC:WPIC.UL], a unit of conglomerate Dalian Wanda Group, said on Thursday it had received early consent approval from bondholders to extend the repayment on a $600 million guaranteed bond due 2024.翻译:大连万达集团旗下中国房地产公司万达地产国际[RIC:RIC:WPIC.UL]周四表示，已获得债券持有人的提前同意，延长2024年到期的6亿美元担保债券的偿还期限。</p>   <p>The regulatory filing in Hong Kong said those voting in favour of the extension represented more than 99.3% of the aggregate principal amount of the bonds.翻译:香港的监管文件称，投票赞成延期的人占债券本金总额的99.3%以上。</p>   <p>Wanda Properties is still seeking final approval to extend the payment date of its $600 million 7.25% note to Dec. 29, 2024 from the current maturity date of Jan. 29, at a meeting of bondholders on Dec. 13 this year.翻译:万达地产仍在寻求最终批准，以在今年 12 月 13 日的债券持有人会议上将其 6 亿美元、年息 7.25% 票据的付款日期从目前的 1 月 29 日到期日延长至 2024 年 12 月 29 日。</p>    <span>Reporting by Liz Lee and Beijing newsroom; Editing by Jamie Freed翻译:Liz Lee和北京新闻编辑室的报道；杰米·弗里德编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 01:21:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">BL225OUTTVISTOKL5VYDCHOAJM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/wanda-properties-says-extension-600-mln-bond-repayment-gains-early-consent-2023-11-30/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>WANDA PROPERTIES</category>
                
                <category>DEBT/BONDHOLDERS (URGENT)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[外交部长：中国聚集性流感病例已得到有效控制]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/CZZUGATUAySU1xofM9RA-_RWBXo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PUVXUNG5SBNLVJ4R5IW2RLWVKU.jpg" alt="10th trilateral foreign ministers' meeting in Busan翻译:第十次中日韩外长会议在釜山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi speaks during the 10th trilateral foreign ministers' meeting in Busan翻译:第十次中日韩外长会议在釜山举行, South Korea, Sunday, Nov. 26, 2023. Ahn Young-joon/Pool via REUTERS翻译:中国外交部长王毅于 2023 年 11 月 26 日星期日在韩国釜山举行的第十次中日韩外长会议上发表讲话。 Ahn Young-joon/Pool 图片来源：路透社</figcaption></figure>       <p>A recent increase in respiratory illnesses in China is a common issue faced by that all countries and Chinese authorities have it under effective control, China's Foreign Minister Wang Yi said on Wednesday.翻译:中国外交部长王毅周三表示，近期中国呼吸道疾病增多是各国面临的共同问题，中国当局已有效控制疫情。</p>   <p>The World Health Organization (WHO) last week requested China provide detailed information on an <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/who-asks-china-details-respiratory-illness-outbreaks-2023-11-23/">increase in respiratory illnesses</a> and reported clusters of pneumonia in children.翻译:世界卫生组织（WHO）上周要求中国提供有关<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/who-asks-china-details-respiratory-illness-outbreaks-2023-11-23/">呼吸道疾病增加</a>和报告的儿童聚集性肺炎的详细信息。</p>   <p>But a WHO official said on Monday that the spike in illnesses in China is not as high as before the COVID-19 pandemic, and reiterated that <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-respiratory-illness-surge-not-high-pre-pandemic-who-official-2023-11-27/">no new or unusual pathogens had been found</a> in the recent cases.翻译:但世界卫生组织一名官员周一表示，中国的病例激增程度没有 COVID-19 大流行之前那么高，并重申在最近的病例中<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-respiratory-illness-surge-not-high-pre-pandemic-who-official-2023-11-27/">没有发现新的或不寻常的病原体</a>。</p>   <p>"Recently we have seen some clusters of flu cases among children in certain parts of China. In fact, that is a very common phenomenon in many countries, and in China that has been put under effective control," Wang told reporters at the United Nations in New York where he is chairing a U.N. Security Council session on the Israel-Hamas conflict.翻译:王在联合国对记者说：“最近我们看到中国一些地区出现了一些儿童聚集性流感病例。事实上，这在许多国家都是很普遍的现象，在中国已经得到了有效控制。”他正在纽约主持联合国安理会有关以色列与哈马斯冲突的会议。</p>   <p>"China's interactions with the international community will not be affected by any factors, and we welcome more visits from friends from across the world," he said.翻译:中国与国际社会的交往不会受到任何因素的影响，我们欢迎世界各国朋友更多地来访。</p>   <p>Both China and the WHO have faced questions about the transparency of reporting on the earliest COVID-19 cases that emerged in the central Chinese city of Wuhan in late 2019.翻译:中国和世界卫生组织都面临着关于 2019 年底在中国中部城市武汉出现的最早的 COVID-19 病例报告透明度的质疑。</p>    <span>Reporting by Michelle Nichols and Michael Martina
Editing by Chris Reese and Deepa Babington翻译:米歇尔·尼科尔斯和迈克尔·马丁娜报道克里斯·里斯和迪帕·巴宾顿编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 19:46:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">JM4FRKIZAFMKTHCXFKETKZVDP4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-cluster-flu-cases-under-effective-control-foreign-minister-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>HEALTH</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/UN (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[克里表示，中美将在 COP28 峰会上合作]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/qRIBDJ8ijLiEaVBO3_DK3u-aoMU=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TTAOMPAQDJNQTJL63PZ4S45L54.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry attends the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 16, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria翻译:美国总统气候问题特使约翰·克里出席 2023 年 11 月 16 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria</figcaption></figure>       <p>The United States will work with China to make the United Nations climate negotiations that begin in the United Arab Emirates this week a success, Washington's climate envoy said on Wednesday.翻译:华盛顿气候特使周三表示，美国将与中国合作，使本周在阿拉伯联合酋长国开始的联合国气候谈判取得成功。</p>   <p>Cooperation between the U.S. and China, the world's two biggest emitters of greenhouse gases, is seen as crucial to securing consensus at the Nov. 30 - Dec. 12 summit, known as COP28.翻译:美国和中国这两个世界上最大的温室气体排放国之间的合作被认为对于在 11 月 30 日至 12 月 12 日举行的 COP28 峰会上达成共识至关重要。</p>   <p>"We have decided to actually work together to get a successful COP, to get a successful global stocktake," Kerry said of his meeting with his Chinese counterpart this month.翻译:克里在谈到本月与中国外长的会面时表示：“我们决定切实合作，以召开一次成功的缔约方会议，并成功进行全球盘点。”</p>   <p>The global stocktake is an assessment taking place at the climate talks on how far off countries are from limiting global heating to 1.5 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels.翻译:全球盘点是在气候谈判中进行的一项评估，旨在评估各国距离将全球升温限制在工业化前水平以上 1.5 摄氏度以内还有多远。</p>   <p>Kerry and Chinese climate envoy Xie Zhenhua met in California where the sides agreed to the revival of a bilateral climate working group that Beijing had suspended last year.翻译:克里和中国气候特使解振华在加州会面，双方同意恢复北京去年暂停的双边气候工作组。</p>   <p>The U.S. and China agreed to back a new global renewables target and work together on methane and plastic pollution, though differences remain on fossil fuels, among other issues.翻译:美国和中国同意支持新的全球可再生能源目标，并就甲烷和塑料污染问题开展合作，尽管在化石燃料等问题上仍存在分歧。</p>   <p>"We intend to work hard to see if there's further collaboration that could advance the cause for all of us," Kerry said. "Without China and the United States aggressively moving forward to reduce emissions, we don't win this battle."翻译:克里说：“我们打算努力看看是否有进一步的合作可以推动我们所有人的事业。” “如果中国和美国不积极推进减排，我们就无法赢得这场战斗。”</p>   <p>The talks in the UAE, a major oil producer, are a critical opportunity for governments to accelerate action on climate change. However, they remain split over the use of fossil fuels, the burning of which is the main cause of climate change.翻译:在主要石油生产国阿联酋举行的会谈是各国政府加快应对气候变化行动的重要机会。然而，他们在化石燃料的使用问题上仍然存在分歧，化石燃料的燃烧是气候变化的主要原因。</p>   <p>Kerry, in a call with reporters, urged major producers of fossil fuels to support language that would commit them to phasing out the use of "unabated" fossil fuels - a reference to fuels burned without emissions-capturing technology.翻译:克里在与记者的通话中敦促主要化石燃料生产商支持承诺逐步淘汰使用“有增无减”化石燃料的措辞——指的是在没有排放捕获技术的情况下燃烧的燃料。</p>   <p>"They need to immediately step up and be part of the solution, not the most significant part of the problem," he said without identifying any particular producer.翻译:“他们需要立即挺身而出，成为解决方案的一部分，而不是成为问题最重要的部分，”他说，但没有透露具体的生产商。</p>   <p>In April the Group of Seven industrialised nations, which includes the United States, agreed to speed up the "phase-out of unabated fossil fuels" in what appeared to be a possible breakthrough over their use.翻译:今年四月，包括美国在内的七国集团同意加快“逐步淘汰化石燃料”，这似乎是化石燃料使用方面的一个可能的突破。</p>   <p>Negotiators have turned to new terminologies in search of a compromise after divisions over the future of fossil fuels failed to lead to a deal on a phase-down at last year's summit.翻译:去年峰会上，由于对化石燃料未来的分歧未能达成逐步削减协议，谈判代表们转向新术语寻求妥协。</p>   <p>"We hope we can send a very strong signal that the nations of the world are committed to work together to transition away from fossil fuel emissions in the next three decades. Period. It's critical," Kerry said.翻译:“我们希望能够发出一个非常强烈的信号，即世界各国致力于共同努力，在未来三十年内摆脱化石燃料排放。就这样。这很关键，”克里说。</p>    <span>Reporting by Alexander Cornwell
Editing by Mark Potter and Gareth Jones翻译:亚历山大·康威尔 (Alexander Cornwell) 报道 马克·波特 (Mark Potter) 和加雷斯·琼斯 (Gareth Jones) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 14:35:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5JI426VP3ZP6THTMUXUGSHO4RM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/us-climate-envoy-urges-wider-support-phasing-out-unabated-fossil-fuels-2023-11-29/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Alexander Cornwell]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CLIMATE</category>
                
                <category>UN/USA</category>
                
                <category>EMIRATES (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
