<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
        <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        
        
        
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        
        <image>
            <url>https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url>
            <title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/</link>
        </image>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 03:27:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>5</ttl>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[跨太平洋贸易协定成员在亚太经合组织峰会上举行会议，表示对新成员开放]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/T6hlMDNzZ_BNnyznrXYO9zveyf4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3ZUMRZMR6ZIK3MCNGLOMB3GSTU.jpg" alt="The United States hosts leaders from APEC nations in San Francisco翻译:美国在旧金山接待亚太经合组织国家领导人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A sign advertising the upcoming APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in see as the city prepares to host leaders from the Asia-Pacific region in San Francisco, California November 8, 2023. REUTERS/Carlos Barria/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 8 日，加利福尼亚州旧金山准备接待亚太地区领导人，即将举行的 APEC（亚太经济合作组织）峰会的广告牌。REUTERS/Carlos Barria/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Trade ministers from members of an Asian free trade pact abandoned by the United States affirmed on Wednesday a desire for more countries to join the bloc if they can meet its standards.翻译:周三，被美国放弃的亚洲自由贸易协定成员国的贸易部长确认，如果更多国家能够达到该协定的标准，他们希望更多国家加入该协定。</p>   <p>The officials from the 12 Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership (CPTPP) countries met in San Francisco just after trade negotiations for the U.S.-led Indo-Pacific Economic Framework (IPEF) initiative ground to a halt <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/yellen-indo-pacific-trade-talks-need-further-work-2023-11-14/">without an agreement</a> this week.翻译:本周，美国主导的印度-太平洋经济框架（IPEF）倡议的贸易谈判因<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/yellen-indo-pacific-trade-talks-need-further-work-2023-11-14/">未达成协议</a>而陷入停顿，随后来自跨太平洋伙伴关系全面进步协定（CPTPP）12个国家的官员在旧金山举行会议。</p>   <p>The lack of an IPEF trade deal is a setback for the Biden administration. It had aimed to showcase the initiative during this week's Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit in San Francisco as a symbol of its economic re-engagement in Asia, providing countries a counterweight to China's growing clout in the region.翻译:缺乏 IPEF 贸易协议对拜登政府来说是一个挫折。它的目的是在本周于旧金山举行的亚太经济合作组织（APEC）峰会上展示该倡议，作为其重新参与亚洲经济的象征，为各国提供抗衡中国在该地区日益增长的影响力的举措。</p>   <p>The CPTPP is the successor to the Trans-Pacific Partnership free trade deal, from which former President Donald Trump withdrew as soon as he took office in 2017.翻译:CPTPP是跨太平洋伙伴关系自由贸易协定的继承者，前总统唐纳德·特朗普在2017年上任后就退出了该协定。</p>   <p>The CPTPP meeting on the sidelines of the APEC leaders' summit was the first ministerial to include new member Britain, which <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/britain-agrees-join-trans-pacific-trade-pact-2023-03-31/">signed up</a> to the trade bloc in July.翻译:在 APEC 领导人峰会期间举行的 CPTPP 会议是首次有新成员英国参加的部长级会议，英国于 7 月<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/britain-agrees-join-trans-pacific-trade-pact-2023-03-31/">签署了</a>该贸易协定。</p>   <p>In a <a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/media/6554b828544aea0019fb2d51/cptpp-joint-ministerial-statement-15-november-2023__1_.pdf" target="_blank">joint statement</a> posted on the UK trade ministry website, the ministers "reaffirmed that the CPTPP is open to accession requests by economies that are ready to meet the high standards of the agreement and have a demonstrated pattern of complying with trade commitments."翻译:在英国贸易部网站上发布的一份<a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/media/6554b828544aea0019fb2d51/cptpp-joint-ministerial-statement-15-november-2023__1_.pdf" target="_blank">联合声明</a>中，部长们“重申，CPTPP 对那些准备好满足协议高标准并具有遵守贸易承诺模式的经济体的加入请求持开放态度。”</p>   <p>The statement made no mention of China's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biggest-hurdles-china-entry-into-trans-pacific-trade-pact-are-political-2023-07-31/">application</a> to join the bloc, nor applications by Taiwan, Costa Rica and Ecuador.翻译:声明没有提及中国的入盟<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biggest-hurdles-china-entry-into-trans-pacific-trade-pact-are-political-2023-07-31/">申请</a>，也没有提及台湾、哥斯达黎加和厄瓜多尔的申请。</p>   <p>It said accession decisions are dependent upon consensus, and since July, they have been "gathering information on whether aspirant economies can meet CPTPP’s high standards."翻译:报告称，加入决定取决于共识，自7月以来，他们一直在“收集有关有抱负的经济体是否能够满足CPTPP高标准的信息”。</p>   <p>Information collected to date "will not prejudge any process, outcome, decision and/or actions to be taken by CPTPP members," it said, adding that the bloc would apply lessons learned in the UK accession.翻译:声明称，迄今为止收集的信息“不会预先判断 CPTPP 成员将采取的任何过程、结果、决定和/或行动”，并补充说，欧盟将借鉴英国加入时吸取的经验教训。</p>   <p>The current CPTPP members are Australia, Brunei, Canada, Chile, Japan, Malaysia, Mexico, New Zealand, Peru, Singapore, the United Kingdom, and Vietnam. Most overlap with both APEC and the IPEF initiative.翻译:目前CPTPP成员包括澳大利亚、文莱、加拿大、智利、日本、马来西亚、墨西哥、新西兰、秘鲁、新加坡、英国和越南。大多数与 APEC 和 IPEF 倡议重叠。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Lawder; Editing by Lincoln Feast.翻译:大卫·劳德报道；林肯·盛宴编辑。</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 03:16:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7YKV6VQ33ZIYHKGIRMMNH4LMAU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/trans-pacific-trade-deal-members-meet-apec-summit-say-open-new-members-2023-11-16/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Lawder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/TRADE</category>
                
                <category>CPTPP</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[习近平会见乔·拜登时APEC示威焦点]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ioXuZqhxYGYc2GOYADPy544yDoM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/Z4LLU5H5DNLMFDHBKUZJ5S46HA.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>California Highway Patrol officers stand guard, as people protest against Chinese President Xi Jinping on the day of Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经济合作组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会当天，加州公路巡警在人们抗议中国国家主席习近平时站岗。 REUTERS/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/F_tW6fZ96mf3HNkf0uVnvf9ye2U=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7OYSA5RH3FOYPICFAF4HDGQ4YA.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People protest against Chinese President Xi Jinping on the day of Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行亚太经合组织 (APEC) 工商领导人峰会，人们抗议中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/qmhC-Xn20p4QuviULa_0PYiYrIo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JORQORFKYVJ5RBXI6HSC7PZCUA.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People protest against Chinese President Xi Jinping on the day of Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行亚太经合组织 (APEC) 工商领导人峰会，人们抗议中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/mHzw_v1AemJoPfV5IzGGk_F8yI0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/EA2DFZKAJ5NW7FGUCLYMYGR7QI.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Protesters taunt people in suit, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会集会上，抗议者嘲笑着西装革履的人。 REUTERS/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/z_I3LF5Q1LNzOdklTyr6xuQ5wgs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3S4NBLOQOBPZ3OXOGNPCWH4CXE.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Supporters of Chinese President Xi Jinping wave a flag at people protesting against Chinese President Xi Jinping on the day of Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 工商领导人峰会当天，中国国家主席习近平的支持者向抗议中国国家主席习近平的人们挥舞旗帜。 REUTERS/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UMFDwww_h47JGqvWkeFsnZ0rKXs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TJQXEP2ANVJMXD47UT2A2VOM4M.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Protesters scuffle with police, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，美国加利福尼亚州旧金山，抗议者在反对亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会的集会上与警察发生扭打。 REUTERS/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TSIg-P9NS4Ne-gHbR_bIxWnkapM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZFDYBYLUE5PSZDJXXFR7OL545Y.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Protesters demonstrate on the ground, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，抗议者在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的反对亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会的集会上进行示威。路透社/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/FbCF-nFb9S5t9yAyO4QUZLIXcKE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TZPHLS7UGRM7RKWTRGW23AQOGQ.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A protester confronts with a person, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，美国加利福尼亚州旧金山，在反对亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会的集会上，一名抗议者与一人对峙。路透社/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/yC244DtSNHKhuneBU8iUTECU2kw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/K5Q3RI6BG5LGHOUNEPPJRQU3DM.jpg" alt="Protest during the APEC CEO Summit in San Francisco翻译:旧金山亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会期间的抗议" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Police get through the line of protesters to reinforce, as protesters block, during a rally in opposition to the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) CEO Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S. November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Loren Elliott翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的一场反对亚太经合组织 (APEC) 首席执行官峰会的集会上，警方冲破抗议者的队伍进行增援。路透社/Loren Elliott</figcaption></figure>                             <p>A demonstrator draped in a Free Tibet flag climbed a flagpole in front of the hotel where Chinese President Xi Jinping was due to meet with U.S. CEOs on Wednesday evening, capping a day of demonstrations against, and for, the Chinese leader.翻译:一名身披自由西藏旗帜的示威者爬上中国国家主席习近平周三晚上会见美国首席执行官的酒店前的旗杆，结束了一天反对和支持中国领导人的示威活动。</p>   <p>Protesters of the Israel-Hamas war, critics of the global response to climate change and other causes all turned out for the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation</a> (APEC) forum in San Francisco, where global leaders and CEOs offered tempting targets.翻译:以色列-哈马斯战争的抗议者、全球应对气候变化和其他原因的批评者都聚集在旧金山举行的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-is-apec-asia-pacific-leaders-head-san-francisco-2023-11-01/">亚太经济合作组织</a>（APEC）论坛上，全球领导人和首席执行官提出了诱人的目标。</p>   <p>The day began with a couple of hundred protesters obstructing San Francisco streets and entrances to the convention center area for the meetings.翻译:这一天开始时，数百名抗议者堵塞了旧金山的街道和会议中心区域的入口。</p>   <p>But the focus of demonstrators shifted more towards anti- and pro-China during the day.翻译:但白天示威者的焦点更多地转向反华和亲华。</p>   <p>Hundreds of critics of Xi marched through downtown around noon, a major protest against the leader. They moved through the city's center, chanting "free Tibet" and "free Hong Kong."翻译:中午时分，数百名习近平批评者在市中心游行，这是对这位领导人的大规模抗议。他们穿过市中心，高呼“自由西藏”和“自由香港”。</p>   <p>Headed by a police escort, the peaceful group - which stretched for multiple city blocks - blocked one of the main downtown thoroughfares, as it moved in a slow circle around the convention center's perimeter.翻译:在警察护送的带领下，这群和平的团体绵延多个街区，封锁了市中心的一条主干道，并绕着会议中心周边缓慢移动。</p>   <p>“We can say beyond a reasonable doubt that this will be the largest anti-Xi protest during the bilateral talks hosted here in the United States in the history of Xi Jinping’s time as a dictator of China,” Pema Doma, executive director of Students for a Free Tibet, said early in the day.翻译:“我们可以毫无疑问地说，这将是习近平作为中国独裁者时期历史上在美国举行的双边会谈期间最大规模的反习近平抗议活动，”学生组织执行主任佩玛·多马(Pema Doma)说。当天早些时候就说过“自由西藏”。</p>   <p>Still, local television showed crowds welcoming Xi, waving huge Chinese and American flags, as well as posters of the two flags together, along a highway south of San Francisco where the presidents met. Some protesters also lined that route.翻译:尽管如此，当地电视台还是显示，在两国总统会晤的旧金山以南的一条高速公路上，人群挥舞着巨大的中国和美国国旗，以及两国国旗并在一起的海报，欢迎习近平。一些抗议者也在这条路线上排队。</p>   <p>And in the evening, ahead of the meeting between Xi and U.S. CEOs, supporters and protesters initially both lined the street. That is where the flagpole climber took the message of Free Tibet up the pole.翻译:晚上，在习近平与美国首席执行官会面之前，支持者和抗议者最初都站在街道上。这就是旗杆攀登者将自由西藏的信息带到旗杆上的地方。</p>   <p>By midevening, a couple hundred pro-China supporters dominated the block, singing and waving flags.翻译:到了晚上，数百名亲中国支持者占据了整个街区，一边唱歌一边挥舞旗帜。</p>   <p>Demonstrators for non-Chinese causes have been active since at least Sunday, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/apec-san-francisco-protesters-span-gamut-political-issues-2023-11-13/">some crowds stretching for blocks</a>. The group early on Wednesday formed a human chain that prevented some conference attendees from walking through the intersection.翻译:至少从周日开始，支持非华人事业的示威者就一直很活跃， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/apec-san-francisco-protesters-span-gamut-political-issues-2023-11-13/">一些人群甚至延伸到了几个街区</a>。周三早些时候，该组织形成了一条人链，阻止一些与会者穿过十字路口。</p>   <p>"I'm actually kind of impressed by the fact that there's so few people here and they've actually kind of gummed up the works a little bit," said Gary Hughes from the advocacy group Biofuelwatch.翻译:“事实上，这里的人很少，而且他们实际上有点搞砸了，这一事实给我留下了深刻的印象，”倡导组织生物燃料观察的加里·休斯说。</p>   <p>Protesters held signs that said "War criminals out of SF" and "From Palestine to the Philippines stop the US war machine."翻译:抗议者举着标语，上面写着“战犯滚出旧金山”和“从巴勒斯坦到菲律宾，阻止美国战争机器”。</p>   <p>Police donned protective helmets, but there were no major clashes.翻译:警察戴上了防护头盔，但没有发生重大冲突。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/san-francisco-patches-over-homelessness-drug-abuse-apec-2023-11-15/">San Francisco has cleaned up downtown streets</a> for the meeting, and it had prepared for potential confrontation with demonstrators: eight-foot-high (2.4-meter-high) metal mesh barriers have been erected to keep people on sidewalks from interfering with vehicle traffic near the convention center.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/san-francisco-patches-over-homelessness-drug-abuse-apec-2023-11-15/">旧金山已经为会议清理了市中心街道</a>，并为可能与示威者发生对抗做好了准备：已经竖起八英尺高（2.4米高）的金属网屏障，以防止人行道上的人们干扰附近的车辆交通会议中心。</p>   <p>The potential for disruptions around the summit site, portions of which were shut to vehicles and foot traffic, led the U.S. Department of Homeland Security to designate the meeting a national special security event, putting the U.S. Secret Service in charge of coordination of policing agencies.翻译:由于峰会地点周围可能出现干扰，其中部分地点禁止车辆和行人通行，美国国土安全部将此次会议指定为国家特别安全活动，并由美国特勤局负责协调警务机构。</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Ann Saphir and Loren Elliott; Writing By Peter Henderson; Editing by Jonathan Oatis and Stephen Coates翻译:Ann Saphir 和 Loren Elliott 的补充报道；作者：彼得·亨德森；乔纳森·奥蒂斯和斯蒂芬·科茨编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 03:00:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">V5Z5PTD2ABL6LAMVFZUIDWAYCM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/apec-protesters-turn-out-early-xi-jinping-joe-biden-meeting-day-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Max Cherney, Matt Mcknight, Carlos Barria]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/PROTEST (UPDATE 2, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[拜登表示向以色列明确表示占领加沙将是一个错误]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Esrf4ZIAUpA87VuVmGspj2PRJH0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZIXIVINHXVMIPH4V3ECM27RGOI.jpg" alt="U.S. President Biden visits Israel amid the ongoing conflict between Israel and Hamas翻译:美国总统拜登在以色列和哈马斯之间持续冲突之际访问以色列" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Biden attends a meeting with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, as he visits Israel amid the ongoing conflict between Israel and Hamas, in Tel Aviv, Israel, October 18, 2023. REUTERS/Evelyn Hockstein//File Photo翻译:拜登于 2023 年 10 月 18 日在以色列特拉维夫出席与以色列总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡的会晤，当时他正值以色列与哈马斯之间持续不断的冲突而访问以色列。 REUTERS/Evelyn Hockstein//档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S. President Joe Biden on Wednesday said he had made it clear to Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu that a two-state solution was the only answer to resolve the Israel-Palestinian conflict and that occupying Gaza would be "a big mistake."翻译:美国总统乔·拜登周三表示，他已向以色列总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡明确表示，两国解决方案是解决以巴冲突的唯一答案，占领加沙将是“一个大错误”。</p>   <p>Biden told reporters he was doing everything in his power to free hostages held by the Hamas militant group in Gaza, but that did not mean sending in the U.S. military.翻译:拜登告诉记者，他正在尽一切努力解救加沙哈马斯武装组织扣押的人质，但这并不意味着派遣美军。</p>   <p>The U.S. president had told reporters this week that his message to the hostages was "Hang in there, we're coming," raising questions about what he meant.翻译:美国总统本周告诉记者，他向人质发出的信息是“坚持住，我们来了”，这引发了人们对他的意思的疑问。</p>   <p>Asked to clarify the comment, Biden told a news conference: "What I meant was, I'm doing everything in my power to get you out. Coming to help you, get you out. I don't mean sending in military in there ... I was not talking about the military."翻译:当被要求澄清这一评论时，拜登在新闻发布会上说：“我的意思是，我正在尽我所能让你出去。来帮助你，让你出去。我并不是说派军队去那里......我不是在谈论军队。”</p>   <p>Biden said he was working on the issue constantly, and would not stop until the hostages - including a three-year-old American child - were freed.翻译:拜登表示，他正在不断解决这个问题，在人质（包括一名三岁的美国儿童）获释之前不会停止。</p>   <p>Qatar, where Hamas operates a political office, has been leading mediation between the Islamist militant group and Israeli officials for the release of more than 240 hostages. They were taken by militants when they stormed into Israel on Oct. 7. Israel says 1,200 people were killed during the rampage.翻译:哈马斯政治办公室所在的卡塔尔一直在该伊斯兰激进组织与以色列官员之间进行调解，以释放 240 名人质。他们在 10 月 7 日冲进以色列时被武装分子抓获。以色列称，在这场暴乱中，有 1,200 人死亡。</p>   <p>Israel then launched an unrelenting bombardment of Hamas-ruled Gaza and late last month began an armoured invasion of the enclave, where more than 11,000 people have been killed, around 40% of them children with more buried under the rubble, according to Palestinian officials.翻译:据巴勒斯坦官员称，以色列随后对哈马斯统治的加沙发动了无情的轰炸，并于上月底开始对这一飞地进行装甲入侵，造成超过 11,000 人死亡，其中约 40% 是儿童，更多人被埋在废墟下。</p>   <p>Biden said Hamas was committing war crimes by having its military headquarters under a hospital, repeating a statement made a White House spokesperson on Tuesday, and he was confident about the U.S. intelligence supporting that "fact."翻译:拜登表示，哈马斯将其军事总部设在医院之下，犯下了战争罪，他重申了白宫发言人周二的声明，他对美国情报部门支持这一“事实”充满信心。</p>   <p>He said Israel had gone into Gaza's biggest hospital, Al Shifa, with a limited number of troops with guns, and was not carpet-bombing the site.翻译:他说，以色列带着数量有限的持枪部队进入了加沙最大的医院Al Shifa，并没有对现场进行地毯式轰炸。</p>   <p>"They were told ... we discussed the need for them to be incredibly careful," Biden said, adding that Israel had an obligation to use as much caution as possible in going after targets.翻译:拜登说：“他们被告知……我们讨论了他们需要非常小心的必要性。”他补充说，以色列有义务在追击目标时尽可能谨慎。</p>   <p>But he said it was "not realistic" to expect Israel to stop its military actions, given threats by senior Hamas officials that they intended to attack Israel again.翻译:但他表示，鉴于哈马斯高级官员威胁称他们打算再次袭击以色列，期望以色列停止军事行动“不现实”。</p>   <p>He said Israel was also bringing in incubators and other equipment to help people, and were giving doctors, nurses and other staff the opportunity to "get out of harm's way."翻译:他说，以色列还引进了孵化器和其他设备来帮助人们，并为医生、护士和其他工作人员提供了“摆脱伤害”的机会。</p>   <p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-military-says-weapons-found-al-shifa-hospital-2023-11-15/">Israel on Wednesday said its troops</a> found Hamas weapons and combat gear in Al Shifa hospital during a search on Wednesday. Hamas dismissed the announcement as "lies."翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-military-says-weapons-found-al-shifa-hospital-2023-11-15/">以色列周三表示，其部队</a>在周三的搜查中在希法医院发现了哈马斯的武器和战斗装备。哈马斯驳斥了这一声明，称其为“谎言”。</p>   <p>Biden said he had told Netanyahu that he did not believe the war would end until a two-state solution was reached.翻译:拜登表示，他已告诉内塔尼亚胡，他认为在达成两国解决方案之前，战争不会结束。</p>   <p>"I made it clear to Israel that I think it's a big mistake to for them to occupy Gaza," he said.翻译:“我向以色列明确表示，我认为他们占领加沙是一个很大的错误，”他说。</p>    <span>Reporting by Trevor Hunnicutt and Jeff Mason; Writing by Andrea Shalal; Editing by Sandra Maler &amp; Simon Cameron-Moore翻译:特雷弗·亨尼卡特和杰夫·梅森的报道；安德里亚·沙拉尔 (Andrea Shalal) 撰写；桑德拉·马勒和西蒙·卡梅伦-摩尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 02:51:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">NH55LHI3AFPA3NUFCPEKNVDQM4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-says-made-clear-israel-occupying-gaza-would-be-mistake-2023-11-16/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Trevor Hunnicutt, Jeff Mason]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ISRAEL</category>
                
                <category>PALESTINIANS/BIDEN (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[拜登和习近平“直言不讳”的会谈达成了军事、芬太尼方面的协议]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/zgBiYjyzV89yRTVDfQz_OzJLYrs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JQJGEZ7WUZPGRE4ZJG7TEOQ5W4.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden walks with Chinese President Xi Jinping at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经济合作组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登与中国国家主席习近平在菲洛丽庄园散步。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/FvilMKflkrYZQdGP7GSAh5f5V5c=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/47OZBB6DJZPCBBXDPLRZ52XHGM.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden shakes hands with Chinese President Xi Jinping at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登在菲洛丽庄园与中国国家主席习近平握手。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/uJlbUuBKlrkFU-CkBFWK1pCOyn8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4LSUN2CXHZKPXNOXEZKFD47QI4.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping attend a bilateral meeting at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经济合作组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平出席在菲洛丽庄园举行的双边会议。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/1aQy68ht2GBcwt8yS92TftHRBS0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/IXQBFFPVX5NWBIPIGGTFBAM2GE.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden welcomes Chinese President Xi Jinping at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登在菲洛丽庄园欢迎中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/tqs78ae9Y1UTE522yIVIOzSVmBI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/P3ULMM4OFBJNRKE5X3M2YDA7FQ.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登在菲洛丽庄园会见中国国家主席习近平。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TG1TEqoix0BmSLzAs_2ZQkKdhx0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XVZII463FBIDNM7WDJMOYPZZ6Q.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden disembarks from Air Force One at San Francisco International Airport, as he arrives to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 14 日，美国总统乔·拜登在旧金山国际机场从空军一号下机，抵达美国加利福尼亚州旧金山参加亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会。 REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lTdjpZN9pb-WDBwFVbkn4Qq-Rig=/1878x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JFCDJ65EHNIW7MVYN3IPSOJ6AQ.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping waves as he arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的APEC（亚太经合组织）峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small/资料照片</figcaption></figure>                         <p>U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese leader Xi Jinping agreed on Wednesday to open a presidential hotline, resume military-to-military communications and work to curb fentanyl production, showing tangible progress in their first face-to-face talks in a year.翻译:美国总统乔·拜登和中国领导人习近平周三同意开通总统热线、恢复军队间沟通以及遏制芬太尼生产，这在一年来首次面对面会谈中取得了切实进展。</p>   <p>Biden and Xi met for about four hours on the outskirts of San Francisco to discuss issues that have strained U.S.-Chinese relations.翻译:拜登和习近平在旧金山郊区会面约四个小时，讨论导致美中关系紧张的问题。</p>   <p>They plan to resume military contacts that China severed after then-House of Representatives Speaker Nancy Pelosi visited Taiwan in August 2022.翻译:他们计划恢复2022年8月时任众议院议长南希·佩洛西访问台湾后中国中断的军事联系。</p>   <p>“We’re back to direct, open clear direct communication on a direct basis,” Biden said.翻译:拜登说：“我们回到了直接、公开、明确的直接沟通。”</p>   <p>In addition, Biden said he and Xi agreed to high-level communications.翻译:拜登表示，他和习近平同意进行高层沟通。 "He and I agreed that each one of us can pick up the phone call directly and we'll be heard immediately."</p>   <p>But in a comment likely to irk the Chinese, Biden told reporters later that he had not changed his view that Xi is a dictator.翻译:但拜登后来对记者表示，他并没有改变对习近平是独裁者的看法，这可能会激怒中国人。</p>   <p>"Well, look, he is. I mean, he’s a dictator in the sense that he is a guy who runs a country that is a communist country," Biden said.翻译:“嗯，看，他是。我的意思是，他是一个独裁者，因为他管理着一个共产主义国家，”拜登说。</p>   <p>Xi told Biden that the negative views of the Communist Party in the United States were unfair, a U.S. official told reporters after the meeting.翻译:一位美国官员在会后告诉记者，习近平告诉拜登，美国共产党的负面看法是不公平的。</p>   <p>Biden and Xi came into the talks looking to smooth over a rocky period in relations that took a turn for the worse after a suspected Chinese surveillance balloon transited the United States and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/biden-says-us-is-going-take-care-of-chinese-balloon-2023-02-04/">was shot down</a> by a U.S. fighter jet in February.翻译:拜登和习近平参加会谈是为了缓和两国关系的不稳定时期，自二月份一个疑似中国监视气球飞越美国并被一架美国战斗机<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/biden-says-us-is-going-take-care-of-chinese-balloon-2023-02-04/">击落</a>后，两国关系变得更糟。</p>   <p>Biden said he raised areas where Washington has concerns, including detained U.S. citizens, human rights and Beijing’s aggressive activities in the South China Sea.翻译:拜登表示，他提出了华盛顿担忧的领域，包括被拘留的美国公民、人权和北京在南海的侵略活动。</p>   <p>"Just talking, just being blunt with one another so there’s no misunderstanding," Biden said.</p>    <h 1="">MILITARY, TAIWAN</h>  <p>Biden requested that both countries institutionalize the military-to-military dialogues, and U.S. Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin will meet his Chinese counterpart when that person is named, a senior U.S. official said.翻译:一位美国高级官员表示，拜登要求两国将军事对话制度化，美国国防部长劳埃德·奥斯汀将在中国国防部长提名后与其会面。</p>   <p>U.S. and China's militaries have had a number of near-misses and acrimonious exchanges over the past year.翻译:过去一年里，美国和中国军队发生了多次险些失手和激烈的交锋。</p>   <p>Biden and Xi agreed China would stem the export of items related to the production of the opioid fentanyl, a leading cause of drug overdoses in the United States. "It’s going to save lives,” Biden said, adding he appreciated Xi’s “commitment” on the issue.翻译:拜登和习近平一致同意，中国将阻止与阿片类药物芬太尼生产相关的产品出口，阿片类药物芬太尼是美国吸毒过量的主要原因。拜登说：“这将拯救生命。”他补充说，他赞赏习近平在这个问题上的“承诺”。</p>   <p>Under the agreement, China will go directly after specific chemical companies that make fentanyl precursors, a senior U.S. official told reporters. He vowed to "trust but verify" Chinese actions on the drug.翻译:一位美国高级官员告诉记者，根据协议，中国将直接打击生产芬太尼前体的特定化学公司。他发誓要“信任但核实”中国对该药物的行动。</p>   <p>The two leaders also agreed to get experts together to discuss the risks of artificial intelligence.翻译:两位领导人还同意召集专家讨论人工智能的风险。</p>   <p>A U.S. official described an exchange over Taiwan, the democratic island that China claims as its territory. China's preference is for peaceful reunification with the Chinese-claimed island of Taiwan, Xi told Biden, the U.S. official said, but Xi went on to talk about conditions in which force could be used.翻译:一名美国官员描述了一场围绕台湾问题的交流，中国声称台湾是其领土。这位美国官员表示，习近平告诉拜登，中国倾向于和平统一中国声称拥有主权的台湾岛，但习近平接着谈到了可以使用武力的条件。</p>   <p>Biden said he stressed the need for peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait. The U.S. official said Biden argued to maintain the status quo and for China to respect Taiwan's electoral process.翻译:拜登表示，他强调台海需要和平与稳定。这位美国官员表示，拜登主张维持现状，并要求中国尊重台湾的选举程序。</p>   <p>"President Xi responded 'Look, peace is all well and good, but at some point we need to move towards resolution more generally'," the official quoted Xi as saying.翻译:这位官员援引习近平的话说：“习主席回应道，‘看，和平固然很好，但在某些时候我们需要更广泛地解决问题’。”</p>   <p>Xi also urged the United States to stop sending weapons to Taiwan and support China's peaceful "reunification" with Taiwan, Chinese state media said.翻译:中国官方媒体称，习近平还敦促美国停止向台湾运送武器，支持中国与台湾和平“统一”。</p>   <p>Biden said he asked Xi to use his influence with Iran to urge Tehran not to launch proxy attacks on U.S. targets in the Middle East as the Israel-Hamas conflict continues in Gaza.</p>    <h 1="">RESPECT</h>  <p>Biden welcomed the Chinese leader at the Filoli estate, a country house and well-manicured gardens about 30 miles (48 km) south of San Francisco, where they will move later for a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/">summit of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation</a> (APEC) forum.翻译:拜登在位于旧金山以南约 30 英里（48 公里）的菲洛丽庄园迎接了中国领导人，菲洛丽庄园是一座乡间别墅，花园修剪整齐，稍后他们将前往那里参加<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/">亚太经济合作组织 (APEC) 论坛峰会</a>。</p>   <p>Xi came into the meeting looking for respect from the United States as China's economy struggles to recover from sluggish growth.翻译:在中国经济努力从增长乏力中复苏之际，习近平参加会议是为了寻求美国的尊重。</p>   <p>Biden, who had long sought the meeting, struck a welcoming tone aimed at showing respect, and treated him as a major player on global hotspots.翻译:拜登长期以来一直寻求这次会面，他以欢迎的语气表示尊重，并将他视为全球热点问题的主要参与者。</p>   <p>"Planet Earth is big enough for the two countries to succeed," Xi told Biden as they and their delegations sat across from each other at a long table in an ornate conference room.翻译:“地球足够大，足以让两国取得成功，”习近平和两国代表团在一间华丽的会议室里面对面坐在一张长桌旁时对拜登说。</p>   <p>Biden said the U.S. and China had to ensure that competition between them "does not veer into conflict" and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-objects-us-proposal-apec-trade-investment-policies-source-2023-11-15/">manage their relationship</a> "responsibly."翻译:拜登表示，美国和中国必须确保两国之间的竞争“不会演变成冲突”，并“负责任地” <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china-objects-us-proposal-apec-trade-investment-policies-source-2023-11-15/">管理两国关系</a>。</p>   <p>After lunch, the leaders took a short walk together in the manicured garden of the mansion following an interaction that lasted around four hours. Biden waved to reporters and gave a two thumbs up sign when asked how the talks were going. "Well," he said.翻译:午餐后，两位领导人在豪宅修剪整齐的花园里一起散步，进行了约四个小时的互动。当被问及谈判进展如何时，拜登向记者挥手并竖起两个大拇指。 “好吧，”他说。</p>   <p>Xi told Biden as they began their talks a lot had happened since their last meeting <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/top-takeaways-biden-xi-meeting-bali-2022-11-14/">a year ago in Bali</a>. "The world has emerged from the COVID pandemic, but is still under its tremendous impacts. The global economy is recovering, but its momentum remains sluggish."翻译:习近平在会谈开始时告诉拜登<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/top-takeaways-biden-xi-meeting-bali-2022-11-14/">，自一年前巴厘岛</a>上次会面以来发生了很多事情。 “世界已经摆脱了新冠肺炎疫情的影响，但仍受到巨大影响。全球经济正在复苏，但动能依然低迷。”</p>   <p>He called the U.S.-China relationship "the most important bilateral relationship in the world," and said he and Biden "shoulder heavy responsibilities for the two peoples, for the world, and for history."翻译:他称美中关系是“世界上最重要的双边关系”，并表示他和拜登“对两国人民、对世界、对历史肩负着沉重的责任”。</p>   <p>"For two large countries like China and the United States, turning their back on each other is not an option," he said. "It is unrealistic for one side to remodel the other, and conflict and confrontation has unbearable consequences for both sides."翻译:“对于中国和美国这样的两个大国来说，互相背弃不是一个选择，”他说。 “一方改造另一方是不现实的，冲突对抗会给双方带来难以承受的后果。”</p>   <p>Leaders from the 21-country group APEC - and hundreds of CEOs in San Francisco to court them - are meeting amid relative <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">Chinese economic weakness</a>, Beijing's territorial feuds with neighbors and a Middle East conflict that is dividing the United States from allies.翻译:亚太经合组织（APEC）21个国家的领导人以及在旧金山向他们示好的数百名首席执行官正在会面，背景是<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">中国经济相对疲软</a>、北京与邻国的领土争端以及导致美国与盟友分裂的中东冲突。</p>    <span>Reporting by Trevor Hunnicutt; Additional reporting by Steve Holland, Michael Martina, Martin Pollard, Jeff Mason, David Lawder, David Brunnstrom and Andrea Shalal; Editing by Josie Kao and Stephen Coates翻译:特雷弗·亨尼卡特报道； Steve Holland、Michael Martina、Martin Pollard、Jeff Mason、David Lawder、David Brunnstrom 和 Andrea Shalal 的补充报道；编辑：Josie Kao 和 Stephen Coates</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 02:43:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZYRPUF6GFRLTHLGM6Y6UA65MXU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Trevor Hunnicutt, David Brunnstrom, Jeff Mason]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA (UPDATE 10, PIX, TV)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[亚洲股市波动，数据公布后美联储暂停预期]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/PmoMGVBFmF6801QYlY199bWN2vo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/NCHVEVWNNVPLVHULYVRKT3SYNA.jpg" alt="Passersby are reflected on an electric stock quotation board outside a brokerage in Tokyo翻译:东京一家经纪公司外的电子股票报价板上反映了路人的情况" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Passersby are reflected on an electric stock quotation board outside a brokerage in Tokyo翻译:东京一家经纪公司外的电子股票报价板上反映了路人的情况, Japan April 18, 2023.  REUTERS/Issei Kato/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>Asian stock markets struggled for momentum on Thursday, after heavy gains this week, as expectations for a pause in Fed policy tightening remained intact despite U.S. data pointing to strength in parts of the economy.翻译:亚洲股市在本周大幅上涨后，周四仍难以保持动能，尽管美国数据显示部分经济强劲，但对美联储暂停收紧政策的预期仍未改变。</p>   <p>U.S. economic data this week has left investors in the same state of confusion about Fed policy as they have been in for weeks. Retail sales proved strong while producer prices inflation, coming soon after the below-forecast core inflation, reinforced the disinflation theme and supported views of a peak in U.S. rates.翻译:本周的美国经济数据让投资者对美联储政策陷入了几周以来的困惑状态。零售销售表现强劲，而在低于预期的核心通胀之后不久出现的生产者价格通胀强化了通缩主题，并支持了美国利率见顶的观点。</p>   <p>"With inflation, labour market and retail sales data now published for this month, and expectations for an FOMC hike in December and January priced at zero, a huge amount of information has been digested by markets in a very short time," analysts at ANZ said in a note.翻译:澳新银行分析师表示：“随着本月公布的通胀、劳动力市场和零售销售数据，以及联邦公开市场委员会 (FOMC) 12 月和 1 月加息的预期为零，市场在很短的时间内消化了大量信息。”在注释中说。</p>   <p>"A period of consolidation seems warranted, especially if Fed officials push back against the recent easing in financial conditions."翻译:“一段时期的整合似乎是必要的，特别是如果美联储官员反对最近金融状况的宽松政策的话。”</p>   <p>Early in the Asian trading day, MSCI's broadest index of Asia-Pacific shares outside Japan <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIAPJ0000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIAPJ0000PUS)</a> was down 0.2%. The index is up 7.1% so far this month.翻译:亚洲交易日早盘，摩根士丹利资本国际 (MSCI) 日本以外亚太地区最广泛股票指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MIAPJ0000PUS" target="_blank">(.MIAPJ0000PUS)</a>下跌 0.2%。本月迄今为止，该指数已上涨 7.1%。</p>   <p>Australian shares <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.AXJO" target="_blank">(.AXJO)</a> were down 0.33%, while Japan's Nikkei stock index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a> slid 0.36%.翻译:澳大利亚股市<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.AXJO" target="_blank">(.AXJO)</a>下跌 0.33%，日本日经股票指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.N225" target="_blank">(.N225)</a>下跌 0.36%。</p>   <p>The MSCI Asia ex-Japan index, MSCI Emerging Market index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MSCIEF" target="_blank">(.MSCIEF)</a> and Nikkei all posted their biggest gains in a year, of 2.5% or more, on Wednesday.翻译:周三，MSCI 亚洲（日本除外）指数、MSCI 新兴市场指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.MSCIEF" target="_blank">(.MSCIEF)</a>和日经指数均录得一年来最大涨幅，涨幅达 2.5% 或以上。</p>   <p>Chinese industrial and retail numbers calmed nerves and lifted mainland stocks on Wednesday, with both data beating expectations in October even as the underlying economic picture highlighted significant pockets of weakness with the crisis-hit property sector continuing to forestall a full-blown revival.翻译:周三，中国工业和零售数据安抚了人们的情绪，提振了内地股市，尽管基本经济形势突显出显着的疲软，受危机打击的房地产行业继续阻碍全面复苏，但 10 月份的两项数据都超出了预期。</p>   <p>China's blue-chip CSI300 index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI300" target="_blank">(.CSI300)</a> was 0.1% lower in early trade. Hong Kong's Hang Seng index <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">(.HSI)</a> dropped 0.35%.翻译:中国蓝筹股沪深300指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.CSI300" target="_blank">(.CSI300)</a>早盘下跌0.1%。香港恒生指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.HSI" target="_blank">（.HSI）</a>下跌0.35%。</p>   <p>While markets didn't react specifically to the news, investors also heard from the first meeting in a year between U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese leader Xi Jinping on Wednesday, that the two leaders had <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">agreed to resume</a> military-to-military communications and cooperate on anti-drug policies.翻译:尽管市场没有对这一消息做出具体反应，但投资者还从周三美国总统乔·拜登和中国领导人习近平一年来的首次会晤中获悉，两国领导人已<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">同意恢复</a>军事交流和合作关于禁毒政策。</p>   <p>On Wednesday, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-signal-more-gains-wall-street-eyes-data-biden-xi-meeting-2023-11-15/">U.S. stocks</a> closed slightly higher, as the inflation data reinforced investor hopes the Fed is done raising interest rates, while retail stocks were boosted by an upbeat forecast from Target.翻译:周三， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/futures-signal-more-gains-wall-street-eyes-data-biden-xi-meeting-2023-11-15/">美国股市</a>小幅收高，因通胀数据增强了投资者对美联储不再加息的希望，而零售股则因 Target 的乐观预测而受到提振。</p>   <p>The Dow Jones Industrial Average <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DJI" target="_blank">(.DJI)</a> rose 0.47%, the S&amp;P 500 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a> gained 0.16% and the Nasdaq Composite <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.IXIC" target="_blank">(.IXIC)</a> narrowed earlier gains to end flat.翻译:道琼斯工业平均指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DJI" target="_blank">(.DJI)</a>上涨 0.47%，标准普尔 500 指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX" target="_blank">(.SPX)</a>上涨 0.16%，纳斯达克综合指数<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.IXIC" target="_blank">(.IXIC)</a>收窄早盘涨幅，最终持平。</p>   <p>Money market traders have fully priced in the odds that the U.S. central bank will keep rates steady in December, as per CME Group's Fedwatch tool. They also see the first rate cut of the cycle to kick off in May 2024.翻译:根据芝商所 (CME Group) 的 Fedwatch 工具，货币市场交易员已完全消化了美联储 12 月维持利率稳定的可能性。他们还预计本周期的首次降息将于 2024 年 5 月开始。</p>   <p>Investors are increasingly pricing in more rate cuts next year with bond yields and the dollar coming under downward pressure. Some of that reversed on Wednesday, with Treasury yields and the dollar <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/global-markets-view-asia-graphics-pix-2023-11-15/">rebounding slightly</a> from the previous session's fall.翻译:随着债券收益率和美元面临下行压力，投资者越来越多地预计明年将进一步降息。其中一些情况在周三发生了逆转，美国国债收益率和美元从前一交易日的下跌中<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/global-markets-view-asia-graphics-pix-2023-11-15/">小幅反弹</a>。</p>   <p>The yield on benchmark 10-year Treasury notes was at 4.5117% compared with its U.S. close of 4.537% on Wednesday. The two-year yield , which rises with traders' expectations of higher Fed fund rates, touched 4.8991% compared with a U.S. close of 4.916%.翻译:基准 10 年期国债收益率为 4.5117%，而周三美国收盘价为 4.537%。随着交易员对联邦基金利率上升的预期而上升，两年期国债收益率触及4.8991%，而美国收盘价为4.916%。</p>   <p>In currencies, the European single currency was up 0.1% on the day at $1.0852, having gained 2.61% in a month, while the dollar index , which tracks the greenback against a basket of currencies of other major trading partners, was up at 104.33.翻译:货币方面，欧洲单一货币当天上涨0.1%至1.0852美元，一个月内上涨2.61%，而追踪美元兑其他主要贸易伙伴一篮子货币的美元指数上涨至104.33。</p>   <p>U.S. crude dipped 0.55% to $76.24 a barrel. Brent crude fell to $80.75 per barrel.翻译:美国原油下跌 0.55% 至每桶 76.24 美元。布伦特原油跌至每桶 80.75 美元。</p>   <p>Gold was slightly lower. Spot gold was traded at $1958.49 per ounce.翻译:黄金小幅走低。现货黄金交易价格为每盎司1958.49美元。</p>    <span>Reporting by Julie Zhu and Vidya Ranganathan; Editing by Lincoln Feast.翻译:Julie Zhu 和 Vidya Ranganathan 报道；林肯·盛宴编辑。</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 02:27:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">UTR47LWQFNMVBDTUK3AV525FAI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/global-markets-wrapup-1-2023-11-16/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Julie Zhu]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>MARKETS/ (WRAPUP 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[要点 - 拜登和习近平会面：台湾、伊朗、芬太尼和人工智能]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Sys3ITcIxKEfDRzHsj9ZPEKYcGk=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WE2S2FRU35JOHO7DY2TFUZUVIA.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden waves as he walks with Chinese President Xi Jinping at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登与中国国家主席习近平在菲洛丽庄园散步时挥手致意。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S. President Joe Biden and China's Xi Jinping met for about four hours on Wednesday to discuss issues ranging from military conflicts to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">drug-trafficking</a>.翻译:美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平周三会面约四个小时，讨论从军事冲突到<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">贩毒等</a>一系列问题。</p>   <p>Biden welcomed the Chinese leader at the Filoli estate, a country house and gardens about 30 miles (48 km) south of San Francisco, ahead of a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/">summit of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation</a> (APEC) forum.翻译:在<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/veiled-swipe-china-blinken-tells-apec-us-believes-free-region-2023-11-14/">亚太经济合作组织 (APEC) 论坛峰会召开</a>之前，拜登在位于旧金山以南约 30 英里（48 公里）的菲洛丽庄园欢迎中国领导人。菲洛丽庄园是一座乡村别墅和花园。</p>   <p>Here's the key issues discussed.</p>    <h 1="">TAIWAN</h>  <p>The two leaders had a "substantial" discussion on Taiwan, with Xi telling Biden that Taiwan was the biggest, most dangerous issue facing the two superpowers, a senior U.S. official told reporters.翻译:一位美国高级官员告诉记者，两位领导人就台湾问题进行了“实质性”讨论，习近平告诉拜登，台湾是两个超级大国面临的最大、最危险的问题。</p>   <p>The Chinese leader said that China had no plans for military action against Taiwan in coming years, but also discussed conditions under which force could be used, the official said.翻译:这位官员表示，这位中国领导人表示，中国没有计划在未来几年对台湾采取军事行动，但也讨论了可以使用武力的条件。</p>   <p>Biden said he "stressed the importance of peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait." He also asked Xi to respect Taiwan's electoral process, the U.S. official said.翻译:拜登表示，他“强调了台海和平与稳定的重要性”。这位美国官员表示，他还要求习近平尊重台湾的选举程序。</p>   <p>Xi responded: "Look, peace is ... all well and good but at some point we need to move towards resolution more generally," the U.S. official said.</p>    <h 1="">MILITARY TALKS</h>  <p>Beijing said the two leaders agreed to resume military contacts that China severed after then-House of Representatives Speaker Nancy Pelosi visited Taiwan in August 2022.翻译:北京表示，两国领导人同意恢复中国在时任众议院议长南希·佩洛西于 2022 年 8 月访问台湾后中断的军事接触。</p>   <p>Biden made a "very clear request" that both countries institutionalize the military-to-military dialogues, and U.S. Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin will meet his Chinese counterpart when that person is named, a senior U.S. official said.</p>    <h 1="">LEADER TO LEADER TALKS</h>  <p>Biden said he and Xi agreed to high-level communications.翻译:拜登表示，他和习近平同意进行高层沟通。</p>   <p>"He and I agreed that each one of us can pick up the phone call directly and we'll be heard immediately," Biden told reporters after the meeting.</p>    <h 1="">COOPERATION AND CONCILIATION</h>  <p>Beijing's report of the meeting, via the Communist Party-controlled Chinese state media, emphasized the need for more cooperation, dialogue and respect. China and the United States should set an example for other countries, Xi told Biden, according to Chinese media, and promote cooperation on trade, agriculture, climate change and artificial intelligence.翻译:北京通过共产党控制的中国官方媒体对这次会议进行了报道，强调需要更多的合作、对话和尊重。据中国媒体报道，习近平告诉拜登，中美两国应为其他国家树立榜样，推动贸易、农业、气候变化和人工智能等领域的合作。</p>   <p>An official briefed on the talks said Beijing was also seeking a show of respect from the trip.</p>    <h 1="">FENTANYL</h>  <p>Biden and Xi agreed to cooperate on addressing the source of the opioid fentanyl, a leading cause of drug overdoses in the United States, the U.S. official said.翻译:这位美国官员表示，拜登和习近平同意合作解决阿片类药物芬太尼的来源问题，阿片类药物芬太尼是美国吸毒过量的主要原因。</p>   <p>Under the agreement, China will go directly after specific chemical companies that make fentanyl precursors.</p>    <h 1="">IRAN</h>  <p>The two leaders also discussed the unfolding crisis in the Middle East, with Biden asking China to weigh in with Iran and urge it to avoid steps that could be seen as provocative, the senior U.S. official told reporters.翻译:这位美国高级官员告诉记者，两位领导人还讨论了中东正在发生的危机，拜登要求中国对伊朗发表意见，并敦促其避免采取可能被视为挑衅的行动。</p>   <p>Chinese officials told the U.S. side that they had engaged in discussions with Iran on regional risks.</p>    <h 1="">ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE</h>  <p>The two leaders also discussed artificial intelligence (AI)and agreed that AI was used in military or nuclear operations, it created real risks.翻译:两位领导人还讨论了人工智能（AI），并一致认为人工智能用于军事或核行动，会带来真正的风险。</p>   <p>The senior U.S. official said both sides were "very much focused" on practices regarding AI that could be dangerous or destabilizing, but not ready for any mutual declaration.翻译:这位美国高级官员表示，双方“非常关注”可能危险或破坏稳定的人工智能做法，但尚未准备好相互宣布。</p>    <span>Reporting by Jeff Mason, Trevor Hunnicutt; writing by Andrea Shalal; Editing by Heather Timmons and Stephen Coates翻译:杰夫·梅森、特雷弗·亨尼卡特报道；安德里亚·沙拉尔 (Andrea Shalal) 撰写；希瑟·蒂蒙斯和斯蒂芬·科茨编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 02:21:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">SRN4I2CPMZIURNTS6ZG3WP5WGU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/takeaways-biden-xi-meeting-taiwan-iran-fentanyl-ai-2023-11-16/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Trevor Hunnicutt, Jeff Mason]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>BIDEN</category>
                
                <category>XI (TAKEAWAYS)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[宏观数据暗示美联储稍后降息，美元坚挺]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/qwA5DF3ouocGNuFReFfk7fIBxbo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BWNBPMNMNJO4HGR73B356D6SBQ.jpg" alt="Illustration shows U.S. Dollar and Euro banknotes翻译:插图显示美元和欧元纸币" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Dollar and Euro banknotes are seen in this illustration taken July 17, 2022. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo翻译:这张摄于 2022 年 7 月 17 日的插图中可以看到美元和欧元纸币。REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo</figcaption></figure>       <p>The dollar held its ground early on Thursday after a volatile two days that saw sharp declines followed by a rebound as traders took incoming <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-retail-sales-fall-slightly-october-2023-11-15/">economic data</a> as signalling the Federal Reserve will wait longer before cutting interest rates.翻译:周四早盘，美元在经历了连续两天的大幅下跌后反弹，周四早些时候守住了阵地，因为交易员将即将公布的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-retail-sales-fall-slightly-october-2023-11-15/">经济数据</a>视为美联储将在降息之前等待更长时间的信号。</p>   <p>The risk-sensitive Australian and New Zealand dollars sank amid a decline in regional equities.翻译:由于地区股市下跌，对风险敏感的澳元和新西兰元下跌。</p>   <p>The U.S. currency was little changed at $1.08425 per euro and slipped 0.15% to 151.15 yen after mounting a recovery on Wednesday from its steepest declines against major peers in a year.翻译:美元兑日元汇率几乎没有变化，为1欧元兑1.08425美元，周三从兑主要货币一年来的最大跌幅中复苏后，下跌0.15%至151.15日元。</p>   <p>The dollar index - which measures the greenback against the euro, yen and four other rivals - added 0.11% to 104.43. It gained 0.31% on Wednesday, following a 1.51% plunge the previous day.翻译:衡量美元兑欧元、日元和其他四种货币的美元指数上涨 0.11%，至 104.43。继前一天暴跌 1.51% 后，周三上涨 0.31%。</p>   <p>The dollar drew support from better-than-expected retail sales numbers combined with more signs of a cooling of inflation, feeding into the narrative for an economic 'soft landing', which would allow the Fed more time before cutting rates.翻译:好于预期的零售销售数据以及更多通胀降温迹象为美元提供支撑，助长了经济“软着陆”的说法，这将使美联储在降息之前有更多时间。</p>   <p>Traders trimmed the odds for a first reduction by March to less than 1-in-4 from better than 1-in-3 a day earlier, according to the CME Group's FedWatch Tool.翻译:根据芝加哥商品交易所集团 (CME Group) 的 FedWatch 工具，交易员将 3 月份首次降息的可能性从前一天的三分之一以下下调至不到四分之一。</p>   <p>"While inflation is falling, the economy remains robust, which might even allow the Fed to increase rates if they chose," although there doesn't seem to be appetite for a hike among Fed officials currently, said James Kniveton, senior corporate FX dealer at Convera.翻译:高级企业外汇交易商 James Kniveton 表示，“虽然通胀正在下降，但经济依然强劲，这甚至可能允许美联储在愿意的情况下加息”，尽管目前美联储官员似乎没有加息的兴趣。在孔维拉。</p>   <p>Elsewhere, the Aussie slid 0.29% to $0.64905, and the New Zealand dollar declined 0.5% to $0.5993.翻译:其他方面，澳元下跌 0.29% 至 0.64905 美元，新西​​兰元下跌 0.5% 至 0.5993 美元。</p>   <p>Australia's currency failed to draw support from a strong rebound in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australia-employment-rebounds-oct-jobless-rate-still-edges-up-2023-11-16/">employment</a>, as traders keyed on the fact that gains were mostly in part-time labour, while the jobless rate actually ticked higher.翻译:澳元未能从<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/australia-employment-rebounds-oct-jobless-rate-still-edges-up-2023-11-16/">就业</a>强劲反弹中获得支撑，因为交易员重点关注的事实是，收益主要来自兼职劳动力，而失业率实际上却在走高。</p>    <span>Reporting by Kevin Buckland
Editing by Shri Navaratnam翻译:凯文·巴克兰 (Kevin Buckland) 报道 施里·纳瓦拉特南 (Shri Navaratnam) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 02:14:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZV3XZ5X4ZFIELFTAIFT6SRKOT4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/currencies/dollar-holds-ground-macro-data-hints-later-fed-rate-cut-2023-11-16/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Kevin Buckland]]></author>
            
                
                <category>GLOBAL</category>
                
                <category>FOREX/</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国不那么特别的经济区体现了严峻的新现实]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ipeugncMrOdjJYE18onSuCHkmyI=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6TBGKKAFRVORXCEV57ZG5WZCBQ.jpg" alt="Qianhai in Shenzhen翻译:深圳前海" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A worker rides a scooter past an unfinished bridge near the centre of the Qianhai new district in Shenzhen, Guangdong province, China August 25, 2023. REUTERS/David Kirton翻译:2023 年 8 月 25 日，一名工人骑着摩托车经过中国广东省深圳市前海新区中心附近一座未完工的桥梁。路透社/David Kirton</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/F6hMgshmTwKFbVqW7srXuXuaMx8=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YZ3NUD2Z3NL3BHO6MA33RUUG2Y.jpg" alt="Qianhai in Shenzhen翻译:深圳前海" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A man rides a scooter past a completed central area of Qianhai new district in Shenzhen, Guangdong province, China August 25, 2023. REUTERS/David Kirton翻译:2023年8月25日，一名男子骑着摩托车经过中国广东省深圳市前海新区已竣工的中心区。路透社/David Kirton</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/h0Mve_LDQHq8peUnD129Zh7qA8k=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CEPNRVPISNKUDPAPF6O2ZMXX5Y.jpg" alt="Qianhai in Shenzhen翻译:深圳前海" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Workers get lunch from roadside stalls near buildings under construction in Shenzhen's Qianhai new district, Guangdong province, China August 25, 2023. REUTERS/David Kirton翻译:2023 年 8 月 25 日，中国广东省深圳前海新区，工人们在正在建设的建筑附近的路边摊享用午餐。路透社/David Kirton</figcaption></figure>                 <p>Tony Xiong is among the latest arrivals to the glitzy office towers in the newest part of Shenzhen, built to showcase China's economic miracle. He won't spend any personal time in the area.翻译:熊托尼 (Tony Xiong) 是最新一批来到深圳最新城区的豪华办公楼的人之一，这些办公楼是为了展示中国的经济奇迹而建造的。他不会在该地区度过任何私人时间。</p>   <p>Most lunch breaks, he drives 20 to 30 minutes to more-established parts of Shenzhen to slurp beef noodles in family-owned restaurants before racing back to work.翻译:大多数午休时间，他都会开车 20 到 30 分钟前往深圳较成熟的地区，在家庭经营的餐馆里吃牛肉面，然后再赶回去工作。</p>   <p>"In Qianhai, it's either a 10-minute walk in the sun to the mall or the terrible cafeteria food," said the 30-year-old, a finance worker in a state-owned property firm. "I don't like being there."翻译:“在前海，要么是在阳光下步行10分钟才能到达商场，要么是食堂的食物很糟糕，”这位30岁的国有地产公司财务人员说。 “我不喜欢呆在那里。”</p>   <p>Office workers are not the only ones grumbling about the unattractiveness of Qianhai, a special economic zone where Chinese dreams of global financial might and economic prosperity that once seemed inevitable are now darkened by half-empty skyscrapers and shopping malls as well as barely used motorways.翻译:抱怨前海缺乏吸引力的不只是上班族。前海是一个经济特区，中国人曾经看似不可避免的全球金融实力和经济繁荣的梦想现在却因半空的摩天大楼、购物中心以及几乎不使用的高速公路而变得黯淡。</p>   <p>This Shenzhen appendix opened for business more than a decade ago after an initial investment of $45 billion, with state media calling it mainland China's own Hong Kong: a future international tech and finance hub; a testbed for liberalising markets and information access.翻译:这家位于深圳的附属机构在初始投资 450 亿美元后于十多年前开业，官方媒体称其为中国大陆的香港：未来的国际科技和金融中心；市场和信息准入自由化的试验台。</p>   <p>But Reuters interviews with 10 executives and investors, as well as real estate experts, diplomats and economists and 10 workers in the area during six visits between September and November paint a picture of a largely deserted district that has given up on its reformist ambitions. At the same time, these people said, Qianhai is struggling to stand out among 2,500 other special zones across China dangling various subsidies at reluctant businesses.翻译:但路透社在 9 月至 11 月期间的六次访问中对该地区的 10 名高管和投资者、房地产专家、外交官和经济学家以及 10 名工人进行了采访，描绘了一幅基本上荒芜的地区的图景，该地区已经放弃了改革的雄心。与此同时，这些人士表示，前海正努力在中国其他 2,500 个特区中脱颖而出，向不情愿的企业提供各种补贴。</p>   <p>Five economists and three diplomats told Reuters Qianhai's travails reflect the limits of China's old "build it and they will come" <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">growth model</a> - one that worked wonders a generation earlier for wider Shenzhen, among the country's first and most successful special economic zones.翻译:五名经济学家和三名外交官告诉路透社，前海的困境反映了中国旧有的“建好后就会来” <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/will-china-ever-get-rich-new-era-much-slower-growth-dawns-2023-07-18/">增长模式</a>的局限性，这种模式在上一代人的身上为深圳创造了奇迹，深圳是中国第一个也是最成功的经济特区之一。</p>   <p>The office vacancy rate was 28.9% in the third quarter, near the highest in three years, versus 23.2% in Shenzhen overall, and 15.1% to 17.1% in Beijing and Shanghai, according to Knight Frank, despite Qianhai's lower rental prices.翻译:莱坊的数据显示，尽管前海租金价格较低，但第三季度写字楼空置率为28.9%，接近三年来最高水平，而深圳整体空置率为23.2%，北京和上海空置率为15.1%至17.1%。</p>   <p>And that's before China's tallest skyscraper of over 1,000 metres and a cluster of other towers are completed. The relentless supply has driven up vacancies, but newcomers other than state-connected firms are hard to find, three real estate executives told Reuters on the condition of anonymity due to the subject's sensitivity.翻译:而这还是在中国最高的 1000 米以上摩天大楼和其他塔楼竣工之前。三名房地产高管对路透表示，源源不断的供应推高了空置率，但除了国有企业之外，很难找到新来者。由于该话题的敏感性，他们要求匿名。</p>   <p>With China entering a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/part-chinas-economic-miracle-was-mirage-reality-check-is-next-2023-09-03/">new era</a> of sluggish growth, Qianhai may never reach the international status to which it aspires.翻译:随着中国进入增长低迷的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/part-chinas-economic-miracle-was-mirage-reality-check-is-next-2023-09-03/">新时代</a>，前海可能永远无法达到它所渴望的国际地位。</p>   <p>Analysts say Qianhai, and China, need to resume the market overhauls Beijing intended to pilot in the special area more than a decade ago, while the economy as a whole needs to rely more on <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-has-no-pain-free-solutions-its-slowing-economy-2023-08-24/">household consumption</a> for high growth to resume.翻译:分析人士表示，前海和中国需要恢复十多年前北京打算在该特区试点的市场改革，而整体经济需要更多地依靠<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-has-no-pain-free-solutions-its-slowing-economy-2023-08-24/">居民消费</a>来恢复高增长。</p>   <p>"When a country reaches the state of development of China today, one cannot grow from special zones," said Antonio Fatas, a professor of economics at INSEAD international business school. "Growth is much more complex, it requires reforms that are comprehensive."翻译:欧洲工商管理学院(INSEAD)国际商学院经济学教授安东尼奥·法塔斯(Antonio Fatas)表示：“当一个国家达到中国今天的发展水平时，就无法从特区中发展起来。” “增长要复杂得多，它需要全面的改革。”</p>   <p>The Qianhai Authority and China's State Council Information Office did not respond to Reuters requests for comment on the local and macro economic challenges.</p>    <h 1="">UNFULFILLED PROMISES</h>  <p>In the past four decades, Shenzhen grew from a collection of villages into a megacity of 18 million people, home to some of China's biggest firms.翻译:在过去的四十年里，深圳从一个由村庄组成的城市发展成为拥有 1800 万人口的大城市，是中国一些最大的公司的所在地。</p>   <p>It became the runaway success story of former Chinese leader Deng Xiaoping's "reform and opening up" policies, with its business friendliness since replicated by other cities, especially along the Pearl River Delta, in tandem with an unparalleled <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/xi-faces-painful-gear-shift-chinas-investment-led-growth-sputters-2022-10-14/">infrastructure build-up</a>.翻译:它成为中国前领导人邓小平“改革开放”政策的巨大成功故事，其商业友好性后来被其他城市，特别是珠三角沿线城市效仿，同时还有无与伦比的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/xi-faces-painful-gear-shift-chinas-investment-led-growth-sputters-2022-10-14/">基础设施建设</a>。</p>   <p>In 2010, Beijing approved the Qianhai project as a policy laboratory to jumpstart a new growth stage for China.翻译:2010年，北京批准前海项目作为政策实验室，以推动中国进入新的增长阶段。</p>   <p>Plans included a Hong Kong-like independent antigraft body, a pilot to pioneer the gradual opening of the country's capital account and internationalising the yuan; and full internet freedom throughout the area.翻译:计划包括建立一个类似香港的独立反腐败机构、率先逐步开放国家资本账户和人民币国际化的试点；整个地区享有完全的互联网自由。</p>   <p>When President Xi Jinping visited Qianhai on his first trip as general secretary of the Communist Party in 2012, predicting it would be "more special than a special zone," those changes seemed just the beginning of a more open China.翻译:2012年，当习近平主席以中共总书记的身份第一次访问前海时，他预测前海将“比特区更特别”，这些变化似乎只是一个更加开放的中国的开始。</p>   <p>But the plans were scrapped one by one over the following years.翻译:但这些计划在接下来的几年里被一一取消。</p>   <p>By the time Xi returned for the 40th anniversary of Deng's changes in 2019, the mood had soured, as state supervision over markets tightened, the capital account was largely sealed after an outflows scare in 2015, and censorship and surveillance intensified.翻译:2019年，当习近平回来参加邓小平改革40周年纪念日时，随着国家对市场的监管收紧，资本账户在2015年的资本外流恐慌后基本被封锁，审查和监视力度加大，人们的情绪已经恶化。</p>   <p>"The last 10 years have not been about real reforms and open doors," said Zhiwu Chen, professor of finance at the University of Hong Kong. "Instead, reversals of past reforms have carried the day," he said, adding this has stifled Qianhai's progress.翻译:香港大学金融学教授陈志武表示：“过去十年并没有真正的改革和开放。” “相反，过去改革的逆转已经取得了胜利，”他说，并补充说这抑制了前海的进步。</p>   <p>"In the old days, officials in Qianhai would have been encouraged and incentivised to experiment with creative policy innovations. In the current political environment, officials put much higher priority on minimising risk."</p>    <h 1="">LOW TAXES, SUBSIDIES</h>  <p>Without the promised changes, Qianhai's remaining selling points are income taxes of 15%, versus 25% in most of China, its proximity to Hong Kong, and some of the country's newest office and commercial facilities, which come with a one-off 30 million yuan ($4.1 million) subsidy for purchases and up to 5 million yuan yearly for rents.翻译:如果没有承诺的改变，前海剩下的卖点是 15% 的所得税（而中国大部分地区为 25%）、毗邻香港，以及中国一些最新的办公和商业设施，一次性价值 3000 万美元。人民币（410万美元）的购房补贴和每年高达500万元的租金补贴。</p>   <p>Qianhai Authority, which runs the area, says more than 100,000 companies have set up shop in the area, including HSBC, UBS and Standard Chartered.翻译:管理该地区的前海管理局表示，已有超过 10 万家公司在该地区设立分支机构，其中包括汇丰银行、瑞银集团和渣打银行。</p>   <p>The zone has attracted family offices, venture capital and private equity funds, said Witman Hung, delegate to China's parliament and formerly the authority's principal liaison officer for Hong Kong.翻译:中国人大代表、前人大驻香港首席联络官洪为民表示，该特区吸引了家族办公室、风险投资和私募股权基金。</p>   <p>But property agents, executives and investors say many firms that registered in Qianhai never physically moved there.翻译:但房地产经纪人、高管和投资者表示，许多在前海注册的公司从未实际搬到那里。</p>   <p>"We don't actually have any people there, I've never even gone to the address," said Brian Miller, who owns a warehouse business elsewhere in Shenzhen but registered in Qianhai on his accountant's advice.翻译:“我们那里实际上没有任何人，我什至从来没有去过那个地址，”布莱恩·米勒(Brian Miller)说。他在深圳其他地方拥有一家仓库业务，但根据会计师的建议在前海注册了。</p>   <p>A tech executive who spoke on the condition of anonymity because of the topic's sensitivity said his firm rents in Qianhai for tax reasons and to maintain good government relations. He had planned to expand operations there but changed his mind as the economy slowed. He now keeps a skeleton crew.翻译:一位因话题敏感而不愿透露姓名的科技高管表示，他的公司在前海出租是出于税收原因，也是为了维持良好的政府关系。他原本计划在那里扩大业务，但随着经济放缓而改变了主意。他现在拥有一支骨干人员队伍。</p>   <p>"It's not a Qianhai problem, it's a macroeconomic problem," he said.</p>    <h 1="">ZONED OUT</h>  <p>Another drawback is that Qianhai's incentives are similar to what other special zones offer, including those nearby such as Nansha near Guangzhou and Hengqin next to Macau. But Qianhai rents are double those in Hengqin and sixfold those in Nansha, agents say.翻译:另一个缺点是，前海的激励措施与其他特区相似，包括广州附近的南沙和澳门旁边的横琴等附近的特区。但中介称，前海的租金是横琴的两倍，是南沙的六倍。</p>   <p>"Before, every area had a little speciality to follow but now anywhere can do everything, it's too confusing," said Klaus Zenkel, who chairs the European Chamber of Commerce in South China, adding no new European companies were moving in.翻译:华南欧盟商会主席克劳斯·曾克尔表示：“以前，每个地区都有一点专业需要遵循，但现在任何地方都可以做任何事情，这太混乱了。”他补充说，没有新的欧洲公司入驻。</p>   <p>"The infrastructure is there, it's just - how do you convince companies to come?"翻译:“基础设施已经有了，只是——你如何说服公司来？”</p>   <p>A chamber survey of 75 companies in June found only 44% were optimistic about the Greater Bay Area, another name for the cluster of southern Chinese cities, down from 68% in 2022.翻译:商会 6 月份对 75 家企业进行的调查发现，只有 44% 的企业对大湾区（中国南方城市群的别称）持乐观态度，低于 2022 年的 68%。</p>   <p>Bill Deng, CEO of cross-border finance firm XTransfer, says he won't move to Qianhai.翻译:跨境金融公司XTransfer的首席执行官比尔·邓(Bill Deng)表示，他不会搬到前海。</p>   <p>Hong Kong "has a global system that's free, they have the talent, they have the experience," he said, adding the mainland has been "very cautious" about financial opening.翻译:他说，香港“拥有自由的全球体系，他们有人才、有经验”，并补充说内地对金融开放一直“非常谨慎”。</p>   <p>On Qianhai's streets, some people are enjoying the serenity. A driving instructor finds the area perfect for first lessons. A shop assistant levels up on a smartphone game.翻译:前海的街道上，一些人正在享受这份宁静。驾驶教练发现这里非常适合上第一堂课。一名店员在智能手机游戏中升级。</p>   <p>At a cafe close to a rock inscribed with Deng's calligraphy of Qianhai, a barista who only gave his surname, Zhang, spends most of his time chatting with other staff.翻译:在刻有邓小平前海题字的岩石旁的一家咖啡馆里，一位只透露自己姓张的咖啡师大部分时间都在和其他工作人员聊天。</p>   <p>"There aren't many customers and I don't think lots of people visit for the rock. Sometimes I'm bored, but quiet is good," he said.翻译:“顾客不多，我认为没有多少人来参观这块岩石。有时我很无聊，但安静很好，”他说。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2780 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2780 人民币）</p>    <span>Additional reporting by James Pomfret; Editing by Marius Zaharia and David Crawshaw翻译:詹姆斯·庞弗雷特的补充报道；马吕斯·扎哈里亚和大卫·克劳肖编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 02:09:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5R6LYAOCZ5KUTGR6SZJH76MNW4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-not-so-special-economic-zone-embodies-harsh-new-reality-2023-11-16/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Kirton]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/QIANHAI (INSIGHT, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国反对美国申请APEC以改变贸易和投资原则]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/Nbtv42O59Qi_sPwyiwKH2llQlxE=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6ZP2QU2TIFNV3CPJ3JD4JVXRPI.jpg" alt="APEC summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Trade Representative Ambassador Katherine Tai speaks during an APEC Ministerial Meeting (AMM) Opening Session in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small翻译:美国贸易代表大使戴凯瑟琳于 2023 年 11 月 15 日在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的亚太经合组织部长级会议 (AMM) 开幕式上发表讲话。 REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/aT13ys4kLYZPJd6mmW-pR6MWjQ4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/H3H5626AX5LVNKQH6NFFPVWDKU.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping attend a bilateral meeting at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经济合作组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平出席在菲洛丽庄园举行的双边会议。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>               <p>China is objecting to a U.S. proposal for Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) members to incorporate sustainability and inclusivity into their trade and investment policies, a source briefed on the negotiations said on Wednesday.翻译:一位了解谈判情况的消息人士周三表示，中国反对美国提出的亚太经合组织（APEC）成员将可持续性和包容性纳入其贸易和投资政策的建议。</p>   <p>Talks on the issue were continuing at the APEC summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行 to try to find language that the group's 21 member states could agree on, the source said.翻译:消息人士称，在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织峰会上，有关这一问题的谈判仍在继续，试图找到该组织 21 个成员国能够达成一致的措辞。</p>   <p>U.S. Trade Representative Katherine Tai told a trade-focused plenary meeting she hoped the proposal, dubbed by the Biden administration as the "San Francisco Principles for Integrating Inclusivity and Sustainability into Trade and Investment Policy" could be still be finalized.翻译:美国贸易代表凯瑟琳·戴在一次以贸易为重点的全体会议上表示，她希望这项被拜登政府称为“将包容性和可持续性纳入贸易和投资政策的旧金山原则”的提案仍能最终确定。</p>   <p>Tai said the U.S.-led effort was "supported by all economies but one and, as such, it is unclear if APEC will fulfill that mandate. Nonetheless, I remain optimistic that economies will finalize the San Francisco Principles soon."翻译:戴表示，美国主导的努力“得到了除一个经济体之外的所有经济体的支持，因此，目前尚不清楚亚太经合组织是否会履行这一使命。尽管如此，我仍然乐观地认为各经济体将很快敲定《旧金山原则》。”</p>   <p>Few details of the U.S. proposal were available, but the Biden administration is promoting the idea that APEC economies increase opportunities for more people, particularly disadvantaged populations, and to incorporate clean energy and carbon emissions reductions goals into their development, growth and trade policies.翻译:美国提案的细节很少，但拜登政府正在宣扬这样的想法：APEC经济体为更多人，特别是弱势群体增加机会，并将清洁能源和碳减排目标纳入其发展、增长和贸易政策。</p>   <p>"Our economies are more than just numbers," Tai said when describing the U.S. proposal. "They are made of people, so we need to make sure that our economic and trade policies work for our people and that the benefits created are shared by all."翻译:“我们的经济不仅仅是数字，”戴在描述美国的提议时说。 “它们是由人组成的，因此我们需要确保我们的经济和贸易政策适合我们的人民，并确保所创造的利益由所有人共享。”</p>   <p>Tai is separately seeking to negotiate a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/eu-seeks-ease-us-tariff-green-subsidy-threats-2023-10-16/">green steel arrangement</a> with the European Union that aims to disadvantage Chinese steelmakers on the basis of their higher carbon emissions.翻译:戴秉国正在单独寻求与欧盟谈判一项<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/eu-seeks-ease-us-tariff-green-subsidy-threats-2023-10-16/">绿色钢铁安排</a>，旨在使中国钢铁制造商因碳排放量较高而处于不利地位。</p>   <p>News of China's objections at the APEC summit come as U.S. President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">met south of San Francisco</a> in high-stakes talks that included discussions between the superpowers over Taiwan and the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza.翻译:中国反对亚太经合组织峰会的消息传出之际，美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">在旧金山以南举行了</a>高风险会谈，会谈内容包括两个超级大国之间关于台湾问题和以色列与哈马斯在加沙战争的讨论。</p>   <p>A spokesperson for China's embassy in Washington did not directly address China's objections but said that all APEC parties should "focus on the region's urgent needs, deepen solidarity and cooperation, deliver on the APEC Putrajaya Vision 2040 in an all-round and balanced way," a reference to declarations by APEC leaders in 2020 in Malaysia.翻译:中国驻华盛顿大使馆发言人没有直接回应中方的反对意见，但表示APEC各方应“聚焦本地区迫切需要，深化团结合作，全面平衡落实APEC布城2040愿景”。参考 2020 年 APEC 领导人在马来西亚发表的声明。</p>   <p>The <a href="https://www.apec.org/meeting-papers/leaders-declarations/2020/2020_aelm/annex-a" target="_blank">Putrajaya vision</a> called for working to "deliver a free, open, fair, non-discriminatory, transparent and predictable trade and investment environment."翻译:<a href="https://www.apec.org/meeting-papers/leaders-declarations/2020/2020_aelm/annex-a" target="_blank">布城愿景</a>呼吁努力“提供自由、开放、公平、非歧视、透明和可预测的贸易和投资环境”。</p>    <span>Reporting by David Lawder; Editing by Jonathan Oatis; Editing by Christopher Cushing翻译:大卫·劳德报道；乔纳森·奥蒂斯编辑；克里斯托弗·库欣编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 01:07:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">IKKK7IPQ65MQHAG55ARUJB4XJY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china-objects-us-proposal-apec-trade-investment-policies-source-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Lawder]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/TRADE</category>
                
                <category>CHINA (TV, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[习近平告诉拜登台湾是双边关系中最大、最危险的问题——美国官员]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/CqoDdYtgyVce2-gB6s_DnJqlgas=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PXY5KGMLVFLFDMCABJP3LPXIIM.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping speaks during a bilateral meeting with U.S. President Joe Biden at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，中国国家主席习近平在菲洛里庄园与美国总统乔·拜登举行双边会晤时发表讲话。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/CD0xzH4LKoP3_jQz1i-RtA_7vTo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZIXZ3IS2VJK7TN3PQKM63XYWEE.jpg" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden meets with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines of APEC summit, in Woodside翻译:美国总统乔·拜登在亚太经合组织峰会期间在伍德赛德会见中国国家主席习近平" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden walks with Chinese President Xi Jinping at Filoli estate on the sidelines of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, in Woodside, California, U.S., November 15, 2023. REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，在美国加利福尼亚州伍德赛德举行的亚太经济合作组织 (APEC) 峰会期间，美国总统乔·拜登与中国国家主席习近平在菲洛丽庄园散步。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque</figcaption></figure>               <p>Chinese President Xi Jinping told U.S. President Joe Biden during their four-hour meeting on Wednesday that Taiwan was the biggest, most dangerous issue in U.S.-China ties, a senior U.S. official told reporters.翻译:一位美国高级官员对记者表示，中国国家主席习近平在周三与美国总统乔·拜登进行的四个小时的会晤中告诉美国总统拜登，台湾是美中关系中最大、最危险的问题。</p>   <p>The official quoted Xi as saying China's preference was for peaceful reunification with the Chinese-claimed island of Taiwan, but went on to talk about conditions in which force could be used.翻译:这位官员援引习近平的话说，中国倾向于和平统一中国声称拥有主权的台湾岛，但他接着谈到了可以使用武力的条件。</p>   <p>Xi was trying to indicate that China is not preparing for a massive invasion of Taiwan, but that does not change the U.S. approach, the official said.翻译:这位官员表示，习近平试图表明中国没有准备大规模入侵台湾，但这并没有改变美国的做法。</p>   <p>"President Xi ... underscored that this was the biggest, most potentially dangerous issue in U.S.-China relations, laid out clearly that, you know, their preference was for peaceful reunification but then moved immediately to conditions that the potential use of force could be utilized," the senior U.S. official told reporters, referring to Xi's comments on Taiwan.翻译:“习主席......强调这是美中关系中最大、最具潜在危险的问题，明确指出，你知道，他们倾向于和平统一，但随后立即转向可能使用武力的条件被利用，”这位美国高级官员在谈到习近平对台湾的评论时告诉记者。</p>   <p>Biden responded by assuring Xi that Washington was determined to maintain peace in the region.翻译:拜登的回应是向习近平保证华盛顿决心维护该地区的和平。</p>   <p>"President Biden responded very clearly that the long-standing position of the United States was ... determination to maintain peace and stability," the official said.翻译:这位官员表示：“拜登总统的回应非常明确，美国的长期立场是……维护和平与稳定的决心。”</p>   <p>"President Xi responded: look, peace is ... all well and good but at some point we need to move towards resolution more generally," the official added.翻译:这位官员补充道：“习主席回应道：看，和平……一切都很好，但在某些时候我们需要更广泛地解决问题。”</p>   <p>Biden and Xi <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">met for the first time</a> in a year on Wednesday for talks aimed at easing<a href="https://www.reuters.com/podcasts/biden-meet-xi-san-francisco-2023-11-12/?%24web_only=true&amp;_branch_match_id=1161293349163474432&amp;utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_medium=marketing&amp;_branch_referrer=H4sIAAAAAAAAA8soKSkottLXz8nMy9YrSi0tSS0q1kvOz9VP1Q9wSwzOLi7O8XZNAgBzJOFkJgAAAA%3D%3D">friction</a> between the two superpowers over military conflicts, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">drug-trafficking</a> and artificial intelligence, and said they had made "real progress."翻译:周三，拜登和习近平一年<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">来首次会面，</a>进行会谈，旨在缓解两个超级大国之间在军事冲突、 <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">贩毒</a>和人工智能方面的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/podcasts/biden-meet-xi-san-francisco-2023-11-12/?%24web_only=true&amp;_branch_match_id=1161293349163474432&amp;utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_medium=marketing&amp;_branch_referrer=H4sIAAAAAAAAA8soKSkottLXz8nMy9YrSi0tSS0q1kvOz9VP1Q9wSwzOLi7O8XZNAgBzJOFkJgAAAA%3D%3D">摩擦</a>，并表示他们已经取得了“真正的进展”。</p>   <p>China has stepped up military activity to try and force democratically governed Taiwan to accept Beijing's sovereignty, despite strong objections from the government in Taipei.翻译:尽管台北政府强烈反对，中国还是加强了军事活动，试图迫使民主治理的台湾接受北京的主权。</p>   <p>Senior U.S. military officers have said that Xi has ordered the People's Liberation Army to be prepared to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-weighs-options-blunt-us-sanctions-taiwan-conflict-2023-10-20/">invade Taiwan</a> by 2027. Beijing has not ruled out using force to take the island, though it has never shared details about war preparations.翻译:美国高级军官表示，习近平已命令中国人民解放军做好2027年<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-weighs-options-blunt-us-sanctions-taiwan-conflict-2023-10-20/">入侵台湾</a>的准备。北京并未排除使用武力夺取台湾岛的可能性，但从未透露过战争准备的细节。</p>    <span>Reporting by Trevor Hunnicutt and Jeff Mason; Writing by Andrea Shalal; Editing by Sandra Maler and Stephen Coates翻译:特雷弗·亨尼卡特和杰夫·梅森的报道；安德里亚·沙拉尔 (Andrea Shalal) 撰写；桑德拉·马勒和斯蒂芬·科茨编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 01:01:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">HS4UVCVU5RKX5DWBLBARXMXL3E</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/xi-told-biden-taiwan-is-biggest-most-dangerous-issue-bilateral-ties-us-official-2023-11-16/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Jeff Mason, Trevor Hunnicutt]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>MEETING (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[欧洲公司敦促中国进一步明确数据传输法]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UH9rid9jkLEt5JsGOJYMoQt30ok=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OOV6PN5M3NOQ3ACUIZ6AADBDYY.jpg" alt="An attendant walks past EU and China flags ahead of the EU-China High-level Economic Dialogue in Beijing翻译:在北京举行的中欧高层经济对话之前，一名与会者走过欧盟和中国国旗" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An attendant walks past EU and China flags ahead of the EU-China High-level Economic Dialogue at Diaoyutai State Guesthouse in Beijing, China June 25, 2018. REUTERS/Jason Lee/File Photo翻译:2018 年 6 月 25 日，在中国北京钓鱼台国宾馆举行的中欧高层经济对话之前，一名与会者走过欧盟和中国国旗。 REUTERS/Jason Lee/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>European firms "urgently" need China to give clearer definitions of key terms in its cross-border data transfer rules, a European business lobby group said on Wednesday, warning firms also stood to waste millions of euros storing non-sensitive data in China.翻译:欧洲商业游说团体周三表示，欧洲企业“迫切”需要中国对其跨境数据传输规则中的关键术语给出更清晰的定义，并警告企业还将浪费数百万欧元在中国存储非敏感数据。</p>   <p>The European Chamber of Commerce in China called on authorities to "provide precise definitions for both 'important data' and 'personal information,'" as outlined in their rules, and also urged that a proposed relaxation of certain aspects of regulations announced in September be finalised as soon as possible.翻译:中国欧盟商会呼吁当局按照其规则中的规定，“为‘重要数据’和‘个人信息’提供准确的定义”，并敦促放宽 9 月份宣布的监管某些方面的提议。尽快敲定。</p>   <p>The world's second-largest economy has in recent years tightened its data laws amid President Xi Jinping's increased focus on national security, and foreign firms fear their lack of clarity could trip them up.翻译:近年来，在习近平主席日益关注国家安全的背景下，全球第二大经济体收紧了数据法，外国公司担心数据法的不明确可能会给他们带来麻烦。</p>   <p>"Ever since the Cybersecurity Law was introduced in 2017, we have gone without a clear definition of 'Important Data.' That's six years," Stefan Bernhart, a chamber vice president, said at the launch of a report based on a member survey on the impact of China's data regulations.翻译:“自2017年《网络安全法》出台以来，我们对‘重要数据’一直没有明确的定义。那是六年，”商会副会长斯特凡·伯恩哈特(Stefan Bernhart)在一份基于对中国数据法规影响的会员调查的报告发布时表示。</p>   <p>BASF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BASFn.DE" target="_blank">(BASFn.DE)</a>, Maersk <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MAERSKb.CO" target="_blank">(MAERSKb.CO)</a>, Siemens <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SIEGn.DE" target="_blank">(SIEGn.DE)</a>, and Volkswagen <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VOWG_p.DE" target="_blank">(VOWG_p.DE)</a> are among the members of the chamber.翻译:巴斯夫<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/BASFn.DE" target="_blank">(BASFn.DE)</a> 、马士基<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MAERSKb.CO" target="_blank">(MAERSKb.CO)</a> 、西门子<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/SIEGn.DE" target="_blank">(SIEGn.DE)</a>和大众汽车<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/VOWG_p.DE" target="_blank">(VOWG_p.DE)</a>都是该商会的成员。</p>   <p>"Many of the laws, guidelines and measures lack specificity, which poses serious operational and compliance challenges to European companies operating in China," the report read, adding requirements like "regulatory security assessment thresholds" were too low, "especially for larger multinational companies."翻译:报告称，“许多法律、指导方针和措施缺乏针对性，这给在华经营的欧洲公司带来了严重的运营和合规挑战”，并补充说，“监管安全评估门槛”等要求太低，“特别是对于大型跨国公司” ”。</p>   <p>Jitters among foreign investors in China have risen over the past year due to a series of corporate raids, predominantly on consultancies and due diligence firms.翻译:过去一年，由于一系列企业搜查行动（主要针对咨询公司和尽职调查公司），中国外国投资者的不安情绪有所加剧。</p>   <p>"Questions about whether or not I am on the right side of the law can be a huge, huge challenge," Bernhart said, adding that it could make smaller firms in particular reconsider investing in China.翻译:伯恩哈特表示：“关于我是否站在法律正确一边的问题可能是一个巨大的挑战。”他补充说，这可能会让规模较小的公司重新考虑在中国的投资。</p>   <p>The chamber's report echoes recent comments from a European Commission official, who said in September that European businesses were <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/eu-says-lack-clarity-chinas-data-laws-is-concerning-2023-09-19/">especially concerned</a> about a lack of clarity in China's data laws.翻译:该商会的报告呼应了欧盟委员会一位官员最近的评论，该官员在 9 月份表示，欧洲企业<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/eu-says-lack-clarity-chinas-data-laws-is-concerning-2023-09-19/">尤其担心</a>中国数据法的不明确性。</p>   <p>China in the same month also said it was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-waive-security-checks-some-data-exports-2023-09-28/">considering waiving</a> data export security assessments for activities such as international trade, academic cooperation, cross-border manufacturing and marketing that do not contain personal information or important data, a move that was welcomed by foreign business chambers and lawyers.翻译:同月，中国还表示<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-waive-security-checks-some-data-exports-2023-09-28/">考虑对国际贸易、学术合作、跨境制造和营销等不包含个人信息或重要数据的活动免除</a>数据出境安全评估，此举受到外国商会的欢迎和律师。</p>   <p>"The release of the draft ... was seen as a signal from the Chinese Government that it is listening to businesses' concerns and is ready to take steps to address them. Companies are waiting eagerly for these positive signals to be translated into action," the chamber said, adding that its members anticipated the draft revisions would be finalised by the end of November.翻译:“草案的发布……被视为中国政府发出的信号，表明它正在倾听企业的担忧，并准备采取措施解决这些问题。企业正在热切地等待这些积极信号转化为行动， ”该商会表示，并补充说，其成员预计修订草案将在 11 月底完成。</p>   <p>The most common type of data European firms transfer abroad is employee's personal information followed by suppliers' and customers' personal information, the survey showed, 96% of which is sent to companies' headquarters and other regional offices.翻译:调查显示，欧洲公司向国外传输的最常见数据类型是员工的个人信息，其次是供应商和客户的个人信息，其中 96% 被发送到公司总部和其他地区办事处。</p>   <p>A third of companies indicated it would cost them "several million euros" to store their data in China if they failed the cross-border transfer security assessment now required by CAC. More than 10 percent of firms said it would cost them "hundreds of millions of euros."翻译:三分之一的公司表示，如果未能通过 CAC 目前要求的跨境传输安全评估，他们将花费“数百万欧元”将数据存储在中国。超过 10% 的公司表示，这将花费他们“数亿欧元”。</p>   <p>Only 6% of respondents indicated that they transferred 'important data' overseas, the chamber said.翻译:该商会表示，只有 6% 的受访者表示他们将“重要数据”转移到海外。</p>   <p>($1 = 0.9322 euros)翻译:（1 美元 = 0.9322 欧元）</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Brenda Goh; Editing by Kim Coghill翻译:Brenda Goh 的补充报道；编辑：金·科吉尔</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 21:55:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">RUZWXP2WQVIZVPMCOEHUIXW4LY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/european-firms-urge-china-give-more-clarity-data-transfer-laws-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Joe Cash]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/DATA</category>
                
                <category>SECURITY</category>
                
                <category>EUROPE (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[美国议员就乔恩·斯图尔特 (Jon Stewart) 的中国内容质疑苹果]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ihlwvgzsGnBRqDzxZ30h6kE-pl0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3MDUJ3B26FNB5MS7MYOFDRNI5Q.jpg" alt="People arrive on the red carpet before comedian and talk show host Jon Stewart receives the Mark Twain Prize For American Humor at The Kennedy Center翻译:人们在喜剧演员兼脱口秀主持人乔恩·斯图尔特在肯尼迪中心接受马克·吐温美国幽默奖之前走上红地毯" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Comedian and talk show host Jon Stewart arrives on the red carpet before receiving the Mark Twain Prize For American Humor, at The Kennedy Center in Washington, U.S.,&nbsp;April 24 2022. &nbsp;REUTERS/Cheriss May/File Photo翻译:喜剧演员兼脱口秀主持人乔恩·斯图尔特于 2022 年 4 月 24 日在美国华盛顿肯尼迪中心登上红地毯，然后接受马克·吐温美国幽默奖。路透社/Cheriss May/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S. lawmakers asked Apple Inc to explain the abrupt end of political comedian Jon Stewart's television show on its streaming service, according to a letter made public on Wednesday, citing concerns that content related to China was behind the cancellation.翻译:根据周三公开的一封信，美国立法者要求苹果公司解释政治喜剧演员乔恩·斯图尔特在其流媒体服务上的电视节目突然结束的原因，理由是担心取消节目背后涉及与中国有关的内容。</p>   <p>The New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/19/business/media/jon-stewart-the-problem-ends.html" target="_blank">reported last month</a> that Stewart's show on Apple's streaming service was ending, the result of creative differences. The newspaper said Stewart told members of his staff that potential show topics related to China and artificial intelligence were causing concern to Apple executives.翻译:《纽约时报》 <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/19/business/media/jon-stewart-the-problem-ends.html" target="_blank">上个月报道</a>称，由于创意分歧，斯图尔特在苹果流媒体服务上的节目即将结束。该报称，斯图尔特告诉他的员工，与中国和人工智能相关的潜在展会主题引起了苹果高管的担忧。</p>   <p>Apple <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a> declined comment to the Times.翻译:苹果公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O" target="_blank">(AAPL.O)</a>拒绝向《纽约时报》发表评论。</p>   <p>"While companies have the right to determine what content is appropriate for their streaming service, the coercive tactics of a foreign power should not be directly or indirectly influencing these determinations," the Republican and Democratic leaders of the House of Representatives' Select Committee on Competition with the Chinese Communist Party said in the letter to Apple Chief Executive Tim Cook.翻译:众议院竞争特别委员会的共和党和民主党领导人表示：“虽然公司有权决定哪些内容适合其流媒体服务，但外国势力的胁迫策略不应直接或间接影响这些决定。”与中国共产党在给苹果首席执行官蒂姆·库克的信中说。</p>   <p>The letter asked representatives of Apple for a briefing on its concerns by Dec. 15, 2023. It said the committee also expected to speak with representatives of Stewart.翻译:这封信要求苹果代表在 2023 年 12 月 15 日之前就其担忧进行简报。信中称，委员会还希望与斯图尔特的代表进行交谈。</p>   <p>"To reassure the creative community in light of these reports, we also respectfully request that Apple publicly commit that content that could be perceived as critical of the CCP or the PRC is welcome on Apple TV+ and other Apple services," said the letter, signed by the panel's Republican chairperson, Representative Michael Gallagher, and Representative Raja Krishnamoorthi, the panel's ranking Democrat.翻译:信中写道：“为了根据这些报告让创意界放心，我们还诚挚地要求苹果公司公开承诺，Apple TV+ 和其他苹果服务上欢迎可能被视为批评中共或中华人民共和国的内容。”由该小组的共和党主席、众议员迈克尔·加拉格尔（Michael Gallagher）和该小组的民主党众议员拉贾·克里希纳莫蒂（Raja Krishnamoorthi）组成。</p>   <p>Representatives for Stewart and Apple did not respond to Reuters' requests for comment.翻译:斯图尔特和苹果的代表没有回应路透社的置评请求。</p>   <p>The letter was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/tricky-politics-menu-chinas-xi-us-business-dinner-2023-11-14/">released ahead of a dinner</a> expected on Wednesday night at which top U.S. business leaders were to dine with Chinese President Xi Jinping in San Francisco as he seeks to court American companies and counter his country's recent struggles to entice foreign investment.翻译:这封信是在周三晚上举行的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/tricky-politics-menu-chinas-xi-us-business-dinner-2023-11-14/">晚宴之前发布的</a>，届时美国高层商界领袖将在旧金山与中国国家主席习近平共进晚餐，习近平寻求讨好美国公司，并应对中国最近在吸引外国投资方面的困难。</p>   <p>The dinner on the margins of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum would follow a day of talks between Xi and U.S. President Joe Biden, aimed at stabilizing fraught ties between the world's two largest economies.翻译:在亚太经合组织（APEC）论坛间隙举行的晚宴之前，习近平和美国总统乔·拜登进行了一天的会谈，旨在稳定世界最大两个经济体之间紧张的关系。</p>   <p>The House committee has made China's controls on media a focus of its work.翻译:众议院委员会已将中国对媒体的控制作为其工作重点。</p>   <p>U.S. lawmakers have long expressed concerns about potential Chinese government censorship given the ruling Communist Party’s strict media controls. The concern is particularly acute for Hollywood films, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/china-film/">as some studios have altered</a> or self-censored scripts to appease Chinese government minders and gain access to the country’s market.翻译:鉴于执政的共产党对媒体的严格控制，美国立法者长期以来一直对中国政府可能进行的审查表示担忧。对于好莱坞电影来说，这种担忧尤其严重，<a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/china-film/">因为一些电影公司已经改变</a>或自我审查剧本，以安抚中国政府监管人员并进入该国市场。</p>    <span>Reporting by Patricia Zengerle and Michael Martina; Additional reporting by Stephen Nellis and Dawn Chmielewski; Editing by Stephen Coates翻译:帕特里夏·曾格尔 (Patricia Zengerle) 和迈克尔·马丁纳 (Michael Martina) 报道； Stephen Nellis 和 Dawn Chmielewski 的补充报道；斯蒂芬·科茨编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 19:25:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6KO56ZNXIFLGJPAQSQP23VJLFM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/media-telecom/us-lawmakers-question-apple-over-jon-stewarts-china-content-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Patricia Zengerle, Michael Martina]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CONGRESS</category>
                
                <category>APPLE (UPDATE 1, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[意大利打击从中国走私芬太尼至美国逮捕六人]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/q17ApiU0bqq2v3yh5BrAc_xeQ4M=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DQ57AQMHKVMXTBZWJYS4QT6WGM.jpg" alt="Italy arrests six in crackdown on fentanyl smuggling from China to U.S翻译:意大利打击从中国走私芬太尼至美国逮捕六人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An undated handout picture released by Guardia di Finanza shows banknotes that were seized as a part of an operation against fentanyl trafficking from China to U.S., in Piacenza, Italy. Guardia di Finanza Press Office/Handout via REUTERS 翻译:金融卫报发布的一张未注明日期的讲义图片显示，意大利皮亚琴察在打击从中国向美国贩运芬太尼的行动中查获的钞票。 Guardia di Finanza 新闻办公室/路透社讲义</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/3hXmboWQLjwkfzJtjCmE7ixe-hM=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CFCW4ALHFJMSXPUISTX34FUEHI.jpg" alt="Italy arrests six in crackdown on fentanyl smuggling from China to U.S翻译:意大利打击从中国走私芬太尼至美国逮捕六人" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>An undated handout picture released by Guardia di Finanza shows tools that were seized as a part of an operation against fentanyl trafficking from China to U.S., in Piacenza, Italy. Guardia di Finanza Press Office/Handout via REUTERS 翻译:Guardia di Finanza 发布的一张未注明日期的讲义图片显示，在意大利皮亚琴察打击从中国向美国贩运芬太尼的行动中查获的工具。 Guardia di Finanza 新闻办公室/路透社讲义</figcaption></figure>               <p>Italian police have arrested six people in a crackdown on a network that allegedly played go-between for fentanyl trafficking from China to the United States, Guardia di Finanza police and prosecutors in the northern city of Piacenza said on Wednesday.翻译:北部城市皮亚琴察的金融警卫队警方和检察官周三表示，意大利警方在打击一个涉嫌从中国向美国贩运芬太尼的网络中逮捕了六人。</p>   <p>"It was really good work, achieved through direct cooperation with investigators from the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA)," Piacenza chief prosecutor Grazia Pradella told Reuters, adding that U.S police arrested 11 other people and seized 2 kg of the synthetic drug.翻译:皮亚琴察首席检察官格拉齐亚·普拉德拉 (Grazia Pradella) 告诉路透社：“这确实是一项出色的工作，是通过与美国缉毒局 (DEA) 调查人员的直接合作完成的。”他补充说，美国警方逮捕了另外 11 人，并缴获了 2 公斤合成毒品。</p>   <p>Washington is hoping to secure more cooperation from Beijing in combating production of the potent synthetic opioid fentanyl, a scourge in the United States, when President Joe Biden meets <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">Chinese President Xi Jinping</a> on Wednesday.翻译:当乔·拜登总统周三会见<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/">中国国家主席习近平</a>时，华盛顿希望获得北京方面的更多合作，打击强效合成阿片类药物芬太尼的生产，芬太尼在美国是一个祸害。</p>   <p>The rate of drug overdose deaths involving fentanyl more than tripled from 2016 through 2021 in the U.S, according to the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).翻译:根据美国疾病控制与预防中心 (CDC) 的数据，从 2016 年到 2021 年，美国涉及芬太尼的药物过量死亡率增加了两倍多。</p>   <p>Among those arrested in Italy is the alleged head of the network, a 51-year-old Italian man suspected of buying fentanyl from China over the past three years. He sold it on to buyers in the United States, and in one case in Mexico, the chief prosecutor said.翻译:在意大利被捕的人中有一名被指控为该网络负责人的人，他是一名 51 岁的意大利男子，涉嫌在过去三年从中国购买芬太尼。首席检察官表示，他将其卖给了美国的买家，其中还包括墨西哥的买家。</p>   <p>The investigation began in April after a report sent by the DEA liaison officer at the U.S. embassy in Rome, Guardia di Finanza police said in a statement, adding the fentanyl arrived in Piacenza inside packages sent from China and labelled as containing electronics or books.翻译:Guardia di Finanza警方在一份声明中表示，美国驻罗马大使馆缉毒局联络官发出报告后，调查于四月开始，并补充说，芬太尼装在从中国寄出的包裹中抵达皮亚琴察，并贴有电子产品或书籍的标签。</p>   <p>Police said they were able to trace 100,000 packaged doses and that related economic transactions amounting to more than 250,000 euros ($275,000) took place through untraceable payment instruments using cryptocurrency.翻译:警方表示，他们能够追踪到 100,000 个包装剂量，并且通过使用加密货币的无法追踪的支付工具进行了价值超过 250,000 欧元（275,000 美元）的相关经济交易。</p>   <p>The judge in Piacenza had ordered seven arrests but a Ukrainian national is a fugitive and international law enforcement agencies have been alerted to track him down, police said.翻译:警方表示，皮亚琴察的法官已下令逮捕七人，但一名乌克兰国民是逃犯，国际执法机构已接到通知追查他。</p>   <p>Italian police also found that the group had minted near-perfect fake Swiss coins, smuggled them across the border to Switzerland where they laundered them through automated sports betting machines and bitcoin ATMs.翻译:意大利警方还发现，该团伙铸造了近乎完美的假瑞士硬币，并将其偷运至瑞士，并通过自动体育博彩机和比特币 ATM 机进行洗钱。</p>   <p>The conversion of bitcoins back into euros was then entrusted to people in Eastern Europe who would return the "cleaned" sum minus 7% commission to the counterfeiter in Piacenza.翻译:然后，将比特币兑换回欧元的工作委托给东欧的人，他们将“干净”的金额减去 7% 的佣金返还给皮亚琴察的造假者。</p>   <p>Police said they seized 300,000 euros in cash, about 26,000 euros in bitcoin, 70 computer devices and three valuable watches, as well as a property and the equipment for counterfeiting currency.
($1 = 0.9207 euros)翻译:警方称，他们查获了 30 万欧元现金、约 2.6 万欧元比特币、70 台电脑设备和三块贵重手表，以及一处财产和用于伪造货币的设备。 （1 美元 = 0.9207 欧元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Emilio Parodi
Editing by Keith Weir翻译:埃米利奥·帕罗迪 (Emilio Parodi) 报道 基思·威尔 (Keith Weir) 编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 19:00:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ZGCKWXSDZJMMDO2M7QZBA3HYGA</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/italy-arrests-six-crackdown-fentanyl-smuggling-china-us-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Emilio Parodi]]></author>
            
                
                <category>ITALY</category>
                
                <category>FENTANYL/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>USA (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[在拜登与习近平会面之前，与中国相关的 ETF 吸引了看涨期权押注]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/phtpuAUxstUjXz0AIES4Vnt1wPw=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PBUKQQHJBFJV5FEUJSN5OL5XGM.jpg" alt="Traders work on the floor of the NYSE in New York翻译:交易员在纽约证券交易所工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Traders work on the floor at the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) in New York City, U.S., November 15, 2023.  REUTERS/Brendan McDermid/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 15 日，交易员在美国纽约市纽约证券交易所 (NYSE) 的交易大厅工作。REUTERS/Brendan McDermid/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>U.S.-listed exchange traded funds focused on China are seeing bullish options activity as investors await U.S. President Joe Biden's <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">meeting</a> with Chinese leader Xi Jinping on Wednesday for signs of easing friction between the two superpowers.翻译:随着投资者等待美国总统乔·拜登周三与中国领导人习近平<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-xi-meet-us-china-military-economic-tensions-grind-2023-11-15/">会面</a>，以寻找两个超级大国之间摩擦缓和的迹象，专注于中国的美国上市交易所交易基金看到了看涨的期权活动。</p>   <p>Some of the bullish positions included call options on the Xtrackers Harvest CSI 300 China A-Shares ETF with a $27 strike price - some 6% higher than where the fund trades today - set to expire Friday.翻译:部分看涨头寸包括 Xtrackers Harvest CSI 300 China A-Shares ETF 的看涨期权，执行价为 27 美元，比该基金今天的交易价格高出约 6%，将于周五到期。</p>   <p>The iShares Trust-China Large-Cap ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FXI.P" target="_blank">(FXI.P)</a> also sport multiple lines of at-money and upside calls with sizeable open interest, including almost 100,000 contracts at the 29.85 strike. The ETF was trading at $27.28 on Wednesday.翻译:iShares Trust-China Large-Cap ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FXI.P" target="_blank">(FXI.P)</a>还拥有多条平价和上行看涨期权，持仓量相当大，其中包括近 100,000 份合约，执行价为 29.85。该 ETF 周三交易价格为 27.28 美元。</p>   <p>Other large China-focused ETFs, including the iShares MSCI China ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MCHI.O" target="_blank">(MCHI.O)</a>, KraneShares CSI China Internet ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/KWEB.P" target="_blank">(KWEB.P)</a>, also showed upbeat options activity, according to Trade Alert data.翻译:根据 Trade Alert 数据，其他专注于中国的大型 ETF，包括 iShares MSCI 中国 ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MCHI.O" target="_blank">(MCHI.O)</a> 、KraneShares CSI China Internet ETF <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/KWEB.P" target="_blank">(KWEB.P)</a> ，也显示出乐观的期权活动。</p>   <p>"It certainly seems that there is generally bullish positioning ahead of the meeting," said Steve Sosnick, chief strategist at Interactive Brokers, noting that the positions had been built up over several days. "The open interest in options expiring Friday is heavily skewed to the upside."翻译:盈透证券（Interactive Brokers）首席策略师史蒂夫·索斯尼克（Steve Sosnick）表示：“在会议之前，似乎普遍存在看涨头寸。”他指出，这些头寸是在几天内建立起来的。 “周五到期的期权的未平仓合约严重偏向上行。”</p>   <p>While some of the upside positioning may be tied to a rally in the broader equity market - including a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/goldilocks-hopes-return-wall-st-after-benign-inflation-report-2023-11-14/">Tuesday surge</a> that saw the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/goldilocks-hopes-return-wall-st-after-benign-inflation-report-2023-11-14/">S&amp;P 500 rise 1.9%</a> on bets that the Federal Reserve is done hiking interest rates - investors are also likely speculating on a positive outcome from the meeting between Biden and Xi, Sosnick said.翻译:虽然部分上行定位可能与更广泛的股市反弹有关——包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/goldilocks-hopes-return-wall-st-after-benign-inflation-report-2023-11-14/">周二的飙升</a>， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/goldilocks-hopes-return-wall-st-after-benign-inflation-report-2023-11-14/">标普 500 指数因押注美联储不再加息而上涨 1.9%</a> ——但投资者也可能对利好进行投机。索斯尼克表示，拜登和习近平的会晤成果。</p>   <p>"The bullish positioning in ASHR and FXI is almost certainly the result of pre-meeting enthusiasm since it is highly biased to near-term upside calls and the positioning occurred prior to yesterday's run-up," Sosnick said.翻译:Sosnick 表示：“ASHR 和 FXI 的看涨定位几乎肯定是会议前热情的结果，因为它高度偏向于近期上涨的呼声，并且定位发生在昨天的上涨之前。”</p>   <p>Biden and Xi arrived in San Francisco on Tuesday, where they were set to hold their meeting on the sidelines the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit. The meeting is set for 2 p.m. ET (1900 GMT).翻译:拜登和习近平周二抵达旧金山，原定在亚太经合组织（APEC）峰会期间举行会晤。会议定于美国东部时间下午 2 点（格林尼治标准时间 1900）。</p>      <p>Investors' nascent enthusiasm for Chinese stocks is at odds with how these ETF's have performed this year. The largest China-linked ETFs are down anywhere between 3% to 9% for the year. Meanwhile the S&amp;P 500 is up nearly 18%.翻译:投资者对中国股票的热情与这些 ETF 今年的表现不一致。最大的中国相关 ETF 今年下跌了 3% 至 9%。与此同时，标准普尔 500 指数上涨近 18%。</p>   <p>Fund managers in the November BofA Global Research survey named shorting China equities as the market's second "most crowded" trade.翻译:基金经理在 11 月份美国银行全球研究调查中将做空中国股票列为市场第二“最拥挤”的交易。</p>   <p>Daniel Kirsch, head of options at Piper Sandler, said recent bullish options flows into KWEB may be to do with a combination of enthusiasm ahead of the Biden-Xi meeting as well as results from Chinese e-commerce companies JD.com and Alibaba . On Wednesday, JD.com reported a surge in third-quarter profit, while Alibaba results are expected after the close of trading.翻译:Piper Sandler 期权主管 Daniel Kirsch 表示，最近看涨期权流入 KWEB 可能与拜登与习主席会面前的热情以及中国电子商务公司京东和阿里巴巴的业绩有关。周三，京东公布第三季度利润大幅增长，而阿里巴巴的业绩预计将在收盘后公布。</p>   <p>"People are looking for areas that could be catching up (to the rally in broader markets)," Kirsch said.翻译:基尔希表示：“人们正在寻找可能追赶（追赶更广泛市场反弹）的领域。”</p>    <span>Reporting by Saqib Iqbal Ahmed; Additional reporting by Suzanne McGee; Editing by Ira Iosebashvili and Jonathan Oatis翻译:萨奇布·伊克巴尔·艾哈迈德报道；苏珊·麦吉 (Suzanne McGee) 的补充报道；编辑：Ira Iosebashvili 和 Jonathan Oatis</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 18:28:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">NPASMWJJYNLH5A2UTAHMGDIDTY</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/china-linked-etfs-draw-bullish-options-bets-ahead-biden-xi-meet-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Saqib Ahmed]]></author>
            
                
                <category>USA</category>
                
                <category>STOCKS/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ETFS</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[加州会谈后中美推进气候合作]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/UXrIOsXLuqEBGqgp6K0eh3Y4cXw=/1832x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SSSVDHPBXFOYVATNIL6GPT7QVY.jpg" alt="U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry meets with his Chinese counterpart Xie Zhenhua in Beijing翻译:美国总统气候特使约翰·克里在北京会见中国气候变化特使解振华" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry shakes hands with his Chinese counterpart Xie Zhenhua before a meeting in Beijing, China July 17, 2023. REUTERS/Valerie Volcovici/ File Photo翻译:2023 年 7 月 17 日，美国总统气候特使约翰·克里 (John Kerry) 在中国北京举行会议前与中国气候特使解振华握手。 REUTERS/Valerie Volcovici/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>The United States and China will back a new global renewables target and work together on methane and plastic pollution, they said in a joint statement on Wednesday after a meeting to find common ground ahead of COP28 talks in Dubai later this month.翻译:本月晚些时候在迪拜举行的第 28 次缔约方会议 (COP28) 之前，美国和中国举行会议寻找共同点，周三在一份联合声明中表示，美国和中国将支持新的全球可再生能源目标，并在甲烷和塑料污染问题上开展合作。</p>   <p>Climate envoys John Kerry and Xie Zhenhua, meeting in Sunnylands, California, from Nov. 4-8, agreed to revive a bilateral climate working group that will discuss areas of cooperation, the joint statement said, though differences remain on issues like phasing out fossil fuels.翻译:联合声明称，气候特使约翰·克里和解振华于 11 月 4 日至 8 日在加利福尼亚州桑尼兰兹举行会议，同意恢复双边气候工作组，讨论合作领域，尽管在逐步淘汰化石燃料等问题上仍存在分歧燃料。</p>   <p>"The Sunnylands statement is a timely effort of aligning the United States and China ahead of COP28," said Li Shuo, incoming director of the China Climate Hub at the Asia Society.翻译:即将上任的亚洲协会中国气候中心主任李硕表示：“《阳光之乡》的声明是在 COP28 之前协调美国和中国的及时努力。”</p>   <p>Li described the relationship between the world's two biggest greenhouse gas emitters as "a precondition for meaningful global progress" and said the Sunnylands agreement would help "stabilise the politics" ahead of the Dubai talks.翻译:李将世界上最大的两个温室气体排放国之间的关系描述为“全球取得有意义进展的先决条件”，并表示《阳光之乡》协议将有助于在迪拜会谈之前“稳定政治”。</p>   <p>The re-launch of the working group marks the normalisation of the climate relationship between the two countries following a hiatus triggered in 2022 by the visit of former House of Representatives speaker Nancy Pelosi to Taiwan, a self-governing island that China claims as its own.翻译:该工作组的重新启动标志着两国气候关系的正常化，该关系因前众议院议长南希·佩洛西 (Nancy Pelosi) 2022 年访问台湾而中断。台湾是一个中国声称拥有主权的岛屿。 。</p>   <p>Partnership between the world's two biggest emitting countries is seen as a crucial element to securing a consensus agreement at COP28.翻译:世界上两个最大排放国之间的伙伴关系被视为在 COP28 上达成共识协议的关键因素。</p>   <p>For the first time, China - the world's biggest emitter of greenhouse gas emissions - will include non-carbon dioxide greenhouse gases like nitrogen oxide in its 2035 national climate plan as well as specific actions to curb methane emissions, major sources of global emissions.翻译:作为全球最大的温室气体排放国，中国首次将氮氧化物等非二氧化碳温室气体纳入其2035年国家气候计划以及遏制全球主要排放源甲烷排放的具体行动。</p>   <p>"This implies that China needs to do a lot more to be in line with ambitious global goals," said Joanna Lewis, a professor at Georgetown University's School of Foreign Service.翻译:乔治城大学外交学院教授乔安娜·刘易斯表示：“这意味着中国需要做更多的事情来实现雄心勃勃的全球目标。”</p>   <p>It also focuses on key areas of cooperation, including abating methane and boosting efficiency and the "circular economy", and exchanging information on policies and technologies to reduce emissions. The two sides also promised to work together to curb forest loss and plastic pollution.</p>    <h 1="">"WORK CUT OUT"</h>  <p>China's efforts to cut its own carbon emissions will be in sharp focus at COP28, with the country still approving new coal-fired power plants in a bid to ensure energy security.翻译:中国削减自身碳排放的努力将成为COP28的焦点，中国仍在批准新的燃煤电厂以确保能源安全。</p>   <p>The United States and China said they support a declaration by G20 leaders to triple global renewable energy capacity by 2030, and also agreed to "accelerate the substitution for coal, oil and gas generation," which would result in "meaningful absolute power sector emission reductions" this decade.翻译:美国和中国表示，他们支持二十国集团领导人的宣言，即到2030年将全球可再生能源发电能力增加两倍，并同意“加速替代煤炭、石油和天然气发电”，这将导致“电力行业绝对排放量大幅减少” “这十年。</p>   <p>That falls short of calling for the phasing out of fossil fuels, a goal that China has described as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-climate-envoy-says-phasing-out-fossil-fuels-unrealistic-2023-09-22/">"unrealistic"</a>. However, a report released earlier this week said that record levels of new <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-emissions-could-go-into-structural-decline-next-year-research-2023-11-14/">renewable installations</a> in China may help "all but guarantee" a decline in China's CO2 emissions next year.翻译:这还不足以呼吁逐步淘汰化石燃料，中国称这一目标<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-climate-envoy-says-phasing-out-fossil-fuels-unrealistic-2023-09-22/">“不切实际”</a> 。然而，本周早些时候发布的一份报告称，中国新增<a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/china-emissions-could-go-into-structural-decline-next-year-research-2023-11-14/">可再生能源装机</a>量创历史新高，可能有助于“几乎保证”中国明年二氧化碳排放量的下降。</p>   <p>Both sides also agreed to include methane in their 2035 climate goals - the first time China has made such a pledge - and committed to advancing "at least five" large-scale cooperation projects in carbon capture, utilisation and storage by the end of the decade.翻译:双方还同意将甲烷纳入2035年气候目标，这是中国首次做出此类承诺，并承诺到本十年末推进“至少5个”碳捕集、利用和封存大型合作项目。</p>   <p>The joint statement said that the United States, China and COP28 host the United Arab Emirates will hold a Methane and Non-CO2 Greenhouse Gases Summit at COP28.翻译:联合声明称，美国、中国和COP28主办国阿联酋将在COP28期间举行甲烷和非二氧化碳温室气体峰会。</p>   <p>Li said COP28 still "has its work cut out", particularly on fossil fuels.翻译:李说，COP28 仍然“有许多工作要做”，特别是在化石燃料方面。</p>   <p>"China also needs to consider what further ambition can be brought to COP," he added. "Stopping the approval of new coal power projects is a good next step."翻译:“中国还需要考虑可以为缔约方大会带来哪些进一步的雄心，”他补充道。 “停止批准新的煤电项目是下一步的好举措。”</p>    <span>Reporting by David Stanway; Editing by Muralikumar Anantharaman, Raju Gopalakrishnan and Nick Macfie翻译:大卫·斯坦威报道；编辑：Muralikumar Anantharaman、Raju Gopalakrishnan 和 Nick Macfie</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 17:13:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">MMEHXKCLHBMKREBS5CHXKMMOXI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/us-china-pledge-cooperation-climate-following-california-talks-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[David Stanway, Valerie Volcovici]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CLIMATE CHANGE</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA (UPDATE 3)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[日本和中国将就贸易问题举行定期会谈 - 媒体]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ou9Sk6ccXVlkLm_qd6XsyX4MZRo=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TD3VAGTBZVJJ5EH53YM4EBOJHU.jpg" alt="Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida reshuffles his cabinet翻译:日本首相岸田文雄改组内阁" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Japan's Minister of Economy, Trade and Industry Yasutoshi Nishimura walks on the day of the cabinet reshuffle, at the Prime Minister's office in Tokyo, Japan September 13, 2023. REUTERS/Issei Kato/File photo翻译:2023年9月13日，日本经济产业大臣西村康稔在内阁改组当天在日本东京首相办公室散步。路透社/Issei Kato/资料照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>Japanese and Chinese trade ministers have agreed to establish a framework to discuss export controls, Japanese media reported on Wednesday, indicating steps on economic cooperation after a period of strained ties between the neighbours.翻译:据日本媒体周三报道，日本和中国贸易部长已同意建立一个讨论出口管制的框架，这表明在邻国关系紧张一段时间后将采取经济合作措施。</p>   <p>Japanese Trade Minister Yasutoshi Nishimura said the talks could help stabilise relations.翻译:日本经济产业大臣西村康稔表示，会谈有助于稳定关系。</p>   <p>"We will hold firm discussions with Chinese officials to build constructive and stable Japan-China relations," Nishimura was quoted as saying after talks with his counterpart, Wang Wentao, on the sidelines of an Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation meeting in San Francisco.翻译:“我们将与中国官员进行坚定的讨论，以建立建设性和稳定的日中关系，”西村在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织会议期间与外长王文涛会谈后表示。</p>   <p>The dialogue is expected to be held by officials at the level of director-general and section chief, who are in charge of export controls, the Yomiuri newspaper reported.翻译:据《读卖新闻》报道，此次对话预计将由负责出口管制的总干事和科长级别的官员举行。</p>   <p>China has recently imposed curbs on the exports of some materials, including chipmaking metals like <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-export-curbs-choke-off-shipments-gallium-germanium-second-month-2023-10-20/">gallium</a>, and is expected to restrict exports of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-ups-critical-minerals-heat-with-graphite-controls-2023-10-24/">graphite</a>, used in batteries, in December.翻译:中国最近对一些材料的出口实施了限制，包括<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-export-curbs-choke-off-shipments-gallium-germanium-second-month-2023-10-20/">镓</a>等芯片制造金属，并预计将于 12 月限制用于电池的<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/china-ups-critical-minerals-heat-with-graphite-controls-2023-10-24/">石墨</a>的出口。</p>   <p>The talks are aimed at preventing an escalation of retaliatory trade disputes with China, the Yomiuri reported.翻译:据《读卖新闻》报道，此次会谈旨在防止与中国的报复性贸易争端升级。</p>   <p>Before heading to the U.S. to attend the APEC meeting, Kishida told reporters nothing has been decided regarding a meeting with China's leader Xi Jinping on the sidelines.翻译:在前往美国参加亚太经合组织会议之前，岸田告诉记者，关于与中国领导人习近平会面的事宜尚未做出任何决定。</p>   <p>"There is no change in our basic stance that both sides must make the effort to maintain stable and constructive relations," Kishida said. "We would like to continue communicating (with China) in various forms."翻译:岸田说：“我们的基本立场没有改变，即双方必须努力维持稳定和建设性的关系。” “我们愿意继续以各种形式（与中国）进行沟通。”</p>   <p>Relations between China and Japan, rarely smooth, have been particularly strained over recent months.翻译:中国和日本之间的关系绝非一帆风顺，近几个月来尤其紧张。</p>   <p>Japan <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japan-says-harassment-calls-china-regarding-fukushima-water-release-extremely-2023-08-28/">infuriated </a>China when it began releasing treated radioactive water from its wrecked Fukushima nuclear plant into the ocean in August.翻译:日本八月开始将受损福岛核电站处理过的放射性水排入海洋， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japan-says-harassment-calls-china-regarding-fukushima-water-release-extremely-2023-08-28/">激怒了</a>中国。</p>   <p>China <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-formally-arrests-astellas-employee-suspected-spying-japan-urges-release-2023-10-19/">last month</a> formally arrested a Japanese executive, an employee of Japanese drugmaker Astellas Pharma <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/4503.T" target="_blank">(4503.T)</a>, on suspicion of espionage. The arrest has had a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/how-an-executives-arrest-struck-blow-japan-china-business-2023-11-14/">chilling effect</a> on business, Japanese officials said.翻译:中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-formally-arrests-astellas-employee-suspected-spying-japan-urges-release-2023-10-19/">上个月</a>以涉嫌间谍罪正式逮捕了一名日本制药商安斯泰来制药公司<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/4503.T" target="_blank">（Astellas Pharma，4503.T）</a>员工的日本高管。日本官员表示，这次逮捕对商业产生了<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/how-an-executives-arrest-struck-blow-japan-china-business-2023-11-14/">寒蝉效应</a>。</p>    <span>Reporting by Satoshi Sugiyama and Sakura Murakami; Editing by Jan Harvey and Robert Birsel翻译:杉山聪和村上樱的报道；扬·哈维和罗伯特·伯塞尔编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 11:20:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6C2CTCIDOBI3NKAZFZDKRPRQBE</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/japan-china-hold-regular-talks-trade-issues-media-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>JAPAN</category>
                
                <category>CHINA/TRADE (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[拜登和习近平将在受阿片类药物危机困扰的城市讨论芬太尼]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/OOzC6ioQ-mgW-8aYP2bkIe3IQFc=/1200x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZCI4IIB2RNMYHP6QARETZE2TBM.jpg" alt="U.S. Customs and Border Protection photo of packets of fentanyl mostly in powder form and methamphetamine which U.S. Customs and Border Protection say they seized from a truck crossing into Arizona from Mexico翻译:美国海关和边境保护局照片，其中大部分是粉末形式的芬太尼和甲基苯丙胺，美国海关和边境保护局表示，他们从一辆从墨西哥进入亚利桑那州的卡车上查获了这些物品" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Packets of fentanyl mostly in powder form and methamphetamine, which U.S. Customs and Border Protection say they seized from a truck crossing into Arizona from Mexico, is on display during a news conference at the Port of Nogales, Arizona, U.S., January 31, 2019.   Courtesy U.S. Customs and Border Protection/Handout via REUTERS /File Photo翻译:2019 年 1 月 31 日，在美国亚利桑那州诺加利斯港举行的新闻发布会上，美国海关和边境保护局表示，他们从一辆从墨西哥进入亚利桑那州的卡车上查获了几包芬太尼和甲基苯丙胺，这些芬太尼主要是粉末形式和甲基苯丙胺。由美国海关和边境保护局提供/来自路透社的讲义/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/TG1TEqoix0BmSLzAs_2ZQkKdhx0=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XVZII463FBIDNM7WDJMOYPZZ6Q.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden disembarks from Air Force One at San Francisco International Airport, as he arrives to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023 年 11 月 14 日，美国总统乔·拜登在旧金山国际机场从空军一号下机，抵达美国加利福尼亚州旧金山参加亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会。 REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/档案照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/lTdjpZN9pb-WDBwFVbkn4Qq-Rig=/1878x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JFCDJ65EHNIW7MVYN3IPSOJ6AQ.jpg" alt="APEC Summit in San Francisco翻译:APEC峰会在旧金山举行" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>Chinese President Xi Jinping waves as he arrives at San Francisco International Airport to attend the APEC (Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation) Summit in San Francisco, California, U.S., November 14, 2023. REUTERS/Brittany Hosea-Small/File Photo翻译:2023年11月14日，中国国家主席习近平抵达旧金山国际机场，出席在美国加利福尼亚州旧金山举行的APEC（亚太经合组织）峰会。路透社/Brittany Hosea-Small/资料照片</figcaption></figure>                 <p>Just blocks from where U.S. President Joe Biden and his Chinese counterpart Xi Jinping will meet other Asia-Pacific leaders this week in San Francisco is a neighborhood where it is commonplace to see people using and selling drugs.翻译:距离美国总统乔·拜登和中国国家主席习近平本周在旧金山会见其他亚太领导人的地点仅几个街区，在这个街区，人们吸毒和贩卖毒品的现象司空见惯。</p>   <p>While the leaders are unlikely to see the blunt reality of the U.S. opioid crisis as they attend the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum, it will be a topic of discussion when <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">Biden and Xi meet</a> one-on-one on Wednesday.翻译:尽管领导人在出席亚太经合组织（APEC）论坛时不太可能看到美国阿片类药物危机的严峻现实，但这将成为<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/what-expect-when-biden-meets-xi-jinping-san-francisco-2023-11-14/">拜登和习近平周三一对一会面</a>时讨论的话题。</p>   <p>The United States wants China's cooperation to stop an illicit flow of "precursor" chemicals that are used to make fentanyl, which is up to 50 times stronger than heroin and is increasingly mixed with other drugs - often with lethal results.翻译:美国希望与中国合作，制止用于制造芬太尼的“前体”化学品的非法流动，芬太尼的浓度比海洛因高出 50 倍，并且越来越多地与其他药物混合 - 往往会造成致命的后果。</p>   <p>In the first nine months of this year, 619 people died of an opioid overdose in San Francisco, most related to the synthetic opioids, compared with 647 such deaths in the whole of 2022, according to the city's Office of the Chief Medical Examiner.翻译:据旧金山首席法医办公室称，今年前 9 个月，旧金山有 619 人死于阿片类药物过量，其中大部分与合成阿片类药物有关，而 2022 年全年此类死亡人数为 647 人。</p>   <p>"It's out of control," said Mike Odeh, 36, a salesperson at a liquor store near where APEC leaders will meet.翻译:“事情已经失控了，”36 岁的迈克·奥德 (Mike Odeh) 说，他是 APEC 领导人会面地点附近一家酒类商店的销售人员。</p>   <p>He said that while the city had been cleaning up the streets ahead of APEC, he normally sees people using fentanyl while walking his son to the park and to school, adding: "You can see it all over. Not this week of course."翻译:他说，虽然该市在亚太经合组织之前一直在清理街道，但他通常会看到人们在送儿子去公园和上学时使用芬太尼，并补充道：“你可以看到这一切。当然不是本周。”</p>   <p>Across the country the rate of drug overdose deaths involving fentanyl more than tripled from 2016 through 2021, according to the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Tens of thousands of people die annually from synthetic opioid overdoses, government statistics show.翻译:根据美国疾病控制与预防中心 (CDC) 的数据，从 2016 年到 2021 年，全国范围内涉及芬太尼的药物过量死亡率增加了两倍多。政府统计数据显示，每年有数万人死于合成阿片类药物过量。</p>   <p>U.S. National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan said on Tuesday that Washington hoped the Biden-Xi summit would result in action to combat the fentanyl trade. A source familiar with plans said the U.S. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-set-take-action-win-chinas-cooperation-fentanyl-2023-11-14/">was ready to remove</a> restrictions on the Institute of Forensic Science, part of China's Ministry of Public Security.翻译:美国国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文周二表示，华盛顿希望拜登与习近平的峰会能够采取行动打击芬太尼贸易。一位熟悉计划的消息人士称，美国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us-set-take-action-win-chinas-cooperation-fentanyl-2023-11-14/">准备取消</a>对中国公安部司法鉴定所的限制。</p>   <p>Washington put the institute on the Commerce Department's "entity list" in 2020 over alleged abuses toward Uyghurs and other minority groups - effectively barring it from receiving U.S. exports. China has long questioned why the U.S. would expect cooperation on fentanyl while targeting the institute.</p>    <h 1="">CHINA, MEXICO, US STANCES</h>  <p>China's embassy in Washington declined to comment on the fentanyl issue. Chinese state media has repeatedly said addiction and demand for the drug are U.S. domestic problems.翻译:中国驻华盛顿大使馆拒绝就芬太尼问题发表评论。中国官方媒体多次表示，这种药物的成瘾和需求是美国的国内问题。</p>   <p>U.S. officials say that small chemical businesses in China make precursor chemicals that are shipped to Mexico to produce illicit fentanyl, which is often mixed with other illegal drugs, sold as powders and nasal sprays, and increasingly turned into pills that look like legitimate prescription opioids. These are then smuggled into the United States, the officials say.翻译:美国官员表示，中国的小型化学企业生产前体化学品，然后运往墨西哥生产非法芬太尼，芬太尼通常与其他非法药物混合，以粉末和鼻喷雾剂的形式出售，并越来越多地制成看起来像合法处方阿片类药物的药丸。官员们说，这些东西随后被走私到美国。</p>   <p>Last month, the United States imposed sanctions on 28 people and entities involved with the international proliferation of illicit drugs, including a large China-based network.翻译:上个月，美国对 28 名参与国际非法毒品扩散的个人和实体实施制裁，其中包括一个大型中国网络。</p>   <p>"We know that this global fentanyl supply chain, which ends with the deaths of Americans, often starts with chemical companies in China," said U.S. Attorney General Merrick Garland.翻译:美国司法部长梅里克·加兰表示：“我们知道，这条以美国人死亡为终点的全球芬太尼供应链，往往始于中国的化学公司。”</p>   <p>Advocates have also accused pharmaceutical companies and related businesses of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/rite-aid-joins-companies-going-bankrupt-amid-opioid-litigation-2023-10-16/">fueling the crisis</a> through downplaying the risks of opioids and lack of regulation. Landmark settlements since 2021 have set compensation at a total of <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/groups-fighting-us-opioid-crisis-settlement-money-can-be-hard-come-by-2023-06-17/">more than $50 billion nationwide</a>.翻译:支持者还指责制药公司和相关企业淡化阿片类药物的风险和缺乏监管，从而<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/rite-aid-joins-companies-going-bankrupt-amid-opioid-litigation-2023-10-16/">加剧了危机</a>。自 2021 年以来，具有里程碑意义的和解协议已将<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/groups-fighting-us-opioid-crisis-settlement-money-can-be-hard-come-by-2023-06-17/">全国范围内的赔偿总额定为超过 500 亿美元</a>。</p>   <p>Biden is also due to meet with <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/mexicos-president-meet-chinese-counterpart-apec-summit-minister-2023-11-14/">Mexican President</a> Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador in San Francisco. Mexican Foreign Minister Alicia Barcena said talks would include how to better control the arrival from Asia of precursors used to make fentanyl.翻译:拜登还将于旧金山会见<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/mexicos-president-meet-chinese-counterpart-apec-summit-minister-2023-11-14/">墨西哥总统</a>安德烈斯·曼努埃尔·洛佩兹·奥夫拉多尔。墨西哥外交部长阿丽西娅·巴尔塞纳表示，会谈将包括如何更好地控制来自亚洲的用于制造芬太尼的前体。</p>   <p>In San Francisco, state and local officials have tried to clean up drugs from the city's streets, with limited success. The crisis has drawn sharp criticism from residents in the city, where drug-fuelled crime has forced some businesses to leave.翻译:在旧金山，州和地方官员试图清除该市街道上的毒品，但收效甚微。这场危机引起了该市居民的尖锐批评，毒品犯罪迫使一些企业离开。</p>   <p>San Francisco's new district attorney, Brooke Jenkins, has made prosecuting drug dealers a cornerstone of her agenda. The city recently formed a law enforcement task force to investigate opioid-linked deaths and poisonings.翻译:旧金山新任地方检察官布鲁克·詹金斯 (Brooke Jenkins) 将起诉毒贩作为她议程的基石。该市最近成立了一个执法工作组，调查与阿片类药物相关的死亡和中毒事件。</p>   <p>The city's Mayor London Breed has pushed to prioritize treatment for drug users, talked of police action as a way to solve the problem, and has called on the federal government to boost its drug trafficking enforcement.翻译:该市市长伦敦·布里德（London Breed）推动优先考虑吸毒者的治疗，谈到警方采取行动作为解决问题的一种方式，并呼吁联邦政府加强对贩毒的执法力度。</p>   <p>"We know San Francisco - and cities across the United States - will benefit from more targeting of the trafficking and production of fentanyl worldwide," a spokesperson for Breed said in a statement.翻译:布里德发言人在一份声明中表示：“我们知道，旧金山以及美国各地的城市将受益于全球范围内更多针对芬太尼贩运和生产的打击。”</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Michael Martina; Writing by Sayantani Ghosh and Michelle Nichols; Editing by Josie Kao翻译:迈克尔·玛蒂娜 (Michael Martina) 的补充报道；由 Sayantani Ghosh 和 Michelle Nichols 撰写；编辑：高乔茜</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 07:03:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">67JHX74B4BIPXL3MEJMYDJ3MRI</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/biden-xi-talk-fentanyl-city-gripped-by-opioid-crisis-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Peter Henderson, Anna Tong, Trevor Hunnicutt]]></author>
            
                
                <category>APEC</category>
                
                <category>USA/CHINA</category>
                
                <category>FENTANYL (PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国工厂产量和消费超出预期，但房地产仍拖累经济]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Summary:<ul> <li>Industrial output, retail sales growth better than expected</li>  <li>Property sales extend declines, investment slumps</li>  <li>Oct indicators still show significant areas of economic weakness</li>  <li>Economists expect RRR, interest rate cuts</li> </ul>翻译:概括：<ul><li>工业产出、零售额增速好于预期</li><li>房地产销售延续下滑，投资下滑</li><li>10 月指标仍显示经济显着疲软</li><li>经济学家预计存款准备金率、降息</li></ul>      <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/LTq4T77li8f_4bULKrm5bT1ogEs=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/KIYGJWK6EFJNVKRZ5J5SSLFNOU.jpg" alt="FILE PHOTO: Leapmotor's EV production line in Jinhua翻译:资料图：零跑汽车位于金华的电动汽车生产线" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>FILE PHOTO: Robotic arms assemble cars in the production line for Leapmotor's electric vehicles at a factory in Jinhua, Zhejiang province, China, April 26, 2023. China Daily via REUTERS/File Photo翻译:资料照片：2023 年 4 月 26 日，中国浙江省金华市一家工厂，机械臂在零跑电动汽车生产线上组装汽车。《中国日报》来自路透社/资料照片</figcaption></figure>    <figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/L7KVqCa_-hprbq8GJSuMHMR2QR4=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/77V6VO752FLN7CTZ4APEUIYDHU.jpg" alt="National Day holiday, in Shanghai翻译:国庆假期，上海" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>People walk along Nanjing Pedestrian Road, a main shopping area, ahead of the National Day holiday, in Shanghai翻译:国庆假期，上海, China September 26, 2023. REUTERS/Aly Song/File Photo翻译:2023年9月26日，中国上海，国庆假期前夕，人们沿着主要购物区南京步行路行走。路透社/Aly Song/资料照片</figcaption></figure>               <p>China's industrial output and retail sales growth beat expectations in October, but the underlying economic picture highlighted significant pockets of weakness with the crisis-hit property sector continuing to forestall a full-blown revival.翻译:中国10月份的工业产出和零售销售增长超出预期，但基本经济形势凸显了显着的疲软，受危机打击的房地产行业继续阻碍全面复苏。</p>   <p>The world's second-biggest economy has struggled to mount a strong post-COVID recovery as distress in the housing market, local government debt risks, slow global growth and geopolitical tensions have dented momentum. A flurry of policy support measures have proven only modestly beneficial, raising pressure on authorities to roll out more stimulus.翻译:由于房地产市场低迷、地方政府债务风险、全球经济增长缓慢和地缘政治紧张局势削弱了经济增长势头，全球第二大经济体在新冠疫情后一直难以实现强劲复苏。事实证明，一系列政策支持措施的效果有限，这加大了当局推出更多刺激措施的压力。</p>   <p>China's industrial output grew 4.6% in October year-on-year, accelerating from the 4.5% pace seen in September, data from the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) showed on Wednesday, beating expectations for a 4.4% increase in a Reuters poll. It also marked the strongest growth since April.翻译:中国国家统计局(NBS)周三公布的数据显示，中国10月份工业产出同比增长4.6%，较9月份的4.5%有所加快，超过路透调查中4.4%的增长预期。这也标志着自四月份以来最强劲的增长。</p>   <p>Retail sales rose 7.6% in October with improvement in both auto and restaurant sales growth, quickening from a 5.5% gain in September and hitting the fastest pace since May. Analysts had expected retail sales to grow 7.0% due to the low base effect in 2022 when COVID curbs disrupted consumers and businesses.翻译:10 月份零售额增长 7.6%，汽车和餐饮销售增长均有所改善，增速较 9 月份 5.5% 有所加快，达到 5 月份以来的最快增速。分析师此前预计，由于 2022 年新冠疫情遏制扰乱了消费者和企业，基数较低，零售额将增长 7.0%。</p>      <p>Analysts struck a cautious note on the upside data surprise, noting that the property sector remains a weak link for the economy and pointed to the lack of major <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-choose-fiscal-muscle-over-big-reforms-revive-economy-2023-10-24/">reforms</a> as another impediment to sustainable longer term revival in growth.翻译:分析师对意外的上行数据持谨慎态度，指出房地产行业仍然是经济的薄弱环节，并指出缺乏重大<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-choose-fiscal-muscle-over-big-reforms-revive-economy-2023-10-24/">改革</a>是可持续长期增长复苏的另一个障碍。</p>   <p>"Due to the impact of holidays and low base effect in 2022, year-on-year figures cannot reflect the actual momentum of the economy," said Xing Zhaopeng, senior China strategist at ANZ.翻译:澳新银行高级中国策略师邢兆鹏表示，“由于2022年假期影响和低基数效应，同比数据无法反映经济的实际动力。”</p>   <p>He said month-on-month figures suggest economic momentum has further weakened with "increasing deflationary risks".翻译:他表示，环比数据表明，随着“通缩风险增加”，经济势头进一步减弱。</p>   <p>Louise Loo, China economist at Oxford Economics, said prolonged weakness in external demand could hamper industrial production despite strengthening last month as destocking pressures eased further.翻译:牛津经济研究院(Oxford Economics)中国经济学家Louise Loo表示，尽管上个月随着去库存压力进一步缓解，外部需求有所增强，但长期疲软可能会阻碍工业生产。</p>   <p>Consumption didn't make much headway either during the eight-day Golden Week holiday earlier in October. Trips made in that period missed government estimate as economists say consumers are concerned about their jobs and income growth in an uncertain employment market.翻译:十月初的八天黄金周假期期间，消费也没有取得太大进展。经济学家表示，这一时期的旅行人数未达到政府的预期，因为消费者担心就业市场不确定性下的工作和收入增长。</p>   <p>The nationwide survey-based jobless rate stayed at 5.0% in October, unchanged from September, the NBS data showed. Youth unemployment, which hit a record high 21.3% in June, wasn't available after the statistics bureau stopped publishing it since July.翻译:国家统计局数据显示，10月份全国调查失业率保持在5.0%，与9月份持平。统计局自7月起停止发布青年失业率后，6月份青年失业率创下历史新高21.3%。</p>   <p>China has been ramping up efforts to revive its post-COVID economy with a slew of policy support measures in recent months, although the positive effects have been marginal so far.翻译:近几个月来，中国一直在加大力度通过一系列政策支持措施重振后疫情时代的经济，但迄今为止积极效果甚微。</p>   <p>Wednesday's upbeat data comes as a raft of other indicators for October released over recent weeks pointed to muted growth momentum. Imports grew unexpectedly, but exports shrank at a quicker pace, household borrowing remained weak, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">consumer prices</a> swung lower while factory deflation persisted.翻译:周三公布乐观数据之际，近几周发布的 10 月份其他一系列指标均显示增长势头疲弱。进口意外增长，但出口萎缩加快，家庭借贷依然疲弱， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">消费者价格</a>下跌，而工厂通货紧缩持续存在。</p>   <p>Authorities are faced with a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/part-chinas-economic-miracle-was-mirage-reality-check-is-next-2023-09-03/">challenging task</a> as any aggressive monetary support would further widen interest rate differentials between China and the West, especially the United States, and dent an already weakened yuan. That could intensify capital outflows, while Beijing is wary of a return to the big-bang fiscal stimulus of the past which created massive debt and hamstrung the economy.翻译:当局面临着一项<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/part-chinas-economic-miracle-was-mirage-reality-check-is-next-2023-09-03/">艰巨的任务</a>，因为任何激进的货币支持都将进一步扩大中国与西方（尤其是美国）之间的利差，并削弱本已疲软的人民币。这可能会加剧资本外流，而北京方面则对回到过去的大规模财政刺激措施持谨慎态度，这种财政刺激措施造成了巨额债务并阻碍了经济。</p>   <p>The economy grew faster-than-expected in the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">third quarter</a>, with analysts generally expecting it to reach the government's full-year growth target of around 5%, though a full-blown recovery is still some time away.翻译:<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q3-gdp-grows-49-yy-above-market-forecast-2023-10-18/">第三季度</a>经济增长快于预期，分析师普遍预计将达到政府5%左右的全年增长目标，但全面复苏尚需时日。</p>   <p>The yuan held near a more than two-month high after surprisingly softer U.S. inflation reading overnight boosted bets that the Federal Reserve had reached the end of its tightening cycle.</p>    <h 1="">PROPERTY, INVESTMENT DISAPPOINT</h>  <p>The country's central bank, People's Bank of China (PBOC), <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cbank-boosts-liquidity-injection-through-policy-loan-rate-unchanged-2023-11-15/">boosted liquidity injections</a> but kept the interest rate unchanged when rolling over maturing medium-term policy loans on Wednesday.翻译:周三，中国央行中国人民银行在展期到期中期政策贷款时<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cbank-boosts-liquidity-injection-through-policy-loan-rate-unchanged-2023-11-15/">加大了流动性注入力度</a>，但维持利率不变。</p>   <p>In a rare revision last month, the government also lifted its 2023 budget deficit to around 3.8% of gross domestic product from 3% to account for the planned issuance of 1 trillion yuan ($137.10 billion) in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/chinas-new-bonds-help-economic-recovery-official-says-budget-deficit-rises-2023-10-25/">sovereign bonds</a>.翻译:上个月，政府罕见地进行了修订，将2023年预算赤字占国内生产总值的比例从3%提高到3.8%左右，以占计划发行1万亿元人民币（1,371亿美元） <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/rates-bonds/chinas-new-bonds-help-economic-recovery-official-says-budget-deficit-rises-2023-10-25/">主权债券</a>的比例。</p>   <p>The PBOC has cut banks' reserve requirement ratio (RRR) twice this year to free up liquidity to aid the economic recovery. Analysts widely expect another RRR cut and an interest rate cut in the final months of this year.翻译:中国人民银行今年已两次下调银行存款准备金率（RRR），以释放流动性以帮助经济复苏。分析师普遍预计今年最后几个月将再次下调存款准备金率和利率。</p>   <p>China's crisis-hit <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/">property sector</a> has yet to see a meaningful rebound despite strengthened <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-its-indebted-property-sector-2023-11-08/">support</a> measures for homebuyers, including relaxing of home purchase restrictions, lowering in borrowing costs and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-is-eyeing-137-bln-new-funding-boost-housing-market-bloomberg-news-2023-11-14/">other programmes.</a>翻译:尽管中国加强了对购房者<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-measures-shore-up-its-indebted-property-sector-2023-11-08/">的支持</a>措施，包括放宽购房限制、降低借贷成本等，但受危机打击的中国<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/">房地产行业</a>尚未出现有意义的反弹<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/china-is-eyeing-137-bln-new-funding-boost-housing-market-bloomberg-news-2023-11-14/">。</a></p>   <p>Property investment fell 9.3% in January-October year-on-year, after a similarly sharp 9.1% drop in January-September.翻译:继1-9月大幅下降9.1%之后，1-10月房地产投资同比下降9.3%。</p>   <p>Fixed asset investment disappointed with a 2.9% expansion year-on-year in the first 10 months, missing expectations for a 3.1% rise. It grew 3.1% in the January-September period.翻译:前10个月固定资产投资同比增长2.9%，低于预期的3.1%。 1-9月增长3.1%。</p>   <p>Confidence among private businesses also remained depressed, with investment in the sector shrinking 0.5% during January-October, narrowing slightly from the 0.6% decline in the first nine months.翻译:私营企业信心依然低迷，1-10月该行业投资下降0.5%，较前9个月0.6%的降幅略有收窄。</p>   <p>"Overall, the data published today suggest that the recovery was struggling to gain a strong footing at the start of Q4, but it was not nearly as weak as some had feared," said Sheana Yue, China economist at Capital Economics.翻译:凯投宏观(Capital Economics)中国经济学家谢娜·岳(Sheana Yue)表示：“总体而言，今天公布的数据表明，第四季度初经济复苏正在努力站稳脚跟，但并不像一些人担心的那么疲软。”</p>   <p>"Policy looks set to remain supportive, and possibly even stepped up to prevent the economy from backsliding."翻译:“政策看起来将继续保持支持性，甚至可能加强以防止经济倒退。”</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2939 Chinese yuan renminbi)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2939 人民币）</p>    <span>Additional reporting by Albee Zhang and Liangping Gao;
Editing by Shri Navaratnam翻译:Albee 张和亮平高的补充报道；编辑：Shri Navaratnam</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:38:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">TPUCTHUAIJI75IGHIQFYSOENNM</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Ellen Zhang, Kevin Yao]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/ACTIVITY (WRAPUP 3, PIX)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国房地产销售延续下滑，前景承压]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/ZK7QFM-uFu1AqxVmYfclsK8eU-g=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/K7JAUPVPWJLGZFL45JNDNQEUR4.jpg" alt="A man rides a scooter past apartment highrises that are under construction near the new stadium in Zhengzhou翻译:一名男子骑着摩托车经过郑州新体育场附近正在建设的高层公寓" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A man rides a scooter past apartment highrises that are under construction near the new stadium in Zhengzhou翻译:一名男子骑着摩托车经过郑州新体育场附近正在建设的高层公寓, Henan province, China, January 19, 2019.  Picture taken January 19, 2019.  REUTERS/Thomas Peter/File Photo翻译:2019年1月19日，一名男子骑着摩托车经过中国河南省郑州新体育场附近正在建设的公寓高层建筑。照片拍摄于2019年1月19日。路透社/Thomas Peter/档案照片</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's property sales fell at a faster pace in October and investment in real estate slumped, official data showed on Wednesday, suggesting the crisis-hit sector is yet to emerge from its decline despite Beijing's recent support efforts.翻译:周三官方数据显示，中国10月份房地产销售下降速度加快，房地产投资大幅下滑，这表明尽管北京方面最近采取了支持措施，但受危机打击的行业尚未摆脱衰退。</p>   <p>Property sales by floor area fell 20.33% year-on-year against a 19.77% fall in September, according to Reuters calculations based on data released by the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS).翻译:路透社根据国家统计局公布的数据计算，房屋销售面积同比下降20.33%，而9月份则下降19.77%。</p>   <p>Sales fell 7.8% year-on-year in January-October, compared with a 7.5% slide in the first nine months of 2023.翻译:1-10月销售额同比下降7.8%，而2023年前9个月则下滑7.5%。</p>   <p>Authorities have been ramping up measures to support real estate, including relaxing home purchase restrictions and lowering borrowing costs, although these have failed to shore up a meaningful recovery in major cities.翻译:当局一直在加大支持房地产的措施，包括放宽购房限制和降低借贷成本，尽管这些措施未能支撑主要城市的有意义的复苏。</p>   <p>Recent economic data has been mixed with industrial output and retail sales both <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/">beating expectations</a> in October although other indicators such as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-imports-unexpectedly-grow-oct-exports-extend-declines-2023-11-07/">exports</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">consumer prices</a> point to persistent drags on growth.翻译:最近的经济数据好坏参半，10 月份工业产出和零售销售均<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-factory-output-retail-sales-beat-expectations-boost-economic-recovery-2023-11-15/">超出预期</a>，尽管<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-imports-unexpectedly-grow-oct-exports-extend-declines-2023-11-07/">出口</a>和<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-oct-consumer-prices-fall-faster-than-expected-2023-11-09/">消费者价格</a>等其他指标表明经济增长持续受到拖累。</p>   <p>While a twice-a-decade financial policy meeting last month offered few surprises for the property market, authorities remain concerned about risks that could spill into other industries, threatening financial stability.翻译:尽管上个月举行的十年两次的金融政策会议没有给房地产市场带来什么惊喜，但当局仍然担心风险可能蔓延到其他行业，威胁金融稳定。</p>   <p>China plans to provide at least 1 trillion yuan ($137 billion) of low-cost financing to the urban village renovations and affordable housing programs, Bloomberg News reported on Tuesday, citing people familiar with the matter.翻译:彭博新闻社周二援引知情人士的话报道称，中国计划为城中村改造和保障性住房项目提供至少 1 万亿元人民币（合 1,370 亿美元）的低成本融资。</p>   <p>Reuters previously reported a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">state-engineered rescue</a> of Country Garden <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">(2007.HK)</a> by Ping An Insurance Group <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601318.SS" target="_blank">(601318.SS)</a>, which would be one of the most significant interventions to date by China to support the sector, though Ping An has repeatedly denied the rescue plan.翻译:路透社此前报道称，平安保险集团<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/601318.SS" target="_blank">（601318.SS）</a>对碧桂园<a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/2007.HK" target="_blank">（2007.HK）</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-authorities-ask-ping-an-take-controlling-stake-country-garden-sources-say-2023-11-08/">进行了国家设计的救助</a>，这将是迄今为止中国支持该行业的最重大干预措施之一，尽管平安一再表示否认了救援计划。</p>   <p>Property investment fell 16.7% from a year earlier after an 18.7% slide in September, according to Reuters calculations.翻译:据路透社计算，房地产投资继 9 月份下降 18.7% 后，同比下降 16.7%。</p>   <p>New construction starts measured by floor area fell 23.2% year-on-year, after a 23.4% slump in the first nine months.翻译:按建筑面积计算的新开工面积同比下降 23.2%，前 9 个月下降 23.4%。</p>   <p>Funds raised by China's property developers were down 13.8% year-on-year after a 13.5% fall in January-September.翻译:继1-9月下降13.5%之后，中国房地产开发商募集资金同比下降13.8%。</p>    <span>Reporting by Liangping Gao, Ella Cao and Ryan Woo; Editing by Sam Holmes翻译:高亮平、曹艾拉、吴瑞安报道；山姆·霍姆斯编辑</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 03:13:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">FRN3TIHRYNMKPIIVX77TKE57ZU</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-jan-oct-property-sales-fell-68-yy-investment-down-93-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/PROPERTY</category>
                
                <category>INVESTMENT (UPDATE 1)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[中国银行通过政策性贷款加大流动性注入，利率不变]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/5WpBhmWCsz2HDENvuzwOegpnOyA=/1920x0/filters:quality(80)/cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YFL7JVKIYBLCNORUY7KN3GS4TA.jpg" alt="A gardener works outside the headquarters of the central bank of the People's Republic of China in Beijing翻译:一名园丁在北京中央银行总部外工作" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"><figcaption>A gardener works outside the headquarters of the central bank of the People's Republic of China in Beijing翻译:一名园丁在北京中央银行总部外工作 October 8, 2008. External and internal conditions are ripe for China to cut interest rates soon to give the economy a lift, an official newspaper said in a front-page commentary on Wednesday. REUTERS/Jason Lee (CHINA)翻译:2008年10月8日，北京，一名园丁在中华人民共和国央行总部外工作。一份官方报纸在头条新闻中称，中国近期降息提振经济的内外条件已经成熟。周三的版面评论。路透社/Jason Lee（中国）</figcaption></figure>       <p>China's central bank ramped up liquidity injection but kept the interest rate unchanged when rolling over maturing medium-term policy loans on Wednesday, matching market expectations.翻译:中国央行周三加大流动性注入力度，但在到期中期政策贷款展期时保持利率不变，符合市场预期。</p>   <p>Market participants believe that a weakening Chinese yuan has constrained the central bank's efforts to aggressively lower interest rates even though the recovery of the world's second-largest economy remains uneven and requires further stimulus.翻译:市场人士认为，尽管世界第二大经济体的复苏仍不平衡，需要进一步刺激，但人民币贬值限制了央行大幅降息的努力。</p>   <p>The People's Bank of China (PBOC) said it was keeping the rate on 1.45 trillion yuan ($199.92 billion) worth of one-year medium-term lending facility (MLF) loans to some financial institutions unchanged at 2.50% from the previous operation.翻译:中国人民银行（PBOC）表示，将向部分金融机构发放的 1.45 万亿元人民币（合 1,999.2 亿美元）的一年期中期借贷便利（MLF）贷款利率维持在 2.50% 不变。</p>   <p>The central bank said the loan operation was meant to maintain banking system liquidity reasonably ample to counteract short-term factors including tax payments and government bond issuance.翻译:央行表示，此次贷款操作旨在保持银行体系流动性合理充裕，以应对纳税、国债发行等短期因素。</p>   <p>"At the same time, it will appropriately provide mid- and long-term base money," the PBOC said in an online statement.翻译:“同时，适当提供中长期基础货币，”中国人民银行在网上发布的声明中表示。</p>   <p>All 31 market watchers polled by Reuters this week had expected the central bank to inject fresh funds to exceed the maturity.翻译:路透社本周调查的 31 名市场观察人士均预计央行将注入新资金以超过到期期限。</p>   <p>With 850 billion yuan worth of MLF loans set to expire this month, the operation resulted a net 600 billion yuan of fresh fund injection into the banking system.翻译:本月8500亿元MLF贷款即将到期，此次操作为银行体系净注入资金6000亿元。</p>   <p>"Weak inflation and the recent liquidity squeeze call for stronger policy support this week," Carlos Casanova, senior economist for Asia at UBP, said in a note this week.翻译:UBP 亚洲高级经济学家卡洛斯·卡萨诺瓦 (Carlos Casanova) 在本周的一份报告中表示，“疲软的通胀和近期的流动性紧缩要求本周采取更强有力的政策支持。”</p>   <p>"Liquidity conditions tightened in October, as a deluge of bond issuance to fund fiscal stimulus and quarter-end cash demand from corporates drove up interbank rates. The most likely outcome is for PBOC to inject more support through open market operations, while leaving the MLF rate unchanged."翻译:“10月份流动性状况收紧，因为为财政刺激提供资金的大量债券发行以及企业季末现金需求推高了银行间利率。最可能的结果是中国人民银行通过公开市场操作注入更多支持，同时退出MLF率不变。”</p>   <p>He added that authorities will remain on alert and continue to support the recovery, expecting another 10-basis-point interest rate cut and an additional RRR cut in December, if not sooner.翻译:他补充说，当局将保持警惕并继续支持经济复苏，预计 12 月份（甚至更早）将再次降息 10 个基点并进一步下调存款准备金率。</p>   <p>The interest rate on one-year AAA-rated negotiable certificates of deposit (NCDs) , which measure short-term inter-bank borrowing costs, is hovering at a six-month high of 2.5653%, about 7 bps higher than the MLF rate the central bank charges financial institutions.翻译:衡量短期银行间借贷成本的一年期AAA级可转让存款证（NCD）利率徘徊在六个月高点2.5653%，比MLF利率高出约7个基点。中央银行向金融机构收取费用。</p>   <p>Wednesday's liquidity support for the nascent economic recovery through the medium-term policy loans has, however, reduced necessity for more imminent monetary stimulus, some traders and analysts said.翻译:然而，一些交易员和分析师表示，周三通过中期政策贷款为新生经济复苏提供的流动性支持降低了迫在眉睫的货币刺激措施的必要性。</p>   <p>"But MLF loans is rather expensive, and we still expect additional reserve requirement ratio (RRR) cuts in the future to reduce (banks) debt costs," said Xing Zhaopeng, senior China strategist at ANZ.翻译:澳新银行高级中国策略师邢兆鹏表示：“但MLF贷款相当昂贵，我们仍然预计未来会进一步下调存款准备金率（RRR），以降低（银行）债务成本。”</p>   <p>China has reported a slew of mixed October economic data, as industrial output and retail sales growth data surprised on the upside, while factory activity unexpectedly contracted and consumer prices continued to fall.翻译:中国公布的10月份经济数据好坏参半，工业产出和零售销售增长数据意外上行，而工厂活动意外收缩，消费者价格继续下跌。</p>   <p>Still, market watchers said the currency remained as a key constraint for the authorities to ease monetary policy. China's yuan has lost about 5% to the dollar so far this year to become one of the worst performing Asian currencies.翻译:尽管如此，市场观察人士表示，人民币汇率仍然是当局放松货币政策的主要制约因素。今年迄今为止，人民币兑美元汇率已下跌约5%，成为表现最差的亚洲货币之一。</p>   <p>The sizable depreciation has prompted authorities to step up efforts to support the currency, with many analysts believing policymakers may view yuan stability as a prerequisite for restoring confidence in yuan assets.翻译:大幅贬值促使当局加大支持人民币的力度，许多分析师认为，政策制定者可能将人民币稳定视为恢复人民币资产信心的先决条件。</p>   <p>China remains an outlier among global central banks as it has loosened monetary policy to shore up a stalling recovery but further rate cuts will widen the yield gap with the United States, putting more pressure on the yuan and risking outflows.翻译:中国在全球央行中仍然是一个异类，因为它已经放松了货币政策以支撑停滞的复苏，但进一步降息将扩大与美国的收益率差距，给人民币带来更大的压力，并带来资金外流的风险。</p>   <p>The central bank also injected 495 billion yuan through seven-day reverse repos while keeping borrowing cost unchanged at 1.80%, it said in the statement.翻译:央行在声明中表示，还通过7天逆回购注入4950亿元人民币，维持借贷成本在1.80%不变。</p>   <p>($1 = 7.2530 yuan)翻译:（1 美元 = 7.2530 元）</p>    <span>Reporting by Winni Zhou and Tom Westbrook; Editing by Christian Schmollinger, Stephen Coates &amp; Shri Navaratnam翻译:Winni Zhou 和 Tom Westbrook 报道；编辑：Christian Schmollinger、Stephen Coates 和 Shri Navaratnam</span>]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 02:42:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">GXDDW2AWXZJSDPGIR6SLALRZD4</guid>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/china-cbank-boosts-liquidity-injection-through-policy-loan-rate-unchanged-2023-11-15/</link>
            
            
            
            <author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author>
            
                
                <category>CHINA</category>
                
                <category>ECONOMY/RATES (UPDATE 2)</category>
                
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
